good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh let's go to
YouTube
let's go to actually I need to go - hold
on a second let's go - I need to go to
my YouTube livestream so I need to go -
I need to go to my channel I need to go
- so sorry I wasn't prepared because so
go to youtube Studio beta you know you
you know you Google always have this
beta software and and the interface
changes all the time then on the new
website then you have you know some old
features you have to click to go back to
old features for example on YouTube you
know that the better I cannot I have to
click to go to this live stream now I
see not sticking okay so back to live
stream now and yes I'm like okay so
switch back to the window
ah so we're gonna talk about I don't
have a topic in mind so we're gonna talk
about random things so just let me just
start talking then so I've been working
on my JavaScript tutorial let's go
through my JavaScript website my
JavaScript web dev blog and I've been
working on you know I've been working on
JavaScript for the AMA tutorial for the
past few we
and I started to write Emacs script
JavaScript 2016 17 18 19 features so
these are the new features now
JavaScript 2015 is a huge change it's
basically a entire new language you have
so many features like over 10 major
features and all the syntax of the
language also gets an upgrade so you
have so many new syntax so it's like a
new language so javascript 2016 there's
nothing much new I mean they they add
small things you know so they added a
new function for array and they added
the power operator which is two
asterisks the power operator you know
this is very convenient because if you
don't have that you use you know the
math dot P o W function which is a pain
then in JavaScript 2017 you have about
five new functions two new functions for
string three new functions for object
data type then you have this whole new
thing about a sync function a sync the
keyword a sink and the keyword await I
don't quite understand that but let me
talk about they are related to
JavaScript promises let me talk about
that and JavaScript 18 also added a
bunch of things I haven't complete this
section yet and JavaScript 19 added
about 6 new functions so yeah javascript
is improving you know every year they
have new a new version JavaScript 19
it's it's already final but the full
spec is not out yet so JavaScript the
process in the new JavaScript version
process is such that
so every year you have a new version and
every year you have a new version and
the process is that people make
proposals and for a proposal for a new
feature and for each proposal you have
four stages for it to become part of the
next version of JavaScript and the
stages are one two three four basically
when a proposal reaches stage four that
means it's final so it's going to be the
next in the next JavaScript expect you
know every year they have a new spec so
so if you want to add some new feature
to JavaScript you you write proposal to
you know the the JavaScript standard
guys by the way let me change the title
so it's correct today is what 28th hi
Israel haven't seen you for a while let
me pop it pop this out so what time is
in Israel let's see
Nile croc in the evening something like
that so Israel says what do you do for
work that you have time to make all
these videos I'm not working that so
that's why I don't have a I'm not
working you know so I make money by
online ads which is about $1000 USD a
month so I am living in poverty below
poverty for the past 10 years so you
know I'm making a neutral you know some
talk show you know when you make a cut
up show when you do videos I always have
this I want to be popular of course when
you are popular you can make money and I
look at all the people also including
for blogs and on Twitter
and so wait stream health is read why is
this read so you know a lot people they
get huge pop you know very popular on
Twitter I see some people you know I
watched them you know since two years
ago from no followers to like tens of
thousand followers and you know that
always kind of annoys me because you
know I do all this work every day right
in you know intensity but I don't get
followers while I see other people I see
what they do you know a lot of people
especially in them programmers you know
they do almost like random stuff
especially today it's popular to do
political talks you know political
commentaries so especially again is you
know the social justice people and
they've become popular you know tens of
thousand followers and so I'm wondering
you know why you know you know why am I
not popular and also among Emacs users
you know I'm well known but not well so
one of the question I'm thinking is that
do you really want to be because in
order to be there are many techniques to
you know the so called SEO or otherwise
you know sales people you know in sales
community sales persons that's a huge
market you know there are thousands of
books written about it and they always
have techniques like how to how do you
frustrate people how do you do the
marketing correctly and I have studied
them basically all my life you know for
10 or 20 years and you know those
techniques in or what you should do you
know how you should post on Twitter
social media there are tons of books on
that and I always it finally comes down
to you know I don't really want to do
the things they do you know they for
example on Twitter you post
you post one-sided stupid opinions you
post soundbites you know thank you for
example a typical example is you know
cat pictures you know as you know since
like 10 years ago 15 years ago they are
a lot so counts they become hugely
popular like let's say few hundred
thousand followers by the way if you are
popular you you make money because if
you are for example if you are if you
have 1 million followers each post you
do sponsored posts you make ten thousand
dollars you know just one post well
anyway so so one example being popular
is you techniques is you post you know
random cat pictures cat pictures you
know photos of things you know strange
things weird things or memes for example
I always viewed those accounts as
scumbags you know and and you know and
and also those people who posting you
know all those photos of architecture or
photo of cats or weird you know photos
or videos you know today you have short
videos like 5 seconds or 10 seconds I
always view them is like scum you know
it's like lower bottom of human society
because what they do first of all or
they oppose basically all of their or
they oppose like 99% of their post is
copyright infringement you know you go
to youtube you you find these cat
pictures or animals or whatever you you
know you edit it you make ten seconds
snip it you know take take the you know
the ten seconds part that's most funny
or something weird then you you you post
your YouTube you know oh you you drove
you you you know go through it reddit
you know there are lots of you know you
got to reddit you get the most popular
you know post and you you grab them you
use you know you take them and post you
to your Twitter without you typically
always never will
with credit like link back to her
original source and and this kind of
behavior has become so extremely popular
in fact it's actually strange to to say
you know where it came from you know the
original source see how people don't and
people don't care about that they just
want to whatever the cat pictures or
architecture building pictures or
whatever you know these are so
technically I mean in some strict sense
of morality these I don't you know they
are not good people I mean they or they
do I mean they they do that just to get
ahead you know just to get more popular
and it became so Punk common you know
it's it's like everyone is doing that
you know since like 15 years ago so you
can't pictures and or that or girls
pictures you know it used to be let's
say five years ago they are dedicated
accounts that just post pretty girls you
know pictures and they get those photos
from you know Instagram or elsewhere you
know it's first of all its copyright in
which infringement and you know society
you know just you just move on people
start to forget that is actually
copyright infringement in fact it's so
common you know it becames like it's a
common practice so you know that's not
what I want to do
okay Israel says I think it's hard to
get popular and you need to up your
production quality and also your desktop
is too messy to get picked up by you by
YouTube algorithm look at how Luke Smith
uses thumbnails yeah so these are the
things you know these are techniques to
get popular in fact there are many
YouTube channels that teach you how
again like I mentioned I studied this
kind of marketing psychology persuasion
I've read you know quite quite a lot
books you know for the in the past 20
years and I've been reading you know
hundreds of SEO articles by the way SC
SEO is kind of falling out of fashion
today you don't see that much anymore
but it was hugely popular but today it's
more on social networks you know social
network techniques instead of SEO SEO is
about search engine optimization
basically meaning you know how to get
your website on the top of such engine
you know on Google you know if you such
a popular subject and if your website is
a number-one link you make a lot money
like few thousand dollars a month but
anyway so what I'm saying is that I act
I kind of I actually know all these
techniques for example you know use
thumbnails you know but these are things
you know that I don't really want you
know it's not something I so much into
doing because if you look at I mean you
can learn these things
in fact YouTube tells you how like if
you go to for example here's a youtube
if you have a if you create YouTube
channels they tell you they have lots of
tips you know ideas because because
first of all YouTube want to sell
themselves the more videos they are the
more they they make money you know so
they tell everyone to how to make you
you know how to make properly market
your videos how you know that what what
equipments to get you know your your
video the camera the what what
microphone to use and so on and and and
there are also videos I mean certainly
there are tons of them
you know usually like a pretty guy or
girl they talk smoothly you know they
tell you oh you know they they have a
good you know smooth you know that's
salesman always smooth when you watch
salesmen maybe car salesmen or the
advertisements you know uncle a TV
commercials they always they are they
should always be appealing to the masses
so these techniques but I find them
rather you know put off I mean they are
like like I said I mentioned before it's
alright to sell your stuff I mean every
of course when you write a book or blog
or video you want to market it because
it's because marking is fundamental you
know with our marketing people don't
know you so marketing is essential I
mean it's a kind of essential in any
capitalistic basically or or today's
industrial countries they are
capitalistic you know wealthy you know
countries like USA including China you
know in Europe so you so marketing is is
necessary and essential I mean as
opposed to some nerds you know some some
of us might think oh marketing is no
good you know as good as your material
is good you don't need marketing that's
not true and poor cover you know what
cover you use what logo you know logo is
actually also important you know it's
just a fact of life so marketing I think
is important but however today on
YouTube is so became so it became such a
self-serving extreme kind of thing you
know it's like you so I mean as an
example you know as an example you go to
YouTube okay let's go to YouTube okay so
for example I go to my YouTube YouTube
channel so I go to youtube and you'll
see YouTube makes recommendations right
let me show you some examples of the
marketing and and why I find them rather
put off you know it's rather it's as
become corrupted it is became you know
into a nature of its own you know which
I don't think is good for society and
you know for example let's look at some
of them game Game of Thrones explain
okay that's fine
first first of all for example this one
censorship packs fires on far-left again
you know first of all lots of them are
quick baits for example if I if I for
example today's video I'm going to make
a title right so I'm going to talk about
okay today's talk show you know titled
Sato show date and and we discuss about
marketing okay that's the proper type of
title you know that's descriptive but if
you actually use that title that's no
good what do you want to do is why
marketing what you know instead you you
want to use some kind of click bait you
know why marketing why why all all about
marketing you know is wrong you know you
want to use that header instead that's
quick bait that's no good because I look
at my youtube I see all these quick
baits you see before example Mike Tyson
the most dangerous boxer in history the
most dangerous you know okay I mean any
kind of video you see quick baits so bad
you know it's like Bernie Sanders is
right about prisoners voting I want to
pick some examples I want to I want to
pick some egregious bad clickbait
examples but I think you get the idea on
YouTube not I mean not just on any
person's channel and also on social
media but rather on on the people you
follow that you trust they also like
they are also going extreme all out on
on clickbait the quick potato I mean
it's true that you want to use some
sometimes I mean often you want to use
dramatic titles so that so that you get
people's attention but it has gone to
such a extreme degree I mean
even people you follow you you know
their videos you know you like their
content but you look at their title it's
like that's not really what I'm you know
how things should be that's you know I'm
trying to fight you know every time I
try to find the examples I cannot find
it because yesterday it's just like few
days ago you know for the past few days
and like every thing on my YouTube
recommendation is like blatant clickbait
then the moment you want to find
examples it's like hard to find for
example team pose okay I think he's
reasonable okay team who I follow
I like his channels by the way he say
basically if you want if you want read
news and not fake news you follow team
four so every day you know today you
know how it is every day you have lots
of fake news turned out by CNN or MSNBC
or Vox box
you know motherboard Vox you know all
these channels the mainstream they have
money and they a New York Times they
turn out fake news if you want to get a
good perspective you know I recommend
following team poor he's got several
count now like or team cast another of
his account name is team cast but anyway
so he he does you know news reporting he
gives you at least some kind of balanced
view okay at least on the other side so
you can so I kept you know and again
watching video is very time-consuming so
but it by anyway so you if you watch me
youtubes you can check out his stuff but
but look at his titles work nice we all
destroy 2020 Democrat no diversity is is
plan backfires you know igniting you
know blah blah blah first of all forced
to admit something something you know
these creeks Bates you know
you know so in so in this respect I kind
of get tired of this
Tim poor guy you know even I follow him
by thang-thang his yeah so sorry about
that it's passing into my headphone so
so what I'm saying yes Tim cast you know
because you know anyway so what I'm
saying is is it has why is it hoto frame
so what I'm saying is that you know
because of the monetization everyone is
trying to focus on that exclusively to
the degree that it's it's become became
abusive and other proportions that's
what happens to social media that's what
all these social media made society
became since like basically beginning
with the beginning of Facebook in 2003
or so actually Facebook did something
good but so it became like 15 years ago
we might say three
I'm being stupid you know now you
cannot hear me okay so how long I
haven't been on voice my god my video is
so bad now I've been talking for 10
minutes and with without a voice okay so
you want to know my opinions about nuke
you know actually I don't know much
about that guy in heaven I haven't
watched much of his videos yeah so so
anyway I feel pretty bad you know my
videos is so bad
it's kind of you know you got this weird
person talking about esoteric stuff you
know and then stupid videos like
sometimes missing video for eight five
minutes okay that's not too bad okay so
let's see questions speak source of
knowledge he's a big source of knowledge
after all Luke Smith I only watched like
two or three of his videos you know I
I'm not getting much sense out of it I
mean okay so first of all so I suppose
part of his video is talking about
technology I mean like technical stuff
like how how do you use like Linux tips
VI tips programming tips something like
that like how do you install and use
extended low tech okay learning I take
tutorial okay and then he's got quite
slattern worth learning and linguistics
isn't 60 years of old you know so anyway
some of these so he's like a nerd or
programmer right and some of the many of
his topics
I share you know the enjoyment of many
of his topics now I just I just want to
make some comment okay I don't know much
about his material but but I want to
make some quick comments for example why
is Latin worth learning and using like
like in general I get a sense that I
probably would not be too interested in
watching his videos for example you know
why is Latin worth learning okay on that
topic just by the topic name itself I
know that he is not a Latin expert you
know if I want to learn Latin he's I
probably go to a linguistic expert and
so I don't know maybe he's a Latin you
know a linguistic expert so but anyway
on the topic you know and he also he
used the mean you know basically this
kind of mean is anti history W so the
attraction in that video is really is at
least in part not about the content of
related to Latin or linguistics rather
it's about his followers you know IIIi
think his followers followers pretty
much like my his anti a can so it's
about you know making happy you know his
followers followers happy and also on a
topic why is Latin worth learning and
using that's a that's a quick bait
first of all realistics realistically
speaking and practically speaking Latin
is not worth learning period okay I mean
all things considered is Latin worth
learning and using no period okay so
what is he talking about is Latin worth
learning
well it's worth not learning if if you
are interested you know in linguistics
okay and oh yeah you know
and also even if you are interested in
linguistic you have to consider all
aspects so for example is Chinese worth
learning is Asian Chinese worth learning
for example if you know Chinese I know
Chinese I grew up in Taiwan I can read
and write Chinese fluently but however I
do not know agent you know it's kind of
like Asian Chinese I do not know that
well so is that worth learning in the
context of all things you know with
respect to so it's Latin what learning
or is it more worth learning of Asian
Chinese also is Middle English or Asian
in Old English you know worth learning
like inordinate English you have this
big wolf thing you know so all things
considered
what's your context is left-lateral
worth learning and using you know easy
become silly you know really it's a
quick way and so all things considered
you know you you had like I mean as far
as general judgments you have to know
these things I mean so so what I'm
saying is that I get a sense that this
video or in general his video is kind of
like popular you know it's not I mean
with a but so what am i interested okay
my take on things my perspective is that
when I see something whether I want to
learn it must be judged of how human
history I mean in consideration of the
entire human history so when you look at
human history
then you think about whether some human
language or some language topic is
interesting you want to make a score of
that let's say what from one to ten
where the topic X in linguistics is
interesting you make a score from 1 to
10 suppose if you can okay if possible
then you think of whether Latin is worth
learning you know you have a score one
to ten
we're the Asian Chinese is worth
learning you have a school whether you
know whether grammar is worth learning
whether italic well you know weathers
Egyptian Egypt Egypt and ography you
know you know Egyptian heliograph is
worth learning of all these things you
make a score you know by the way when
you make a score when you make a
judgement you have to have context like
with respect to what now if you are if
with respect to archaeology is Latin
what learning
yeah so much more than with respect to
let's say if if learning Spanish or
French yeah if yo Co is to understand
archaeology then learning Latin is far
more worthwhile than learning say
Spanish you know so for each judgment
you have to have a context but even with
our context if with our context what is
the context the context is with respect
to all possible criterias as a human and
more in modern society that is a context
ok so anyway so you make judgment you so
you have this you know general context
you know with respect to human history
you make a judgement so for example is :
worth learning what's your criteria I
mean if you want to make job making you
know if you want to you know make money
or is it if you want to study
interesting programming language aspects
you know like depending on what your
goal okay then with if we without
specifying a goal there is still a good
criteria in general like what
programming language is worth learning
because for example for each particular
criteria you can also ascribe a score
for example the criteria of making money
you know also programming finding a job
you know that criteria in general has a
higher score then let's say for the sake
of studying programming language design
you know because
a programming language designed that
topic is rather esoteric and it's rather
less practical you know as opposed to
finding a job you know language you know
which language is more most popular you
know for a job or which language makes
the most most money so you have two
criterias you know which job makes money
you know that is the practical you know
everyone is of a concern to everyone on
the other hand the criteria of which
language language to learn is fruitful
to study the aspects of computer
language design you know other aspects
of computer languages design that is
also a very good topic valid you know
especially of interest to us nerds but
you know without geek you know without
picking a criteria I mean in general
then the criteria of finding of job is
more important than the language design
aspect therefore when you church when
you say you know which language is worth
learning then you consider these two
criterias in and also all the criterias
for example which language is easiest to
learn which language is the most elegant
you know all materials you have then you
can create a scores then you can decide
which languages in general you know the
the best language to learn so you see
what I'm saying is that you make a
judgment you have criterias and you have
general criteria so whatever so what I
like in general the way I when I say
something or way I perceive something
it's usually I would prefer you know
ideally I'd like I usually the context
I'm taking from is with respect to all
human animals history all the greatest
works all the greatest figures
historical figures the greatest computer
scientists the greatest mathematicians
the greatest linguistics you know the
greatest incidence in for example in
human history the greatest evolution you
know
something happened French Revolution you
know the greatest politicians the
greatest was you know things like that
so so that's how I like know to make the
judgment so when I look at this Luke
Duke Smith guy and his content and my
reaction is now that's not someone I
would be interested that that doesn't
have much attraction to me because first
of all is EC one of the modern greatest
programmer no is he one of the greatest
does he contain the most is he one of
the most knowledgeable in today today's
social justice you know culture war
issues no is he well no link linguist or
you see a you know we're no expert in
particular linguistic issues maybe not
probably not right so so you know I you
know he he would not I I think you know
I you know I don't think he is someone
who I would value very much but by the
way that does you know I I think he is
you know it that does not mean I do not
respect him or and if even even possibly
his videos content and he's thinking is
actually better than my you know
actually that doing that may be true
because but however he he may not be
valuable for me because you're you also
have to consider you know I'm 50 years
old you know I don't have much time you
know I'm not that young guy you know I
suppose most most of you are much
younger you know so my time you know
what time I have you know and what I
already know is kind of different from
you guys so for young person for example
in today's world maybe you are
millennial you know young maybe you are
thirty something or you know then you
you would find Luke's means material
much more attractive because
you know you learn about things you know
you learn about egg-like you form a
culture you form a community with him
you know because he he talks about you
know different things of interest to
programmers then he also talked he also
talks about linguistics and social
social justice things you know for
example this one the paradox of
documentation you know so he also talked
about documentation so and his ideas I
suppose his kind of novel you know it's
not I suppose it's not mainstream that's
why many of my followers you guys also
interested in him so he would be
valuable for you guys for example he
also have this video ok in defence of
pseudoscience that's by the you know
face of it that's that's clickbait in
defense of pseudoscience because by
definition serial science is negative
you know so you know i suppose he
provides some novel perspectives but to
me okay I'm kind of old and you know I
don't you know I don't give myself too
many you know five years to still to
useful still to be able to actually
think you know critically and you know
not say no you know I've stressed only a
few more years to be to not be seen you
you know so I'm already gone through
this you know my face of being young
I've already I have been hip you know
doing these following nutrients you know
I've been through that so to me this is
not you know I don't have much time you
know the time I want to spend for
example with respect to programming or
math you know there are some topics in
math I really want to get my hands on
you know to be a you know to be know you
know for example proof proof proof
theories you know homotopy type theories
those kind of things and for programming
i would like to
hope to write a compiler you know create
my new language that and many other
projects maybe I should talk about you
know what what are the projects I like
to do so you know so you get this you
know so that's that's how I so you know
you get a sense what I'm saying so so
that is my opinion of Luke Smith and by
the way the the first video I saw of his
video is I think I said I forgot where
someone recommended to me or from some
people I follow is his video talking
about when Lena's subscribed to the code
of conduct so he made a video about that
I watched it you know I think so I think
it's interesting in actually I friended
yeah I find it interesting but you know
so anyway that's my opinion about Luke
Smith about Donald Knuth actually I
talked up there's the one video I think
maybe about a month ago you might check
out because on that video I talked you
know like the full hour about what I
think of Donald you know I I'd rather
not repeat because it's a huge topic
basically yeah I don't I don't like
Donald you know okay
that's a that's kind of a controversial
opinion because I say that oh you don't
like Donald good news then people have a
lot you know if people want to know why
you know and and also people will
immediately immediately think that oh
you are just stupid you know how can you
anyway so I did a video up you know I go
I went in length and in detail about why
what I think of news and why I don't I
don't really like his his his his way of
viewing
things his ideas you know you know so
that is about that so Luke Smith Great
Green Tech says he likes UNIX philosophy
and term terminal only programs and his
workflow looks really good yeah I I
suppose yeah and I suppose you know I I
think one of his video he mentioned I
think you know I read from all that post
like he is a VI guy him and I think
someone mentioned that one of his video
mentioned because I was doing wink off
the other day so I think someone
mentioned that he made a challenge like
you know someone convinces if someone
can convince him using Emacs you know
then he would something something so I
made a video I saw a few days ago I made
a link of video using Emacs with sawfly
keys I think I kicked the I think
anytime you know I think I can kick the
same people out of you know out of their
efficiency so I did one video but it was
not it was not squarely addressing his
video because I haven't watched his
video I don't know but anyway on the
topics you know I'm you know again I'm
old you know I being on this VI Vince
stuff for 20 years you know Emacs so
I've seen pretty much I've seen all
possible takes you know all possible
opinions or possible counters or
possible behaviors there's nothing you
know I'm kind of like owed you know you
know I'm about to die soon so it's not a
topic that I would be excited you know
the oh let me show you why oh you are
wrong you know you know
being there you know it's like Oh topics
so so that's about that so anyway what
what what else topics so I was you know
so today's topics I have South talk-show
I think I think I already talked for an
hour 48 minutes um so today's so maybe
that's about it you know I'm kind of
hungry I want to go eat um I'm kind of
feeling bad at the moment at moment
because because party because you know I
talked for five minutes with a hot voice
and so the topics today's topic is kind
of become random ish and seeks out talk
show so what so what what do you guys
think any any other more questions or
like counter-arguments or something
let's see
round three for me it's big so it's
knowing after all he is a big source of
knowledge after all
so Victor says what is what's the
difference between clickbait titles and
normal titles most of the time I can
understand the content of the video no
matter how quick beta the title is well
if you are still here clickbait titles
basically means they are dramatic for
example in in today's video chat I might
say you know I talk about what is
clickbait you know for example I'm
talking about the nature of clickbait or
what is the definition of clickbait you
know that is my title for today you know
what is the nature of clickbait oh but
if if I want that click to be a quick
big title then I would say Oh everything
you know about clickbait is wrong ok or
in defense of a clickbait ok that's
another title Oh why clickbait is
actually valid you know that's another
possible clickbait title so what is the
difference the difference is that
basically the code definition of
clickbait is you want to use a title
that's dramatic okay dramatic to a
degree to a degree that is you know
basically just wrong okay so for so what
does it mean to something to be dramatic
basically means you want it to be
dramatic yeah drama you know that's what
drama means like when you have movies
you know drum every like theater you
know the definition of theater if you
study you know in human humanities you
know there's a theater is one of the
department or play or Shakespeare play
you know you have usually a icon of a
sad face and happy face you know that's
what drama is drama you know is what TV
is you know because when you watch her
play a story a movie you know even
poetry they want to exaggerate things
you want to you know sad becomes sadder
you know heavy becomes happier you know
instead of being injured you want people
to die you know so so that's drama you
know that's what it is
and and drama attracts people because
because if you know so what's the
situation you know like blood you know
cool you know your movie they say cool
you know that's also part of the drama
for example when you have a murder
thriller okay oh you have a scary movie
horror movie you know where you have
some murder or something you know you
you want it to make it dramatic you know
you you know you don't want to just tell
a story okay this guy killed you know
murder someone and you want to show
blood you want to show for example a
girl you know being cut up and in the
refrigerator you know that is dramatic
even though maybe in reality that really
you know almost never happens but if
your story is about someone you know a
murder you want to make that you know
you want to do that as part of the scene
you know because because then all the
people oh my God look at this you know
this is someone being cut up being a
refrigerator you get people's attention
people want to watch it that that is
what drama is so instead of saying okay
so talk show date clickbait on clickbait
titles you know oh you know we talked
about the nature of clickbait
that's a like a descriptive correct you
know very correct because the
descriptive title but instead of you
want to use a creek bed you know
oh and like everything you know about
clickbait is wrong okay Oh
in defense of clickbait that's drama you
know then people say what in defense of
creeping are you crazy you know then you
could they quick you want to see okay
what are your reasons or another part of
what I do is
ten reasons you you should use clickbait
or you should not use clickbait and also
the science of clickbait or the other of
clickbait there's a lot techniques you
know for example you want to one of the
techniques is using human psychology you
know so white drama so why why does when
you exaggerate you get kicked people to
you know see and pay attention to your
video or post or whatever writing big no
that's part of psychology you know so
psychology study this kind of phenomenon
so in then we dive into psychology and
then also marketing marketing also uses
psychology to study to come up with
techniques of how how to get people's
attention you know like people mocking
Indy you know companies has spent
billions of dollars studying that for
example you know about how mean happens
right you know the definition of me one
of the characteristics what one of the
defining characteristics to for
something to be a mean is that it has
become hugely popular like millions of
views like that's why it becomes you
know that's a definition part of the
definition of the mean meaning that
everyone be know kind of online knows
about that like when you show a picture
every know that is about that you know
it's a mean so so people have studied
people have looked at all the means or
all the posts that becomes hugely
popular you know they have died they try
to dissect scientifically what makes a
post hugely popular because that's
tremendously powerful you know because
for example if you if if for example me
you know I want I don't have money you
know I live in poverty poverty and I
want to you know I want to save myself I
want to you know if you
if I can make a post you know let's say
once a month that post becomes have 1000
you know 1 million views I will become
rich you know I will become you know so
rich you know I will become wealthy so
how can i you know how can I make
something you know how can I be
successful successful in making posts
that's you know millions of views so
that's what people study that that is
why these corporations this marketing
they have you know this corporation said
marketing department you know they have
title they also have dedicated marketing
firms you know companies that specialize
in marketing for example Google hires
them Amazon hires them you know they pay
you I pay you you know hundred thousand
dollars you market this thing for me
Apple paste them you know Apple always
have great marketing you know they are
nineteen eighty-four ads you remember
that ads you know and think different
you know that's another thing different
that's grammatically wrong but however
it's hugely successful marketing success
and also time and a diamond is forever
now if you are English speaker you
probably are familiar with that phrase a
diamond is forever or concept you know
that was also a hugely successful
marketing slogan or today we call it a
mean okay now there are books written
about this so you know so P so they you
know corporations you know psychologists
study what makes something hugely
popular you know because they want to
study that because it's it is one of the
main way to make money even if you don't
have a product if you just can just post
something some idea or some concept some
slogan you know some sentence of English
that becomes millions have millions of
views you pick you make money out of
that you know just you know G you
and and you know there's lots lots of
stories I can go on so so yeah so these
are about marketing and you know so back
to the clickbait as I was saying
clickbait is one of the one of the
element or technique or tactics for
marketing and you know if you are
selling something or if you are making
videos you know if you are writing a
blog that is also that's also important
that's what I'm saying so so and okay so
so what makes marketing so what are the
elements that makes a creation
successful okay one of the thing is
drama okay that's one of the element now
I'm not going to go into you know give
you like the ten most important things
about mac marketing techniques you know
I've seen them you know actually if you
just web search you know the most
important marketing tactics you'll find
them actually so but I'm giving you some
you know I'm giving you the detail about
the background the why who studies them
why is why is it important the nature of
it you know and why you know drama you
know being dramatic is one of the
elements and techniques to for why
clickbait clickbait is successful
so what do you so no man good morning
Norman by the way Norman did you ask me
a question before like in some videos I
fail to answer something
yeah post it again so maybe we can talk
about that maybe we go for another 5 or
10 minutes
then that's it for today so today so
today's main topic I guess today's saw
talk show is about marketing and
clickbait ok so so do you know man says
do you have a long-term plan for writing
your language or comprise compiler no
actually that's one of the bad thing
about me because whenever I have a plan
I fail it's kind of has to do with
procrastination you know the the the
personality we who does you know who do
procrastinate procrastinators because I
am one of the biggest procrastinator
I've tried always to read I'm you know
I've read all there is about that how to
face the solutions you know like many of
you nerds are procrastinators I know
because that's because you are following
me probably because we share many
similar personalities or interests or
habit you know so I know many of you are
professional eaters too I'm probably far
more than you guys you know so correct
procrastination one of the thing about
procrastination is that you are a
perfectionist perfectionist or someone
who is ambitious usually tends to be
procrastinators because when we do
things we want to like we have or maybe
we think of too high of ourselves you
know we because we have we are ambitious
you know we gonna do this you know
because I know you know I think I know
everything about this you know so when I
do something I want to be very specific
this way and that way
you know you know we have big plans but
then there there comes a fear of failure
because you know then we are not
successful we fear that so we don't we
put it off we don't do it so that's one
of my issue because when I try to plan I
usually don't do well because then
because for example if now I said that
you know one of my plan is to create a
compiler or you know create my own
language then I know it's not I'm not
going to do it because every time I
think of starting to do it then I know
you know there's criteria 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 you know I these have I have a
bag of things I really want to get right
you know so I kind of avoid doing it you
know so what makes me do something is
something I don't I do not have plan oh
I do not have ambition like you know
like I noticed that with saw talk show
because every time I think okay today
I'm you know I I think I want to
okay this episode I want to talk about I
want to teach you guys about geometric
inversion you know which which is a
topic I know well you know I want to do
a good lecture when I start to do that
you know where I have that in mind in
mind usually I just I do not do well
because they are start to start you know
I have a pressure you know you know you
know on the other hand if I do not have
a plan you know and you if I do not you
know it's like I just want to chat okay
then someone mentioned oh by the way you
you you you you have a dispatch
geometric inversion you know I want to
so what's what is that about then I get
excited you know I talk about that like
a continuously let's stop talking about
geometric inversion for one hour and
that tends to come out well because
because I am confident I'm just you know
doing
my things I just want to talk and I know
what I'm talking about and I start to
talk about you know oh you know because
I you know because this topic I have I
know the topic well and I've seen other
people you know talking you know I've
read you know books or videos of other
people you know some of them many of
them also sometimes even computer
mathematicians I think that's not you
know he's not doing a job so I just want
to start and you know I just saw to talk
spontaneously and I covered it really
well confidently so that's one of the
issue so about doing my own programming
languages I don't you know so you know
it's something I want to do so I don't
know if I've actually finished yet you
know you know I I have lots of ideas you
know as you know for example let me show
you them I mean if you read my articles
you know that I have like you know over
a hundred articles about programming
language design you know syntax OOP
these semantic noodles and talk by
dummies and you know so so yeah it's
something I I might do you know let's
just say that if I did if I actually do
it that's good yeah so I don't have you
know let's just put it that way because
right you know right now I have been you
know I don't have money to live on so
that that is one big worry for me every
day like every moment like right now I
feel there's a pin and you know you know
I don't feel well so you know I'm not
sure what could happen so so any you
know so I'm so you know part of the
reason I'm doing video is kind of to
have a record so you have a there's a
record of you know me talking about my
ideas and things
so rmw hi inw god I haven't seen you
before and Amy I haven't seen you before
so uh MW says honestly you also lose
people with clickbait many of those
creek beds videos doesn't don't have
great moment not not although they don't
have great content not although that's
true that's but i also want to mention
if we are talking about in general then
that is not true you see clickbait you
know this corporation's marketing you
know google they study that they do it
because they know that's you know this
the whole literature or marketing you
know they talk about that because it is
something tried-and-true I mean that is
what works for the whole history of
humanity in general I mean consider the
general popular population without any
specifics okay that's that's the context
I mean for me for example for me for my
followers obviously you know a lot of
people like me you know they don't want
they don't like quick baits so for me in
particular click to in creepy it is not
something too good for me
for example but however that's not true
you know that's why that's also part of
the reason I do not become popular I do
not grow for example you know like once
you like I have maybe a few hundred
followers I mean all social media and
bloggers considered maybe I have few
hundred followers I mean on Twitter I
have two 2,000 followers
yeah like myoga emails I Twitter account
I have close to three thousand followers
but my real followers who watch me often
you know maybe a few hundred it's
reasonable likes let's say let's say 500
that's a good you know let's say 500 ok
that 500 is like nobody ok
you don't you know like for normal and I
mean even average Twitter accounts you
have few thousand I mean actual
followers or YouTube you know you you
need to have you need to have hundred
followers hunt hundred thousand
followers to be is considered like you
know like you know 500 followers like
you have some audience okay so so what
do you do you need clickbait you know
that's when yeah for example let's say
you have 10,000 followers you want to
grow to 100,000 followers what do you
have to do I mean by the way hundred
thousand followers is nothing you know
they are like thousands of you know
there are probably millions people with
hundred thousand followers okay so the
point is you want to grow your own the
audience so you got hundred thousand I
mean you got ten thousand followers you
want to grow into 100 thousand what do
you do you need to use some of the tried
and true techniques of marketing such as
quick bait
you know I mean we are not talking about
going extreme like like a title that is
offensive and insulting that almost have
little to do with your content you know
a lot mainstream people are doing that
in mainstream publishers like New York
Times they are doing that you know so
but still you want to be you know you
want to be reasonable to use you know
dramatic titles or click weights to
advance you have to you kind of I mean
especially in today's situation it's
almost like you have to so that's that
is a situation you know yeah you lose
some followers but those the people you
lose you know that the people you do is
are the really rare you know very few
niche percentage of the population you
know they may be they are you know
professors they are philosophers you
know they are accomplished
mathematicians accomplished professors
accomplished philosophers or
accomplished you know
programmers yeah you lose those people
but in general those people are not the
general population they are not the type
who will give you money in the first
place you know that's also another fact
about marketing about you know making
money if you if you want your audience
to be you know greatest philosophers in
the mathematicians you we are not a
followers few hundred he is the tops you
know not to you know you know those who
give you money tends to be actually
those with medians you know there are
several accounts with you know many
accounts with millions of followers who
are their followers they are general
population many meaning that many of
them are just stupid people just to put
it bluntly okay they you know they don't
have they don't know anything about
anything you know that's all people are
like that you know they follow of
celebrities you know that's a fact of
life you know so what so what I'm saying
is that if you are a Content producer
doesn't matter you write a book you
write you do YouTube or whatever or you
blog you if you want to grow your
followers after you know one thousand
after ten thousand after one hundred
thousand you know after a certain
certain circle you cannot grow any more
unless you go beyond you know you preach
certain certain let's say principles or
something you know you stick to you know
for example if you want to have 1
million followers you know you your
content your main subject cannot be math
period you know that's a fact of life
okay if you want to talk about
I mean suppose you are a the greatest
mathematician today let's say you are
one of the greatest mathematician or
let's say one of you are one of the
greatest you know let's say what you are
one of the top
1,000 great programmers well no you know
you are you are ranking top 1000
programmers now if you are going to do
video or writing about your programming
stuff you will not have 1 million
followers period you know get out of you
you know you will not you'll never have
one medium followers you know on the
other hand you know those celebrities
movie stars they will have 10 million
followers you will not even not have 1
million someone can you do your well
there is something you can do because
once you have you know a sizable
programmer followers because of your
programmer content you start to talk
about something outside of programming
technical technicalities such as you
talk about the life of startups how to
make a startup how to be successful you
know to to be a programmer you know you
start to talk about those kind of things
what language to learn basically you
start to talk about things that's not
really technical that not really have
real you know technical valid technical
answers or scientific answers that's
what happens and this way of progress is
in fact a lot of people become popular
you know they start you know some people
do you know programming leanness Linux
reviews for example they start others
Linux reviews of programming language
reviews some people start with keyboard
you know programmer programming keyboard
or gaming keyboard reviews then they
reach certain audience size then they
want to grow they start to you know they
start to do other things and when you
know oftentimes they became you know
clickbait they became spam they are
content degenerate they be they start to
do like you know one video every day all
three videos
everyday like the team pool guy you know
and for the original followers you start
to see their their content like like
they don't you know you don't want to
follow them anymore but that's a fact of
life but to them they are actually going
they grow you know from 10,000 to
100,000 followers that's you know they
make 10 times more money you know that's
what they need to do you know if you are
in the same boat you are more likely you
know to do the same so it is a
unfortunate fact of life you know that's
just how things are you know this
there's nothing you can do about that so
do I think so do you have any known
episode so Victor says do you think
there are any ethical problems with
using dramatic titles and marketing
tricks no not if you're Creek bait
becomes so extreme you know like no more
quick bait you know click bait is a new
jargon that began about 10 years ago
okay but however the concept the
practice practice exists you know like
long time you know it I think it exists
the moment when there is publishing you
know so so let's I mean quick baked is I
mean quick paid the the name itself is I
could it's a quick paid okay so it's a
jargons invented ten years ago but
anyway the point is the essence of
creepy basically it means dramatic being
dramatic
now that is with us you know ever since
storytelling started you know verbally
you know overly we older generation
tells us story to the new generation we
when we tell a story the story becomes
true
taking more dramatic and that's how you
attract audience you know so do I think
that's an ethical problem not really I
mean because that's how things are
that's how human behaviors how we behave
how we react to drama and that's it's
kind of it's part of now it's me it's
natural it's with us okay not this
really nothing wrong with being dramatic
because when you tell a story you know
that's what drama theater you know
movies stories fictions you know place
Shakespeare's plays when you know you
look at Shakespeare Shakespeare's plays
they are all dramatic you know so so
being dramatic is not itself a problem
but it kind of the clickbait kind of
became a problem today because of social
media because because we get into the
new technology you know the technology
you we got we got into this social media
era this artificial intelligence
intelligence era where you know digital
things like social media writings post
they become they can influence the whole
society to a degree they they create
civil war they create wars between
countries you know from online
information you know fake news you know
info war you know you are familiar with
that right and click bait is part of
that because for example the example New
York Times New York Times is a number
one respected publisher you know in much
of history but however today they have
become it's my opinion okay they have
become quick they become they have
become a manufacturer factory of fake
news and much of their I mean basically
all they opposed all titles are
clickbait so is clickbait a problem
well so ethical you know it's an ethical
issue yes
I mean it's because it you know
originally it's not an issue but today
in today's social media era this digital
a you know era artificial intelligence
era they become I think it has become a
problem not just clickbait concept
itself but as part of the whole fake
news you know the digital websites the
information how they can be manipulated
you know to create to to actually have
significant consequences such as war
between nations or civil war or you know
you know I'm very sure you guys are
familiar with that situation so I think
that's it
anything else I'm going to like I'm kind
of hungry and I'm going to get something
to eat anything else like you have to
say within you know ten minutes I mean
ten seconds otherwise I don't see your
comments and and that's that would be it
for today
all right thank you okay so Victor says
all right thanks bye okay
thank you guys for watching and I hope
to see you in next one thank you thank
you rmw hey no man have a good days guys