Hello, good evening. Welcome to another
episode of Exile Talk Show. We are going
to code event of code 2025
day four using wuam language. Uh if you
don't know, I have a wam language
tutorial for programmers covering
everything from the ground up. Um so
look for it. Search for kasali wuam
language for programmers on kasali.info
info just search it
wra language
http no s okay okay there wam language
tutorial and in it you will find the
download link on wufam language uh wufam
research website wufam.com
there you can download it for free you
need to turn JavaScript
okay wam language is the most high level
language
by a magnitude high higher level than
them all then python then lisp then has
then rust then ok camel obviously then c
first and java those are kind of low
level okay so woven language we're going
to code that if you are watching this
offline play at 1.5 speed or play at
twice as fast if you are here say hi
love to see your comments Okay, post
comments here.
Uh, so we going to start wam language.
Uh, so let's start. Uh, that's my todo.
Uh, okay. There's a bunch of my
work. So let's start wu language and
let's read a vand of code. Let's see
what we get. Uh, yesterday we did day
three part two and we spent five hours
and we didn't complete it.
uh because I was going into some kind of
mathematical solution. So you can see
all the past advent of code for this
year here and so yesterday we we we
spent five hours and we kind of failed
at the end. Uh we could you know let so
maybe uh next week or after that you
know after a few months I'll come back
to it and uh just finish the problem.
But we tried some kind of mathematical
solution and didn't work out. So that
was fiveour session. So let's go to
today's uh talk show. Okay. So today's
talk show what is warning. Okay. There's
some something uh so video check audio
check. Okay.
Okay. So
code they uh here. Now the v code is
very lousy. So they have fixed layout.
So you can see the layout um so for
example today is day four. So click
let's open day four and the layout is
fixed so that
you know it if you enlarge the font
let's do
uh
then part part of it off uh went off the
screen. So let me do this. Let me show
it in Firefox browser without JavaScript
and tone of CSS. Let's see if that'll
make it better. Okay, so uh view. Now we
going to do my usual style randomish and
uh easy. Go slow and have fun. Okay, I'm
not just going to concentrate on solving
this problem. So if you are watching
this offline and you are interested in
um solution in wuam language to advent
of code you want to skip around. Okay
just like play my video at twice as fast
and skip around. Okay. So apparently now
they can
you see turning off uh CSS screw their
website [laughter]
and you see this customized tag. Now
this is illegal
let me tell you. You see then you look
at the source code of advent of code. So
is that part of the source code? You got
this thing.
You got this. Uh why now? Why? Why is
that? Let's see. So, control U to look
at the source code.
Actually, we are digressing here. But um
new page, paste their HTML and uh search
for wait
for
Y tag. Now, why do they have a Y tag?
Two zero. Uh let's search for that.
You see why why do they show this um
this this Y thing? Very interesting.
Let's ignore it now. Okay, it's not
okay. Close close. Okay, so event code
day five,
you write the escalator down to the
printing department. They are clearly
getting ready for Christmas. They have
lots of large rows of paper everywhere.
Large rows of paper paper. And there's
even a massive printer in the corner to
handle the really big print jobs.
Decorating here will be easy. They can
make their own decorations.
What you really need is a way to get
further into the North Pole base while
the elevators are offline.
Okay, you you got you go down the
escalators to the printing department.
Uh you need to uh something something.
Actually, maybe we can help with that.
One of the elves replies when you ask
for help. We are pretty sure there is a
cafe cafeteria on the other side of the
black of the back wall. If we could
break through the wall, you'd be able to
keep moving. It's too bad. All our
forklifts are so busy moving those big
rows of paper around. Okay, some CV
story. If you can optimize the work for
the forklifts are doing, maybe they
would have time to spare to break
through the wall.
Excuse me. [clears throat]
That was me coughing. I still have code
linguing cold virus.
The rows of paper
uh represented by a at sign. The rows of
paper are arranged on a large grid. The
elves even have a helpful diagram. Your
personal input indicating where
everything is located. For example, this
diagram. The forklifts can only access a
row of paper if there are fewer than
four rows of paper in the eight adjacent
positions.
Okay, so eight adjacent positions. Left,
right, top, down, northeast,
northwest, southeast, southwest. Let's
see. 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8. So those are called um there's
[clears throat] a name for this
particular type of neighbor. The other
type of neighbor is that you don't c you
don't count the diagonals.
So that's part of the cellular automata.
If you study cellular automata so one of
them is called um
do you guys know what I mean? Comments.
Okay. But anyway let's skip that. So
anyway you got this grid that's your
input. So that you each uh each um each
point on the grid each cell you have
eight neighbors. Okay. Uh
so uh the forklift can only access uh
can only assess a row of paper if there
are fewer than four rows of paper in the
eight adjacent positions. Okay. So if it
has fewer than four neighbors, then it
can access. If you can figure out which
rows of paper the forklifts can access,
they'll spend less time looking and more
time breaking down the walls wall to
cafe to the cafeteria.
Cafeteria
cafeteria.
Uh so
so you got a grid and each S sign is uh
is a uh is indicates a row of paper.
Okay. So,
so there is one of the rule is that if
if a cell has fewer than four rows of
paper then something
in this example there are 13 rows of
paper that can be accessed by a forklift
marked with X. Okay, so let's see. So if
we look at random okay so let's magnify.
Okay, this is look like a
this looks like a cellular automata
problem. Okay, let's just copy the
input. Okay, let's copy that. Let's do
it in Emacs.
Uh, showing browser.
Showing browser. Then let's start code
here.
Um, wait, let's just paste that. And
there is the other input. Uh, let's copy
that.
Copy.
Copy. Switch back and uh put it here.
And uh let's say
uh text.
Okay. And uh let's say text. Okay. So if
we uh view this and uh shift alt scroll
so we truly magnify it. Shift.
Okay. So, you can So, let's look at this
is hard to read. Okay.
The add sign is a problem. It'll be
better if you change the add sign to
something else, but let's stick with it.
So, the so this X has Okay, so fewer
than four neighbors. Okay, one of the
criteria is
something about fewer than four, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Fewer than four rows of paper.
So if it has one
if it has zero or one or two or three
neighbors then there's a X. Okay. So
let's check one or two or three or zero.
Okay. X check this X check one two. This
X check one two. This X check one and
two. This X check one two three. Okay,
this X check one, two. Okay, good. Now
there's X here. One, two, and three.
There's X here, one, two. Okay, so okay,
we got it. Zero, one, two, or three
neighbors, then it's X.
Okay, so but what is your problem?
What is your problem?
Consider your complete diagram of the
paper row locations.
How many rows of paper can be accessed
by a forklift? This is like a
trivial.
Okay, let's put it back.
Uh let's let's magnify. Let's shrink.
Not magnify so much. Okay. Uh showing
browser. Okay, we got that. So,
so okay, let's get our personal input.
So, in this case, the answer is 17. So,
what is our personal personal input? Oh,
big one. The big one. Copy. Copy. Close.
Uh,
so let's go to input, paste it so we can
look at. Okay. So, how many lines? Uh,
lines. 139. Ah, they're not 140. And how
many characters per line?
See
139. So it's 139 by 139 square grid.
Okay. Save it. Close.
Okay. Let's work on this problem. Then
uh
copy. Let's start a wolf
language code.
Okay. And uh here. So select allo.
That's going to be a string.
Okay.
So what you going to do about this? So
let's see how we solve this. So
basically you want to determine how many
neighbors are there.
Now advent of code has this kind of
problem often.
So you can turn this into a matrix but
wam language has a lot of um functions
that deal with cellular automatter. So
let me show you. We shift enter to start
the kernel and uh let's let's magnify
and uh let's find uh
let's say cellular automata do they have
shift enter
automatic cellular automation. So you
got that cellular automation
generate a list of okay let's look at
the big documentation cellular
automation let's turn on enlarge
okay let's turning on enlarge okay
generates a list representing uh the
evolution of the cell automation okay so
so this. So let's let's see. So we got
this pattern
now uh we got this pattern we want to
for each cell. So you can think of this
as a matrix for each cell you want to
look at the neighboring cells
and uh you want to count them. Each cell
has two states on or off. On is
represented by a add sign. Off is
represented by a dot. Okay. So a dot is
like zero. You can also represent it by
zero.
Add sign is one means on. Okay. So you
got a matrix of zeros and one. One means
on zero means off. Okay. A matrix. Now
for each element in the matrix you want
to know how many of its neighbors are
on. Okay. Now you now since you explain
in this way it's easy to code
given a grid.
We can
represent
this as a matrix
as a 2D matrix. Okay.
Each cell is either on
represented by one
or sign
or off
as zero or dot. Okay.
Okay. So
okay. So then
the problem is for each cell deter uh
check all its neighbors
including diagonal.
Now what's a term for diagonal
neighbors? Let's uh look up. Okay. So
before I mentioned uh so one of them is
called
I forgot but let's let's digress. Okay.
In context of a grid diagonal neighbors
of a given cell are the cells that share
exactly one corner with a given cell.
Okay. There is a name for this uh this
this kind of consideration of a cell. Um
it's called
[clears throat] yeah Vong Newman
neighborhood. Okay. So one of them is
called Vong Newman neighborhood which
does not include like diagonals. The
other one is called um
you see you see they have stack overflow
about finding neighbors in a
two-dimensional array.
Silly.
Uh so you want to look at
cellular automata. Okay. Let's go to
Wikipedia.
So because that cell cellular automata
is a spectacular object. Okay. Oh yeah.
So so this if you consider the diagonal
also as neighbors that's called more
neighborhood.
Okay. That's a terminology.
[clears throat]
Now, if you only consider the horizontal
or vertical, that's called von luman
neighborhood. Okay, that was the phrase
I was looking for.
Anyway, so let's go back to the to our
description. Uh
if if
a cell has zero to three
neighbors that are un then we consider
that cell as
um how do you put a name to for that
cell special or
the problem ask
how many special cells are there. Okay.
So now once we
put this problem into matrix now it's
easy to do. Now it's just triv it's kind
of now just trivial. you you turn this
string into a you know you replace at
sign by one the number one you replace
the dot by um
by uh zero then you turn it into a you
can turn it into a two-dimensional
matrix or nested array in Python for
example nested list or al alternatively
you can just deal with this as a string
uh well that then then okay There are
many ways you can turn them into lines
of strings. Each line is a string. Then
you Yeah, there are many ways. Then you
just um then you just loop through each
character. Then um then you use the
index to check the previous. So it's
kind of tedious. Okay, advent of code
has quite a lot of these problem. It's
it's kind of just tedious. Okay, so what
I'm going to do now?
Uh we are we going to try to solve it.
Okay. Yeah. So but I want to look for a
special um solution or should I just
like directly just solve the problem use
whatever means just solve it instead of
like thinking about fancy ways. Uh so
what do you guys like to see
because
how can I cure my browser hopping? What
do you mean Brave Sync is trash? Okay,
stop talking about trash. Okay, Brave
Sync, I don't use sync. Okay, I don't
use sync feature
uh in any browser.
So,
okay, stop talking about trash guys.
Now, let's talk about math or focus on
the programming or you know, don't watch
my show.
So, let me think about this. What we how
we going to do this?
Yeah, we want to solve the problem. So
uh
so there are many ways. Um
so the question is like do I want just
like focus on just just how do you do
this in wufam language
because if I don't do that I risk the
possibility of me talking for an hour
and uh not solving it
because there's a lot ways to solve this
because there is a lot um for example
you But you know, so I have this
dilemma. Should I which way?
For example, array. Okay, there's like
100 functions for array.
Uh, okay, let's do it again. So, it's
like u
Okay, this still needs to be larger.
I want them in two columns. Okay. So you
see uh there there are like maybe 100
function on array. Array array
components array depth array filter
array flatten array mesh.
Now uh what is array mesh?
Array mesh. Oh okay it generate. So this
is actually this is what I want. This is
fitting for this problem. Array mesh
generates a mesh region from a array of
rank D. Oh wait no this this is a visual
representation
of a grid like our problem a grid but it
it represent so-called mesh by you know
uh represented by a you see you can
rotate this fantastic
uh you know it it turns the array into
this grid. Okay. So that's what array
mesh is. Um so that's not what we need.
So array mesh array pad that that does
the padding which is very convenient
because otherwise when you do this kind
of problem you have special case when
you when you want to find some the
neighbors of the cells on the edge
because there's no index you you know
array out of bounds either on top or on
the side. So that in that case you can
you can uh array pad so you auto
automatically pad like nothing to the
array so you don't have the out of bound
problem. So that's one solution. Okay.
So array mesh I mean that's one of the
useful thing array for byte array by
array format array reshape that is when
you want to turn a let's say
one-dimensional list to a
two-dimensional array or
threedimensional array. That's that's
what this array reshapes is.
So array reduce, array reample, array
reshape, array rules. Uh that's uh gives
the rules uh specify elements in a
sparse array. Okay, that that that that
shows a way to define a sparse array
instead of you know a given array. It
just simplify it into a list of rules to
create that array. Okay. So you got a
center array. So that's for generate
center array creates a list of length n
with elements a at the center and zero
everywhere else. Okay. It creates a
array with one single element
in the middle.
Bite array array by two strings center
array
uh center array. Se
array have no idea what those are.
Semrum array. What are those? Computes
the power septum of data. Okay, I don't
know what that is.
Computes a specified type of septum of
data. Now, what is that? That's some
kind of mathematical septum.
Septro analysis
has been used for characterization of
echoes, separation of convoluted
separation of convolved signals and
pitch detection application in signal
processing. Okay. Rio spectrum is
computed as the inverse for transform of
the log magnitude for real transform.
Okay.
So computes the power spectrum of data.
So it it it does some kind of um
you know it's a mathematical function.
It gives a number. So you have a array
then it returns a number. Okay.
Uh wait it returns a it returns each
element into another number.
Okay. That's you know that's for signal
processing okay I don't know anything
about it
complex array plot constant array that
generates array of all the same number
coordinate coordinate bounding array box
okay that generates the coordinate kind
of
uh delimited array so what is that
delimited
array oh that's
that's this is kind of uh Um this is
kind of a bug. It shouldn't be there.
It's like uh delimited array document
web. So it's not there.
Export export byte array function
compile export by array array. So why
are we going through this? Because you
know often times wam language has it has
7,000 building functions. Okay. So often
times something you want to do in other
programming languages you have to write
it takes you an hour and you may not be
sure your your solution is the best
quality or robust or efficient but wam
language may have it built in so because
7,000 so often times when you want to
use wam language uh to solve a problem
you want to look at what are the
possible functions so but here. You
know, I'm not too familiar with this
array um all these array um functions.
So that's why I'm taking my time just to
look at them.
So that's why I'm asking you guys should
I focus on
you know like don't don't look at you
know don't talk about this just just
just focus just do the problem you know
in the basic way just maybe it's tedious
but just finish it or I can
like my usual way I want to solve it in
the most elegant proper way then you
need to you know um look at this right
okay so This this these functions whose
name contains array they are basically
um
generating arrays. Okay. Structured
array structured array data represents a
uh something something array with
structured type st as specific content
data. Okay. So what is that
superseded by individual types as
quantity array and symmetriized array.
Okay. That's like obsolete function.
Okay. So,
row array
at least row array. Uh
that's another bad thing, right? Why is
that showing up
net array? So,
okay. So,
now let me think about this problem. So
this is about this problem is kind of
like cellular automata.
So what are helpful things? So let me
just start to think about them. Okay. So
this when you type this, it lists all
functions with such uh wild card pattern
in it. So that's the best way to find
the function you want. But
alternatively, you click on array, then
you go to the help. The the help is also
uh here. So for example, if you type
array
completion and uh in suan mode for
emacs, that's what I'm using. Uh you can
press a key
tap f to call ox wam doc lookup and then
there it is. So this page the wuam
documentation is like millions of pages.
They are identical to the documentation
in the wuam language. It it come with
wam language. Okay. So here is a uh wait
I don't. So here's the array. So once
you get to the documentation then you go
down here there is um technotes and uh
related guides that will
help you
uh do stuff related to this topic. Now
for example technotes usually it's more
technical okay it's it's usually much
more technical so if you click on
technotes vectors and matrices open it a
new tab
that is basically kind of a indepth
tutorial on everything you want to do
with arrays or matrices or um all the um
what they call it u uh tensors okay
which is kind of nested matrix
Uh but this is usually very indepth so
there's a lot to read and they have like
like they have tens or hundred of these
page called technotes. Okay. Now if you
go back here so that's technotes then
there's a technotes on tenses. So if we
click on that so it's all about tenses
and linear algebra. Okay. So go back
this kind of in-depth tutorial. So go
back but usually then you have related
guides. So con constructing matrices. So
you click on that then that this guides
uh basically list all related functions.
For example when you look for array you
are probably interested in all sort of
functions related to matrix or array. So
there you have it constructing matrices.
So this this is about so on this
particular page it's about all functions
that construct matrices. Okay, there are
there are other functions about matrices
but this page is about constructing
matrices. So you have table array
coefficient array sparse array normal
band gives value on array collection of
bands for tri diagonal. Okay. So like
you can specify a diagonal of a array
and it generates array something like
that. It generates array with those
diagonal. So identity matrix diagonal
matrix constant array center array. So
let's see uh array flatten. Okay. So
partition join pad left part pad right
array pad hilbert matrix hko matrix
to plit matrix I don't know I don't know
what these are actually those are matrix
matrices with particular property okay
for example let's go to hubert matrix
gives the n byn hubert matrix with
elements of the form okay that's the
definition 1 divided by I + J minus one.
So what does it look like? So let's
check. Okay, so any matrix
uh so this is called Hubert matrix.
Okay, so it's generated the definition
is 1 divided by I + J minus one. So the
so each entry is a fraction
and uh they get
smaller
as the row increase or the column
increase. So they they get they becomes
smaller towards the lower right. Okay.
And the denominator is one is J + I
minus J minus one. So it's like just I +
J. So the column number plus the row
number.
So so it has this form. So now what is
the significance of this? I don't know
Hilbert matrix. Okay. So so W language
is very good if you want to learn all
sort of mathematics. So I don't know
what is this significance of the Hilbert
matrix. We can look up
Hilbert matrix. Okay. There it is.
Wikipedia. So, so what is the why why is
this matrix important? There it is very
uh succinct definition historical note
and so on so on so on you know and today
we can ask AI
in linear algebra a Hubert matrix
introduced by Hubert oh is a square
matrix with the entries of this
fraction. Okay. Uh that is okay. So the
entry also can be defined by the
integral that that is as a gramian
matrix. Okay. For powers of x it arises
in the least squares approximation of
arbitrary functions by polomials. Okay.
So that is the significance that it
arises in the least squares approximate
approximation
of arbitrary functions of polomials.
Okay. So basically you have you have
random data
you want you know like random data in
2D. Okay. So each you got run you got a
bunch of dots. Each dot is two numbers x
and y coordinate. You got bunch of dots
and they they are kind of like a
function. So they are not like all over
but they they are output of a function.
You want to find you want to approximate
this random dots by a function by a
polomial function. So that's what
so this method to approximate this data
by a polomial function that's called
list squares. Okay, that's a that's a
way to find the function. Okay. So when
you do this then
it says that this matrix Hbert matrix
become comes up useful.
The Hubert matrices are canonical
examples of EO condition matrices being
notoriously difficult to use in
numerical computation.
For example, the two form condition
number of the matrix above is 4.8 * 10
to the 55th power.
a two nome condition number. I don't
know what that is. Lots of mathematics.
Okay. So,
so I digressed into uh random things.
Now I wanted to know what is I want to
ask AI tell me what is the significance
of uh Huba matrix. Okay. So let's ask
AI.
What is the significance
of taste here matrix? Answer me.
Okay, G. Nice answer.
The Hubert matrix is a square matrix or
it's always a square matrix introduced
by mathematician David Hbert in Hilbert
in 1894 with entries defined as this for
example that key properties symmetric
and positive definite obviously all ang
values positive
okay special case of hko matrix constant
along diagonals and co uh gshian G
matrix. Okay. So it's okay. The
diagonals are
so that's constant. Oh, all the
diagonals are equal. That's okay. That's
obvious from the definition. All the
diagonals are the same. Totally
positive. Every submatrix has positive
determinants. Okay. Has closed form
expressions for its determinant and
inverse.
Okay. So but but what is the
significance? That's my question. So
primary significance, the Hilbert matrix
is renowned in numerical linear algebra
as the classic example of an EO
condition matrix [laughter]
y condition. So it's like a monster
example, right? I mean I thought it's
useful for uh something else. It's it's
condition number in the two norm growth
exponentially with size n approximately
as uh e to the 3.5 * n power making it
extremely sensitive to rounding errors
and pertations
okay I don't know what is a two norm
even though it appears well behave
behaved symmetric positive definite this
year conditioning arises because the
matrix is the gram matrix for the
monomile basis.
Okay. Uh which is a poorly conditioned
basis for polomial le square
approximation.
Small changes in data leads to large
changes in solutions when solving
systems involving hub matrixes. Okay.
Historical and practical importance
originally used by Hubert to study
polomial approximate approximation
theory and bounds on integrals of
polomials with integer efficients.
A standard benchmark test matrix for
evaluating numerical algorithms
due to its nonexact properties and
extreme yield conditionally. Oh okay. So
when you have a numerical
sol uh methods
then you can then this matrix is helpful
to test how how well behaved is your
numerical algorithm something like that
uh demonstrates limitations of floating
point arithmetic. Okay. So that seems to
be the significance. It's kind of like
um
special you know monster you know kind
of special uh example.
Um
okay so we are kind of far from our from
the end of code. Okay.
Is this interesting?
[sighs]
Okay. So, so let's go back to um Hilbert
Matrix. Okay. So, let's go back to the
browser. Let's go back to Wuam language
list H matrix. Let's go back. So, in
fact, let's go here because it's it's
it's
um so let's go to Huba matrix vectors
and matrices. Okay,
that's a tutorial on vectors and
matrices. Go back. Let's I want to go to
guides
constructing lists constructing
matrices. Okay, so there we are.
So
array flatten array pad hub matrix hko
matrix to pleads matrix geometric
matrices rotation matrix scaling matrix
shearing matrix
structure matrixes box matrix cross
matrix diamond matrix disk matrix
gossian matrix okay let's see cross
matrix so cross matrix This looks like
that obviously.
Go back. Now box matrix looks like um
[clears throat]
gives a square pattern of ones extending
our positions from the center. So what
does that mean?
box matrix R W gives a 2 R + 1 * 2 R + 1
block of 1
centered in a W * W matrix of zero.
Okay. So, so you can have let's let's
say 10 by 10 matrix. Then you want the
center to be filled with one. So that's
like a box. So it's like um
uh
you know like this like like this
example. Okay. So that generates a
matrix of this form. That's what this
uh that's what this um box matrix is.
Okay. That so this so this will this one
be useful for our purposes? No.
But okay. So now we have some we we got
a overview of all the functions that
construct matrices.
Now let's see um
vectors and matrix. Okay. Now let's
let's try to find uh functions that
directly give us a sales neighbors.
Okay. Let's see if we can find that. Uh
in fact
in fact we can we can code this quickly.
Okay. So let me just start to do it.
Okay. Um,
one 2 3
Wait.
One, two, three. So four
7 8
9.
Okay. So we got our matrix. Now I want
to find given a index
given a position of a matrix I want to
find I want it to return all its
neighbors [clears throat]
as a list. How can we do that? Okay. Uh
I know I I I I so you want to look at
parts. Okay. The function parts.
[clears throat]
So let me think about this. Uh so for
example I can
parts XX and uh let's say uh
two two is would be five. Okay, it would
return five I mean two two sorry. Yeah.
So wait
[clears throat]
two two
is the second element and two is the
second main element of that. Okay. So
that would return five.
[clears throat]
Okay. Uh,
what
did I get? Uh,
what's
comma in? Oh, we got you see wuam
language do not like trailing commas. So
you got a comma at the end of a element.
Wu language consider that a syntax
error. I mean if you have a comma a
trailing comma then that would be
equivalent to this. Okay language adds a
new to it. So that up the matrix.
So that's not what we want. So that's
why it says warning. Okay. So let's
remove that. So let's now remove the
comma and do it. It'll be five. Okay,
you see five. Okay, let's do it again.
So you see that returns the element five
in the middle because that's a second
element of the second element. Okay. Now
I want it to be able to return all the
neighbors. I want it to return 1 2 3 4 6
7 8 9. Okay. Now if I'm at six then I
want it to return 2 3 5 8 9. How do you
do that? Okay that's that's the
question. Let's let's do that. If we can
do that then then it it it became like
very trivial. Okay we don't have to
tediously do do loop and check
boundaries and and so on.
XRD. Hi. Hi. Checks. Uh, checks. Man,
Firefox also censoring talk show. What
are you talking about, guys? Man,
Firefox also censoring your talk show.
What do you mean link? Oh, yeah. When
you click the link, it says HTTPS error,
right? Yeah, Firefox does that. And also
Google Chrome. But actually, Google
Chrome, I think I tried few days ago, it
actually works.
So you just remove go to the URL field.
Go to the URL field. Now where is my
browser? Yeah. Go to the URL field.
Delete the s in https for my website.
Okay.
Okay. So now let's uh actually try to
solve this
now.
What we want to do is to find a function
or write one
so that it returns a
cell returns all the neighbors of a
given cell of 2D matrix.
For example,
Five returns.
One, two, three, 4, 6, 7,
8, 9
in the above.
And uh
six
six returns 235
89.
Okay. So that is what we want to do. If
we successfully found this function then
we consider we done with this problem
for for my talk show for today.
Okay. So let's let's you know let's
wander around the computing universe.
Okay. So what is this um let's use mouse
track ball. Track ball is the best
vector in matrices. What is it talking
about? So I used to read you know I've
been reading movement language like for
I read you know there's like over 1,000
pages manual. I read I read it from
cover to cover just you know three times
in different years cover to cover. So I
just read this for fun, you know, like
like like what I'm doing today, you
know, you look at Hubert Matrix, you
read, you know, oh that's what Hubert
Matrix does and then so you you'll
learn. So here's my recommendation, you
know, that's like off topic. So you you
you download Wuam language, right? you
download from you know my link
and then you um
then then you just uh play with it and
you read their documentation you you can
just like just read it for fun if you
are uh let's say college students or
whatever you are young people so you
just read it for fun you will learn
tremendous if you learn if you read the
whole thing you you become
you would have a equivalent of a college
degree uh even beyond you know like
beyond like a master's degree if you
spend four years just to read and
understand all the functions of wuam
language okay so that's one what I'm
telling you guys it's superb it's like
nothing like it
in my 30 years of computing experience
there's nothing uh like like this wolf
language system
Nothing not mat lab not Maple not you
know nothing like competing products you
know this competing products Maple Mat
Lab Statistica and today you have like
Python with a huge numpy and so on you
know that's nothing compared to the warm
system
okay so let's see so constructing
matrices now let's see applying
functions repeated so we want to find
this kind of um kind of getting the
neighbors. Okay. Uh we can actually we
can we can do it quickly. So let me just
try to do it quickly. Let's not Okay.
Let me just read it. Might be mentioned.
Um
okay. So this is the thing we are
focusing on. Okay.
Um
so let's focus. So you want to find the
neighbors. So given a matrix a 2D matrix
and given a particular
position a specification for the indexes
you pinpoint a particular cell in a
matrix then you want the function to
return all its neighbors. Okay,
including like out of bound, you know,
if there's no, you know,
the special case. So
how do you do that? So one way
is simply to pad the matrix. So let's
quickly Okay, let's let's code this
quickly. Now let's begin to actually
matrix pad array pad. Okay. Array pad
padding on every side. Okay. Array pad.
Okay. So, yeah. Array pad. Yep. Two. So,
array pad one. So, okay. So, we can do
this array pad.
Okay. So, let's do this quickly.
array pad xx and uh and what is the
specification you array and it pass zero
okay so uh one so uh one means
uh one row per side okay delete that
delete that okay run it
fantastic
let's see
fantastic and beautiful Okay, that's
what we want.
Okay, so that's so that's one that's one
method, one approach. Once we do this,
then
then the then use uh Okay, so you see
here a neighbor. So let's now let's just
quickly search for neighbor. Okay.
N E G H
corner neighbors nearest neighbors G
neighbor data neighbor graph neighbor
nearest neighbor graph nearest neighbor
degree. Okay, let's see. Corner
neighbors is option for real array and
image processing functions that
specifies whether diagonal adjacent
corners should be considered neighbors.
So that's an option to many functions.
That's not what we want.
Okay. Uh but what functions use this
option? So that would be key. So they uh
Okay. So eight cornered components. So
example.
Okay. So you see this is critical but
the key so this is option to many
functions. The key now is which function
uses use this option?
morphological
components. Jesus, what what function is
that? Morphological components gives an
array in which each pixel of image is
replaced
gives an array in which each pixel of
image is replaced by an integer index
representing the connected foreground
image component in which the pixel lies.
Okay, it's like so this is uh used in
part of image processing
morphological components.
So it uh it for each pixel it returns a
integer or comp uh connected connected
components. Okay.
So you see it can so it it kind of
manipulates a matrix
you see given this matrix it returns
this matrix
okay but that's related to image
processing okay
now imagine one of advent of code
question ask this you know it face it
phrase in a different way but if you
know just one single function will solve
it okay That's interesting. So, let's
let's um
let's make a screenshot of this. Okay.
Like because it's interesting.
Um
what
morphological components. Okay. Now go
back.
Now what else uses? What else? Okay. Not
many uh chessboard distance, Manhattan
distance,
diamond matrix, box matrix.
Got it. Finding the morphological
perimeter of an object. Okay, so you can
kind of do that.
Uh and diamond matrix just generates a
diamond matrix. That's uh is that
useful? No.
Corner neighbors. Let's go there. Corner
neighbors is an option, right? Yeah. But
that uh
Okay. So, we need to get the parts. Now,
again, you you need to get the
neighbors. So,
easy way. So, each you see normally uh
this is like this is how you get the
part. So first of all you got row number
then column number. So the the neighbor
above the row is just minus one. So
minus one and plus one and the column
number is minus one and plus one. So you
can you can write it trivially. Okay. So
let's write a function
a ghs.
Okay. Get neighbors equals to um so get
neighbors
matrix. Okay. Then uh
row
column. Okay.
And uh you return
you just return um
well you you you you first of all you
pad the matrix
[sighs and gasps]
[clears throat]
so block.
Okay. So you
block uh
okay so this is padded matrix equals to
that then what you do you just um well
so before we do that let's experiment
first okay so you just say pad uh uh
actually part
and what is the matrix here? So let's
just copy. Okay, so
wait part that matrix. Okay, so two
uh so wait.
Okay, so let me
Okay, so
So you actually you got a list. Ah,
easy. Let's just hardcode it. Actually
hardcoded. [laughter]
Oh god, this this is so funny. Actually,
I know what to do now. Okay. So, it's
like um okay,
we just we just hardcode the fog,
you know, because if you got
two-dimensional matrix, you can hardcode
it. But if you got threedimensional
matrix or fourdimensional matrix,
you can still hardcode it. Then it
becomes like for two dimensional you got
eight
eight lines of hardcoded you know for
three dimensional then you got
um
you know you got like twice as much then
four dimensional and so on and so you
can actually write a loop but but for
now let's uh hardcode it and see what we
got. So
uh x row
minus one.
So something like that. Okay. So minus
one.
Yeah. So
So [snorts] now I got a better way.
Hold on a second. Now we got a better
way. Anyone following me? You guys know
what I'm talking about. You know, you
guys don't know what I'm talking about.
Let's say 35. We want to get um
[clears throat]
+ one minus one.
Okay, let's see.
Okay.
Okay. So, wait. I got more ideas. Okay.
So,
Okay.
Okay, let's run that.
Fantastic. Can you see how beautiful it
is?
So, one, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine. One, two, three,
four, five,
6 7 8 9. So you we we don't want the one
in the middle.
See
first minus. So yeah, you don't want the
one in the middle. Okay, let's do it
again. We are trying to get the neighbor
index correct.
Symbolic computation. This is the power
of symbolic computation. Okay.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 Fantastic
and beautiful. This is the power of
symbolic computation. Can you can do you
guys see what I'm doing?
Okay. So, actually um
actually this will this will uh you're
going to get you're going to flatten it.
Okay. Do you guys see what I'm doing?
So, you got this. You got all possible
neighbors. So,
one, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight. That's the neighbors of the cell.
Okay. Delete that. Delete that.
Okay, beautiful. Now,
now, now remove our testing code. Now,
yeah, now we don't need this manual. We
don't need to manually code this
anymore. So, we just generate the we
just do this. Okay, now we got this. Um
Oh, you don't want them to be um
You want them to be Wait, eight of them.
Wait,
hold on a second.
So,
one, two, one, two, three, 4. One, two,
three, four. So,
so x x is the row number. Okay. Plus y
is a row number. So,
so x is has two variations minus one and
+ one.
And y has two variations y minus one and
plus one. Okay. So this evaluates two.
Oh, okay. So
y has two. So you want to flatten this.
Okay.
Okay. Then you feed that to purpose.
Let's see. Let make sure.
Wait, wait. You wait. Um,
two.
So how do we generate this correctly? We
are almost there.
Anyone watching?
Okay, we are almost there.
So let me think. Okay. Otherwise, I'll
just non-stop trial and error.
So you want
you want all tpples. Okay. But each topo
is
so
X [clears throat] and white.
What's
One, two, three, four. Oh, but so this
does not count diagonal.
So wait, x + one, y + 1.
Wait, that's a diagonal. So wait, one,
two, three, four.
Oh, so wait. So you need the you need
the zero case
if Yeah. So you need the zero case.
Zero. Yes. Then you need to remove the
zero. Okay. You need to remove the zero
zero case.
Right. So this in this case
it returns nine of them. I think one,
two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine. Then you need to remove the
zero zero case
which is it's like
annoying.
So is it possible to not
I mean you can remove it manually
because that's one two three four five
that's always the fifth element you can
drop you know you can delete that
element but um
okay so this so this is how you generate
then you need to delete the fifth
elements then that's inelegant.
Okay. Or if you do this. So
yeah, you need to drop that middle.
Okay. And uh [laughter]
Okay. Then you just then you um
Yeah. Let's do this. Let's copy that
there. This is how we should do it.
And you need to drop the um
So, let's go to my tutorial.
[clears throat]
list. You want to go to list operations.
Then you want to uh
delete elements
drop. Yeah, delete end items. Uh
delete end item. That's how you do it.
So you can
yeah you can use delete cases or you can
just actually
Okay.
Uh we can you know what we can do is
first of all generate it. Let me show
you. Okay. Then we can just uh
delete cases
that you want to delete uh the case of X
and Y.
Okay. So that
you see you got this X and Y. That's
what you don't want that. Okay. But if
you do this, it'll it'll work.
Okay. So
you see that XY is gone. So you can do
this. Okay.
So and uh then okay this generates the
indexes of the neighboring cell. Okay.
Uh so so let's so let's delete that. So
let's delete that
de. Okay.
Then then this we don't need to manually
code it. Okay. So we just basically just
do this kind of
and uh this x would be x row. So replace
X row
and the Y would be
X column.
Okay,
that returns.
Oh, then then it it just generate that.
Then you need to apply parts. Okay, then
you just you just what you do is you
map.
Let me show you.
Okay. So
there. Okay. Map function parts at
Wait,
let me um
Uh if you don't know what splice is, it
just remove the outer brackets. Okay, so
let me show you for example. Um FF you
have a function you splice it just
return FF ffx comma y. Okay,
let me show you what this uh
Wait,
what?
Wait, not splice. Okay,
this is experimental. No, that's we are
one I want is sequence.
Yeah, sequence 1996. That's right. Not
splice. We want sequence.
Okay. So, let me show you what that
does. It just remove the square
brackets. Okay.
Uh no.
Uh what you have to do is you have to
do this.
Yeah. Well, if you want to do that. So
wait.
So the problem usually is you have
something there. Okay. So let's see.
You see? So,
what you want is, do you guys know what
I'm doing? I don't think so. Okay.
What you want is um
which is apply.
You see what you want is this. So
basically you got a function ff and you
got some kind of argument a value a list
right but you want to feed that to a
list. So you that's basically that's
what you do. Okay.
So that's why that's what basically what
we want to do is uh here.
[clears throat]
No actually we don't need to do it. We
can just say x row.
Uh we we uh well that that is the well
we can just say
first
second okay it's the part two yeah
so this function
Or you can say last. Okay, let's just
say last
and let's just say first
is they are the same thing. Okay, first
x last x.
Yeah, that will return
this function will return.
Now this function will return the
neighbors. Shall we try it? Yeah, why
not? So So why why don't we just try it?
Okay.
So we need to define
so we um
delete that delete that delete that
show example of using
sequence. That's what it is. Okay. It
basically
removes the
races.
Okay. Now uh so that's kind of example.
Let's uh
let's put the example somewhere at the
end. Let's Okay, now we back to this
this issue. Array padding is another
example. Let's um
Okay. So
So let's clean up. Okay.
from language array padding example.
Then create another
language block. Then let's put another
example. Um
wait, hold on a second. Let's look at
the comp. So yeah.
Okay. So
there and uh create another wra language
block and uh there's more things we want
to move to the example. So we want to
demonstrate the flat. Okay.
So we want to demonstrate this. Okay.
That returns that. So you guys know
cut
and uh hold on a second.
So
So that returns that. Then we do
turpples. Okay.
Okay. So, actually we want the we want
to include the zeros. Okay. So, yeah.
So, cut that. We want purpose.
example of purpose to be that. Okay. And
so
wait.
So cut that. Paste.
Run it.
That returns that. Okay. Now delete
delete and tle that returns that. Okay.
That's a like good example.
Okay. Then uh rest delete
delete. Okay. Delete. Delete. Okay. So
we
cut put it back and put it there. Syntax
value the whole page show in browser. So
we have now kind of
cleaned up uh what we are doing. So it's
it's more organized. Show example of
sequence. Show example of these tpoles
symbolic computation. Show example of
this um
automatic expansion of you know auto
apply to each element of a list.
And then here we show a example of the
get neighbors. So now the code is like
uh clear.
What? Uh
what?
Okay. So now
now let's go to work on our code,
right? That's that's the input. So now
no now uh
okay now let me do this. Okay. So,
yeah, that's a tose. Okay, that's a
topos.
So, we don't need So, you Well, you need
you have to have the DD case. Okay, so
we need to use the DD case.
not include.
Okay, cut. Put it back.
Now,
let's do this here.
Okay. Now that's a better documentation.
Now this is example of
expanding
auto apply
operator
to list element.
Okay. So that's clear
uh toology purposes. Okay. Now
syntax collect go to the things we are
working on. Showing browser should go
down. Go down. Yeah. Now let's go to the
things we are working on.
Okay.
Now
cut.
Put it back. And the new one will find
language.
No that.
So
it neighbors
uh neighbors x uh
yeah. So copy it. Let's run this in wam
language.
Paste the code. There it is. That's our
matrix. That's our function. And shift
enter.
Uh wait, it's not evaluate. Oh, you
forgot to give a you have to specify
what which neighbor you want. Let's say
one two two
and two. It should return.
You see uh do you know? So do you guys
know
me doing
control shift D to separate it? So shift
enter to evaluate it and let's say
matrix
form
show that as a matrix
and uh this actually this we need to
turn that into um
to a inline documentation for this uh
function. This is how you do it equals
to and uh this is a string. So that's
the inline documentation for this
function. So you need to say that
matrix
um matrix 2D
column uh row
column.
Okay, that's a documentation for this
function.
So,
if
matrix is
then
cell uh cell five return that
Okay, something like that. That's a
documentation for our matrix and that
that needs to put there. Okay, so
we are doing a lot of these. Um so um so
now separate these two
and
then this shift enter
two two
Okay, this is incorrect. 0 02045
2 4 5 2045
2 4 5 So it's actually returning Oh
yeah, that you forgot to add one because
since you padded the matrix then you
need to add everything plus one. Okay,
so that's what we need to do.
first one. Now I need to know the
default
um
stickiness of the operator uh precedence
of the operator. So if you type first
add x + one does the x + one get
computed first or the first. So it turns
out the first computed first because you
can click it three times. You're just it
will show you the connection. Okay, you
see. So the so in other words
in other words you do not need to put a
parn. You can if you want to but it's
not necessary. Okay. So first plus x1
then the last also needs to plus one. So
now we redefine our function and now
let's test this two two. Okay. Select
all. Select all. Go here. Click.
Paste. Shift. Enter.
1 2 3 4 6 7 8 9. That seems correct.
Okay, that seems correct for the
neighborhood of five. Let's do it again.
First of all, let's have a visual crew.
Now let's say one one. Okay. Let's see
what you get. One one.
So you get 245. That's correct. Now what
do you say if one two? You should get 1
3 4 5 6
1 3 4 5 6. Beautiful.
Now if you say
three 1 three which is this element the
first row the third column is three so
the result should be 256
shift enter 256
perfect
now let's try another case the last one
33 okay
shift enter
33 is 56
568 Perfect.
So let's make a screenshot of this. This
is basically we did it. Fantastic.
Beautiful.
Okay, I think we are done.
So anyone watching? So what do you guys
have you guys been paying attention? Do
you guys like this stream?
Uh so actually you know we did it. So
this function now is perfect.
So can you answer the problem? Yes. So
now it's trivial. Okay. Five minutes.
Five more minutes.
Okay. So given the matrix. So okay.
So let's put it back. Syntax collect
show in browser. So we got this.
Okay. So far so good. Yes. Very good.
Now all we have to do is to
wait. Where's our code? Oh, our code is
here. Okay. Now all we have to do is to
we we need to turn this into a matrix.
Then
apply our function to each and every
cell. then
just then just um if it's not zero we
add it I mean if not if is you know if
if more than um
if if if
there are
let's see zero or one or two or three
neighbors.
So if the nonzero total number of them
is either zero or one or two or three
then you consider that special then you
just count total number of special
cells. What's your opinion on Epstein
files okay? Are you guys trolling? Okay,
stop trolling. You know I have my
opinions but today we are doing this uh
wuam language. We not going to talk
about that.
Um,
so, okay. So,
fantastic. Okay. So, f fantastic. Um,
yeah. So, if we're going to code that,
that'll take 10 minutes. Okay.
Uh, yeah. So, if I code it without
talking,
it'll take 10 minutes. But if I code it
and talking doing live stream, it'll
take like 20 minutes or more.
But anyway, this is what we want to do
and it's fantastic. How long we've been
going?
We've been going almost two hours. Okay,
let's continue. Why not? 10, you know,
since we are already here. Okay,
so
Okay. So, let's let's do it. Okay. So,
let's do we have Yeah, we don't have
that. We don't have Okay. So, now
um
Okay. No.
So
I want to make sure I have everything.
Yes. Okay. Now
wait.
Yeah. Okay. So,
yep.
Okay. So,
how do you turn this into a matrix?
Well,
Jesus,
we did this before in previous advent of
code, but
Okay, let me quickly try to code it.
Okay, characters.
You got character and you got characters
represent a single character in read
there that returns a list of characters.
Okay.
Okay, let me just code it. Okay.
Uh,
string replace
SP.
Okay. string replace x input
uh then what do you do sp okay so dot
becomes uh that's not regular expression
right no
zero and uh extra rules
so you need
uh
add sign
replaced by
one. Okay,
do we get it right?
Oh,
you get stringy expression.
Right. That's right. So, um,
okay. So you do that. Okay. Then
then
string splits
that
by
uh
He's too occupied with string expression
to
to read up on any of that. What's your
opinion?
No, I just read it. I just explained
that you don't know what I'm you guys
are not watching
kind of city.
Um,
so, so what's going on? This uh
So what is this string expression? this.
Uh,
oh god, I need to I want to finish this
quickly because I don't want to uh this
is in this is why does it return this?
I don't want to end up spending like
another hour and not have this done.
Yeah, the people before you they are
asking about what's your opinion about
this political topic kind of idiot. So I
explained that this is not the time we
talk about that. Okay. Um today we are
focusing on this wam language. That's
what I'm saying.
Okay. I want to finish this quickly. Now
this this is uh this is incorrect. Now
this string replace why does it uh tell
me that oh yeah because 01 that's not a
string of course you need to that's you
know you need to that needs to be string
idiot.
So
okay so delete that delete that delete
that and go back here. Here, here, here,
here, here, here, minute here. Return a
string.
Okay, beautiful. Now that now that's
what we want. Okay, now put the
semicolon. So, it's suppress the output.
So, once you have the uh string, then
you can you can kind of string split
at this expression. Okay, let me just
code it. Okay,
suppress that output.
Uh then you you you uh we are turning
this into a uh matrix. Okay,
so so let me just do it. Okay, so so you
do that then.
Okay, so
you do that and uh
Okay. So, you need the characters
to string. Okay. So, you so you get the
list of characters then.
So that's a list of characters and
basically that's it. Okay. So if you do
that
that's a result. Okay. So if you guys
don't know let me show you in this
notepad this here notepad. Paste it.
Okay. You run it shift enter. So you see
they become a matrix and each of these
are um they are strings. You need to
turn it into digit. Yeah. Okay. So turn
the string. So you need to then you need
to map
two expression to all the all the
elements zero and one. Okay. So two
expression
>> [sighs]
>> uh two expression
map at that.
Okay. Basically so copy that. Go back to
notebook. Paste it. Shift enter. So now
those are numbers. Okay. If you don't
believe me, shift
control shift
L
to copy the output. And so you can see
those are numbers. On the other hand,
this if you do control shift L, you see
those are strings. You see? So right now
they are numbers because we called two
expression that slash add is like map
okay that's a shortcut syntax for map a
function something so in this case this
is a function and this is a something so
we have like two maps there so in other
words I mean so now we can clear so so
this turns it into a matrix so let me
comment
one.
Okay, that line turns the matrix into a
matrix. Then then uh then we just uh
yeah, so
x matrix equals to okay then we don't
need that. Then then you can say part
xmatrix.
Uh
so now if you say uh well I mean you
don't need to do that. So copy or
paste shift enter then you say x matrix.
Okay. Then slash slash
matrix form
slash slash is a postfix notation. So
this would be this is a syntactical
shortcut for matrix form bracket matrix.
Okay. So if you run that it shows you
that. Okay. Fantastic and beautiful. And
in fact, let's make a copy of these two
so that uh because this is a good um
kind of a summary part of our
code. Okay. Well, it needs to be bigger.
Okay. You don't you don't want it to be
too big because the I mean you got
because the font is super big here.
Yeah. So now it's better.
Fantastic and beautiful. You see this
this single line of expression turns
this this uh text into a matrix of zeros
and ones. So you guys want to see what
I'm saying? Okay. So we we got a
screenshot here.
Where's the screenshot?
There.
So this is today we did this kind of
thing that that that
okay so anyway it's back. So now we got
the matrix now.
Now put it back. Now showing browser we
need our previous neighboring function.
So we need to copy that. Copy.
So okay. Yeah. So there's error of
course because this this is not valid
HTML because this greater than equal
sign that's why when you show this in
browser it automatically does a validate
then you tell you there's a syntax error
of your HTML now if you do
syntax color the code so you see those
greater than equal sign become in amp%
encoded now you showing browser. Now it
says valid. It there's no error. So now
now it shows. Okay. But now we need to
copy our code about um about this
neighborhood uh function. So go back
here
uh
yeah back okay then neighborhood
function.
Fantastic. Okay. So we don't need this
test need. So now define our
neighborhood function.
Okay. So
then
so let's just quickly
uh let's [clears throat] quickly turn uh
let's quickly solve our problem. So I'm
just going to code it. Okay. [snorts]
get neighbors. So this is actually
inefficient but because each time
neighborhood get neighbor is called it
actually create a padded array. That's
not good. So we we should we should do
the pad array
to our in to our uh you know input array
instead. So but anyway let's
let's let's move on. Okay.
So you want to get neighbors. So you
want to get neighbors
then once so get neighbors of a um of
like x and y okay of column number and
row
so the matrix uh
dimensions okay
dimensions uh in this case it returns
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 11 uh
11.
Wait. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10. Okay. 10 x
10 matrix. Okay. 10 x 10 matrix. Then
then what? Um then you want to so 10 by
10. So 10.
So array.
So we want to generate a 10 by 10 array.
Okay. So
what what
uh let's say 3x3
we don't want to generate array but we
want to generate the index. Okay. So 10
by 10 would be yeah. So we want the
index
10 and this will be a list. Okay. So
it'll be 1 one two 1 3 and so on. So you
see we want the index of 10 by 10.
Uh and we don't want array. So actually
uh
now the way to do it is
Yeah, that's what you want. Okay. So,
so what you got after you do that be we
want all possible uh indexes because
we're going to map over it. Okay. So,
you So, now you map over uh you want to
map. So, let me show you. So, you want
to map
map a function. What function you want
to map? uh you want to map this function
uh you have to write it. Okay. So well I
get tedious but never mind let me just
code it. Okay. So the function uh oh god
so this would be x matrix
uh no not tag name. What
what
why am I get the tag name? Uh where does
tag name came from?
Not sure where that came from. So X
matrix. So,
so you want to map this function to
to to
matrix.
Wait, wait, wait, hold on a second. So
to not to not to matrix but to this tle.
So
yeah,
that that will return things. But um
Okay, close.
Okay. So, go
six.
Did we define X matrix? Yes, X matrix uh
there.
So, when you get neighbors, so let's
see.
base. Shift enter.
Okay, you got a problem.
One one
shift enter.
So what is our matrix?
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10. So
So matrix 11 one you got this is not
correct. Why do you get 245?
Because our X matrix they got hardcoded
something. Okay. I mean because our get
neighbors we probably hardcoded
something. Yes. You see you got you got
a xx here. Where does that come from?
This xx. Can you guys see what
you see that xx? That's a mistake. Uh so
that should be the matrix.
Okay. So, you need to clear that.
[laughter]
Make sure check one more time.
Is that correct?
Make sure you don't have leaked
variable. Okay, I think so. Okay, paste
it there. Run it. Now go back here.
Go back to uh
now go back here. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Let's see. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
neighbors. Correct. Now let's say 110
the 10th um item first row 10th column
shift enter it should be 111 111 correct
now
now um now let's say 10 10 okay 10 and
shift enter
one one one correct okay fantastic so
our neighborhood get neighbors function
now is correct.
Now put it back.
Now let's remember to
to correct the code over here as well.
Okay.
At xx.
Okay. Shift enter. I mean I mean uh
syntax collect.
Okay. Now let's show in browser back to
here. Pop it out. Okay. So perfect. Now
now when you do this you get all
neighbors. In fact you can paste it.
Okay you got you got a list of num uh
you know neighbors. It's all neighbors.
Then you just
submit.
Okay, let me just show you. Okay,
total
total. Let's see an example here.
P
four. Now if
total.
Hold on a second. Okay.
If total
is less than
less than four
then it's special. Okay. Then
one else zero. Okay. So you want to map
a function
function.
Okay.
X
map that to that. Okay. So, do you guys
see? So, you can do that. Okay.
Then you just total it again. So, I
think that's it. That's the solution.
Okay. Uh I'm getting impatient. So, I'm
not doing much examples. I mean, I'm not
doing much explanations. Okay. Now
there's an error because function if
total equals to less than four and then
x otherwise one zero. So,
Is that because I don't have a return?
Not sure.
Shift enter. There it is. Then just say
total. Okay. Total
at the last output
19. So it is the result 19. This is uh
advent of code say 19
of code let's see go here
uh 13 there are 13 rows so our answer is
incorrect
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 So
uh but we get 19 so 19 is incorrect.
Okay.
So now we need to debug.
Okay. Let's see what you say.
I just joined. Okay. Are you passing a
text grid into binary data?
Uh close. I'm I'm passing a text grid
into a matrix of ones and zero. So it's
not uh binary data. It's just a matrix
of integers.
So two expression characters at string
split pipeline joining it together
cleanly. Huh? So solid text matrix
conversion and stuff. Yes, just in uh
justing just one. Okay. So anyway, we
are very close but something something
screwed up. So um I think I'm going to
stop because it's pretty late. Well,
so now it's two two hours. I've been
doing this for two hours. Um,
why not continue
and I want to break.
Okay. So, we got it wrong somewhere. I
don't know where.
So is it less than four? What does the
problem say? Uh
if fewer than four rows of paper in the
eight adjacent positions, fewer than
four.
Yeah. So it's if it's less than four. If
it's four, then it doesn't count.
Okay. So,
so we basic so why is it not um
what's it which uh
are we using the
one two three four five six seven eight
nine 10. Yeah, this is 10 by 10 matrix,
right? This is such a simple matrix.
We haven't even got to our um
so according to this problem it says
there are 13 solution should be 13.
Consider your complete diagram of the
paper row locations. How many rows of
paper can be accessed by a forklift?
In other words, how many cells
has less than
four
neighbors.
I mean less than four of the
occupied neighbors. So less than four
ones. So let's say one one one. Yeah,
it's all represented by one and zero.
Uh so why
so where did so we got too many old
results here so we scroll down scroll
down
so we got our input two expression yeah
and so we are turning this text
into a matrix by this line of code
so we got the matrix tricks of zeros and
ones integer.
Okay. And the dot is zero. Add sign is
one. That's right. And then dimension is
10 10. Okay. Then uh
then we fixed our neighboring code which
is this one. Yeah.
So for each neighbor it returns this
list of
for for each cell in the matrix it
returns a list of its neighbors. So for
example this is the upper left cell. So
the neighbors are 011
two ones right.
Okay. So suppose that's correct then
okay then you just uh then this would
also work you know then you just so this
is a matrix check yes
then you just um yeah this is a
definition of matrix function then you
just map
you just get a tole of to is
all possible
positions in the matrix. Okay, so you
you map your neighbors function
to the topos. So you want so you get the
list of neighbors for all cells.
That's what you get.
Okay. Then for each of these sequence of
neighbors, if
you total them,
the result is a number integer. That
means how many neighbors that cell has.
So if less than four you turn it into
one otherwise you turn it into zero.
Then you just map this function
this total to to all the list of
neighbors. Right?
Then you just get that
and you total that would be you got 19
which is incorrect from 13.
Uh
okay I think I got to go. Hold on a
second.
Hello guys, we are very close but we
didn't make it. So, but I have to go
because I've been coding this for close
to 3 hours. So,
actually just two hours and 10 minutes.
Yeah, we are close. Uh but we did lots
of things. So I think that's it for well
this maybe I will probably finish it
offline. So let's put it back syntax
correct show in browser.
Uh so that's what we did very close.
Okay we you know at least we got this
very nice neighbor functions. Now they
are actually there may be better ways to
do it actually. So but you need more
time to explore wam language you see. So
the whole thing is one single line.
Uh well actually more than one single
line because you got neighbor functions
but they can you know I'm pretty sure
they they can be made into a one single
line much better ways but I got to go.
So yeah. So bye guys. Thank you for
watching. Bye.
Check. Yeah. So video check, audio
check. So, we gonna go to Google.