hi guys I'm going to show you today a
interesting programming problem about
grep so and I might be writing some emag
Lisp so let me show you what's a problem
so if I go to let's say shell and I'm
going to grab I want to grab it with
some so called grep command let's say I
want to add a scowl and in the directory
this directory so okay wow that's not
what I'm going that's not what I want so
let me show you here so cd2 web guru max
do max so I'm going to grab
that let's see
so grab Pascal and for HTML files only
and in Emacs directory so okay so that's
a result you see for example let's say
so this is a file for example this this
file uses such Emacs and this is the
line that contains Haskell you see the
word has goes here and and so on there's
another line you see but there is no way
for me to jump to to the lie so Emacs
comes to help so if I do grab in Emacs
I'm using each shell you make sure and
it shows the result so I can go to their
tab and I can open it and here I'll show
the line that contains the word I
grabbed now now however if I if I save
this great file let's say xxx I save it
close it and let's say tomorrow
I open we start in Max and open the file
again and you can see that I can still
jump to the to the line you see it's
still locate the line so so let's try
another example I go here it shows it
goes to the line how does it do that it
knows which one it is you know the
location because because it records the
file path and you see there's a number
here that's I think that's a that's how
that's a line number you see 538 line
number 538 so that's how it remembers
you know which line it is but for
example when I first returned on on this
place or if I move my cursor around
let's say here has returned how does it
know to open the file because in a
normal text file
insert a new line how does it know
because because when you open this file
in the beginning beginning you can see
it tells Emacs to to load the graph mod
so you can see current mod is grip so
you can you can tell by coding and see I
call describe variable you can see the
command is quite variable and I can say
major mod and if I'll say you know the
value is great mod which is the mod of
this buffer so Emacs open the mod and
and the mod when when the Marcie your
path file paths I mean each line is a
path basically the beginning is a pair
file path followed by a colon
that's a separator then then the line
number then you know whatever so that's
how you max can can know you know can
color the path and also when you press
ENTER on this on this on a path you open
the file ok so so that's the issue it's
close that close that close that close
that close that now good let's go to my
Emacs blog me max vlog so but I have
written a package called
codex ah find this package this package
basically it's a grep in maclisp
and I need to do the same thing so let
me try your example so this is a command
so I want to call I cook sapphire text
and then I give it a let's say a scowl a
scowl in this directory or HTML files
okay and here's the result so here's a
result so first result is is this this
in this file so let's the order is a bit
different from from the grab I don't
remember what older my command use or
abuse but anyway so anyway so all these
are occurrences and you can and so I
save the file let's say xxx save the
file and and I can move my cursor to the
Haskell and press ENTER it will jump to
the location same as before and that
let's say the next occurrence let's say
this one press enter
he'll jump to the location
but if I if I save this file it's saved
I close it and I reopen it and I move
the cursor here I press ENTER it will
not work anymore because actually I
don't have I don't actually have the
line number information in the file you
see remember how grave attaches the line
number information but I don't have it
here so that that's the thing I'm going
to do that's what I need to do so let me
try that again
so wait yeah but but how does it know
the first time why it will jump to
because of let me try that again so
search for s Cal that okay so now if I
press ENTER you jump to the file how
does it know because of text properties
you know in Emacs Emacs Lisp in Emacs
any text you know in a buffer any any
position from Big E from any position to
another position you can have what's
called text part properties embedded in
it it's not visible you know it's not
visible in the sense it's similar like
in JavaScript you have an object an
object has properties or in Java or
Python Ruby you can have a object you
know class object an object has
properties you know it's like variables
with the value you so so this has called
for for each Haskell word here there is
actually a text property in in memory so
when I press ENTER it will look up that
text property and that property will
contain the line number info maybe I can
show you so let's go to Emacs this this
side
let's see write a major mod ok so here's
text properties so
so I want to show you how to look at the
properties so do I do I have it here so
here is a protects properties that has
the text property beginning position and
position and and the property name and
property value text properties is
basically a list of key value pairs so
that's how you create a property and
what I want to do now is to actually
look up the property so I can like demo
it
what's text property function to okay I
probably don't have it here without
looking carefully but exempt properties
there it is
get text property years so I can call
text property get I can call this
command so if I'm in this buffer let's
go to the bottom and get text properties
let's say and property name position
okay I need the position so let's say
this one this word the position is from
here to here okay so let's say let's
just say that position and I need a
property name but I don't remember
what's the property name but anyway
let's let's let's not do that then but
anyway so I'm gonna show you the code so
let's go to
okay fine text this is a command so you
can see so what what do I want to do
here you see so I wanted to be such that
when I saved this file save it and close
it and reopen and when when my cursor is
on on these words I want to be able to
press ENTER it and it should be able to
still open it it won't work right now
because text properties is not saved
with the file you see that's the problem
remember our earlier grab result that
contains the file path and line number
right in the file so that's how it can
still work but here I'm using text
properties so it doesn't work so what I
want to do now is to modify my command
my package my command so that the
information about line number or
position of the occurrence is embedded
in this file like right here so actually
this number you cannot see it this
number five ones 87 is actually the
position of the first character of
Haskell occurrence I I added that
yesterday but it's not complete so it's
not it doesn't work it doesn't work
because right now when I press ENTER on
a Haskell word its it relies on text
properties to open it but since I you
know I saved this file in the reopen
text properties is gone so what I need
to change is that instead of instead of
instead of relying on text properties if
there's no text properties then you
basically just move kusa forward and and
look for special eliminator that
contains the position
of the of the character so so so that's
a problem basically that's that's what I
want I want to show you you know it's a
bit interesting issue about embedding
information in a result you know say a
report or something so that so that you
can the information still there you can
jump to it and stuff so so let me go
back to my email it's Maude I mean the
this function so you see this function
it's not too long we it's not too long
so basically just
he basically asks you a bunch of
questions like which what would you want
to search in what directory you want to
search so this is like you know what
would you want to search what directory
you want to such fire rejects like Oh
HTML files or something else and
case-sensitive print result surrounding
tech surrounding text like the context
of the occurrence and after you get all
those information then you you
you create an output buffer input
directory you normalize the input
directory you basically create alpha
buffer then print ahead print the header
that that is the date the fine text you
know the directory to set look for
things like that then this is the main
part of the program it's calling map map
see map sees basically map without
returning results so mapped see function
here is a lambda function then you
traverse a directory so this is a fine
few tourists this returns the list of
directories you know with only HTML
files or whatever we regular expression
you used recursively so so the main part
is is this function this function so
path is file path then with temp of a
temporarily switch to a buffer then
insert file contents so path is the
current path you want to look such for
the text so you insult file contents
then you search for word for such stream
then you so you if it's return true then
used in increase count then this is the
main part let's see
so when it's true yeah so this is a main
part so when it's true you found the
text you increase the counter then this
part is to print the result to a hot
foot buffer so when print context is
true you want to you call this command
because now find a cur output match
beginning that's the position of the
beginning of the occurrence match end is
the end occurrence position then you
print the then you pass the file path
the file path and the witch buffer you
want to output which is which is that
one so let's look at this is the main
part so I'll find output so let's go to
let's go to that definition so this is
the this party's main thing that
produces the output so you can see in
the in this function we have several put
text properties that's you know that's
how we are able to to jump to the
location in a file of the occurrence so
we we so look at let's see protects
poverty but p1p2 our positions like
beginning and end positions position 1
position 2 and face is the property name
then a face value value is a face means
in eMac in Emacs it's basically the
coloring or found you know so that's how
you can see color so add property face
and here is where we add the file path
as a text property embed the fire path
so that's that's why when we press
return on our currency it knows which
file to open
and in others this this one is for mouse
so that when you actually when you use
mouse mouse to click on the currency you
also do the same thing and and highlight
it so anyway so so here's so we we were
using text properties but actually
instead of text properties what we want
is let's go back to output you see
instead of like if I press ENTER now it
will look for properties but when you
save the file and we open it the
properties is gone unless unless you we
add the text properties but you can you
cannot do that unless you have the
actual information about what position
this word is on Oh in what file name so
I started to change the command to
include the position let's see so it's
easier to see so this is a position so I
started to include a position so that
now what the command so so now if I call
command he should look for the you know
line number information and look for the
file path information so there and you
should you know do the right thing so
that's one that's what I'm going to do I
think I so let's look at yesterday I I
added the position however I did not
complete a command where is it okay here
wait something okay
yeah so yesterday I made change here
so p1 is the beginning of the occurrence
position of the occurrence so I added
this is left bracket basically this is
right bracket so I did that yesterday
now now if we go back here to the output
if I press enter the command it actually
call is is this Safa and jump to place
so when it is in not in an active area
enter we will just add a new newline
but when I mean in the hot area enter we
actually try to open a file so the
command is actually this one's a jump to
jump to place so let's go back to the
file so let's let's find jump
so you can see here here is this command
is bound to the key returned so let's go
to the definition of that command oh
yeah so here is the definition and and
this part needs to change because
because before it was you know it's last
modified hyung 2017 I should add that
okay so this is modify at that time but
yesterday I modified it because in the
old version you see it's it tries to get
text property you know where the cursor
is add point
yeah so so this is how you get text
property get ex poverty position then
the property name so this property name
the value is a file path then it gets
saved here and position position to jump
to its again a text property and the
property name is case I'll find POS
position so once you get that so you
check if if it's actually a value I mean
if if the property actually exists so if
a if it exists then you check if the
file exists if it does then you use a
fine file other window it actually tries
to open the file you know the window
then it jumps to go to cha to the
position so that's how it works
but but now I don't want to be based on
properties so if property does not exist
it should start to he should start to
search for the eliminators you know this
special parent before and try to use
that as the position and and also use
this as file path so so yesterday I this
is a new code I did yesterday where it's
not complete its yeah so so this part is
now complete
so anyway that's what I want to show you
I was going to you know if we have
enough time you know I'm going to you
know just start to work on it so you can
see you know some how I work in email is
you know you can you know see some email
eMac this stuff but I think we already
took I don't know how long they're 20
minutes or so so so let's stop today for
now so I'm gonna work on getting this
fixed complete thank you for watching if
you have any comments comment comment on
the youtube if you want to see me work
on something or some Emacs demo just let
me know thanks bye