good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show
today
is 2021 november 24th
and i'm going to work on my website so
lots of tutorials on live coding
javascript emac beast wufang language
golen
or some maybe some other things golan
and all powers power script
so if you look at the youtube
description you'll see uh you know pick
a topic in the first five minutes so you
guys here
uh if you guys are still here i mean the
you know whatever in the first five
minutes if you post the topic i'll talk
about that otherwise i'm going to uh
just uh
you know doing what i whatever comes up
what i'm gonna do so first stop
so first stop is going to we are going
to do these um you see this so
you know every
hour i walk around
with my surface tablet
uh let's let let's show you keyboard
okay you are looking at my keyboard this
is kinesis advantage 2
and the
and the other one is ultimate hacking
keyboard okay kinesis advantage to
ultimate hacking and then you go to my
keyboard blog
then you go down
miscellaneous tech
click
uh then here is microsoft surface pro
i got it from a friend
uh this is from
you know five years ago
so
every
hour or two i take a walk
to prevent asteroid
uh because you know i sit here too long
it creates back pain and all that so
every every hour or two i i take this
surface tablet i walk around and i take
notes okay
copy
back to emacs
what is this page showing browser close
close pink window shows all my command
cores and the keystroke i'm typing okay
paste the link here showing browser
microsoft surface pro so
every half hour i take notes and
you are looking at one of the notes i'm
taking so
now i just closed it down
okay no problem so let's go to
uh
downloads
okay actually
x to do
okay so i have a bunch of pictures here
open in iphone view so i have a emacs
command that i just opened in the iphone
view iphone view is a great windows
application for microsoft windows for
image viewers it's a classic you know
it's very popular it's almost the most
popular uh during 1990s and 2000s
today they are still going so it's this
this is very old school so i take notes
and you know you can see my notes um
you know about things i need to work on
you know on my website for example these
emoji characters
they don't look good now
you know they should be colored you see
so i'm going to work on this
you see these emoji characters so let me
show you what is that about okay so go
to keyboard
close that
okay close uh
has a running process keyword yes this
is uh
emax problem okay close that showing
browser so go to keyboard
go to javascript okay the first thing
not this page javascript in depth
so you can see on the left panel there
are emoji character unicode emoji
characters what i want to do
is let me explain what's going on okay
so video check am i am i am am i doing
good video check audio check yeah good
okay
comments good morning alan
and good morning arnold's greeting from
california great california arnold's hey
okay so
you know pick a topic if you if you like
me to talk about something but otherwise
i'm not gonna continue so this is about
emoji and the font issue unicode so you
can see
these
for example
javascript in depth this is my
javascript tutorial buy it okay this is
the best tutorial in english
in depth and
condition and precision accuracy
okay so so this you got this emoji
character so let me show you where they
appear so let
so you can see
here is the let okay let's turn on
global highlight mod so you can see
these lines those are the emoji
characters now why why they show let me
show you a
alternative okay so
yeah okay so let's copy that
paste it here
let's
make a
span uh what
wait
what happened to my spam tag
well it's uh it's broken
yeah
okay let's fix that so emac this html
mod
describe function describe key press the
key and so here is the command cause htr
insert tag right now i want to insert a
spam tag but somehow
somehow it's not working so let's go to
search for spam
so there is the span but why is it not
showing okay
press the key
span
press a key
yeah i don't know what's going on
okay let's forget about that because
let's continue with this topic so let's
just uh let's just add a p
let's change this to span okay
so
i'm gonna show this how this works okay
style equals to
font family okay
let's magnify well let's do it like this
way so font family and font family will
be equals to split window go to my css
file and you can see
font let's search for emoji
search for e more g
okay
so you want to use the fonts let me show
the difference okay
so
so for family circle ui symbol okay
so you can see that part okay let's make
it clear okay so let's do it this way
fun family circle
uh ui symbol then
this one circle ui emoji let me make it
that way
okay so now we have these two lines one
is using the circle ui emoji font and
one is circle ui symbol those are
default microsoft emoji or symbol fonts
okay now show in browser
you can see there's a difference now the
first one is shown as emoji the second
one is shown as a symbol no color so
in my use case
you know for this index navigation panel
i want them to be emoji so they stand
out so let's change that
so
so let's change that now
i have a better way because for example
let me paste it here so for example
instead of
instead of using a style specifying
style inline i can just say a class
okay the class is going to be
emoji xl xli okay now you go to the
browser refresh you can see
you see using the class emoji
okay so
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
change so i'm going to delete those ddos
delete those
and by the way about the font you can go
to my css tutorial
you know javascript in depth go up the
directory web dev tutorials you click on
css then you go down there's font family
there's common web fonts click on that
then you can see uh explanation or
tutorial about all you need to know
about font
then you scroll down you can see several
uh
metric compatible fonts so helvetica
aerial liberation sense
remo all those are essentially the same
font created by different companies
okay helvetica is on the mac able is
windows liberation sense is linux a remo
is created by google they are basically
exactly the same okay in the same way
you have calibre and
calito kalito is from google calibro is
microsoft's new font
10 years ago then you have times news
roman okay and so on okay then
you have standard emoji fonts so on
microsoft platform it's circle ui emoji
on apple's it's apple color emoji the
name must be exact so this is useful for
your web devs you know you you guys who
work on you know web dev when you want a
font
you want an emoji font you want to
specify one of these you know then noto
color emojis from google so these are if
you have a character that's emoji you
want to make sure it's it's it is shown
as colored emoji then these three are
what you want to use
now on linux
i don't think linux has a dedicated
emoji font basically they just use
google you know so noto color emoji so
so that's about emoji font now if you
want the font to show
as a symbol
um
get close
you know as a symbol for example you can
see all these are
emoji characters that are shown as
symbol and meanwhile these are shown as
emoji you know color so if you want to
make sure they show a symbol then you
want to use the standard unicode symbol
fonts so
circle ui symbol apple symbols
neutral sense symbols now notice there's
a little now there's again naming of
things issue so you can observe you know
as a technologist you observe what other
people are doing so here is a naming
issue so microsoft they don't use
plurals they just say they just call it
sergio ui symbol there's no it's not
server ui symbols
meanwhile for apple and
google they say apple symbols and
neutral sense symbols
it's interesting because now in the
emoji case they all just say emoji they
don't say because
well emoji can can be also plural you
know
um
so anyway the naming of things it's
interesting how you know here we see a
difference between microsoft and google
on the plurality on the um
you know the naming of the font
okay
so that's how you uh
that's about symbol and font so let's go
to talk show page showing browser uh not
this page today today's talk show show
in browser and let's paste the link so
we
have a log of what we talked about
common web fonts okay close that and uh
yeah common web fonts okay
then um
yeah
okay so
so open the browser so again
so now
combine those
now
let's go back to the javascript page
okay
now let's go to back to javascript page
now
remember
now i want to replace all the star sign
characters by the
by the you know
by that okay let's do it
so
you know
in this directory
there are
about
800 files so you basically you want to
do a find replace on all the 800 files
why because
each one of these
panel appears on every page okay so
let's do that so i call the command this
command is
something replace text okay it's on my
website you know if your emac user buy
it let me let me demonstrate how it
works so such string
such string is going to be this star
symbol let's magnify
okay then replace string is gonna be
that
okay wait
uh okay well actually let's not use that
let's just re
let me show you okay let me just go
ahead and show you okay hold on a second
so instead of we just search uh
query replace
star
by
making a span class okay
do it okay actually not that one
um
do it
do it do it do it do it do it do it do
it do it do it
do it do it do it do it do it do it okay
there's no more now
show in browser
you can see now they are all shiny stars
fantastic now we need to fix that one
thumb down you know you see that thumb
down that's a really ugly thing you know
this font i you know
uh sergio ui symbol microsoft that's
really ugly and
in fact it does not serve communication
purposes well because that thumb down
doesn't look like a thumb down does it
look like a thumb down to you no so that
doesn't communicate
you know it failed
failed the purpose of the emoji
character okay so but anyway so let's
make it color emoji let's fix that so
let's go to
copy this character go back to the top
interactive find replace
okay
then this is the emax feature you can
see let me demonstrate so
replace that thumb down by
this thumb down
span some down okay do it
do it
okay there's only one occurrence okay
that's fantastic shrink the window
showing browser
fantastic now you actually have a thumb
down okay now what we need to do is we
if we click on another page let's see
you know right now
this is the index page page javascript
in depth now if we click on another page
for example if we click on let
you see they are back to the symbol font
why because we haven't changed those in
those pages and we are going to do it
now so copy the url
back to emacs then i call this command
that will open
[Music]
whatever the path in the click board you
know just one key press so you can see
the command is open file from clipboard
so we are now at this page java
javascript let decorate declaration
which is this page
okay like showing browser you know so
now we we we want to find and replace
all the text for the left panel so
so search for panel so there it is
this section
you know this whole section
we want to replace it so copy the whole
thing copy it
then i call the command
you can see the command is
the command is casa find replace text
okay
we are going to to find replace on a few
hundred files okay so
the fine text is this whole giant block
of text you know few thousand characters
you know try to do that in
in in unique script in set you know it's
you cannot do it
uh you know that so this this this is
about the topic of the unix philosophy
which i despise so much you know it
cannot do lots of things
because the unix grip and set they are
based on they are line based
you know they are line based so if you
are find text or replace text you know
if your text you want to find these
multi multiple lines then you have
difficulties with unix tools
okay so that's right so i have this
package cause i find on my website you
know
search focus saudi emacs start find dot
e l you'll find it if you like it buy it
okay pay me
so i want to find this uh text enter and
it asks me for replace string okay so
replace string close this file
okay let's cancel okay so replace string
is going to close this file so replace
string is going to be copied so let's
call the command again
so search string press up arrow the last
search string okay uh replace string
let's paste it this is the new replace
string okay now if we go to the top you
can and move down you can see
you know it's got the
class emoji span okay this is a replay
stream now
directory name okay this is a current
directory yes
file path regular
expression.html correct
now directory depth starting from depth
0 correct and at depth 9 okay
write changes to file yes
fixed case in search yes fixed case in
replacement yes
make backup yes okay now it's going
through 800 files
okay done now if i press down arrow you
can see a different file changed and
replace change you know so there are
about
100 changes you know basically
basically every
link in this panel okay go back to emacs
for example i can go jump to any of this
file oh press enter to open it show in
browser you can see this is one of the
page javascript allowed characters in
identifier so so you can see now they
have emoji color fantastic we
finished okay close that close that and
go back to diet
directory you can see all these
uh backup files those are files that has
been changed and a backup has been made
you know
uh many of them so okay close that
show in browser what's this page okay
close that close that back to emacs
close it show in browser
okay so we have done
the task you know let's you know you can
see
any of these pages are done you see
fantastic so that's one job that that's
finished the first
task on working on uh
emacs website
i mean not emacs our website okay close
that let's double check one more last
time usually um
oh there's more there's more i forgot
you see this rocket
rocket okay let's do it quickly now now
we can do it quickly
um
pipe functions so search for
so first of all copy these
show the ping window
xr find paste the search string
enter
cancel
now go up search for
functions okay now there is a rocket now
the rocket needs to replace by call
query replace
up arrow to show the last
uh find and replace string
copy the rocket sign
change the change it the thumb down to
the rocket
press enter
then
replace that one replace replace yes yes
yes yes okay done back to browser now
watch this one refresh now it's a rocket
fantastic
what does a rocket mean
a rocket means
that page contains my
personal code function you know written
javascript that allows you to do
something for example this function
get prototype chain
given any object it will show the
prototype chain the entire prototype
chain of that object that is the
object's parent's experience parent
there's no default building function to
do that in javascript so i wrote one and
and
okay so now refresh the browser wait i
missed this one pipe functions okay
let's go up
yeah because we didn't start at the
beginning okay
uh no wait
go up
replace
pipe functions oh oh yeah it's uh it's
not replaced on all those pages yet so
anyway let's do it now so copy this
block
call
code star copy file uh
code software find replace text
then
up arrow
to
to find this old text
let's see
yep you see enter now pasting the new
text you want to
replace
enter
the path and the
regular expression file for file
extension and and basically say yes to
them all
okay now again it's done lots of changes
okay back to browser refresh fantastic
you can see the rocket click on that
okay this page has also been changed so
this one add method to prototype i show
you how to add a method to prototype
in javascript okay now all these are
changed fantastic this task is done
that concludes one of the tasks of xsa
working you know website close that
close the javascript click close the css
file reopen it close it close the
help message
showing browser okay keyboard okay we're
gonna we are going to do the same
oh we don't need to do this because
on this keyboard page
by intention
these characters i want them to be shown
using the symbol
um
character
yes
why
you know the other emoji i want them to
be shown as emoji why is that because
you know it's getting into technical
details of the unicode because if you
look at the
if you use uh emoji font for this return
symbol they don't work well for each
because for example okay
i talked about this uh two or three days
ago okay
so i'm not going to do it so close that
close that
okay um
so that's okay so go open the talk show
page again open say today's talk show
okay that we finished uh doing one of
the thing which is this one
make emoji character color on javascript
page and the keyboard page actually we
don't need to do keyboard page show the
show the digital pen written notes so
here's the digital pin written notes
okay actually so we need to do that as
well so that is on the keyboard page so
let's do it
go to keyboard
bookmark let's show the ping window
showing browser so ergonomic keyboard so
you can see
there's a thumb up that doesn't look so
good
so i need to change it okay so
[Music]
yeah okay copy the url back to last
app
open
the
path in the click board
then you scroll down
search for
advantage okay so there is your thumb
so what i want to do now is to replace
those thumb characters by
yeah i don't really
want to do this you see what i want to
do is replace this by
uh you know this is what i spent all my
day in the past 10 years working on you
know
writing either new articles or maintain
my website so there's lots of to do
because
so this this comes to you know let me
show you another one of my article
so you go to code ksari.info
and you scroll down
you will see
complexities
complexity and tedium of software
engineering
you know
it's fascinating you know imagine
software you know coding is so should be
easy right because what else to do you
know if statements expressions you know
should be easy but why is it that we
spend all day working a job eight hours
a day for years after years decades
what are we doing
so for example you know so this is a
funny picture
so for example
you know let me tell you for example
where
what is it that you work on every day
not just me you know including you guys
working at google facebook book or
whatever what is it i mean why is there
so many things to do the bugs where do
they came from
you know then then there's agile
you know agile
uh
oil snake snake you know so so let me
explain one of the complexities where
they come from okay let's copy that back
to emacs
open my today's talk show
open today and uh
paste that link if i show in browser so
you got
a link to uh
this page
uh a record of what we talked about so
why where does the complexity come from
let me talk about one example in this
case
so on my web page you know on my web
page i want to so open that delete that
go to the browser refresh you know i'm
talking about keyboards keyboard review
right kinesis advantage this one
ultimate hacking this one i use it as a
markup
so i want you know so
emoji has been invented which is
fantastic by unicode you know so they so
what it does do it you know a sim simple
character that allows you to express
emotion
you know so for example this keyboard i
want to say this is a great keyboard you
know among the many here
you know people get confused so i want
to highlight some of them for example i
consider this one is a great one
and relative to the price too because
some of them are fantastic but however
they are 500
you know this for example this one this
one they are fantastic but
dollars
so
so i want to pick highlight some of them
i consider very good excellent and also
not too expensive so you know
so you you could so one of the ways to
use the thumb up you know very universal
symbol
by now by today you know you know in
modern society number means you know
it's this is a great one
trust you know concise communication
concepts you know you just have a thumb
up so people can see oh this you know
maybe you should check out these you
know these
these ones are fantastic right
so emoji
but now
this complexity comes in
where is the company because then you
have found you have the symbol found
you know i talked about you know you
have the symbol for i talked you know
watch my video about a few days ago this
week this week or last week okay i did a
whole episode talking about the
complexities of symbol
characters versus emoji in unicode very
complex
so
so i recently made some change to my
css you know then then there's a
complexity of the css
uh entire language you have to learn
okay
css
conceptually it's very simple you know
if you want something bold you just say
you know
class and both but actually in reality
it's then another layer of
very complex css it turns out it became
in the past 30 years it became 25 years
it became very complex
so anyway i begin you know i just want
to thumb up then
because i recently i changed you know to
some font to on my website then it
becomes this ugly thing
and the problem is that then
you have the difference you know
they are not universal you know font
on microsoft windows you have the you
know
circle circle ui symbols and servo ui
emoji you have different fonts on apple
you also have two
and google chrome also have two
symbol versus emoji
and even if you use the same symbol font
you know doesn't matter on apple or
microsoft or google chrome
symbol font they look different
so when they look different so there's
another issue about emoji okay so
for example emoji
you know you are talking with friends
you use the emoji but depending on where
you are on windows on
apple on google's chromebook or if you
are on discord or if you are on twitter
the
facial expression
do not look the same
so sometimes you pick one you you think
that indicates smile smiling but um
but what they see
is laughing you know it's like [ __ ] up
[ __ ] up [ __ ] so this complexity
so back so back to you know in my use
case you know i want the sim
i want the thumb up
but now it shows like this you know this
you know it's even it's hard to
see what that what the [ __ ] that is
you know
you know i i like simplicity okay i
don't i don't want to dive into detail
about oh actually i prefer you know the
emoji of apples because a certain way i
don't care
i only i care about the essence about
the basics
so
unicode is a great technology okay so i
use it so
thumb up is a good character you know
indicates you know simple communication
precise and concise okay so i use it
but then
the font issue is but but now it that
doesn't look like a thumb up at all so
people don't unders that's a problem
so so that's why
that's why so i have collected a index
of articles i
wrote in the past 20 years
about tediums and complexities of
software engineering all sort of [ __ ] up
you know
very well captured by this
rubik's cube painting over rubik's cube
you know all sort of
like you cannot even explain them to
simply because you know maybe your mom
asks you what you do all day you know
you work as a devops or whatever what
you do all day
what is there to do
yeah you cannot even explain starting to
explain break because when you because
for example when i try to explain this
issue
about this
this number why is it why why do i need
to change it's already taking what 40
minutes now 40 minutes 35 minutes
uh so um
any comments questions posted okay
so okay that's about complexity of
software engineering so let's go to talk
show let's see we record we have a
record of that no so copy the ui oh
let's go back go to the top copy the url
back to emacs
paste it here make a link combine the
lists okay
showing browser
yeah [ __ ] vivaldi bug it doesn't
update
the url
you see
you look you go back here you go back
here you see this page
is complexity and tdm software
but if you look at the url
it says
ergonomic keyboard index
the [ __ ] the variety that's another
complexity
so right now i'm trying to [ __ ] fix a
bug you know on my website i'm working
to fix a bug this this
this thumb up you know issue and then
[ __ ] another bug so infinite
recursion now i need to
you know i need to
i know what's going on now but if i
don't then you have to what the [ __ ] is
going on you you then you go to stack
overflow you go to stack over you search
the web you know i did already
for example let me show you okay vivaldi
url
doesn't update okay people have been
reported that address bar doesn't update
url after you see
you see so let's click on that
so mobius says so this is this this is
fairly recent okay in the past three
months or so so is there a date
somewhere um
let's see
you know these
[ __ ]
complex you know they don't they don't
show a date
your browser doesn't support javascript
uh
javascript mozilla so i need a [ __ ]
date
i don't need these version numbers just
give me a date when it's posted
you know
anyway so let's okay turn on javascript
okay there it is last reply july 2nd
2021 you know a few months ago this
happened the [ __ ]
complex complexity [ __ ] [ __ ] the
programmers [ __ ] the unix philosophy
[ __ ] [ __ ] the c programmers
they they did this and [ __ ] the python
the elite people they tell you what to
do they they spread idioms oh you should
do if you follow this idiom emac this
you know this too you should tug in your
parenthesis you should you should use a
tab or space you should indent your
lines of code this way or that way you
know and and
web design gurus saying that oh you
should use a grey font you should use a
reactive you know
ui or
[ __ ] [ __ ]
you know that's my experience after 30
years starting begin where does all this
crap begin it began
it began with the unix philosophy unix
and c that's my that's my that's what i
tell you that's my um
that's my experience okay
you begin with the c and and the unix
you know kind of thinking they hack they
have heck happy hacking like like like
like exactly richard stroman he you he
likes to say happy hacking
happy hacking yeah you [ __ ] up the
programming industry
you know google is showing me you know
google is like
you know uh
you know doesn't allow me to monetize
another modern jargon euphemism monetize
does you know google already
you know demonetized several of my
youtubes because too much swearing
okay this vavaldi let me go back to the
vavaldi problem okay let me show you
complexity of um
where's that page
okay this page complexity and tdm of
software engineering now look at the url
okay
now if i press enter it's going to go to
some other page
you know that's incorrect so go back
let's see if we can go back now
now you look at the url copy the url now
that url is correct okay
[ __ ] the factor provided factor unix
people
and the unix people they are saying oh
microsoft microsoft no forget about
microsoft it is you that is the [ __ ]
face
you begin it unix the worst
you know the the worst security like no
security the unix that's the history of
unix because you don't know because you
got brainwashed propaganda every day
since you know
so now we have a proper link delete this
duplicate caused by this you know the
software industry scans
you know so this powerful you know
anyway so that's uh okay now let's go
back now
let's go back try to fix our
um
uh where is it
my um
the logo keyboards okay so now let's fix
the thumb up okay so
copy the url back to emacs show the pink
window open the path from the clipboard
and you can see all my commands are
there you see some open file from
clipboard and if you search that you'll
find the source code
or just use stuff like keys okay i'm
using stuff like this so okay
so search for advantage
okay so now copy that
paste it here i want to change this to
emoji right remember
um
so i'm just spiraling that so copy
because we have um
so you can see
i want to change this line into this
line okay so this sign into this line or
actually just uh
just the thumb character okay
okay let's do it so
copy that go to the top
let's do some other
because there are more efficient ways
you know this is how i work on my
website aside as i work on it i find
more efficient ways so
so what's the efficient way so let me
let me tell you um okay
so for example let's copy this okay now
this you see this block that corresponds
to this one okay so i just want to copy
it
so
press a key
it cuts it paste
paste again so now we have a copy here
now
this emoji replace it by that okay now
show in browser
you see now now that is the that is the
proper okay that is a
proper uh
way
so what i was planning to do is to
replace every occurrence of the thumb
character inside a link
into
rabbit with a span tag
but
i have a better way okay so the better
way is actually not wrap with the stamp
span tag okay go back to browser refresh
we are back to our engineer
now so the better way is just to edit
your css file okay go open the css file
then what you want is
okay so what do you want let me go to
the bottom and show you here okay so
whenever you have
a link okay
yeah whenever you have a a link okay
actually i already have a
okay let's this this one okay so
copy that
so whenever you have a a link you want
to say
split window search for emoji
so whenever you have a link you want
it to uh
use a particular
[Music]
font ah god this is getting complex then
now i've discovered another problem i
don't really want to do it
but basically
the solution was i was thinking whenever
you have a a link you specify font
family first of all ariel okay because
that's a found what i'm using
then
after aerial then use circle emoji or
apple emoji or noto emoji okay
remove the font size
so that's one way to do it for example
if i leave that if i refresh you you see
those thumbs becomes
colored emoji
now
this is not a good solution because
because sometimes inside the link i have
other unicode characters
such as arrow okay so let me show you
okay so searchers
so for example sometimes i want to say
right arrow okay so
look at that refresh you see there's a
red arrow symbol
not as emoji
um well let me show you some example
where it is emoji for example this
character okay
um
okay
now
now watch i refresh
you see
that
that return key now becomes this
emoji ugly
you know that's not what what you want
what i want
is you can see
it's just an arrow okay it's just a
arrow with a hook that's the standard
symbol used by apple to indicate the
return key
but now with the microsoft emoji
uh font it becomes you know with the
background color blue that's not why
that what i want and worse is that
was is that if you have some
you know sometimes i'm talking about
mathematics
uh sometimes i'm talking about
mathematics or something and or
lots of arrows
you know for example it shows emoji i
don't want some of the arrow to become
that okay show a symbol so that's a
difference you see
so that is why
okay copy the url go back to talk show
today's talk show
paste
linkify close
close okay so i want to
[Music]
so show in browser
so
this new solution is not good so okay so
back to css
remove that
okay don't change
so rather we just stick with our
original solution of making all the
thumb up into our emoji okay
so let's do that
okay shrink shrink shrink okay
find and replace
um
find replace so a lot of complexities do
i make sense replace replace replace
replace replace okay show in browser
okay
now they are kind of too big
uh so this is another problem so if you
use a class emoji they have
by default certain size i said in my css
so
so there's a lot of complexities so the
way we can fix it is go to css
so like before
we add a
that
so when
when you have a a tag which is this tag
a then when it's
then when you have
it
emoji class
inside it
then
you want to say the font size
just one
iem iem is the default font size okay so
once you have that that will fix it now
watch this i refresh refresh you see
now the question is we added another
complexity to our css you see
this is going to be loaded you know we
added you know 10 characters also for ev
for the 6 000
every html file
they will use this css file and now we
added you know more complexity
so this is
this is why this very complex because
now you know this css file
is 245 lines it's a maintenance you know
maintenance you see
so this css file
245 lines of code and it's only 10
kilobyte
if you look at other websites css file
they are one megabyte you know
my css file is very
condensed okay this is because i pay
attention to every aspect of it i know
every character what scene i see is
every every every uh detail every
character
but if you go to other website you know
twitter
wikipedia
google
facebook you look at this css that's
one megabyte or two megabytes that's
bloated hell you know that's modern java
modern webdav oh you are not using
modern web dev you are not your website
doesn't look good
[Laughter]
but their website is idiotic
you know the modern css framework there
are lots of you know lots of them
uh so that's why i'm telling you xa
you know you go read my tutorial you buy
my tutorial javascript in depth
and
css
you know visual css i show you
um you know all the essential things
uh you need to know
okay
so now back to this should we really do
this uh if we do this
if if it's a link use emoji font size
one yeah we can do that
you know so but
so there's a trade-off so if we use this
then
then we do not need to you know have
multiple span
for every
you know every
every occurrence we can just
you know have a thumb up character
yeah but so
so which one should i go
or alternatively for example
alternatively you just say style
font family
then you add
you know
circle ui
emoji and apple emoji and auto emoji so
it's gonna be like you know very long
line
very long you know
a few hundred characters
then
that means
for example let me show you
yeah so this basically you want to add
this for example let me show you one
yeah so that's essentially
yeah not time installment [ __ ]
yeah so here
so basically you want to say here so it
becomes this
and replace the double quote by single
quote because it's inside the double
quote already
so
you can see
compare
what
so you there are three
options
first option is a single character
but then
you need to
add this line
in your css
okay
the second option is for every
occurrence you have this crack class
emoji
oh no
we don't need this option anymore so the
other option is you have the span style
okay i think that's it are we talking
too much i think you guys get what i
mean
you know try to not use the [ __ ] word
because google is you know
disallowing me using
you know to monetize my youtube
so good morning dior stills foot deuce
what is your name
is it true that your name came from a
cross
because
yesterday i happened across it
yeah do you use vote
god wheels it is a latin catholic
motto associated with the crusades
oh my god
now google is gonna ban
fan my
video so do you vote deus vote says good
morning i've recently changed my
keyboard layout after 30 years using
quality okay
very difficult so far that is true it's
a pain in the ass pain in the air in es
because i typed i touch type quality
beginning in
to
1994 so for six years i was a touch
typing quality then i switched to vorac
in 1994
and that took two months extremely
painful because every few key strokes oh
mistake you know then
so the question is
how long did it take you to become
comfortable
with your new layout yeah so two months
two to three months if you type every
day for one hour a day that will take
you two months and very painful okay to
to finally switch
so do you spot you bought my emac this
this tutorial fantastic thank you okay i
think that's it for today so
so i haven't finished working on this
page
what am i going to do right
decisions
uh you know so this emoji
then with that
it's getting complex okay i'll think
about it offline okay
if i don't have that line
refresh then the thumbs is like too big
i'll think about what's the final
decision
to do with that on my website okay so
that concludes today's talk show
yes you could you know if you have you
know if all my comments is the 4chan
types you know
you know all the sensitive words yeah of
course you're because then google we all
know
my channel is associated with this kind
of thing
they obey me
so don't do that okay
before they ban me i ban you
the word of ban
that's what we are in
um
jewish votes okay so that's latin
okay interesting so linguistics issue so
let's
let's write it down
okay i'm hungry and close that we don't
need that dearest vote close that i'm
shutting down in two minutes donate to
me
okay donate to me patreon paypal amazon
gift card
uh it's all on my website
you can see where's my big money links
where is it
oh it's at the bottom okay
so
close this
so today's talk show close it
without debug url doesn't change
close it
unicode error problem emoji font was a
simple font problem complexity of
software industry close it
complexity and tedium of software
engineering close it somehow close it
close it buy my javascript tutorial in
okay
uh
javascript in depth
i spent three years full time to work on
this and you can also see there's also
other issues
so you see in this panel this is a
navigation
related links panel for example if you
are reading my javascript tutorial
or
and reference it also serves as a
reference
so if you are looking at this page add
method to prototype sometimes you would
also be interested in you know maybe you
forgot how object works in javascript or
you forgot you know you want to know how
to find a type a subtype of
javascript object
so there's a relative related links you
can click on that at the bottom you know
they are
you know javascript script object and
inheritance related articles so you it's
convenient they are all together for you
to click around
so in here you also have this rocket you
know so it's not fixed here so
so
so that you know it's very time
consuming so that's that's why we talked
about before you know me that maybe it's
a good solution to simply add a line
uh to these
um you know to this css file for all
because now if we do that now go back to
browser and refresh you'll see those
change okay try it
it doesn't it doesn't because
if you open the page um you can see it
doesn't because
anyway it should
what
wait
refresh
why is it not changing
so what file is is uh
so a
oh yeah so actually what i need to say
is
okay yeah i know what to do so let me
let me fix this okay so
let me copy that
so font family should be ariel then
sergio ui emoji
okay then apple color emoji
then
noto emoji okay
okay then send serif then forget about
margin
okay
now
cancel that line this is the line you
need
now if i refresh
what
oh you you don't want this emoji uh
let's do it again
yeah just everything inside a
it should be that okay
remove that
now watch this
refresh
why is it
yeah that's because ariel already has
this rocket
is that true so this you know then
complexity then you go to debugging
inspect element so
inspect element so this element go to
css
computed
you can see
circle ui symbol so why is it using
circle ui symbol because
maybe it's because the order shouldn't
be
let's refresh
watch this
refresh
why is it circle yeah so very time
consuming complexity of software
so it's a
and wait go back to the file
where is the file
yeah
copy
open the file
so
this rocket is inside the a
this rocket is the inside a
and
we have fun family area circle ui emoji
refresh
okay let's
i'm gonna fix this for sure i'm gonna
so i'm stuck with this
the constructed language question uh
if the construct language topic would
have been about esperando no
well i know you know esperando is
is one of the constructed language but i
don't actually so if you are thinking
i'm going to give a technical tutorial
on esperanto the answer is no but i'm
going to talk about esperanto artificial
languages constructed languages human
languages how they compare to you know
i'm talking about philosophy basically
philosophy of these issues
simplicity regularity in human languages
and in computer languages
um you know then that's what i'm talking
about
if you wanna you know
so uh right now we are trying to fix
this problem why does this have no
affect this font um
so we specified color emoji so let's go
back to the file
so this is the file this this chrome
object
so
it's inside the a tag it's inside the a
tag
yeah
and uh
let's put it at the bottom okay maybe um
some the order certainly matters some
you know
in css refresh let's look at this line
refresh
it does not work
now if you delete the aerial
look at this line refresh
what's going on what the [ __ ]
okay i think
maybe i we have a bad syntax in css
while i was talking i [ __ ] up some css
syntax could that be
true
i don't know
so let's
go back here
let's
use a saved copy of my css okay so let's
do that
copy the
file name
go to shell
e shell
then
git
check
out
that will
revert the file but before we do that
open it copy this line
close it
do it okay so it updated go to diet
it updated this css file open it again
so you can see now it's back to the
original okay
and
now
look at this line refresh that's correct
no change but now let's add this line we
just did
oh syntax error how idiot
how idiotic i am you see i'm missing a
comma here
you need a comma so comma okay back to
browser
magnify
watch this line refresh now
finally the rocket
bye guys