hello guys welcome to another episode of
s talk show today we are going to talk
about keyboards keyboard layouts
keyboard layout diagrams Uh Russian
layout Germany layout French layout and
uh uh ergonomic layout so there's a lot
uh things I uh did update uh keep layout
so we're going to talk about that and
maybe code some JavaScript so first of
all let me show you my keyboards this is
slab board s v a l b o a r d data hand
search for data hand you'll find it on
the web and you'll also find my review
my video review so this these are the uh
magnetics switches this TR truly
fantastic Okay small
board I'm still learning it I'll do a
you know I'll be typing on it down the
road and this is glove 0 okay I also
have a review fantastic wonderful this
is Ultimate hacking keyboard great
fantastic uh and including a mouse you
see okay so let's do let's begin that's
my keyboards let's begin to do the
keyboard layout uh stuff okay let me
show you some uh very interesting things
uh emac so I'm using emac and this is
you know I'm using sofly keys if you
don't know already search for my name
Kar fly Keys
fly okay and you'll be more efficient
than VI o VM uh and on the pink window
is all my command call command names in
emac and keystrokes on the left you can
see can you see yes okay hello guys if
you are here say hi anding donate okay
uh now I don't have YouTube video ads on
for about a year so if you see if I
watch if you watch my YouTube video if
it shows ad let me know okay it's not my
ad Google has been very corrupt you know
even if you turn off ad they they add
ads uh I heard you know I heard that
happen so I need I need confirmation so
if you see my video that has ads
let me know I don't have none because I
turned them all
off uh okay uh so if you want to donate
me PayPal okay PayPal is the best if you
pay by live chat Google takes half of it
like uh about half like half of it or
40% something like
that so yeah let's talk about keyboard
layout so F you know so fantastic so let
me show you guys so you see you see this
is a keyboard layout that diagram you
can find it ergonomic keyboard layouts
ons.info so we have
um if you have questions post it now
okay so you have the qualy this is a
heat map so you can
see uh can you see it uh yes okay so you
can see the quality keyboard layout and
the bigger Circle that means that letter
is most used more frequently so Heat so
Cy vorak comac these are the popular
comac and ergonomic layout comac and
vorac so you see qu is all over the
place so you uh you see n is one of the
problematic key because you have to move
your hand all the way
diagonal and and and a is on Pinky so
vag is better it's you know the most
frequently used uh characters online oh
okay
so let me do it again so here so that's
Cy vorak you see what I add now now you
can support French for example quy this
is Cy for English key map okay now I
just added support for French ping and
Russian so in French it looks like
that uh you see
it's okay so this is qu in French and
ping in is is a Chinese input system you
use English alphabets to input Chinese
it's the most popular Chinese input
system used by like 90% of people uh
Chinese like you know a million a
billion a billion people more more less
so p and Russian so for Russian you need
to I also added a Russian layout so this
is a Russian
layout so you can see you can see the
heat map for using the Russian layout to
type Russian
so and let's go back to uh quy okay quy
and English now you see the question is
you know there's a common question about
vorak versus comac which one is
better okay my claim is that they are
about the same okay all of these vac
comac you know qf ml Workman Norman
comac DH
bco you know all these are created by
nerds and they they Proclaim that my
layout is more efficient than the the
other but actually you know not really
first of all they all assume
English so if you are an English speaker
you never type you know Chinese P or
Russian or French or German language any
other or Japanese then yeah maybe you
optimize you know just like tiny bit I
mean even in English even if you type
English all your life all these claims
that you know this layout is better than
the other is like minimal like it really
depends on what kind of text you type if
you type Shakespeare's
text versus if you just type hi Mom or
if you are a gamer you know what the
[ __ ] you doing you
know they are completely different so so
all these layout you know minor
differences so for average people if you
don't know anything about layout I would
recommend um you you you can stick with
quy but quy really sucks okay but so vak
and KAC is better however the issue with
them is that if you go to the library or
if you go to your friends house then you
cannot touch type anymore so it a little
bit inconvenience
you know if you go to your friend's
house then you have
to you know you have to switch layout on
his computer things like that so anyway
so what's new is the the addition of
Russian
okay so that's the layout
um okay so that's about that layout so
let me tell you some other news about
layout in emac Sly keys so
well let me finish about the Russian you
see the Russian layout it's very
inefficient you see the Russian layout
this is a standard Uh Russian layout uh
they are like a couple but the most
popular is this one it's from you know
Microsoft Windows if you change layout
to Russian it's this
one uh it's so you can see the most used
letter it's very bad you see the most
used letters is is is is the diagonal
you know you your your hands have to go
all the way there and there uh let me
start my alarm
cl
so Russian layout very inefficient and
also another major problem with Russian
layout is that if you are a
programmer you know if you are a Russian
you know you you type Russian and if you
are a programmer the Russian layout does
not have all these symbols you know the
add sign the pound sign the dollar sign
the correct sign the end sign ENT the
vertical bar pipe symbol the square
bracket the curly bracket the greater
and less than you see you don't have
those symbols because Russian has 33
letters which is Sever more than English
alphab bit so all the punctuations are
used up so you don't have those symbols
so what do you do if you want to type
three greater than uh X you have to
switch layout so it's a major
inefficiency major problem with the Rion
layout okay so there's this guy I highly
respect uh when I use I used to have
comments on my blog and this guy Yuri K
he's a expert in Python he's also a
expert in emac lisp you can you know you
can see him on the E gunu emac de
mailing list at least used to I'm I'm
not sure today I think still he's still
there anyway so I respect his opinions a
lot usually he uh uh give expert
opinions on many program programming and
programming language related issues so
so he wrote a comment about how Russian
you know he's Russian how you Russian
the problems with Russian layout so
first of all you don't have these
symbols so whenever you need to type
type them in a programming language you
have to switch
layout so you know he goes into detail
so yeah basically that's the issue so
that's a ran
layout okay so now I there are several
things I did uh major major upgrade for
CA flly keys for those of you using
emac uh if you don't know what CA flly
Keys
is it's a key binding very extremely
efficient key binding system for emac
emac is editor you know like like the vs
code so if you use emx you know so you
can try soft like is it's a model system
more efficient than Vim than
VI or Neo Vim more efficient meaning
that to type the same thing you type
less keystrokes okay you can try it you
know I did it several times you know the
Vim golf you can try it yourself you
type less key strokes to do the same
thing that's Sly Keys
um and uh yeah so I did a major rewrite
restructure of the key layout system so
right now it supports um
you know it supports all these layouts
ADN W that's a efficient German layout
for German language a a German people is
officient layout for French KAC KAC DH
verac in grammar which is a new
efficient layout for English H MAAC new
efficient layout for English and Ki is a
efficient layer for German you know so
it supports and of course quy uh and qu
AB andt which is a quy used in Brazil
and quy Norwegian so so what I did new
what's new is that so you can try it
okay so if you are emac users try it so
what I did new is that
um now the
code uh let's okay so let me show you
here s FL Keys news you see before you
used to do this okay let me let me show
you the
code not e okay s like
Keys uh news yeah so hold on a second
so go to
there if you have questions uh type it
okay okay so here is the old version of
s like ke let's
see you see
before before a few days ago when you
want to add a new layout you have to do
this so you you need to create this uh
kind of dictionary key value
pairs to remap key so you have the uh
for example this comac layout you have
comat dhm angle layout then you have uh
optimod layout which is a very weird one
someone wanted me to add it but
now but now it is you do it just this
way so you just create a text
diagram so when you want to add a new
layout you just create this text diagram
and that's it okay that's so that's new
in sofly Keys it's on GitHub and also so
there are several additions of new
layouts and some of the old you know
some layout I removed because it's
esoteric nobody uses so if you want to
use a layout that's not here you just
add it
yourself uh so PT navito is a efficient
layout for POI Keys used in uh Brazil so
there's also new uh I I don't know I
don't remember if this is new programmer
vorak okay uh and uh what is it okay uh
yeah okay so the new thing is a Russian
layout so for I know a lot people
Russian people like my we website my
emac stuff so if you are Russian now you
you know it supports Russian
layout okay let's see the questions what
uh am I good am I doing good yeah okay
so for going to move the camera to the
left so let's see the
questions
wdyt what the what does that mean I'm
not too familiar with the Zuma Jons
the you go hi hi did you generate the
heat map yourself
yes uh yes of course
so what we might do today is we are
going uh we might be uh creating a new
layout so you go to my EXA keyboard
block you go to the ergonomic key uh
layout okay so you can see right now is
supports okay so
let's so let's add a peopleo layout
people is a very the most
popular efficient ergonomic layout for
French okay so you can but it's not
here okay so let's add a b layout so for
example search for people so you can see
French ergonomic layout you open it go
here so for French layout there are
several efficient ones the earliest one
is vak French and then people improve it
so you got B so bot is the most popular
so that's how it looks like so we going
to add a people layout
to to
um to this JavaScript application
diagram so that we can like pick
French uh okay so
actually French there's a mistake this
shouldn't be
checked remove checked French remove
checked ping in yeah so English should
be the default showing
browser yeah okay French
English French ping in so one of the
interesting question is you know I CL so
if you are uh thinking about vorak
versus Colac so you see in English
this is the heat map for vak wait that's
not
right so you know here's a heat map for
vorak and you switch to
coac you see
vorac
comac vorak you see vorak got the L for
your ring finger and uh I mean for your
pinky that's bad over there R and L so
these two fingers that's not so good but
coac is Improvement of that but if let's
try French okay so far that's English
now let's see French what happens so
this is KAC in
French
okay pretty good it's KAC
in uh vorak in French okay not so good
you see so you
see yeah
so KAC seems to be better than much
better than vorak in
French okay but now let's try ping in
okay so this is vorak let's try ping in
so this is vorak for ping ping a typ in
Chinese okay so this is Ping in vorak
and in
comac let's see
vorac comac so in coac is much
worse p in coac is far worse because you
see the home Row for the left hand it's
all empty except the pinky but now in
vorak it's much better you see so that's
very interesting thing about a efficient
layout because all these efficient
layout basically they just optimize for
English so if you all your life you just
type English that's fine but many people
uh you know type multiple languages so
so that's an interesting issue okay
let's look at the comments let me finish
answer the
questions then we're going to generate a
people layout
do you use vac with pin in yes uh so
what you can do is that you know you
click on keyboard search go to my
keyboard blog pin in so you can
see uh wait I want to okay so here's a
pin
frequency and uh you want to
uh where's
my Chinese input methods okay let's go
to Chinese input
methods and
uh D I didn't link it here so there is
article so let's go
to so basically on Microsoft Windows
when you switch to pin in it's using the
quy layout for pin in so but you can you
can change it to vorac by uh you you go
to s website
search then search for pin in yeah there
Windows set Chinese pin to vac layout
so you just run this in your you know in
a terminal in a Windows
Powershell then you get the pin in
layout I mean the uh the VAC layout for
typing pin in okay on the Mac on the Mac
it's very smart so if you switch on the
Mac if you switch from quy to pin in
then it's using quy layout but however
if you when you switch the layout you
will on VX then you switch to P then the
p is using the V for p so Mac is very
smart Okay so that's about that uh and
also if you yeah actually the best thing
if you type P is just to buy a
keyboard
that buy a programmable keyboard so all
these so for example my gra8 it's using
vorak by default so I don't have to
switch you know the window
stuff okay that's uh that's about
that so Norman seems to be the best one
for different languages well really I
haven't checked yeah so one of the great
idea about ergonomic keyboard layout is
that you want you want a layout that's
generic and best for you know the top
five most languages so let's look at
Norman so here's Norman in English okay
in French pretty good in
pinging uh not too bad
okay and I also need to add Russian and
Spanish here yeah so that's something I
need to do maybe we can do it
live so all you have to do to to add a
lang language is that let's look at the
code okay so for example to add a layout
all you have to do is just add this text
diagram now to add
frequency all you have to do is just add
this basically Json dictionary so this
is frequency for English here is the
frequency for pinging
and here is a frequency for
Russian and here's a frequency for
French so I need to add one for
German and
Spanish and maybe other you know Finland
whatever Denmark whatever whatever
languages they use okay so uh anything
else so let's go back to some talk show
let's see if there's something else I
wanted to
say yeah okay that's it uh let's
see oh yeah so let's go back to look at
the normal layout
noral
French ping
in
French English Okay
French now let's see wman English
French now English and French are not
much different English
French English
French okay
ping so why do you say Norman layout is
the most efficient for different
languages
seems Seems so
anyway jman Molina
hello how do you calculate the frequency
it's very common okay
so so if you want to calculate the
frequency you can just go
to uh key binding
design layout design so that's keyboard
layout there's a character character
frequency plot so you
can select or delete
start typing and you get frequency chart
okay that's one way to do it there's a
application you can do it you you can
type Chinese or Japanese for example
let's try
Chinese uh let's try
Japanese okay
so so let's go
to computer keyboards let's go to
Wikipedia and let's go to Japanese
language
there it is okay then let's copy this
text copy it go back to the page select
all paste there it is the Japanese
frequency and right now it's excluding
Chinese characters but you can turn it
back on okay yeah it doesn't show
because oh top 30 only okay so now it's
so many top 30 no Chinese okay that's a
Japanese frequency that's one way to you
know you can do
that okay German so let's do a okay
let's do a German
one yeah okay let's do because you know
it seems
let's do a German one so you want to
know the German layout
frequency so one way to do it is you
just find a German text let's say Alice
in
Wonderland so suggest me what to search
to find a German text uh let something
very popular German
text actually let's you know let's we go
uh
so yeah so you guys suggest me you know
the keyword to search because you cannot
paste link so you suggest me a a a
German language text like something very
popular but let's let's just do it uh
via okay no troll okay no political
trolling
[ __ ] so we go to keyboard layout and
let's go to German
language now this I believe this is
Danish okay okay DH
something okay so here is
uh German language let's copy that
you know when you do
layout uh analysis usually you have the
question how many text you know how many
words is
sufficient usually that doesn't matter M
much you know usually people try to you
know grab all the text like 1,000
books uh usually that doesn't ma matter
much so here is a German pasted so here
is the frequency for German layout
okay and you can copy
that
copy paste that
so make it make them okay so what is
this so you need to
replace A2
Z replace
A2
Z
by uh let's just say replace a DOT
by by that with a space
okay okay then
you make this each one into a line no
then you
replace
space dot Space by just
dot okay let's try again space
dot Space by
dot okay then you make it into a line
like
that okay wait so you need to ah this is
bad let's do it again
copy new paste here now you query
replace
by
each letter A to
Z when you find the letter you replace
it
with adding a
space okay now it should be much
better uh
oh you also need to add a space in front
Okay so
okay do that then
you make them into
lines then
you
okay okay this is not efficient let's do
it this
way
that f followed by that replace it by
space that yes
yes no do it
again replace
by yeah let's do it again
[Music]
copy select all paste paste okay now
let's do this now this time one
shot each time you see a
letter
then you add a space in front and add a
space in the in in on the right
okay yeah wait let's do it
again you add a add a new line in front
okay yeah that's much
better so here is the here is kind of
the German character frequency now
there's not enough text so let's just
copy the whole article copy
it and uh paste it here so now we
got lots of
text uh not limit to top 30 okay
so copy that no digit no space merge
case yes no
punctuation no
punctuation okay no Chinese okay copy
that copy select all
paste okay now let's do the query
replace again
uh okay that's about
that then all this zero we don't care
because they are too small oh and there
is
some you see those umot characters they
are not used frequently
okay that's basically the German
character
frequency okay now you need to make this
into adjacent format so uh what we can
do
is
uh replace Space
by okay okay then let's callar
command square
brackets comma okay now you need the
comma
here okay so the whole thing is inside
the bracket so this is this is
Javascript
syntax and uh okay so you you
need that there and you don't
need that okay so this is a frequency in
terms of percentage for German language
close close uh let's go to the
library okay so you need to add that so
new
German okay that seems it let's
see yeah that's that seems
it cut okay now paste it
here
paste make a backup predy the code
compile typescript to JavaScript that's
it close that search for French now we
need to add German
here showing
browser so now we got German let's try
it so
quy fr
FR German
[Music]
fantastic let's see
English
French
German why is it uh
[Music]
so okay so in German language e is not
huge
outliers because in English e is like
far more used than than the rest
in French it's even more
so and in
German it's more fairly distributed the
top five most frequently used characters
so let's go to the statistics
again so in German the E is
99.5% in French is
14% okay in
in English 12% okay so in
German the E is just 9% okay so we got
German okay now we added a new language
now let's add new layout for German
uh there's also German language uh
efficient layout for German language
let's go
there yeah so there it is is so we need
to add
Neo let's add Neo for German layout then
let's add beo for French
layout you didn't pick the omot
thingies you know it turns
out in you know this om load they are
not used you see I mean they are not
used much you see this a om Lo Au
o so many German keyboard you know they
have dead keys for those those om it's
kind of inefficient because they are not
really use
much oh using wo firm language that's
right I forgot yeah I I I kept
forgetting about how wolam language has
all these spill in so all you have to do
is you know if you want to know the
frequency of a
language let's let's do it let's run
it fantastic
so does it agree with uh so let's do
that
in table form
so the this one this part is we have
English German Spanish okay so
English German uh this table form is not
so
good okay I need to actually understand
the code so let's do
that wolam language
mod so we have have language
data okay language data then you map it
to so let's turn this code into the
normal way so people can
understand okay so this
code so this part is a function wait
this
uh yeah so this part
is a function let's write it
out here is the
expression and uh here that's the
X so this way people understand what it
means okay that's a function then this
means map okay
so map this function
to to this
list okay we don't need the level so
that is the code so we map a function so
you can
see if you run this let's copy that copy
that make it one line run the current
line
and here is the
output quantity uh you know wam language
return this fancy quantity SC so this is
a
quantity of a number
12.7 and uh it's a
percent okay I don't want I don't like
that so anyway so you got the you got
the English frequency let's copy that
let's see what
it
paste yeah this annoying quantity thing
you know just just get a number now you
can easily do that you can easily do
that
by let's see
yeah so you apply a
function and actually we
don't you simply
replace
replace okay replace
what
happened replace
quantity a
number and uh anything by
just
in that's much
better so now we copy
that select all paste
fantastic now now remove the outer
bracket so we got each
one and uh
remove that rechange that by a new
line okay so this is
English English German Spanish so
German okay in German actually e is much
higher yeah so the reason all the reason
reason our
um our data is because it's only two
paragraph I mean it's just you know one
page of Wikipedia so actually this
is uh this is more appropriate German
okay so let's use this okay so you need
to convert this to the JavaScript Json
format okay
okay okay
so replace that by a
comma and
uh at
square bracket and
comma oh and uh
wait we don't want the ending comma
comma New line replac by just new
line okay
now add square bracket and comma okay
now cut all square bracket
paste okay I think that's it cut go back
here go back to our JavaScript
code so the German should be
this e t a o i okay e n t i
Okay
so move
that you don't need that don't need that
prettyy the code
fantastic okay compile
JavaScript typescript to
JavaScript now close that close that
close that close
that S Talk Show go to the
layout now we got
German French
German oh so German in German e is
actually used a lot so in English e is
12% in German is 16% oh my God is that
is that
true let's see German character
frequency Wikipedia usually have that
data L
frequency so you want
German text English
uh they have German there it is so
magnify so English you need to turn on
JavaScript
so English 12 French French
14% German 16 16% so in German e is
actually far more
used uh okay so let's go
back wow so in German language is
actually far more used
French wait did I
refresh English French
German oh but in German uh I mean it's
far more used but
however so is the second most frequently
used let's close that close that let's
go to
here so in German e 12 T is
nine yeah okay so
anyway anything
else wolam language is general purpose I
mean I did so much wolam language video
so you should watch it okay uh I mean I
I mean I talked so much about wam
language and so okay so let me just show
that quickly
yeah so I did a lot wfam language coding
for the Advent of code so you just
search YouTube Advent of code so for
example here's wfam Language tutorial
you can see
how do you do comment how you do print
how you do string you know so it's just
like a python Ruby Java uh JavaScript
it's just a different language so you
can do mathematics with it to solve
equations integrals
matrices but it's also the most general
purpose and
uh uh very extremely high level so you
know I did so many videos so you know
you can watch it by for
example uh
tutorials uh and uh so these are
actually some old videos so there's a
lot I you know I did
a Advent of
code wolam language okay soent of code
is not mathematics and uh but I
did you know lots of videos using wam
language to s that there it
is okay
so so we talked for almost an hour so
now
we add a new layout yeah let's add a
German layout okay so let's add a German
layout
so you need to go to the German layout
page so people is French uh okay so
let's go
to
German so go to German
layout you want to German keyboard
ergonomic layout that's right go there
and yeah Neo okay so let's add Neo so
first of all you need to add the asky DI
diagram which I already did so here is
the emac Syntax for
Neil copy C and you need to turn it into
this JavaScript syntax okay
so okay so create a new paste it
here let's start to work on
this so JavaScript syntax you
need okay that's a template
string and uh delete that cut cut
cut paste
okay and uh template string you need to
escape that now turn Go to JavaScript
mod to to get the color syntax
highlighting okay that's
it so this is Neo
layout that's right so I believe then
you need a comma here cut close and add
here okay n so let's go alphabetical so
let's put it
where n is minia Max so right
here paste
it and copy
that
paste okay so let's make the
format same as the other I think that's
it now pedify the code fantastic try it
again prettyy the code
fantastic compile to JavaScript
fantastic so now we support Neo
now uh this should be just Neo not Neo
to
okay compile it close close okay now
let's go to the keyboard
layout add a Neo here so Neo is non
English so let's add it here Russian
uh yeah
Neo showing
browser Neo fantastic so let's
try fantastic so this is Neo layout now
Neo is for German right so let's click
German it should be Improvement okay now
when we click on on this it should
be
Improvement do
it oh okay not not that
different kind of improved yes okay not
that different English German now let's
go to
vorak English English German okay so
wait English and
German wow so they actually do not
differ that
much let's see comac English German they
don't differ that
much as far as character frequency goes
but uh but the Bagram and trigram may be
different okay I think that's it for
today anything else
okay so now we added
Neo let's
add let's add um
so here are the
layouts and
uh then English
layouts Russian
Russian KAC
Neo and now let's add
so and this part is
English
French Okay add Spanish okay so let's
add Spanish we can trust this wolf and
thing so Spanish is just that
copy okay now we can do this quickly
Okay so so we need them to be in
JavaScript format
so that becomes
comma okay and the comma New line change
to new line okay and uh yeah that's
it space we move
space okay then do it do it do it okay
so Spanish okay that's
it double check yeah good close now go
to the
JavaScript search for frequency okay
that's what we need so Russian Spanish
French German
let's add
here so
Spanish
okay cut
paste okay I believe that's it prettyy
the code fantastic now it works now we
need to kind of organize them into
alphabeticals so e p
r f okay so French needs to go
top EFG okay let's not worry about it
let's just prettyy the code compile it
close
it search for French okay now add
Spanish here
okay
now now we need to kind of make them
English Spanish is a second most used
language I mean Chinese is first then
English then Spanish then German and
French I don't know about the same and
actually p is far more used but anyway
let's leave it
that so there it
is so quy English and Spanish okay
significant
different
English
Spanish
French there we have
it see the Spanish have accents so the
frequency may be higher so let's see
English
Spanish okay yeah so the accent you
know yeah so there is you know there's
uh but compared
to characters without
accent those accented characters are
still relatively much less used let's
see
Spanish you
see so you know the most frequent use is
o or with
a a cutees I
think oh yeah
so native speakers Spanish
is is uh is second okay
okay I think that's it for today thank
you guys for
watching bye guys we shut down so
fantastic we uh great we added so uh you
know this I have been wanting to know
this for a long
time let's
see okay
let's let's put German on top
up let's go alphabetical FG so French
German
okay predefine the code compile no error
fantastic showing
browser
fantastic
English Spanish
English Spanish Let's see vorak
English
Spanish oh Spanish you see A and
E are very frequent
English
Spanish
French
German bye