hello welcome to another episode of
excel talk show
so today we are going to do continue the
Advent of code
okay continue the Advent of code and
problem number three
now for a change let's see
let's see how much problem I can solve
today uh in our it's
um yeah let's do that
uh so yesterday just review yesterday we
did Advent of code day two problem two
and before that problem two and before
that problem what so today we are going
to continue to problem three okay Advent
of code problem three
and by the way I'm on I'm on
Odyssey
uh but I haven't really started to get
used to it yet so I'm on Odyssey so you
can see all my um
all my YouTube uh
uh videos there
so where do I see it sync your channel I
mean I'm not I'm afraid
it's the Analytics
uh regular expressions
most recent reviews 35 followers so I
started to have some followers let's see
home
yeah how do I get to my channels
it used to be this button but now it
says sync your channel I'm not sure what
that is
uh
I wanted to show all my videos you know
usually they auto sync so anyway Arena
code number three okay let's do that
and I haven't read the problem yet well
I did a little bit yesterday so let's
see how far we can go hello Jr
so a domain of a code let's begin okay
today so let's start Wolfram language
um
at the end of code in Wolfram language
okay let's see
you know there's already problem 12 or
something released so I'm kind of late
uh at this rate we won't catch up so I
need to do much faster
okay start the Wolfram engine uh okay
number three okay questions come and ask
me okay uh that expose I don't know
about the Expos
so number three rucksack correct
reorganization okay one elf has an
important job uploading all the
rucksacks with supplies for Jungle
Journey unfortunately that elf didn't
quite follow blah blah each rucksack has
two large compartments or items of a
given type are meant to go into exactly
one of the two compartments the elf that
did the packing failed to follow this
rule for exactly one item type per
rucksack okay so they are
there's a bag two compartments or we can
say okay two components two
compartments of a bag
and there's some mistake okay the elves
have made a list of all the items
currently in each rucksack
okay that's your personal input
but they need your help finding the
arrows every item type is identified by
a single lowercase or upper case letter
that is a that is a and a refers to
different type of items okay lowercase
and uppercase so each character
represent an item case matters okay the
list of items for each rucksack is given
us characters
given us characters all on a single line
okay one line has lots of characters
each character represents a item
a given rucksack always has the same
number of items in each of its two
compartments so that means the number of
characters is even
so the first half of the characters
represents items in the first components
where the second half of the characters
represents item in the second
compartments okay for example suppose
you have the following list of contents
from six rucksacks okay copy that that's
the problem input
okay so let's see okay
so that's the input
okay so now it tries to explain further
so the first right side stroke Sac
contains the items J R W something
something which means it's first
compartments contains the items that
you know up to R
okay and 12 the second compartment
contains the items that basically you
split this string into two it should be
even
the only item type that appear in both
compartments is lowercase p okay now
let's let's do some checking okay
so count content uh counts
count the number of characters there's
24 characters you can see at the bottom
20 24 characters so the first half in
second half so each one is twelve each
bag each compartment has 12.
uh characters okay
and uh let's see what about the case so
lower K uh wait I don't know wait let's
see
the second rucksack compartments
contains that okay
uh
and that okay so J q h r
J q h uh something something then SSL
SSL okay the only item type that appears
in both compartments is uppercase L okay
so apparently there is a item
and that appears there's a letter
there's a character that appears in the
first half of the string
and got repeated in the second half of
the string so far there's only one such
case in each of this line Okay the third
Rockside components contain that in that
pmm okay that's the third one okay and
the only common item is uppercase P okay
here p and p
oh okay so in this case both of them
wait what
the wait the third rucksack
the third rucksacks compartments contain
pmmd
so that's this one
so hold on a second there are three
Capital P's here okay now I don't know
nothing you guys see it okay so there
are three capital P here so an item has
been repeated three times
so this is the third rucksack
okay so they divide that by two into two
compartments so the first compartment
the p is repeated
okay so a character may be repeated in
one compartment
but the
but the problem is trying to emphasize
whether the item are in both
compartments okay so let's see let's
read further the fourth rucksacks
compartments only share item type V
okay that's the fourth one
uh it shares wait the fourth one what
one two three the fourth one is this one
item v so V is here
uh
and also appear here and here and here
so it happens four times
but
okay so what what what what is he
talking about I mean
the only item type the only item type
that appears in both compartments so
that's what he's emphasizing
so if a letter repeats in one
compartment we don't care
but we really want to care if later
happens
in both okay so that's the fourth
rucksack the fifth only share items t
okay t t t t okay there's a lowercase T
there check the sixth
only share item Type S Okay so
okay makes sense so far so good
so each line is a sequence of characters
and the characters are supposed to be
split into two parts the first
compartment and the second one
and if you and what you want to find out
so far it's saying that you want to find
out if a item are repeated that appears
in both so you want to find a character
that appears in both
in the first part of the string and the
second half of the string
that's correct and case matters okay
so to help prioritize item Arrangement
rearrangement every item type can be
converted to a
priority
now I'm a bit confused about his uh
concept of item type
so do the characters represents a item
type or it's just the item
so let's see here
lowercase a and capital case a refers to
different types of items Okay so
it appears that each of the character
represents a type of items maybe it
doesn't matter
uh
okay
so it's a bit confusing you know I don't
think the Advent of code their problem
description is written in a perfect way
uh anyway so let's read on
to to help prioritize item rearrangement
every item type can be converted to a
priority okay lowercase item types A
through Z have priorities 1 to 26 and
uppercase has priorities
27-52 okay
and say a priority okay
so what that means you probably need
some kind of map you know you want to
turn a character into its number you
know one of the one to 52.
okay in the above example the priority
of the item type that appears in both
compartments of each rucksack is
okay so yeah so
apparently in each line there is a
character that's repeated
there exists one and only one character
that is repeated in the first half of
the line and the second half of the line
okay and if you convert to you can
convert you know each of the character
into a number okay
and then okay then it says the sum of
this is 157 okay so apparently you need
to sum them up
okay find the item type that appears in
both compartments of each rucksack
okay what is the sum of the priorities
of those item times okay simple problem
a lot a bit worthy but problem should be
simple hello quick quick and dark
okay so let's summarize so you you are
given a bunch of
you are given a string
which is several lines in each line
is a bunch of characters
now you are supposed to
divide this line into two parts the
first half in the second half
you know the number of characters is
always even supposedly
okay let's let's let's double check okay
so okay so this one
what
32 characters okay
18 characters okay
30 even correct 16 even correct for 24.
so yeah so each line a bunch of
characters you want to find a character
let's repeat it that appears in both the
first half and the second half
once you find that you once you find
that character you want to change that
character into a number
you know 1 to 26 or 27 to 51 you want to
turn that into a number then sum it
you know some such a character in all
these
and also it assumes that
there is only one character that is
repeated in first half and second half
you know it it does not it
um yeah so
he says that
uh only one occurrence okay this is
important because when it comes to
efficiency
you know when you find that character
then you let's repeat it you can stop
otherwise you have to go through again
so let's see make sure that it's the
case
uh one of important job something
something something
unfortunately something something
uh something the elf that did the
packing failed to follow this rule for
exactly one item type okay now this this
story Italian description of the problem
is imprecise
because first of all there's a confusion
between item and item type you know in
here it mentions item type it's not
necessary you can just say it's item you
know people understand you have two semi
well okay you might introduce type
because you have if you have a two bag
of peanuts
you know to use do you can you know so
you you want to use the type to indicate
they are
um
the same type
okay anyway so item type so this
basically so each line there's just one
one character that's repeated in first
half Instagram so what's your so we need
to find one
easy okay let's first of all let's write
a mathematical description
given a string of lines
for each line
there is a
character that appears
in both first half of the string and
second half
of the string
find that character
cool
find that character for each line
change the character to a number
sin
find the Sun
okay that's the that's a mathematical
description of the problem
instead of these
verbose verbosity
okay so so that is a problem so okay
so even a string so
you want to find uh
first half so let's start with the
single line let's see how to work that
out starting with a single line you want
the function that gives a bunch of
string
first so you want to find
a character
that is both in the first happy okay
interesting problem
interesting problem so this problem
is the test of efficiency because if you
if you don't do it properly your program
will be very inefficient because it is
going to involve combinatorial
comparison
okay so there are many solutions to
solve it first of all you divide the
string into two parts you want to find a
character that appears in both so there
are so many ways to do it so for example
one way is to use you sort them sold
them sew them then you just compare one
by one
uh wait
um
well yeah you can sew them then then
no you don't well yeah sorting saw them
first is one one of the step you can do
uh but then you have to still go through
you can yeah then you can use binary
search to see if a character is doing in
the second one but that gets complex
okay 13 is one thing the other the other
way is simply
start with the first character in one
part
and go do a loop check if that's in the
second string
second part of the string
if not start with the second character
in the first
half
then do the same okay
so there are quite a few ways to do it
um
so there is always one character that
repeats so you have to think about this
in order to come up with the most
efficient algorithmically efficient way
uh so I prefer to do that that's how I
usually code
so of course I mean the alternative is
just start to code you know just start
to do a loop then but I like to you know
my typical way of coding is to think
about the problem first
so
okay so let me think about it it's gonna
be boring for you guys just skip
so there's only one character that
repeats and your job is to find that
character
uh
so
and then you can do
character comparison one by one
whole
you could also use regular expression
yeah so this problem has a lot of
solutions
the way you do a regular regular
expression is that you just
you just maybe use the whole
no actually you use a to z and capital A
to Z
of a single yes there's so many
solutions it apparently so many ways to
approach but the problem is to determine
which one is the most efficient and
doesn't seems too obvious
so you can so I think regular expression
you can use that or you can just like
a hardcore character by character
comparison
which one is more efficient you don't
know because sometimes regular
expression it automatically do the
comparison but you don't know if it's
gonna be more efficient or not because
you also need to capture you need to
find out
that letter you know which one is repeat
not just Daddy
it repeats you need to know which one
so okay so actually I have to I still
need to think about this
so you can sort possible solutions sort
and regular expression is also
not sure the sure way is just to com
compare a character by characters so
remember
there's only one such
there is
there exists a character that's repeated
and only one of them
so you always have such a letter
so let's just go through each character
then
oh God there's so many ways to do this
because if you simply go through each
character you also have inefficiency
because once you did the comparison you
then you know the second part do not
you you know you know
what that character is already so
so okay so back to sorting now if you
saw them you can you can then apply some
kind of uh binary search
you know start from the middle of this
uh first part
uh no okay
I don't know let's start to code it then
okay let's see the first this uh Wolfram
language okay
so
start to code X input okay that's one
let's say X1 okay
so that's a stream so first job is the
uh you want to divide it into two parts
so
length at X1
then
okay so uh
divided okay let's say l in
uh
so that perhaps we need the length later
I don't know for sure but
so then excellent divided by two
string take
okay that's probably X1
so that's the first pet first half
let's say front Okay I mean the art of
naming
um
and
let's say pouch one okay pouch one and
pouch two
that's the first compartment in second
compartment okay uh then
string take
okay there are so many ways to do it
actually so do I want to maybe we should
turn the Stream
so one way is to turn a string into a
list of characters
yeah in Wolfram language you have that
Advantage because you don't have to deal
with you don't have to deal with strings
you can each string can become a symbol
like a variable name then you you just
compare the equality of the symbol
instead of the comparison of the string
equality uh so many ways so once if you
once you turn it into a list then you
have lots of tremendous number of
functions that work on at least just
like this
so
um
now let's look at the string take
function
right right now I'm thinking what's the
best way to split the string
um
okay so we can do this uh
okay let's repeat it
okay let's try that
let's just for the sake of
trying
to see
what
X length oh not length you need string
length in Wolfram language
okay so yeah
put some cling up here
yep
okay so that is the
uh why is it not
wrh
WR okay you got the arrow here so this
means this needs to be plus one let's do
it again
okay perfect that's how you split the
string into two parts
now
for each character in stream yeah
let's see all the string functions okay
so this is how you see all string
functions in wufa language technically
all
functions that contains the word string
okay so let's see this face string
so in string
we can do that now remember we found
language is a very very high level
language so almost for any algorithm it
already has a building function like you
don't have to uh
you know there's a building function
already so
but if you are not careful each of these
functions are very costly you know each
of these function equals to 10 coding 10
functions in python or Haskell so you
want to be very careful because
otherwise it's very slow
so for example there is the function in
stream
uh you know in string is a global object
that's that is assigned to be the text
of the nth input line okay that's not
what we want
um
string and string DD string com string
contents okay that's
you know so so you can use that
but if you use that
in a loop it's going to be very
inefficient
so right now I'm thinking do we should I
just what do whatever to come out with
the answer or should I think about the
the most efficient way which is what I
usually do I don't want to you know I
don't like to just come out with an
answer that's because that if you do
that you lose the purpose
of doing this exercise
you see these are you know trivial kind
of trivial parliamentary problems so the
fun part is really get you to think to
know the language you are working on to
to explore what is the most efficient
way what's the cost of each function you
call or the construct you know getting
the properties or object if you are
using object-oriented language that's
that's the that's a key that's a that's
a benefit
you know if you just want to solve the
problem that's not interesting
uh you know
but depending of course if you are new
to the language if you are a beginner in
programming yeah you know you'll be
happy you solve the problem but
um so let's go back to these
um let's see let me think about what to
do the best
um Spring Break by constraint cases okay
between cases give a list of substring
that matches the string expression
pattern
okay so let me think again
if we go
The Brute Force way
which we start with the character do a
loop go through the second half of the
string
to see if each one
to see if it's there okay this is the
most Brute Force
way
and if you find it
if you do this in most languages
especially low level languages this is
the most efficient way
but that does not apply to wufam
language because if you do wufam
language in general the more function
you call the more expensive it becomes
because each of the function is very
high level you know you want to re you
want to make
your code
the least number of functions
including in a loop and in general you
don't want to do loop at all
so
you know you guys know what I'm saying
um
I think this video is mostly just me
talking to myself what is the best way
to describe in solving a problem Grunt
Style I don't know what is a gun style
or atomically simply without any
predefined functions
you cannot
you know so what is going to explain and
uh
and in general you cannot
have solution without calling any
predefined functions what do you mean
Assembly Language
he is at what Grunt Style mean I don't
know explain okay
Okay so
string come string contains we can use
sure that checks the pattern
now does it return though
no so string cases
so string case string contains you know
returns either true or false
of a pattern that's not what we want
because we need
to know exactly which is the character
that matches okay so we cannot use
string contents now but we can use
string cases
string pattern give a list of the
substrings
in string that matches the string
expression pattern okay I think this is
what we are going to use because
this if you call this you just give it
one single quote one single function
call no Loop involved because the
algorithm the function will do the
algorithm for you
so yeah I think that's that's the one we
want okay let's try this one
string contains okay X1 uh wait it needs
to be the second part okay
expouch contains the then hex pouch one
okay
but here it needs to be a pattern okay
not just let's see if it works
let's
go to my Wolfram Language tutorial or
copy paste and
put the link here
okay today's talk show with a Language
tutorial uh
we are working with streams and we are
working with string patterns now in
Wolfram language there are two stream
patterns one is regular expression
the other one is string expression
they are essentially regular expression
but with a different syntax okay
so now
remember we need to get the character
not just true or false we need to get
the characters so
um
so let's see normally in a regular
expression
how do you
um string cases okay so let's go back to
the code
not strange stream
cases okay
okay I think but we I think I know what
to do string cases patent okay so string
cases the pattern
the pattern needs to be
actually multiple patterns
uh
so the result will be one single line
two function course in Wolfram language
the solution will just be one single
almost one single line
now
we need to
so we need to represent a pattern
um
yeah and also we need to say one limit
to one because otherwise it's going to
continue searching
so includes only the first n substrings
of that match
okay again there are so many ways to do
this
okay
but we do need
one for sure that means tell it to stop
when it found one
uh because we know there's only one
character that repeats according to the
spec
and then now
uh so now we need to represent the
pattern expression okay
so here is regular expression
but you also have
foreign
regular expression okay
so
here
okay create a regular expression and
here will be that and the join string
uh string join we need to join string
let's use the okay let's use
a foam that it's easy to understand okay
but more cumbersome so here we want to
add
okay
this is a regular expression for
any of these cat characters okay and you
need to
first one
wait one single character okay one
single character
and uh
Okay so
let's see what it does now
there it is supreme
[Laughter]
a supreme
one single line
one shot solution
so now
so now that's one single character you
you need to turn that character into a
number okay so we need to construct a
map lowercase A to Z
is mapped to 1 to 26 and uppercase A to
Z is mapped to
uh 27 to 52 is that right
there it is that's that's correct okay
so let's construct the map okay
turn characters to numbers okay there's
a probably a building function okay
there's probably a Podium function let's
see
string Q string repeat string replace
uh
same thing so I think the name
might be two string two
uh integer string what is that
integer string gives a string consisting
of the decimal digits
okay
now remember we need a function that
takes a character into a number
and one two six or one to 26 or 27 to 52
okay now one way to do that is to change
each strings to their code point
Unico code Point ask equal Point okay
because let's see
you know printable ASCII okay that's not
what we want let's see
Unicode okay uh
code point
let's see two character code okay so for
example there's these two character code
let me show you example so here you give
it a string let's say lowercase a that
would be 97
I think oh maybe it's capital A let's
see see lowercase a is 97 so you just
minus
minus whatever
minus 97.
minus 96 is for so for each
character you yeah we can do that yeah
so actually this is a good
um
solution okay
copy that
so let's let's write for document you
know so you guys can understand Wolfram
language I mean
so let's say
chart to
no okay
so you can understand what I'm doing
big no normally I would just write it
without you know with with with
um Anonymous function
Okay so
so X is a string okay then you just turn
that
um
let's say cha okay so it's easier to
understand
so
that that in minus 96 okay that's
yeah so a becomes one okay now let's try
capital A let's see what is that
okay 65.
oh yeah but they are
um
this is no good this approach
uh if you do this you cannot you know
depends on Okay so
uppercase you have to do different
uh you have two minus a different number
that you know it's because it's that way
because of the
ASCII
because of the ASCII table they have you
know they have a bunch of punctuations
between the lowercase letters and the
capital case letters letters you can see
here
so you can see here's a capital case
they start with 65
uh you know and so on
then you can see here is a bunch of
punctuations so that becomes 9192 and
blah blah blah then
then you have lowercase okay so can we
make this
turning a character to a number without
using an if statement
you know when you code
it's
in many math problems you can avoid the
if statement because in mathematics
usually you don't want if statement you
don't want you know depends on which
case then that's not math usually you
you know you turn things into numbers
and apply one single function such as
modular arithmetics we did yesterday
yesterday the problem is a good example
you don't do if statement you know
condition if this this check this you
know you simply use modular arithmetics
there's no if statements you know
everything works out for the whole case
so similarly we want try we want to try
to do that
okay so but can we do that that's the
question so
Capital case and lowercase a
um
Capital case in lowercase a
is there a way to know to get to Target
into a number without using
if statement
you can you can turn into a number and
if the number is greater than certain
number you add
10 or something
yeah yeah but that's still uh that's you
know
if statement
okay do you see do you guys see what I'm
saying
so what you can do is something like
that
if
okay
if this is greater than 27
then U minus
you know U minus
minus like one two three four five six
okay
then you do that
n minus six otherwise just return that
X or whatever
so but if you do this yeah sure but you
got uh you got a conditional you got
conditional so
oh God when you think about the fission
yeah that's probably the most efficient
uh is there any other way
because otherwise you just create a hash
table
you know a maps to a number bmaps to a
number a hash table that is actually
not efficient you know because here you
all you have to do is one single if
statement
but if you use hash table that's um
for each character you have to
find the bucket
okay so we are you know we are just
so which way to go so
let's just do this okay let's see if
this works
Okay so
then
okay let's say
a
and say a
okay then we need to uh God
hmm
[Music]
you need to make this correct
Okay so
x equals true
665 actually minus 65.
okay
so if x equals to
something like that probably incorrect
but
but okay here is a whole code it's
probably incorrect let's think about it
now we can either just try it you know
start to try our enroll trial in error o
actually think about this then one shot
it will be correct so let's do the one
shot correct
so
two character code two character code
is is gonna be
uh if it's capital A U minus not 65
minus 64. okay
now if it's lowercase a
so you got 97 minus 64 97 minus 64.
97 you got 23.
oh wait there is more complexity because
in this problem the lower case has
smaller numbers the uppercase has larger
numbers yeah
so this algorithm is not
gonna work
or it's going to be more complex
and also if you use this algorithm there
is is somewhat inelegant because you
have this magical two character code you
know according to the ASCII standard you
know why for example Y is a65 well
there's no
there's no logical reason except
historical reason a capital A is 65 you
know what you know why why is lowercase
you know
so this
this ASCII code is a historical reason
and if you use that ASCII table you are
your code becomes dependent on some
historical thing so if you want so if
you judge your code by Elegance then
it's kind of problematic because the SC
code is not part of mathematics do you
guys what see what I'm saying the SC
code is just you know that's why
programmers and mathematicians usually
they are thinking their ways are very
different you know programmers will love
to use ASCII code especially the C C
plus plus Unix people they they see they
they love to use it they use it right
away without thinking you know they
think this would be great this would be
clever this would be you know very fast
too because every language has
is built upon ASCII character code
but from a mathematician's perspective
what the is ASCII called you know
that's just arbitrary historical thing
you know your mathematical formulas does
not
refer to some human created complexity
you know so that's why so they are you
know so they are trade-off here in terms
of how you judge the code you you can
use you know you can kind of do a
credible hack using ASCII code or you
can
well the other way is just to create a
hash table then
actual table so
but I mean so in either case I mean even
if you use ASCII code you have to do
more than one if statement
or you can check the whether it's
uppercase
okay let's first of all let's do the
let's write some code just to solve this
problem okay let's not worry about
too many things so to solve this problem
is just first of all you check the
letter case
easiest way okay so
so is here a function that checks
uppercase
there it is tool uppercase uppercase q
okay then you have lowercase
uh back
so you have lowercase q that returns
true or false so let's do this
okay so let's write this
if uppercase cha
then
then that else then okay I hope this is
clear
okay if it's uppercase then let's see
the ASCII code
uppercase
uh I guess
yeah minus 64. okay now if it's
lowercase otherwise if it's lowercase
then
minus
96 okay
okay so that that works okay let's
remove remove the other
this is you know not not optimal because
the if statement is ugly
then and then you have to use uppercase
level case then okay let's whatever
let's just do it
okay
test
okay incorrect
oh yeah well of course obviously minus
if it's uppercase
minus
64 plus 26 okay and actually that
uh so
we can we can rewrite this
so you if you rewrite the function this
way you don't have pattern matching
which is much faster
um but uh
but then the function so
the function currently take one single
character at a time
so you need to for every character you
need to call this function the other
alternative is that you can make this
function takes a string and
then in that case you return a bunch of
numbers okay no we don't we want the
single yeah okay
string cases then all you have to do
okay let's put this function
here
okay then string cases then let's just
uh
map
charter number
map to this thing
and let's see X2 okay
okay
let's see how it goes
p is 16 is that correct
I don't know so let's try a different
yeah p16 that's correct
now let's try the second line
okay
copy that
paste
evaluate L is 38 correct
so here's a solution you see
16 38 42 22 okay then let's try the next
slide
run it 42 correct so far so good now
let's just try the whole thing okay
looks like we are on the right track we
are on the right track
so now here is the input let's say
so there is the X there's the input and
here is our function then test ignore it
then
we want to split the input into a bunch
of strings Okay so
what we can do is
split
stream
split okay
spread by a single line that's correct
once you split that we got a list okay
let's say lines
okay so we got a bunch of lines
it's okay
we got a bunch of lines and the length
uh
[Music]
we don't want all that too many so let's
see
yeah but we want it to be efficient Okay
so
in fact we can call a stream partition
you know so a lot of Wolfram specific
functions string partition we are just
spin the string into two substrings okay
so you can see
you know so we don't need to manually
like manually do the pouch one part
pouch two
okay so string partition
and we don't need to even calculate the
length anymore
okay string partition
speed the string into a list of strings
two of them
oh wait uh
oh yeah so you have to have length here
so
string length
uh wait we need to work on a single line
so hold on a second so that's lines
that's lines you want to apply the
partition to a string so
okay map
mapple function two lines what is a
function
function is here okay
string partition length
um
yeah so
there there this is a function okay
so what this means is that you map a
function to
to a list of lines Okay so
here
so string split you know so let's do
that we don't even need that so this
this will first so let me explain this
one okay
so map takes two arguments the first one
is a function the second one is the
input then you split it so you got a
list of lines a list of lines now so
this function applies to each
line of a string and this uh this
sharp sign
number sign means the argument so you
take the argument and you also compute
the length then you partition it so it
should return two so for example let me
show you okay
so anyway we will show it okay we have
done it
so what this will come out is a list of
a list of
things and each thing is a list of two
parts
a list of two strings one is the first
the founder of the string and end of the
string okay so actually let's show that
so you can see
uh uh wait where is it
did it partition
all right
I think I'm too going too slow but so
no it the partition failed
let's try again okay so let me let me
show this
partition failed let's try
oh you you forgot to divide by two
idiotic of course you need to
string length divided by two okay so now
there it is okay that's the and then you
can do this
so now you can create a c clearly see
each line is split into two parts okay
so so so that is the result of that now
we have to do is we
string cases okay so then we do this
we want to again map a function to each
of the line
each of the line now this line is now a
list of two strings okay so again you do
a map
two things the first part is the is this
thing okay
I don't know if I can
this is the code is getting complex
but so here now the first part needs to
be a function okay
the function will be this okay
basically okay
let's do that okay the function
the same cases pouch one pouch two so
this will be
arguments
second elements
okay well actually let's just say last
last part pouch one is the first part
okay
fantastic I think our code is getting
uh
fantastic okay let me show you
there it is p l p v t s
p l p v t s okay now all you have to do
is just map them it's so easy so again
you need a map okay
again you need a map and the second part
now you see the nature of lisp this is
how you see the nature of the heavily
nested syntax
now you know normally people don't cover
language in this way too much nesting
but I'm trying to avoid
you know the shortcut syntax because you
don't you know because that requires
memorization and it's hard to understand
if you uh don't have the experience so
anyway now we map uh we map just
we map just this uh
chart to number
yeah each one is just a number okay
we map and and give it a
okay I think that's that's that
to we we map it to level two that's what
this means okay
and see
to yeah level two
okay we got then then can we do total
let's see
oh
fantastic one shot coding solution so so
the solution is
two lines but I can I can shorten it
much you know I can make it one line you
see here is just a function so this part
you just put that there it becomes one
single line
and then all you have to do is you
change the
um this code into a shortcut syntax so
it's much more condensed and in fact
more readable
so yeah let's do that okay
you know for example if you
change this you know if you use
anonymous function then you don't have
the name chart to number so it's hard to
understand
so anyway so that's the solution let's
let's move on okay let's get my personal
input let's see how huge it is okay huge
fine
okay select your copy now let's go to
talk show
open it
okay and uh let's open a new buffer
now save this AOC
let's see
day three I think
okay drop to diet
turn space to low line okay now open it
and actually rename
okay that yeah so we open it that's your
input okay copy that close close
uh actually open copy the link
file path and linkify there okay now
open it copy it curse back to the
Wolfram language
and we can just paste it there that's a
whole
input
copy it
back here
paste
Eva
oh what's the result we forgot the total
okay it's it's at the total here
okay so let's see
X list equals to that okay
total X list
okay seven five eight one
let's submit
hmm
I'm 99.99 is correct
that's the right answer you are one gold
star closer to collecting enough star
fruit okay
uh continue to part two
okay
who is watching probably nobody
let's see
five oh six oh God hey cousin people
watching say hi okay say hi
okay let's get back so back to the code
we want to finish this coding problem at
the end of code day three okay now
okay now let's uh before we go on let's
clean up the code so that
so that
um
so for example this part just copy it
you know Wolfram language has automatic
formatting so if you look at the code
you can see the intend your code
depending on your window width
automatically you know you don't have to
you don't even have to call command to
you know it's like on the Fly
so that's why you know in my last few
videos I've complained about the in
Industries programmers idiocy about
their you know formatting and
coding style you see
so that is represent you know this part
okay so
and now I want to clean the code okay
because that's
usually you don't write that usually you
let me show you okay so I'm going to
transform this code into something else
let me show you okay
so
um
so actually you need head pod okay
[Music]
okay
map it
here is another map
[Music]
okay it's much simpler
and then
[Music]
this chart to num let's let's also
and it's also
reduce it into
some
[Music]
Okay so
this
okay so the second part is equivalent to
the first one
let's see so of course the 64 verse 26
minus 64 plus 26 we can combine that
combine that into one number but let's
leave it
okay I think that's it
so this part let's just comment it out
and
comment it out
uh okay let's do it again
seven five eight one okay that's correct
now let's
let's
um
let's remove that okay put back the
original
let's go to
uh God I hope I don't mess up let's go
back to original problem what's the
original problems input
do we have it here or there okay that's
good
original problems input
okay pop it back
refresh I mean make it color syntax
colored so here is today's stock show
the problem number one
and the solution is just this single
line okay well actually you need to put
the total
you know together that that's the
solution okay language
okay part two then
so it's now been 90 minutes not not too
bad
uh because when you do I have to talk so
if I do this
by myself
it's probably 30 minutes
yeah well
20 minutes if we are 10 20 minutes if we
go by speed because then I don't have to
worry about
you know which algorithm to use and
explain
at every step
okay part two let's finish this
as you finish identifying the misplaced
items the elves comes through you with
another issue for safety the elves are
divided for safety what the word
for safety the elves are divided into
groups of three
okay every elf carries a badge that
identifies their group
okay for efficiency within each group of
three elves
the badge is the only item type carried
by all three elves
somewhat confusing so are you talking
about so it's a badge now a food item
is is the badge considered a food item
in a pouch in the compartments because
previously
the things the items
in the rucksack are food supposedly
you know then types of food but now it
says the batch is the only item type
carried by all three of so are you
talking about in the rucksack or not
so that is if a group's batch is is item
type B then all three helps will have
item type B somewhere in the rucksacks
and then all three elves will have item
type B
somewhere in in their rucksacks okay and
at most two of the elves will be
carrying any other item type
so if a group's patch is item type B
then then all three elves will have item
type B somewhere in there rucksack
so each elf carries a rucksack
Okay so
if groups badge is in height is item
type B then all three elves will have
item type B somewhere in the rucksack
and at most two of the elves
will be carrying any other item type
what a illogical description
uh you know this advantage of code
description is not very good
because here the problem is first of all
the item type you know first of all
there's a confusion between item versus
item type
the type is not really necessary but
let's assume they introduce the type
concept so that we can clarify you know
two bag of peanuts are different you
know so we can say they are the same
type
anyway it's confusing they shouldn't
introduce type
but now
you see before they are talking about
food
you see one elf has the important job of
loading all of the rucksacks with
supplies for the jungle Journey
surprise okay now they are talking about
badges in the rucksack badges are not
supplies and the
is this this this uh okay I'm you know
I'm ranting and pitching this is just uh
not well done and
given that I suppose they got a lot of
sponsors you know it becomes fairly
popular quite a lot of sponsors
uh but the problem is not professionally
written
yeah it's it tries to sell Christianity
you know which is fine but the problem
is not professionally written
it is to a mathematician you know
probably through most programmers you
don't you don't care that's that's my
complaint most programmers
they don't they don't they don't get
they don't see the details of things
they when they don't analyze you know
typically the most programmers they just
all start to code it like you know trial
and error
but through a mathematician the problem
is problematic
okay so now they are talking about batch
they are talking about badge in each elf
so you have a bunch of elves
each elf has a badge
the elves are grouped into threes
so every three elf is one group and they
carry the group's badge and this badge
is apparently
it's the only item type carried by Earth
three elves oh okay so okay
so every three elf
in a group they have a badge which is a
item you put in the rucksack
and but no there's only one of it
you know not not a badge for every elf
but
one badge for a group of three elves
so
what wait wait look at the way they
phrase you know then all three elves
will have item type B somewhere in the
rucksack and and at most two of the
elves will be carrying any other item
type what what other item
idiotic
foreign
if a group's patches item type B
so now there's another you know it's
it's so bad it badly phrased so now you
are you are saying
you know before these items are food or
a surprise but now you are saying
run with the character
in the input is a batch that's what you
are seeing
and confusingly it uses the letter B so
like b stand for badge very idiotic
okay so the problem is that someone
forgot to put this year's updated
authenticity sticker on the badges oh
God another concept authenticity sticker
on the badge over the badges needs to be
pulled out of the rucksacks so the new
authenticity stickers can be attached
additionally nobody wrote down which
item type corresponds to each group's
badges okay very
um
corrupted you know very how do you say
hot very uh
up writing you know so so right
now they are saying you know these
supplies the item types
okay you see they are saying a badge is
the item type basically
okay and uh nobody wrote down which item
type correspond to each group's badges
the only way to tell which item type is
the right one
is by finding the one item type that is
common between all three elves
okay so it looks like they are trying to
you know each line is a string they are
trying to find
yeah I almost get the problem they are
a repeating character a single character
that repeats so you know remember before
the input is a list of lines so now
essentially you are trying to partition
each the lines into groups of three
where you know the group has shares one
single character that's the same that's
what probably
so now now now it comes here you know
every set of three lines in your list
corresponds to a single group okay but
each group can have a different batch
item type yeah of course shut up so in
above example the first group is
rucksacks are the first three lines okay
over okay in the second group of SEC on
the next three lines okay apparently the
group is already ordered
right so it's already like three you
know older three three you could be you
know so your job I guess is to find that
item
I mean the character that represents the
badge the the item type that is a supply
but represent the badge the
idiotic
the unprofessional writing the problems
stupid
okay
so the second group so so in the first
group the only item type that appears in
all three rucksacks
lowercase R so there you see they are
trying you know the the problem is for
you to find a character
for each three lines
you know in that order in a given order
there is a character that is that
appears in each
of the line
and your job is to identify it
you know the stupid story
types and badging elves
unprofessionally written story
uh
you know and this the problem is simply
identify the
the letter that appears in each three
consecutive three lines
okay in the second group there are badge
item type must be Z because Z appears in
each and every of these two these three
lines let's see
capital Z there it is capital z
there it is capital z
but here it appears twice
okay priorities for this item must still
be found to organize their sticker
attachment now introduce another
concept stickers
you know why why do they introduce the
concept of stickers because
not to not to help describe the problem
but to help to describe the story so
that this somewhat makes sense
he already doesn't because Supply types
now you your badge becomes a supply item
type
it's all doesn't make sense you know you
have a rucksack
you have two compartments they are
supplies you know but now
one of the supplies a batch
but you know normally you know the real
world a badge represents each elf has
one badge each person has one batch
so but now it's like three elves have
one single batch
and this patch only appears in one of
these
these three elves back rucksack
it's so this is It's not like real it's
not it doesn't make it's not doesn't
make a common sense
stupid writing this is this is my
problem with this
and and my problem is not just with you
see my problem this is a common problem
of me framing the typical industrial
programmers the problem
is that this story this description of
the problem is not well done okay for
example the problem number three it
applies to problem number two and day
one two but problem number three part
part two in particular okay very
confusing
so the description of problem is not
well done
but the problem is you will find not a
single programmer that criticized this
not a single one
industrial programmers
common and when I do like
right now I describe what's the problem
what's wrong with the writing they'll
start to call you a troll because they
don't know you know that's a problem
you know the more you like it's like
typically and more the more I look into
detail the more problem I find but but
the insulting thing is that nobody no
other programmers see it you'll find
like zero
people criticizing the description of
the problem but when you do criticize
they'll say oh we're so cold oh yes
please suppose open source you know
idiots
so the problem now is you know actually
just to identify that letter common in
every three lines okay seems like
in the second group their batch item
type must be Z okay and I suppose
there's only one letter
that has this property you know appear
in it in all three lines
uh yeah seems to be okay
so priorities they you know organize the
sticker which is non-concept attached
efforts attachment efforts here they are
18.
they are 18 are
for the first group so then again you
have to convert the letters to the
number
and sum the number you see this is
another stupidity of the problem
because you see in order to try you know
why do they want to turn the number I
mean why do they want to turn the
character into a number why can't you
for example the first solution why can't
you say just say
you know find the sequence of letters
but instead they want the number why
because if you have a number that's that
helps the solution that makes it easier
to say you know just one single number
so in order to do that so they
introduced in the story in the
description of the problem in introduce
this
kind of thing well that's you know you
could say that adds extra step to the
problem okay
so okay so you convert the character
into a number and sum them up okay find
the item type that corresponds to the
badges of each three elf group what is
the sum of the priorities of the two
item types
of those item types okay easy okay so
now
copy the code
and this let's start to let's do a
problem too okay
two okay and uh okay let's let's get
let's get the elaborate
okay let's get it's a code but before we
do that let's get into
um
okay and same thing with problem one
you see what I'm doing in a moment okay
show in browser
so today's talk show problem one
you know description input
solution okay and we are dealing with
problem two now okay so now let's start
to code so problem two is you want to
group each three of them easy okay
uh very easy okay let's just start to
code
so first of all so okay so input let's
let's just write code okay
uh
string split X input okay uh let's let's
just Define a bunch of variables so it's
easier to understand the code
okay so now you have a list of strings
then you want to Partition
okay oh you don't need to split too
front and back anymore so actually uh
actually you partition into three okay
so
yeah so
string length
X1
divided by three
you want to
partition into groups of three Okay so
let's do this okay so wait
partition X1
by X1 divided by and 3 not divided by
three just three
partition into each three of them okay
and in fact we can do it you can just
try it and show okay
so you can see the result
yeah okay I typed it wrong
not partial d
partition okay
you see so here's one group of three his
second group of three
okay
so now you have a list of least each
sublist is three strings okay
now
and now you want to find you want to map
a function that takes a list of three
strings one to find a letter that's
common in them all
okay interesting problem
Sam says will you be documentation your
Solution on your website with an
expansion
uh no
so Sam's question
uh because
uh you know I have Excel talk show so
each day's solution is already there
so
um so your question is whether can I
document it in detail let's take that
takes too much time because I already
you know if you watch my live stream
it's kind of slow but you can fast
forward you know I explain in detail how
everything works in Wolfram language you
know I have a full tutorial as you know
if you watch my video so in woven
language has full documentation so you
can look up so I'm not going to do that
but let's solve this problem interesting
problem I mean uh interesting problem
because now it wants to day three yeah
day three problem two uh now you want to
for each three strings you want to
um
find a letter that's common in all three
okay there must be one single wufam
language function that do that I think
foreign
[Music]
of things you want to find
a character that appears in all three
[Music]
so in other languages low level
languages scholar and JavaScript python
you basically start to do a loop you go
through each character and check if that
character is in the second string and
whether it's in third string if so stop
you found it okay that's typically low
level language in wufan language you can
do that as well you can do that but
usually there is one building function
that
that declarative declaratively just give
you the answer so but
the trick is to you you need to be
familiar with Wu fam language so you
need to think what is that function's
name would be
uh
so I have to think about that
so you want to a list of things you want
to find that's common you want to find
the item that's common in all
okay
um
that's an interesting problem
[Music]
string rifle string refill is string to
list
no it's a these two string okay
we want some kind of combinatorial
um
exist something like exist
or
let's see if we if there's such a
function
string position
string difference maybe string
difference
yeah string difference
is here a string difference
string intersection okay let's try
there it is
now easier string intersection no but
you can turn a string into a sequence of
symbols then this will work let me show
you
okay
so you have a this one let's say base
two let's say
this three
let's say a a a
b c okay let's say B Z Edge okay let's
say you need a b here too so let's say
whatever
uh you you let's say h and b okay
there it is that is what you want
so in order to use this intersection
function each of the item is a symbol so
what you have to do is you can turn the
string each character into a symbol or
in fact it would be nice to turn them
into a number first you know using this
number because in the end you want the
numbers anyway so
fantastic let's do that
so so first of all turn the input into
so okay so
yeah intersection is what we want
Sam says rejects on common frequency
count
[Music]
that might that might work but needs
some work yeah so intersection would be
a
be a good um you see that's a you know
it's kind of the the nature of wufam
language when you call wufam language
you want to find
a building function that kind of do what
you need because in this case typically
just about in every programming language
you just you just do a loop go through
each character and check if it's in the
other two if you find it stop so you
write a loop yourself you can do that
exactly in Wolfram language but if you
do that your result is actually going to
be slower okay slower in Wolfram
language but if you use this you know
some kind of building it's shorter and
in fact much faster as well
Because the actual algorithm you know
how how does it do intersection anyway
you know act you know you can sort it
first then you can maybe do binary
search and you know many ways you know
intertext section can take a thousands
this
so it automatically figure out
you know again bio algorithm
uh
to decide on which algorithm to use so
yeah so anyway so the building uh
functions and they have a lot of power
so anyway so in order to use that we
need to turn the numbers into either
symbols or
um
or a list of characters
so let's see what um functions do we
have for characters
okay so there's a
characteristic character name characters
okay
character string gives a list of
characters in a string fantastic that's
what we want okay so
so instead of you know
a string becomes a list of characters
now once we have a list of characters we
can use intersection okay
so
partition so you want to turn to them
into X3 equals to
character
okay needs to be uh so you need to map
this actually
map I'm gonna just use shortcut okay map
the 8x2 partition
now last time the result is
last result is
yeah the result is like that
too
map to level negative one that means map
to each of the atom which is a string
okay
so you want to map a function to X2 and
what this function the function is going
to be just character okay
okay let me show you
how that works so far
okay that doesn't work because
uh
you see it applies uh but why is it not
work
what is the character
oh you have two characters you have to
say s I think
yeah Cactus not character okay
copy that back here
paste Eva
fantastic then now you have to do is say
intersection
not the interval
okay then again you need a map okay map
something to X3 then you need a function
function is just intersection and in
this case you need to map to level two
so let me see
so the
the input will be a list of list of
characters
so you need to map to level
one
now level two is correct okay let's just
do that
let's say x4a what
okay let's say X4 equals to
okay copy copy
no
it did not return the right answer did
it
let's try again
let's try on this single
what
oh intersection needs different
arguments
okay I know what to do so instead of
that you need that that Supply okay
let's shortcut the add add is a shortcut
for the okay there it is okay so this R
is the first three lines okay so now we
just modify this intersection into
okay you probably don't know what I'm
doing but that's
uh
let me explain that okay so here is a
solution
uh okay so you got something wrong wait
okay oh yeah so you want to apply to
level one okay so let's try again
okay so R and Z the original sample
input
the result is I and Z then all you have
to do now is just turn each the letter
into a number and submit it up okay
so now uh but this this part is
interesting
I'm gonna copy screenshot it and that's
the event the solution for Advent of
of code day three
[Laughter]
it would be fun you know dramatic so so
now we almost done okay so
so
um yeah so we have to do now is X5 is
just
convert it to
uh
this function
this function mapped to
map to what what did we get okay we need
the level okay
so
so map the arguments the you want to map
a function this function you want to map
to X4 which is a list which is this
thing and you want to map to level two
okay so here is a solution okay let's do
it again
oh then you need to total total it up
okay total so let's see
X6 equals to
tal X5
okay 70. now is that the correct answer
70 correct all we have to do now is to
use our previous input okay now pop this
back so we clean up we don't need that
you don't need that okay that's the yeah
so pop this back and copy the original
input
and uh
okay so paste that there
paste okay
it's a huge input and now let's
add semicolon so it suppresses the
uh intermediate output
because otherwise you're gonna have a
huge list of things okay so press the
intermediate output
just give me the total my friend
25 25 okay let's submit without blink of
an eye
we did this for two hours
submit
that's the right answer my friend
day three
at the end of code day three
passed two problems in day three both
passed now let's syntax color the Emax
buffer showing browser here is today's
solution
here is Wolfram solution to Advent of
code number one one single line
and here is the solution to advance code
number
day three problem two
also one single line you know you just
combine those remove those variables
it's one single line and and what is
interesting is that we use the
intersection function
now actually can you do that in other
languages oh actually you can yes in
other languages you can there is also
intersection in Python
you know intersection the function
intersection is in Wolfram language
since 1990.
okay 30 something years ago but the
intersection is added to python in the
past 10 years 5 or 10 and similar the
language still you know
still don't have it you know like C and
you know so anyway so yeah high level
high level math
high level programming language okay so
that solves the problem I'm happy and
I'm tired I need to get up and walk any
comments we shut down in three minutes
so random chat now
how do you get your command log mod
output to another window okay so emacs
command log mod which I'm using uh which
is I modified a little bit just a few
lines so let's show you
okay so you can see I'm calling the
command start command log
and you can see the source code which is
just here so
because the so I'm using the package
command log mod that's the package okay
that's open source you can find it now
mailpa so let's open that file so can we
open that file there it is so it's by
2004 by uh who did it first
so the original guy is Michael Weber I
guess
yo folder.org he's famous he's famous
for
uh wait did I mix him up with someone
else
free dictionary no that's not
I forgot this is him or not I guess you
know this is old page this is like
there's a free online dictionary for
focus on functional programming
I don't know if that still exists or not
anyway so he he said you know he wrote
that in 2004 initially
so anyway this is the command lock mod
but it's problematic you know so and
it's hard to start it's kind of
confusing but if you read the detail you
all know okay so yeah here's my
explanation so you first of all you have
to do that then you want Global you do
that then you have to call this to show
the log buffer so
okay so let for example let's close it
yes do you want to save no okay so what
I do is I open a new window then say saw
start
and that becomes the
that okay so let me show you the code
again
so you can find this in my
do I have it somewhere no I don't have
it
online so you just copy my screenshot
okay just do it
thank you guys for watching pay me okay
if you enjoyed you know if you enjoyed
my talk and enjoyed my tutorials pay me
five bucks 20 bucks
you know consider it as a service
like a coffee okay bye guys