hello guys welcome to another episode of
s talk
show Cheers so we're going to do emac
lisp randomish we're going to go slowly
and if you are here say hi I love to see
your comments comments if you are not
here skip around and play at 1.5 speed
because I Rambo and uh so before we
begin let's relax and we I got this
D Julio D Julio something
something
Reposado tequila okay A friend on
Twitter says I should have this so let's
enjoy life a little bit while you
can how does this work
oh wood made of wood can you see
that uh you know alcohol bottles are
always fancy you know one question I
have is what do you
do with all the fancy bottles when the
wine is done you know some of them are
beautiful bottles like do they
actually have some value can you let's
see let's pull some okay not too much
this
is this is uh tequila
okay nice now you can just pop it in I
hate those wine bottles where you know
you have to use a cork opener to open
then you cannot put it back
in now this is
scientific excellent
okay now this is Coke and Tequila let's
see how it
tastes M tastes good okay I like
it emac lisp the best editor the best
programming language
for text process sessing okay hello guys
hello I don't know hello Lis hey uh
friends hello Thiago hey hello GCS hey
hello Crystal so all of you guys I
know Tequila what does tequila taste
like
tequila I think it's almost like
tasteless like like vodka I don't know I
uh I don't remember when's last time I
had tequila you know I'm not a drinker
so
but but this thing now I have Coke in it
so I cannot purely
say do I miss my long hair yes kind of
you know you can do that when you are
younger but now starting at age 40 you
know I get Bor so it doesn't look good
anymore don't be like those those
idiotic rock rock and roll Stars you
know when they are 18 they created the
band rock and roll they are doing great
all the girls you know girls and guys
they are
hot but sometimes you still see them
when they are 50 and 60 even like the
Jack Migo you know they go on stage and
still sing those teenage songs you know
that
become uh idiotic
rotten so you go with your age so
you know for now it's not suitable for
me to have long
hair okay what we going to do today
we're going to code some emac list okay
so this is my too list huge okay so
write uh right decimal to hexad decimal
okay let's just do that one okay so copy
that fiago is spold too you know I don't
know how you guys looks so I can't you
know I have no idea most of you guys
half of you guys are pseudonyms or not
so and a lot of people not you guys you
know I kind of know you guys came here
often but a lot of people on Twitter or
you know they come like they and they
change their handle all the time like
they create new account that got banned
they create new one you know this random
Zuma
Fox okay I despise them
okay let's write this one go to talk
show there there there
there there there there there there
there okay right decimal to hexad
decimal okay see okay let's do
that so copy so do do that that that
okay cut then make a emac
lisp code section and and pop it out
there it is and uh comment that out
default defund uh so we want to write
this function so the function name is
that and the C also that okay so I
already have a command s hexad decimal
to decimal so describe function yes so
here's documentation for that
okay uh so hex decimal to
decimal uh okay prints the decimal value
of the hexad decimal string on the curer
okay so for example f f FF becomes
6535 and uh you can take different
formats so 0x f f FF also works or pound
sign X the zero X prefix that came from
C bit dling
[ __ ] okay this pound sign X that is
the emac thisis convention okay so you
can also use Capital case okay so I
already have this function this function
is
defined uh in this source code okay and
there is a website you can go to so if
you like this command you can grab it
and possess it
yourself thank thanks
to
uh
magnanimousness of
s and let's go to source code okay there
it is the source code there it is last
updated
2024 February
27 uh uh and uh oh 2024 February 27 so
it's the same version but uh I kind of
tricked the format there anyway so here
is the
function what we going to do so let's
test it okay so uh open open new buffer
so let's put let's
say FFF here and let's call Meta
xar hex a decimal to decimal okay TX
there the shortcut key do
it okay so at the bottom can you
see yeah you can see at the bottom you
see it says you know uh it says radex 16
FF FF radex 10
6553 now Radix basically mean base okay
rad radic is the more traditional word
for the base of a number base notational
system okay so this command works great
beautiful so this is
a hexad decimal to
decimal so you put a cursor on a hexad
decimal then you can see the value okay
now I want a version so first of all
let's copy the code so copy it close it
close that close that put it here as
well okay so we
got you know here's the
code it displays the decimal in the in
in the display area okay now uh I think
I want the version that insert instead
of just display so anyway that's
something to do okay for this command
but I also want to command on decimal to
hexad
decimal uh so first of all there's a
question uh user interface question
should you
merge these two functionalities
together like decimal to hexad decimal
or hexad decimal to decimal should you
merge it or
uh into one command let's say no
okay so we going to write this okay
let's just write this okay instead of
just talking hexad decimal to decimal
that's uh obvious what it does so we
don't
um let's write some documentation con uh
okay
convert the
decimal and cursor to hexad decimal okay
beautiful documentation beautiful
English writing beautiful composition it
is a acquired skill most of the Zuma
idiots they are incapable of doing that
okay writing
documentation uh that involves technical
writing
involves you know involves some skills
that you have to practice to get right
okay
so so decimal to he decimal that's easy
to do actually okay so let's just start
to write it easy quick okay um let begin
and uh let begin and local variables and
uh uh first of all you want to grab the
word and the cruiser
okay
set uh
current word so there is a command
called current word okay so here's a
documentation for current word return
the word at at or near Point as a string
okay the return value includes no text
properties okay uh strict is if the
strict is n
Neal if it's true then return NE unless
point is within or Jason to a
word otherwise look for a word within
points line okay so I want it to be NE
uh true okay strict I want the word
under CER not nearby words okay so um
then what is really word so really word
if it's the ne only characters of word
syntax that means does not does not
include possibly The Hyphen or the
underline the low line okay so really
what true okay okay current War true
true now
[Music]
um okay so that grabs the word under
cursor under the cursor for example
2025 um so that grabs the word so you
you don't want just the word you want
the boundary position positions so that
you will be able to delete
it h okay so that's not so this is not
good you know we cannot use
that okay so let's just say use thing at
Point okay thing at Point word let's
just use that thing at point is kind of
slow but uh but let's just use it that
we grab the word Sim as that so actually
we want thing at Point boundary
uh bounce of thing thing at
Point okay
so there uh word
okay that will return the boundary a
cons pair of two integers beginning
position and end position okay beautiful
now uh okay
so let X
expounds do do do do do that that that
that that that that that set expound
equals to that boundary okay once you
got the boundary
then set X
begin uh let's change this to
bounds okay so X begin equals to Car X
bounds and X end equals to
C
oun okay that will basically set the
begin and end position to the beginning
and end positions which are integers
is that beautiful yes clean up the code
now
next
next so we got the boundary of the word
now you just turn it so let's format
okay let me show you okay
um X num which is a number so set X num
equals to
sub string no properties
okay from X begin to X
end so that so that will return the
actual number okay so then we got the
number next
then you just convert it to hexad
decimal okay so you can do that by
format format X num first of all that's
a string so you want to turn the string
into a number so string to
number okay that
then you want to print it hexadecimal so
format percentage X that Returns the
hexadecimal okay then you want
to uh so what you do first is delete
region okay delete delete the region
begin end then
insert okay what you want to insert you
want to insert this hexad decimal okay
that's
it clean up the code a little bit that's
it for the code congratulations you've
done it thank you so this is the code
evaluate the buffer now test let's
say
2025 okay call the command s decimal
to hex decimal okay do
it error run type argument string P
432 Okay so let's
see wrong type argument it string P it
means it is looking for a string but it
got
um I'm not sure
what you know I know the arrow is
somewhere here but let's just so let's
print it instead
evaluate it call the command do
it
error what what is error I I don't know
okay so let's
um so
let's let's print
what do you want to print xn so let's
see what this x
num evaluate
it cor it do it wrong type argument 471
okay I don't know where that came from
so I will know if I look at the code
more carefully but another way which is
probably what you guys want to do is
turn on the buger info so you press this
key debug on arrrow enabled globally so
that key
is describe key so that key cause Targo
debug on error so I just turned it on
okay now let's call this command again
decimal to hexad decimal do it now you
got full error uh so so you see
substring no properties that's
where oh that yeah that's what I was
wondering this is the wrong function
okay it's not substring it's
uh both a substring no properties okay
yeah that that I was wondering why is
that
um set X num that okay so this wrong
okay so now comment that out that um and
this should be insert okay so let's just
do
insert okay commment that out evaluate
the buffer close the
debugger Now call the command do
it
2025 becom 7
E9 fantastic now let's try to turn this
hexad decimal to decimal so let's call
this command Okay correct
hexad decimal to decimal do
it
2025 can you see it at the
bottom so successful so today we set out
to do this
command this this command he hex decimal
two decimal and remove remove so this
successful okay that's it for today I
think anything else is there any
questions
cheers maybe that's it for today just 20
minutes short one
today let's get the drink let's
see there is a clear glass cup let's see
if I can
let good game good game
so let's see how this
tastes
okay this is tequila
H so how does it taste
it's more or less tasteless
okay I think that's it
so here is a code convert the decimal
number under cursor to hexad decimal
yeah sometimes you need that uh
convenient and uh this one hexad decimal
to decimal it does not replace the
current hexad mod it only shows you what
is the
value so which is also good you see this
two there there's a difference between
because one of them will just delete the
current number and replace it the other
one only displays it but I think that's
fitting because most of the
time when you have a hexad decimal you
do want to
uh turn it to decimal you don't merely
want to I mean you you do want you you
you all you want is just to see what is
a decimal value but not change it
because in lots of code you got hexad
decimal
number and you want to know what is that
in decimal but you don't want to change
it on the other hand when you have a
decimal
often times you do want you want to turn
it into hexad dimal because hexad dimal
is used a lot in code okay that's it for
today I think
um n people watching fantastic so now
let's put the code back okay so let's
copy that I'm not going to do anything
with that
so it it works so let's put it back
showing browser back to emac press press
press so it syntax color the emac this
code showing browser so you can see now
it's all beautiful okay that's it bye
guys now donate to me okay go to c. info
c. info all the way at the bottom just
PayPal me $100 okay or Amazon gift card
me 100 bucks bye guys