welcome to another episode of Santos
show today is May 26 2009 teen I am
Alive not dead yet so today's talk show
I'm going to talk about a few things one
is SPLC this is rather unpleasant topic
this is Southern Poverty Law Center
now that SPLC is one one of the biggest
hate cooperation hate creating
organization biggest scam they have like
hundreds millions of dollars off shore
from donation what they do they create
hate they generate hate they you know
they spread the news the information
they manufacture you know fake news
about hate crime so that you know the
more hate the more donation they get you
know the SPLC they began decades ago I
think because of the Martin Luther King
era so originally it was good but in the
past at least in the past ten years they
become they are the one of the biggest
you know like today you have so many
political situations people violent you
know and people believe there are so
many you know and you know in a you know
the certain political party of the
Germany back then and I believe there
are a lot of that and they believe there
are a lot violence committed by these
people you know this so-called whatever
you know but they are all fake news they
are created by this you know SPLC is the
the men I think it's a primary
organization that
ADEs these are these fake news so what
do you mean by fake news like how can
they how could it possible you know it's
like you know it's money basically it's
a money they use it essentially
fundamentally the more hate the more
donation they get you know so they want
to create you know they want to push
your emotion anger like they they want
to exaggerate news exactly you know and
and you know do we report things that's
not hate but they want to rewrite it so
it's hate and it's you know it's it's
it's it's it's you have to look into it
you know like today most people you
don't have time you know most people are
busy with their work or whatever they
read news and that that's it all in read
new some violence and you know committed
against you know black people or women
yeah you know and and you know you are
angry and but that's about it you know
you go on with your life you know then
maybe once in a while you you go donate
to the SPLC that's today's modern life
nobody you know it's like do you ever
spend you know even like every day you
have tens of news you know kind of
dramatic you know emotional news do you
do you spend ten minutes to actually
look into them so today's situation is
like that you it's hard to know what is
true and what is not true but here's
what you can do okay you don't have to
believe me okay because I was you know
I'm talking about SPLC because there now
I've been talking you know with email
with Danielle so so so SPLC you know so
so what you have to do is that you know
try to do this every time every day you
know today every day there are some
dramatic news about you know let's say
Trump okay because it's mostly dramatic
and and then then you have you know some
anti-trump news old you know this or
that usually very dramatic such as about
violence about you know about you know
there are these words and I want to
mention okay because you know it Google
you know with this all these censorship
going on and this the the reason of this
censorship happening is because SPRC is
one of the major reason they they create
this situation because so they have
control you know what so I mean just
exactly what they did you know like okay
so what you say they are bad or scam but
exactly what you see I'm gonna tell you
okay but but you know they could they
create hate and they want to suppress
any information doubt about what they
are doing like I mean you know what I'm
doing now and so many people get banned
you know or D monetize you know because
I talk about it you know I always say
nobody you know I so you you you
question what they are doing you know
you question the reports on the news you
know it's often by these major
corporations you can you question you
know they wait a second you know that is
true that is not true or you might say
you know hey that's not you know they
they exaggerate you know clickbait they
you know any news you can when you write
it you can phrase it in such a way that
gives certain picture you know that it
almost it is almost unavoidable to you
know to to to tell story without any
kind of like personal bias why it's kind
of possible you have to try you can't
you can try it as much as you can but
but first of all you know what is buyers
that's hard to define you know everyone
is different but anyway so so yeah but
but
what they do is this cooperation is that
you know they reproduce they they color
it you know they spin it so you know
let's say there's our two group fighting
you know on the street you know there's
violence and you know let's say goop a
and B and if you are prone to believe in
Group A because well because we all have
biases let's say some Chinese fighting
an American it's say not Americans
fighting with the United Kingdom guy
okay then I look at it I probably have a
bias towards a Chinese guy you know I
think oh you you you you you know the
the Britain guy hit Chinese guy first
you know something like that even though
maybe in the you know that's sometimes
it's you know it's question about who
who did wrong first you know so anyway
each person you know you you almost
always have bias so they so if you
believe in group a you know a to group
are fighting a and B you tends to
usually not always if you are you know
you sometimes you have like a bias
towards like group so you kind of
believe that then you know organizations
like SPLC they come up and they spin you
know they write it in a way such that it
appears that P is bad and then you would
be their news you you suddenly obviously
you know you you tend to see that is
that is right you know this is a news
report that sets into your brain
good morning Norman so so that is that's
that is fake news but this SPLC okay
this now let me let me try to put it you
know they are one of the biggest scam
group you know like we are talking about
hundreds of millions dollars they have
you know they put it outside of us a you
know all from donations because that's
how they make money you know this so
there's huge amount corruption you know
this is just one instance like so I'm
telling you you know you Eve maybe you
are what you have you know
you know you don't have you you have a
family you don't have time to read this
but try to do so every time you okay
here's a few things to try I'm telling
you okay
every time every day you're in use try
to spend I would say pick up pick up one
you a week every week there is pick one
thing okay Oh a day you know pick one
news topic that's very dramatic you
think it's utterly bad for something
okay a hate crime or whatever you spent
I would you know spent one hour to dig
into it what so what does that mean you
you try to read the opposition news
organization like the other side you
know you you you spend I mean that you
spent one hour to dig into it
try to do that yeah you know you know
every day there's news you try to do
that you know pick pick when you're in
one hour you know let's say it's half an
hour okay you do that
you know after after acquire okay you
gonna you're gonna find out much of
these are just fake news I mean you're
gonna find out that what you used to
think is you know you change you can you
are going to change your mind I
guarantee you that
now that's one thing you can do okay
every time you read news you try to see
the opposite you spend half an hour to
verify to verify the fact to read the
different sources that's are different
political parties you will see the new
nuances you change your point of view
okay you know you you get closer to what
is actually true so that's one thing try
to do that every time now I'm going to
suggest you some sources okay but I
don't want to color your part you know I
don't want to color your judgment but
you know I think I'm going to suggest
you some sources you might be able to do
that which i think is more fair news
sources okay that's one thing every time
you read news try to spend some time too
question I'd like to research okay
that's one thing good money India yes I
know
Noam Chomsky very very much I look into
that let's talk about that bit later so
that's one thing you know spend 30
minutes for every news item okay dig
into the detail that's one thing now
back to the SPLC I'm saying they are the
one with a very evil scam like a
criminal gang okay this is not not it's
not just a smoke kind of scoop of gang
violence they are organized okay I would
say okay they are organized crime a
criminal organization with hundreds of
millions of dollars you know they are
cooking those money by all means but but
almost all means they can do it you know
they'd like that they [ __ ] folks you
know I'm going to you know I'm wondering
if I should get into details like pics
specific concrete examples but I'm
hoping I'm thinking maybe I don't you
know let's not do that okay because I
can do it right now and I'm going to do
it in real time like you know this is
not prepared I haven't you know try to
you know pull up some pages you know I
can do that right now Mike then you are
see did you know but but let's not do
that because then you gets through you
know political you know since the shape
things so what I'm saying is that you do
it you know Danielle okay Danielle or
anyone because I know I know I notice a
lot there's so many fake news no most
people do not have the time to look into
they don't know they just hear the news
oh they they get a sense of what's going
on but today there's you know much of it
is like just force because I I looked
into because beginning in 2016 October
you know with the rise of social justice
okay things okay
the issues and things you know I was
like quite amazed you know white where
people are talking about these things
why are people acting this way or that
way so I started to casually you know
every time I read news you know I check
what is a source you know I go to read
the news I go watch some videos real
footage you know today almost every
violence on the street in incidence
there's almost someone has real footage
so you I go watch that you know you
don't want to watch whatever is from New
York Times you know CNN or let's say
even [ __ ] Fox News Fox News is tends to
the right okay so you general change in
general don't you know don't trust those
from corporations you want to watch
whatever small people like street people
you know so anyway whenever there's an
instance usually these days this almost
have tons of videos recorded by phones
you know just people on the street they
are not journalists they are not you
know they are nothing they just happen
to be there that we call it so it's on
YouTube every incident you know there's
antiva you know many many big and small
violence or even a violence incident you
you know for those you know protests or
you know violence things you can go to
youtube there are lots of videos I so
you watch them I did you know because
you know I'm not working for a company
so I have you know I let's say I have
quite some time you know besides
studying computer stuff you know so
because these are angry emotional things
you know I was wondering what way is
this happening
so I started to watch you know since out
October 2016 so our average I would say
I spend statistically average would be
two hours or three hours every day since
October 2016 so I know quite a lot about
these things okay so so about SPRC
again I'd like to ask you you know if
you if you if you don't know
you know if you don't believe what I'm
saying or if you have doubt or you don't
you know you don't think I'm you don't
think oh you know you you might think
I'm exaggerating you know I'm saying
they are one of the biggest criminal
organization okay
that's my belief okay I don't want to
get sued so I want to put qualifications
this is my belief okay so you you go you
to it yourself you know I'm not going to
you know you I might give you some
resources later but you know you can
ignore it
you know I'm asking for those who don't
believe you go you go looking into this
situation like research you know it's
normally it's called research research
into SPLC do that for our okay now if
you are watching my video so you know
obviously in some way you trust what I
say what I think so so so I'm saying
that if you have time spend one hour on
the SPR thing is SPLC group you know
look into them so so they you so they
are this one of the biggest you know
like 100 million dollars criminal
organization and then because you know
I'm not going to start to show you
articles because you know today the
information is out there it's just it's
it's like a it's a matter of whether you
have the time you are willing to spend
the time to look into you know that's
the thing and this all these big
corporations fake news they spread
because most people are not going to do
that you know most people are not you
know most people in program including
programmers you know they are not going
to look into Oh the you know whatever
language design or you know this
dramatic news or language you know they
are not concerned by about that usually
most most people more including
programmers you are mostly concerned
with your daily life you know well-being
is you get your job done or you learn
some practical programming stuff like
JavaScript something
practical you know you read the web you
know YouTube you watch you YouTube
you know you get practical tutorials you
know and you make money you you go you
know you work for whatever company
Google whatever you know you make money
and you spend time to watch movies spend
time with your family you know boyfriend
or girlfriend whatever you know that's
what most people do you know you are
concerned about your kind of a small
your own way of being then of course you
have opinions when it comes to for
example you know Sargon of Akkad or its
SPLC this dramatic thing of course then
then you feel strongly oh that's that's
that's a hate group okay you know you
want to you want to wear but you see
someone talk about it you want to
express your view but so what I'm saying
is that and as ask you guys to do it you
know spend you know an hour to look into
you know these things you you will see a
vast majority of the social justice
related things I like you know I'm
pretty sure you will see you will see
your change change your mind if you are
not you know already know about those
things now I think I'm gonna talk about
this actually I'm gonna read comments
but there's so many things I want to say
if I don't say it I forgot so yeah so in
summary SPRC
you know any in summary there are two
things about the enemy may be summarized
two things about this one is that every
day there are some dramatic views
dramatic news you okay
I asked you to go spend half an hour you
know at least on each news you know do
research to see different sites keep
that try to make that a habit you know
like you know half an hour for each news
article that you actually read you know
I don't know how many how many articles
you read the day but you know do that
every time you see a
traumatic news try to do research on
that that's one thing the other thing I
want to the other thing is about the
SPLC
thousand Southern Poverty Law Center
they are I think they are it is my
opinion they are one of the biggest
criminal organization kind of like that
okay with 100 you know they are you know
there they are they account there I'm
you know they they exist today okay not
in the past today you know let's say in
the past let's say in the past five
years they are you know they are they
are tuesd to swindle cheek no cheek
money via donation you know but by the
way Google Apple they are alternating to
SPLC you know they are donating like
millions or something you know the you
know so this and this is also why you
know Google is so you know Facebook
these big corporations they are starting
censorship because they are they you
know this social justice movement they
are kind of all connected they so why
are they did you know why are they
fighting because money you know because
you know I've gave them politely like
the SPLC you know they why censorship
because people like me who says you know
wait a minute you know contrary opinions
that possibly expose them they cannot
allow that because once they are exposed
there's no more money no more donation
to them you know this you know and also
these organizations they are the big
heads of the boss you know executed they
they are you know stinking rich okay
they are like you know stinking with
twitch now about SLP there are so many
incidents concrete incidents in the past
few years if anyone is paying attention
you know not just reading the news oh
you know SPLC reported this this are bad
that is that no you need anyone who
actually have any vague doubt about SPLC
we all know in the past three years
you've because they are so many
incidents big and small incidents happen
that's why did he report it so I you
know do you know if you don't believe
that do spend you know try to spend on
our SPLC I think that's that's that for
that topic now now the other thing is
that you know I'm thinking I'm going to
give you some resources you know because
because I've been you know spending all
this time in the past three years
looking you know casually you know I'm
not even like trying to actually you
know trying to read it does write a book
about this but you know everyday you
know because these social justice
justice things are happening every day
there's you know angry fit stuff so
every time it happens I looked you know
I was you know why is people doing that
oh you know oh oh you know maybe it's so
bad you know this virus I looked who is
Right who is wrong you know you know
whatever they say you know their faces
you look into so I spent the time I you
know looked into the picture I got is
that that that is why I hate the social
justice so much that the the general
picture I got is that today we have this
you know corporations and you know this
supposedly it is nonprofit you know SPRC
is nonprofit that means you know legally
they are not they don't have to pay
taxes you know but they they are not
actually you know nonprofit usually are
like some kind of like organization they
are good doing good things for humanity
you know like they are not their purpose
is not to make money
their purpose is you know you give us
some money as a donation I use the money
as my resource to help you know to do
something that's helpful for the whole
country or nation you know or the world
you know that's what nonprofit is
usually are but today from what I see
okay
oh is any big nonprofit they are almost
very corrupt I mean they are like the
yeah they are not actually nonprofit
they are making huge amount of profit
like we're talking about hundreds of
millions of dollars
it's PLC is merely one of them okay and
and you know so again you know sometimes
you know you might you know you if you
are a normal person you don't read this
news then you you you suddenly you know
you see my video you think oh this guy
is what what is his conspiracy theories
you know that's what this organization
always like to say because because they
want they want to wipe out any you know
any information any let's say fact you
know anything that that we are threat
them from making money if making this
huge amount of money you know they are
so rich so corrupt and powerful to and
so I'm saying and they are connected to
in certain ways okay not not you know in
certain ways they are all connected to
Google and Facebook and New York Times
this big media you know this all these
are very powerful and to Hollywood you
know they are that is why you see this
overall the social justice thing because
and and also you look at you know what
the social justice people are saying you
know what do they want you know you look
at what they want basically the result
is that if you follow what they want oh
oh follow what they say okay the result
hey hey come on in tenure the result is
that they will become more and more
powerful they will have you know like
what one one of the things you know the
SPLC order all these social justice can
people okay what well over the thing
they want is censorship bit why because
they say you know we don't want hate
speech they want censorship that's what
I say okay okay but now for my point of
view like like was what I said with
before okay like if but if you look at
if you think about what what is a result
you know if you
take my point of view why do they want
sense censorship of course they want
censorship because then they wipe out
any report on their possible corruptions
that is what Google Facebook Twitter are
doing you know they they don't want you
to talk about anything related to trans
feminism you know this free speech they
don't want they you know they have
reasons you know they say they don't
want hate speech they want you know so
so what they so this censorship you know
it's just one of their method you know
they take growing this powerful one of
their method to wipe out any opposition
that's what I say
so I would say you know you guys okay
and you know you know since you know
since you guys are watching my video you
know try to try to you know take an hour
to to research yourself you know find
out if I am you know good correct or not
okay that that's that's about that topic
okay so about fake news you know Trump
Trump is kind of the guy who blew the
whole thing up in around you know
election October 2016 you know what what
is my take on Trump you know in the
beginning I don't care about Trump
because why because because of my
personality okay my my whatever if
everything the way I grew up being poor
and all that I do not trust anyone who
is silver spoon you know meaning that
you know who grew up being a rich family
you know they can do it you know they go
to Harvard they look pretty they have
power you know I don't I do not trust
them by default when I see a rich guy or
people handsome guy beautiful guy talks
no.3 hi first of all yeah that's a
[ __ ] okay then
then I judge then from there ugly you
know you know that's not always true
some people you know you cannot help it
if you were born rich just like some
people you know I cannot help it I was
born poor you know you know so you
cannot judge you know oh he's rich
therefore he's bad you know so but you
look at
his behaviors what you know what he say
okay what what the person say usually
you can you know look at what his past
behaviors you know what company what you
know behaviors like when there's an
incident what did he do you know you
look at then then you can make a good
judgment so anyway about Trump you know
I was not too much into politics so I do
know that I hate I hate George Bush very
much and you know before let's say 2000
no you know before but before the past
five years I do not like the
conservative groups the God believing
groups because they are the ones they
want censorship you know today people
forgot maybe young people don't know
because but back then in 1990s up to
2000 you know it is a concerted
conservatives they they don't want they
want to ban gay they want to chair okay
they don't want they want censorship you
know you cannot swear you cannot say
[ __ ] you know the conservative groups
can't believe in groups they want
censorship they want they don't want
pong they want to ban home do you know I
like poem okay so you know it was like
that but but you know since around 2010
or let's say you know 2015 there's a
180-degree turn you know and this is
just amazing it's like and you look at
today's news it's like almost you know
this were all these social justice they
did it seems like you know seems like
the reality is guns you know this is
somehow so anyway so that that is the
thing so why why am i yeah about Trump
so what am I thinking of him what do I
think of him so I don't know much about
him you know so in 2006 I don't like him
because simply because he is you know
rich he is his silver spoon he is rich
because he said it was rich super rich
you know so these people I don't you
know in general
but by default I don't trust them I
don't like them but today I like Trump
I support from fully hundred percent
whatever Trump do I support 100% why
because from what I see I don't care
what Trump is okay I don't care what is
he's you know because from what I see
okay the concerns to me each person have
different concerns from my concern is
that I see this the social justice can
they become extremely evil they pen
people they lie you know like no the
social justice they have many issues
they have you know they have you know
many particular issue let's say abortion
you know you can be proportional anti
okay doesn't matter what's your opinion
you know I don't even have okay okay it
doesn't matter
what I'm saying is that these people are
bad not because they are opinion are
certain things but because they are the
what the things they are doing is just
lying you know
smearing people like maybe today some
you know SPLC or somewhere else you know
they are reports um the this rich
powerful journalist you know they waste
a lot of money they'd report oh there's
a Cossack guy you know he's a outright
helper you know you will see that right
now I'm small so you know nobody knows
you know maybe you don't see that but
maybe you'll see your mum programmer so
you say oh this disc saga he said out
what might help
he's poor nasty you know it's you know
things like that
so anyway so what about Trump yeah so I
don't really know much about him but
today I'm for Trump because because of
the social justice can did this because
I see them as the Evo the extreme evil
you know whatever word you can describe
the utmost evil and and and they are
encompassing you know right to me to me
like the civilization that Western
civilization the USA and the you know
white people
they have been corrupted they have been
degenerated and they are rotting you
know they are rotting you know they are
falling apart so so you know and you
know and you know so yeah that is you
know that is why you know I know a lot
of people you know a program Muslim like
when when it comes to Trump's and you
know anyway so that's that's the thing
so you know to to look to look into
details because I have so many story to
tell you know because I have some so
many now Danielle we had a disagreement
right but not it's just it's not just
because I have other people on Twitter
on the on master then you know and some
of them are actually talked to you know
our video I asked him oh if you you know
let's get on video because some video we
can actually we did hang out you know I
did hang out with the other guy because
he was talking about Taiwan and he was
you know he is kind of Pro Taiwan but
anti-china he's in France okay and so we
talked out you Google hangout and there
are other people you know when it comes
to politics like I so my followers you
know some I've noticed someone suddenly
one day I post something and they are
like jump up you know like you know like
he did you know well you aren't wrong
you know you know they say you know they
want communism communism is a good thing
then you know you start a Twitter post
you know reprise then you have this
incidence with you know democracy that's
another thing you know American
democracy we yeah you know
and the so I I was asking you know this
guy French the French guy so I was
telling him the story you know so I have
a fellow who wants
who wants communism and he says oh no
you know so the thing is about politics
each person has
of their own ideas okay so what is my
solution what is my take on that my take
is that Annie I mean forget about all
the policies not even digging into
details you know every political
hot-button gay marriage abortion
democracy or not you know communism or
not whether it should be crab bellisimo
not you know all these issues it's like
well of course I have opinions on some
of these but but why what I'm saying is
that you know you can like forget about
all these but instead focus on what you
want is you you don't want people to lie
you don't want politicians to lie you
don't want politicians to do bribery you
don't want you know corruption basically
you don't want you know these things
happen just make sure these things these
things are be your bad things you don't
want people to steal you know when these
things are good when nobody is stealing
nobody is lying you know all the rest of
policies I think that we are
automatically for to the right place you
know you don't need to like worry about
what is it like that especially like
things like democracy the word democracy
the word capitalism the word communism
everyone is like all the politicians
every day they have you know opinions oh
we're the socialism is good and you know
that it's almost meaningless like what
exactly you mean it's almost like this
big giant words you know they it's like
meaningless and today society is so
complex the economics you know what do
you think of the trade war with China
you know today's economics the modern
society really is so complex that nobody
can really understand it you know
average people you have no idea really
what's going on you know the for example
one of the incident is you know net
neutrality net neutrality all those
idiotic programmers is like for net
neutrality of
who is not for again is net neutrality
we all want need to be neutral but the
real truth is much more complicated than
that okay so what I'm saying is that
forget about this you know don't worry
about actually these are less important
these big ideas this political hot
buttons this you know weather should be
democracy is better or communism or
socialism or you know of abortion or you
know gay marriage or you know whatever
gay military or you know or the right
right this all right or which bathroom
to use okay those are not the what is
more important to me is that you want
politicians or you know politicians and
whoever empower cooperate boss you know
you want them to not lie whenever
there's a like punish you know that put
them in jail you know a death penalty
whenever there is a corruption bribery
you know when so in my view you focus
more on these kind of things
no stealing you know the real thing that
everyone can agree what is good what is
bad then I think the big topics are
likely to you know fall into place and
people won't be so you know angry and
you know confused by everything so so
many so okay that's about that so so let
me read the comments so so many comments
so do I know Noam Chomsky yeah I kind of
know I he's one of the person I respect
very much I pay attention to his muse I
heard you know of course I heard of him
since like ten years ago but so
gradually you know I pay attention to
him he has got a lot of YouTube videos
you know he talked about you but he's
very old you know it's kind of sad he's
like 80 you know he's you know he cannot
can barely talk like Donald Knuth
also like you know very old me anyway
Noam comes Chomsky
so I kind of agreed to his opinions and
ideas you know he is one of the guy who
is very anti-us far in public policies
to put it in a precise way you know the
typical way people would say he's very
anti u.s. foreign policies the way you
know critical of USA and I believe what
he said is true in general yeah so I
read you know I'm seeing his videos in
the opinions a lot a lot so so many
comments so let me go through the
comments so there's no way to keep
people passive and obedient is to
strictly limit the spectrum of
acceptable the smart the smart way to
keep people passive and obedient is to
strictly limit the spectrum of
acceptable opinion but allowed very
lively debate within that spectrum so
that is from Noam Chomsky I remember
reading that but so I guess that's from
Nam comes come ski so normal says that
describes the US two-party system pretty
accurately you know the two-party system
is a the reason two-party system you
have two major parties in USA that is a
result of the voting system we have
which is called there's a name to that
but basically the voting system is that
you know you have won you know you have
like let's say five candidates each
person have one vote and you know you
vote for one of them and in the end the
person who get the most vote wins
now that is one of the voting system now
there are several different ways for
example you can also have a voting
system where you give a score to each
candidate you know let's say score from
one to ten so maybe you say Hillary
Clinton you you give him you give her a
score of nine
Trump you maybe you give her him a score
of you know eight then another candidate
you know you you you rate each each you
know candidate then in the end you know
whoever candidate has the most score
wins you know so that's another voting
system so you know so you know math
mathematically they are quite a few
voting systems and the two-party system
is a result of our current voting system
you know there's a Wikipedia article
which is fascinating you can read voting
systems they describe several voting
systems but anyway the two-party happens
because when we have the system right
now we have types of voting system you
know your nectarous system so maybe
let's just check this one for now it's
done so so so because because the way
our voting system is right now so when
you have let's say three people ABC you
really like see the most you like see
the most but however you know that most
people will vote a and B so between a
and B you let's say you like be you know
so instead of voting for see if you vote
for C you know your vote is will kind of
be wasted because most people will vote
a and B so so instead of voting for see
you you instead you vote for P you know
what one of the you know two most
popular was in hope in hope that the one
you like them the least we are not you
know get into we are not we so that is
why because of our old voting system we
tend to have you know it's always like
two parties so that's very interesting
because this shows us that you know
mathematics and the voting system they
kind of they create you know the the
voting system they create situations in
society
you know so here is a Wikipedia article
on voting systems you can see there are
quite a few voting systems so the one we
have is first-past-the-post okay that's
a funny name I don't know how that
phrase became but the voting system most
people are familiar with the one we know
that is first passed the world but
anyway for those of you interested in
math there is another very interesting
thing about the voting system is that
there is among all these voting systems
it has been proven mathematically that
that none of them it is it is impossible
to have a voting system that satisfies a
bunch of criterias that normally we
think is desirable and that theorem is
called arrows impossibility theorem so
you might you know read that so it's
it's you know it's very easy it's if you
are into math this is interesting
voting systems normal so Dion says I
think you can even extend it to
so-called fringe political groups which
I suspect actually exists to drive
people away from radical political
orientations okay I'm sorry
I'm kind of late in reading comments so
I forgot what's these context
so so
[Music]
so good morning good morning Danielle
wait when a guy burns a hundred Bo in
front of homeless person just for kicks
okay Deion says Deion says Trump's
philandering and obsession with image
off-putting but if I have to suffer
through many more prompt jokes where the
tapestry of germs come up I'm going to
spontaneously combust
now philandering now that is another
topic I have a lot to say this issue
about sex and and you know basically
it's about sex you know but let's skip
that because I said I'm not ready to
talk about that so all right it's just
yeah you know Trump he's got this
character you know he's certainly a very
dramatic entertaining guy in inter
containing is the word you know and he
you see Trump is interesting okay
because he you know if if the social
justice thing did not happen then I
would probably make fun of Trump every
day because because you know typically I
always criticize people you know that's
kind of my thing you know observe what
they do and and often and of the you
know there are a lot of people I like
but usually you know I talk about them
this I respect you know there are many
programmers I respect I talked about
this in one of my video before you know
I give a list of people you know I
respect this programmer so computer
scientists or you know or even
politicians they are I think they are
well in politicians they have very few I
would say I respect because the most
politicians are just you know lying and
head for themselves but you know there
are many philosophers are like so but I
tend to focus you know on the you know I
criticized the people so if there's no
just social justice thing then I would
probably probably criticize from you
know Trump Trump is this so I so he is
silver spoon you know who he grew up
rich you know but it turns out you know
if I'm going to come and um Trump you
know I'd it turns out it seems like he's
very capable person he is really not
just not just a capable he's one of the
like very talented extremely capable for
set for so for some reason he being
which did not spoil your him now this
this is I would say is almost like the
opposite the opposite of George W Bush
jr. okay you know the George Bush jr. is
also silver spoon but I don't think he's
I don't think he's very capable he's
very corrupt and but Trump is he seems
so you know because he got elected and
he's not the politician he's a you know
smooth talker he's a businessman he he
he is capable of you know you know
salesman you know making millions
billions business and he so he's not
politician but he got in you know outer
border you know surprise you know he got
in and so far it looks like you know
despite you know many people may not
agree but from what I see so far I see
he's doing very well not just pretty
well is he's doing very well
you know and the economy's improved the
unemployment decrease you know so he
seems to be doing very well you know as
a president you know but one thing about
him is like he okay I like him actually
I like him about this he
he's using the social medias tactics to
you know to wing social media you know
it's a social media like Twitter for
example let me talk about Twitter you
know one of these things social media do
they want to make money that's all they
are concerned only concerned of social
media you know Twitter Facebook is to
make money they don't care about nothing
else they don't care about like
spreading information spreading news
help countries help freedom of speech or
democracy that's pure [ __ ] they just
want to make money one of the primary
reason you can see that is you know have
you ever tried to check your history of
your treat you will see that it's almost
impossible it's like you cannot score
back enough then the system gets hostile
and also you know a few years ago they
introduced a feature where you can
download you know your archive you know
I'll say as a measure of you know they
are open oh you can download your
archive that's let's [ __ ] that's a lie
okay what do you want I want to be able
anyone want to be able to see your past
trees easily like Search Search my own
treat only and find it you cannot do
that why is that you know it you know
because because that if you provide that
that doesn't make them money that that
decreases you know they are making money
so instead what you know every design
about Twitter is to squeeze my money to
increase their traffic as much as
possible and one of the most important
thing is that they want to they want you
every user to keep posting so every
decision made they make every design
button color is clear is designed every
decision you know it's designed so that
users will keep posting like keep
posting that's one of the things they do
so that's let's see you know and also
they make it so they all these
corporations they make it so that you
don't realize it you forgotten you don't
remember you know you forgot like know
you go to trader nobody is complaining
you know you cannot search history but
actually a lot of people are complaining
oh you know really almost everyone we
are complaining about that but Twitter
you know they have algorithms they
control which shows up which you know
they they remove everything that's not
good for them you know that's what they
do so they and they force people to be
you know treat every day so you know
once I treat something today after today
you know after month it's like forgotten
then I need to say this again like I'm
talking about how Twitter is you know
you know they want to force people to
keep posting but next month I want to
post that again you know you you have to
like every opinion you have to keep you
know they want you to keep posting so it
degenerates the society that you know it
also that's part of the reason for the
rise of social justice as well because
you know you get angry on Twitter you
and they limit your character count why
because that way you will post more you
know instead of an article you know you
will post more and because short
messages are less capable of
communication especially our angry stuff
so you so so you tends to you know argue
you know with you know angry you know
emotional argue argue so more more drama
so they so there is more traffic and
they you know and then they can tell
their advertisers
Kaiser's look we have so many people you
know so many people are talking about
come conversing about the word affairs
you know that's treated scum and why
does nobody like almost nobody mentioned
these because twitter has like they
create the system so that this kind of
information they don't spread you know
the Jesus it's like every it's like
every path you try to go they they they
they are stopped by them you know
extremely evil you know it's can you
know this along with social justice you
know treat our social justice Southern
Poverty Law Center and you know Facebook
you know they are owning it together
money it is money you know money they
profit you know they that's that is why
so you know so you might think you know
well you are rational people I'm a
rational people we rational people maybe
can you know you know they we can treat
things and logical no but because they
create the infrastructure so anything
you want to try to do it's very
difficult you know ok so see if I'm okay
I'm still here and for people watching
ok so it's kind of one hour kind of rant
so anyway so let's keep reading a
comments
Trump's surrounding ok Oh drat is just a
swear word yeah so Trump is this you
know
yeah Trump so he he's you know see he
sees the social media flaws and he is
using it to his advantage so he everyday
is creating this dramatic treat they are
really funny you know sometimes they are
truly funny like like he posts about you
know North Korea
you know leader you know I got a nuclear
bomb oh I got a bigger bomb than you
then you know so he see the journalism
flaws you know then every cooperation
New York Times this journalist you know
corporations publishing they want money
they want clickbait they create
clickbait every day so Trump says that
everyone is like immediately try to talk
about Trump you know so you can so you
will click and visit their site then
their ads they make money this
CNN Fox well almost all of them CNN
Firefox you know MSNBC you know there's
a okay let me give you a list of the
fake news the top fake News
Corporation's New York Times okay
vice MSNBC The Verge Gizmodo Washington
Post Huffington Post AJ AJ plus our
cheer as something AJ plus the
motherboard of the motherboard of Vice
the motherboard and that's a name
well these these are the big fake news
corporations they churn they churn out
fake information every day you know like
on Twitter they churn up every two hours
it's like you follow them your your
stream is spanned by them New York Times
you know this any of these corporations
is you know spent so this these are a
big fake news corporations I know you
know old all these are left lefty okay
extreme kind of extreme left they also
the right but you know because these
days the vast majority of social media
and the social justice scanned is like
taking control of the media okay the the
you know you have Trump as as president
but the other media entertainment you
know industry Google Facebook you know
they are all organist the Conservatives
you know and they are you know they are
controlling or this information so they
are also you know some news oak that's
biased on the right you know to the
right I'm not going to mention it
well actually I I should but you usually
this you know Narottam you you already
know which one you know what they say it
all the time
so this so I think Trump's okay so write
the reaction to Trump has been no miss a
political cat people lose IQ points when
they get too close to a cat he has the
same effect this is why he was able to
draw the media yeah right into launching
his campaign into the stratosphere
gratis yeah Daniel says all right the
term is here defined I agree but I can
perceive a loosely connected far-right
why nationally okay that's a good not
don't mention that word may be
perceptive but also your defined our ad
this that I mean largely online movement
okay guys well you know those words
squads it's kind of [ __ ] you know I
think it's it's really hard to talk
about this topic with you know all these
words coming up you know I don't really
want to delete this video
Daniel you are like I think you are
outdated fortune is nothing fortune is
long corrupt fortune watch and
god
[Music]
okay so that's it that's it okay guess
so that's what our talk you know sighs
so so there's so many topics and you
know when you talk about topic it's like
non-stop and I wanted to talk about
there are some other issues about
because I was thinking I'm gonna do some
soms talk odeon you going to okay yeah
these one hour it's like talking to DOM
every time so anyway I was you know
going to think I'm talking about Emacs
yeah a lot of things actually I can talk
about every day but you know so I was
thinking maybe I'll do more than one
video a day but then I'm thinking no
don't do that because then you'll just
be you know I you know it's like yeah
political topics always takes over
everything else yeah I want to mention
some people you know I got I haven't I'm
kind of you know I should have I haven't
been what I haven't been doing being or
doing what I really should do like I
have emails I kind of almost stopped
checking if like four months ago so some
people have written to me thank you
yeah I'm going to I hope to try to
answer some of the emails and stuff
anyway okay so that's it for today well
that that is the topic today then okay
Thank You Diann for coming by and Daniel
Daniel is already left and Norman thank
you guys so until knit next time bye