good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today's 2020 May 11th monday right
now it's two o'clock in the afternoon
San Francisco time
cheapy time and we gonna do so we are
going to do a bunch of things I have the
topics listed here and if you have
questions type it in a YouTube chat with
my name then we gonna do it okay so
let's begin so Allen actually asked me
some questions
Ellen are you here Allen livestream why
am I not hearing more about genly's so
jaqen has a question why why is he not
hearing more about shandi's I have seen
a cup of times and looks fantastic
okay that's one of the question from
jaqen and another question from Allen is
uh you know do online shopping in real
time comment on UI design of sites you
navigate through teachers about consumer
manipulation tactics in marketing okay I
can do that but you know but I got some
other topics out the real Meuse key good
morning
Allen good morning so you see I have now
my input systems I have a bunch of input
systems from pin simplified in doing and
drooling in pain traditional enchancia
and varrock and us and here Khanna I'm
getting multi multi cultural okay
online shopping yeah I'm not I'm not
going to do online shopping you know
online shopping you know well I'm
thinking of actually buying you know I
need to buy you know I need I have a
need to buy
help the economy oh look at this one
feet lovely I want I wanna buy this one
I want buy her that is advertised Minh
that is effective Adam Heisman okay so
that's the you know that's a
demonstration that's exhaust explanation
what is effective advertisement girls
naked you know half-naked girls that's
effective advertisement and in general
you want pleasing things you know like
like this one using coke cozy cozy and
casual loungewear and showing you no
skin showing feet oops I clicked by
mistake oh this one what is this one the
last Panther what is this the last
Panther slaughter of the Reich oh [ __ ]
coogo is going to buy me
it's the slaughter of the where did that
happen over here okay oh Jesus okay well
I'm not going to do online shopping but
look at this now I cannot stop it though
you know now you see this and it makes
me angry
this is brainless modern idiots you see
that you see Ireland so you see this
this you know you know this freezing
present present and present that's the
thing [ __ ]
it's very noisy here they are starting
to build stuff here outside they are
start to build things you know the bad
death seems to be over so how are you
guys doing let's see let's check my
status
Cosi bloat okay arrow you are not
receiving on a video shut the [ __ ] up
floats blowed blood and cosy and bloat
in cozy and bloat
stop playing there okay SART ISM
scientism you know drop the T you know
that likes autism that doesn't you know
that's that's an ISO so you should have
it should be exact ISM you know it's
just my name and I ISM not not with an
extraneous key so Jake and says how
could you use some of those casual
Styles oh yeah I could I could use some
of these casual Styles this [ __ ] this
[ __ ] plebeian commonplace and [ __ ]
you know this this angers me these you
know these freezing things this brain is
that that's that's commercially the next
consumer reason that you know it eats
your brain that's what they are
you know it's Americans you know as in
particular Americans since you were born
you consume this this you are reading
this and American soup you know the
concepts of American things you are
brainwash the moment you were born
that is why well that that's true you
know cultural differences that's true
for every country you know in the moment
you are born in China you were taught
certain ways and similarly in Japan and
other places but you know we were
talking about you know in America in
particular it has this consumer reason
in modern of you know [ __ ] and today it
has become it turned into the social
justice fact very sinister and you know
you don't know what will happen in the
future we don't know
anyway we digressed a lot actually I
wanted to do some some coding and some
other things quite a lot of things to do
okay
so actually you know there's so what I
want to buy you know I want to you know
I have you know this is a problem when
you have a tablet you know these days a
lot of people have tablet right I'm
going to show you my keyboard block you
know a tablet then a tablet only has one
USB port so every time you need to type
or you need to use the mouse
you only have one USB port so that's a
problem what you're gonna do
you know you can do you know they say a
wireless let me show you okay my they
say are wireless keyboards and wireless
mouse but usually they come oftentimes
they come with a tongue go so that
doesn't work because once you plug in a
Dongo then you cannot plug in your
keyboard and every time you have to plug
in like when you let me show you my okay
so yeah let me go pick it up okay so let
me show you
so you see this is this is the micro saw
so soft tablet there's only one USB port
so why you know because I sit all the
time so I have to every hour or so and I
now walk stand up and walk around and
just go read you know read on this thing
and when I read this you know the the
touch pad the touch screen UI is the
worst [ __ ] okay it's very slow and it
it's prone to errors you type a lot
errors super slow and your finger has
this your finger get tired of you know
rubbing with on the grass and also you
get tired of with with this shape you
know you have to put your finger into
this particular shape you know it gets
tired it's super slow and and also the
Microsoft you know the they are idiocy
you know they are keyboard they are
touchscreen keyboard doesn't matter what
preferences you said you can never be
the in the right position or right size
you cannot even adjust the right size
you know the idiocy of the Microsoft
user interface designers it's actually
it's not because Microsoft they don't
know how to design its rather because
you know like you wonder why after 20
years Microsoft UI is still like
blatantly suck in many cases why is that
I mean is it because they don't have
talents I mean no nobody at Microsoft
know how to design that's not true
Microsoft they pay you know big money to
designers to great programmers so they
have people they know what to do but
then why is that Microsoft you know many
aspect of the u.s. sucks
after 20 years still sucks it's because
I realized you know once your
cooperation your company becomes big it
you cannot you know doesn't you know you
cannot just make it good just like
Google today
once you your cooperation your company
comes very big you know the it kind of
doesn't work it doesn't work so you know
you cannot have good UI you know that
they are great talents at Microsoft
you know UI designers you know they know
what they are doing but there's just no
way for your idea to go into the product
that's that's what I what happens so
that is my that is my experience and
conclusion you know one you know I guess
you can say one of my insights when you
are you know you are watching Microsoft
Hawks show that's one of my insights why
is that you know that answers the
question why is that Microsoft or some
of these big corporations it seems like
you know 20 years like sometimes you see
something that's obviously wrong but
it's just there you Microsoft you know
in in the OS and also then you know
don't talk about Linux okay Linux is a
[ __ ] the worst [ __ ] 10 times worse
they Microsoft you you know many of you
guys Linux phonetics know know what you
are thinking you don't know what you're
talking about
no I had no idea this Linux phonetics
okay so Microsoft Surface you know I I
sit around I have to walk around so he
only has got you one USB you know so so
when I walk around round you know I
don't you know I can I use a physical
keyboard you know I'm stuck with this
finger in fact you know this this
fingering [ __ ] but then but then
sometimes I sit down right I take it you
know then I sit down then I plug in a
keyboard that that's a pen you see I
have to plug it in then why I need to go
there I have to unplug it you know
disappear then once you plug in a
keyboard
I'm tired using my fingers I want the
mouse but there's no hole for the mouse
no more so you have to that's a problem
so so the problem is that so how do you
solve this problem you guys you know how
to use so I guess the solution is
bluetooth
blue choose what Bluetooth keyboard okay
so that's what you need you need a
Bluetooth keyboard and bluetooth mouse
not just wireless well this is not good
enough you need bluetooth so you need
that and you need a mechanical one like
this one okay and so actually I'm
thinking of buying let me tell you what
I want I want this is my review of the
Microsoft Surface pro okay I happen to
have it because how long have I been
talking 30 minutes not too long okay I'm
not getting boring so let me show you
the the mouse or keyboard I want so I
want you know I mean you know I want one
I want you know I demand
I want a mouse so like right now I have
two choices either get this one okay
this one Logitech g600 you know create
many buttons and this is bluetooth so
either get that one oh let me show you
the other one I possibility you saw I've
been looking at them for long but you
know oh this one okay so I have I can
there's people buying my Emacs tutorial
and some donations so I have Amazon
gifts cards gift cards now so I can buy
them
so either this one actually I think I'm
getting this one you know this trackball
because right now I don't have a travel
other than very old one like 15 years
old ones so maybe this one or this one
both of them supports bluetooth and the
mouse is better because it's got you
know
programmable buttons it's it's really
better but one thing I'm worried about
this Logitech g600 4 is that they have
the G hub there are new G hub gaming
software which is which sucks donkey ass
ok Alex
that sucks donkey ass so I wonder if I'm
stuck with that so anyway these two I'm
not sure they are about the same price
like $70 or something so am i doing okay
so what is the next question
Reaper says mone Ripper Ripper says why
not use a very very slim USB hub switch
such travel USB hub I Amazon Reaper has
a opinion on everything expressed in the
most expert style with certainty and
assurance survivor says why not why
don't you use a very thin USB hub switch
such such and the ripper tells you how
to find it search travel USB hub on
Amazon they are very small I have one
and it works great forgive me if you
already said what you won't work ok has
expert opinions so let's follow the
expert opinions travel USB hub
so let's the so allons allons omen
prediction comes true
let's do shopping on Amazon so repossess
travel USB oops let's see what we find
Travel USB hubs oh and that's no good
it's not good you plug it this it's a
tango you know you plug this in and like
your you know your dick hands out like a
kick and swing and you swing the wrong
way it breaks your you know you pray
breaks your port no good you know you
you have to go with bluetooth you know I
never liked wireless especially I don't
like Bluetooth because I always worried
about you know ink hacking once you go
wireless
for miles it's kind of okay for before
but for keyboard or your password you
know you go wireless it's you are you
are vulnerable and you know of course
bluetooth the protocol has encryptions
this or that with whatever you know
cryptography jargons but the thing is
usually they you never know because you
know the hack is like a cat-and-mouse
game cops and robbers Kim you know or
take kickers or the spy versus spy or
the tech kickers versus the spammers you
know each one thinks they are doing
better you know the technology whoa
so so what am I saying yeah so so the
Bluetooth you know you are vulnerable to
it but this like but if you really want
a wireless with this one USB port I
guess you it's a choice between
convenience you know whether you want it
or not
so that's that's what I'm thinking so
let's go back and that's answer so let
me answer one more question
between that and fugging or herb well
but the point well my point is you know
so I have this I need to you know take
it and walk about to and fro you see
usually in my room I don't have space no
this is my mom's room okay my mom passed
away but so let me demonstrate the main
strength demonstrate the walk back and
forth now you I don't need to
demonstrate you know you just walking
back and forth in carry these so you
need so you don't want to plug in and
pull out and all the time so that's the
thing so let's go through the next topic
okay how do you did you okay if you have
a question for me putting on my name to
it so it looks orange okay did you
develop some weight of coping with
stress through your life how do you cope
with stress how do you explain that how
do you cope with stress well you first
of all of course you reduce the source
of stress but if you cannot do that what
how do you say
you could do minute meditation and relax
or you could try to think about it in a
logical way like calm down and then well
that's that's how I would solve it that
is you know I'm a logical very logically
obsessed person so I saw problems by
logic most of the time kind of you know
so actually I want to talk about some of
the things we have quite a few things
good morning Matt five-match hey Chad
okay hi guys so so if you have a
question for me put my name to it okay
so fasten f says I noticed you have V s
code do you prefer it over Emacs or
something no I BS code I think it's
great but I never actually started to
learn it you know it's in the plan you
you know it's in the plan I don't know
when or if I'm going to get to it but I
think it's you know Emacs is kind of
dying is video so anyway so I actually I
have quite a lot of things to to to do
let's let's start with that okay so
actually close that so so let me show
you some articles pearl how fast is
running pearl in sick wing or using NTFS
on Linux so if you are running pearl mi
come out clear am I come out clear to
you guys
let's see I've been talking 20 minutes
hello hi Freddie hi Antonin so we have a
lot to say let's see what I want to say
okay that depends on what you guys want
Hey so reaper says use enlightenment in
use enlightenment era rationalism to
think his way out of stressful
situations
yeah well stress you know when you have
stress okay so I'm trying to think how
to how to how to answer the question
about stress because that's a common
problem in people are interested you
know so when you basically when you have
stress typically you want to find the
source of the stress so in other words
you want to avoid stress you know get
rid of stress therefore you don't have
stress that's that's the thing but
however that of course that doesn't
answer the question once you are if you
don't have I mean the question really is
if you really have stress I mean
unavoidable what can you do so anyway so
I would find you know the source of
stress what what what is causing you I
mean what's the source of stress and try
to avoid it or rid of it or change your
lifestyle that's what they say change
your lifestyle so you don't encounter
that stress for example you go to a job
there's a meeting there's a deadline
deadlines you know you have to finish
this coding project by this day okay
stress then you have headaches landing
then you know you have problems you can
now sleep okay so so you need to get rid
of the stress so what you do is just you
know go
I have a meeting with your boss okay and
tell them tell him I quit go [ __ ]
yourself you quit then you know then you
get rid of that stress then you lead a
nomadic life or homeless life like me
and then you don't have stress anymore
that's healthy for you you know that so
you want to get rid of stress but once
you have stress so what can you do well
you can like try to calm down it depends
also depends on the personality you know
depend on what kind of person you are
how you and also you know some people
they have a lot of friends you know some
people are social people social they are
you know they a lot you know in fact a
lot of people they are very social and
they because they have family you know
you have some people have like family
members they take care of each other
they can talk to each other where you
know on the other hand I don't have that
and and usually then you know that's not
my personality so you resolve stress by
coming down and logically thinking about
it things like that imagine stuff like
he's on vs code indeed you know if you
wanted pay me pay me let's say $300 our
coded I'll create a cough like he's on
vs code you know people being asking
that but it takes time to code it I
would be interested but you know I have
to code it then then the open source
problem you know everyone is bugging you
all the time no pay or maybe you get a
cup of coffee a month but you spend one
hour or hours every day on it so anyway
so let's talk about some other things I
want to say what do I want to say
so I've been talking for 26 minutes okay
let's go over some of these topics okay
some of these which is programming
related technical I've been doing in the
past few days I've been doing a lot in
the past two or three days you know a
lot on my website the endless endless
you know coding and you know stuff so
anyway this is a very old article this
is written in 2013 2013 so the question
is if you are running Perl for example
on Windows you know you can install Perl
you can install pearl virus sequence
cygwin is kind of the UNIX emulator so
you can you know once you install sequin
on Windows you have the entire UNIX or
Linux system on your Windows machine you
can install any Linux or UNIX software
to run on your Windows machine so that's
one of the H that's one of the classic
solution
cygwin okay I have installed it you know
so many times so sequence once is so so
if you are running Perl in sequence on
Windows or you can install a native Perl
you know someone that has supported
pearl to Windows so the question is how
fast you know what's the speed
difference that's one example
native Perl on Windows versus pearline
cygwin on Windows what's the speed
difference that's one question the other
question is for example if you are
running Linux you know suppose you have
a dual boot Linux and windows because
you need to play games the Linux also in
combat incompetent [ __ ] [ __ ] Linux in
every ass every way they cannot do
anything except you know Python Perl
coding compile C that's that's you know
run server sets that's what it's good
anything else audio/video it's crap the
user interface is crap the thinking that
everything is crap you know the
keyboarding remapping Kiki
keys to me Makos it's crap Linux is crap
crapping every way except you know the
tech kickers coding yeah if you called
compile that's what you do yeah Linux so
if you have a machine that's do a boot
because you want me learn Windows and
then you also want to run Linux do a
boot so once you have that sometimes
when you are in Linux you want to access
the windows
you know files on Windows you cannot do
it well you can so you can do that you
know so the Linux we all need to run we
all need to read the windows file system
the window is using the NTFS filesystem
NT F stand for by the way NTFS stand for
new technology filesystem NTFS came from
Windows NT Windows NT the the NT stand
for new technology and by the by the way
Windows NT is certified UNIX PASOK's
okay the UNIX standard PASOK's Windows
NT now if you guys are Millennials you
may not know because you are not too old
like me so you know once you get old you
so anyway so that so you may not know so
let me explain okay Windows lidly the
history of Windows Microsoft Windows so
you have Windows 1 windows through then
Windows three windows 3 in 1993
something like that then Windows 95 in
1995 right then then ok they kind of all
suck then you have then you have Windows
NT ok NT Windows NT NT stand for new
technology so this came out about 1997
or something so Windows NT is completely
different you know with Windows 3
Windows 95 they are completely different
they are rewritten from the ground up
a new operating system Windows NT okay
so Windows NT but back then it requires
lots of memory so kind of but it's very
stable it doesn't crash okay
it rarely crashes so in the 1990s the
Mac OS is crashing every day look the
[ __ ] crashing every day multiple
times not once not twice more more than
one times every day every [ __ ] day
from about 1995 to 1999 the Mac OS
although it's great but is fashioned by
anyway so Windows NT is a completely new
organ system the NT stand for new
technology then then it I think starting
with Windows Vista or Windows 7 I forgot
they started to switch to the Windows NT
branch so they are basically based on
Windows NT so NT so aunt is you know new
technology and Windows NT by the way is
the certified POSIX compliant you know
it's actually or UNIX
mean why our Linux is not Linux of fact
the Linux people in fact the Linux
phonetics know by the way Linux is not
Unix
what do you mean by Unix they don't know
they have no idea what they mean you
know Linux phonetics what they mean by
Linux or UNIX
what they mean is that what they like is
Linux what they don't like is not Linux
you know for example if I give lots of
example where your Linux sucks they all
say oh that's not Linux Linux is
actually the kernel my friend Linux
kernel you don't understand did that you
know thar - that's not Linux yeah they
suck I'd agree x11 those those are not
Linux Linux is a kernel you know that
these [ __ ] Linux [ __ ] meanwhile
this Linux UNIX fans knew you say when
it comes to Mac you know Mac you know
they say oh ok my God look Linux is so
powerful to such a degree even the Mac
what they wanted to use new nuts
[ __ ] innards [ __ ]
so we digressed a lot and what what what
is the what are we talking about what am
I talking about
I don't know I don't know and you don't
know well I have to know because Knights
I've been talking for 30 minutes so yeah
so this article I was talking about this
article and we digressed into the
Windows NT so this article we're talking
about yeah so it's you know comparison
of speed comparison so basically if you
use if you are on linux and and if you
are on linux and you are if you are
using the microsoft accessing the
Microsoft NTFS filesystem you it gonna
cost you a lot of time you know like 50
more time for example if you have a
script perl script that access you know
process or file single directory so
let's say you have you know 1,000 files
you have a perl script you need to visit
each file let's say do you find replace
or something so if those files if you
are on linux and if those files are on
the windows system so you use you know
you know that's gonna be it's gonna be
300 seconds on the other hand if those
files are on the wind linux native file
system the ext4 for example it's only 6
seconds so that's a difference of 50
times so that's a filesystem difference
you know it's very slow if you try to
read the windows file system on the
other hand on Windows if you use a
native perl then it's like 555 seconds
meanwhile if you use a
cygwin pearl it's 555 seconds it's a
difference between 35 seconds versus 55
seconds that's the difference of native
pearl was a sequin pearl okay so about
twice me there's another example about
using the windows file path convention
versus a UNIX file path convention you
know UNIX is / windows this backslash
you know they don't agree
anyways that's about this page okay so
what's the next topic let's go to the
next topic let's see are you guys happy
are you guys happy I'm kind of getting
nowhere and tired did you take a look at
the poor OS is used on the disk owed can
you post the link I don't know I didn't
poke ya so mad okay so so mad he wanted
this this is a strange request okay so
on this code if you haven't already
joined this code ok just such mock sorry
discord the you are the invitation link
is on my website so join this code lots
of people interesting ideas we chat we
talk here so matt has the idea Matt Matt
from Germany he wanted to do a poor you
know he wanted to do a poor like who is
using which operating system Linux you
know what distro you know Linux BSD
FreeBSD OpenBSD dragon bsd what's the
net bsd okay Oh Mac OS or Windows you
know he want to do a poll so that you
know to see who is using what
okay now I was sneaking why I mean
what's it's like what's the point what's
the point of doing that you know because
on this court you know the score doesn't
support porting Peter does you know
other side Twitter does you get on
Twitter you can do that but anyway Matt
wants to do that so and I'm thinking
that what's the point because so disco
doesn't support that if discussable that
we can have that but anyway the problem
the thing is that once you do the paw is
gonna scroll off like within one week
it's ephemeral it is like have no use
whatsoever no use whatsoever
I mean what's you what like what why do
you want need a pour about you know who
use what and also we don't have like
thousands members here we only have like
a few hundred you know or the active
members of our discord is like you know
let's say 50
what are you doing powerful I mean you
already know who is using VST who is a
big fan of BSD in our forum that is
Emily Emily and L cook and the crash
hacker who is who is not into FreeBSD
but into the open BSD yeah so we only
have like four or five people into BSD
and Alan Alan is the newcomer to join
the DSD and you know so why do you want
the poll about who is using what
operating system it doesn't make sense
to me so you got a link so I don't know
I don't remember where is the link we
have to find it on this code okay so you
know people are asking me to mention it
in a stream live stream so okay I'm
mentioning it but I don't know where is
the poor and BSD
what do I search I don't want to search
it [ __ ] you know so there's a poor like
you have to go to another website that
does pose you know I don't I don't see I
don't understand what's the purpose
what's the purpose what's the
significance of doing who is using what
always poor I mean on the other hand if
you want to really know what's a
distribution I mean there are tons of
website they tell they tell you the
market share you know actual like
percentage so I don't get you're like
Matt what is the point about doing a
poor on this scored about who is using
what operating system guru Linux okay
guru yeah Richard Stallman immediate as
usual there's no you don't know what I'm
talking about
shamak we have a shamak Tabak he says if
you love windows so much why don't you
why are you using Mac you [ __ ]
you've a kid okay fasting says I used
Mac OS until Apple changed their
keyboard to have super low key travel so
I switched to think pad Linux yeah yeah
that's you know that's a good point
because Mac you know the Mac keyboard
sucks this code is for [ __ ] like
sorry haha shamak you are about to be
bad get banned you and tone antonin says
oh man he's gonna really disappoint me
he is always four so look more hammer
TV so Reaper say snow Ranger not ok ok
so we got a troll we got a saw hater so
what's the next topic let's see CPU
benchmark okay here's another old thing
so I you know so there is I wrote this
in 2002 so it here is a Perl script you
can copy and you can can run on your
system let me show you ok I'm gonna run
it so you can find the code on Sardi
programming block ok just go to my
website you'll find this page so let's
go to saudi programming block and let's
showed my keystrokes ok not a breathing
ok magnify and we want to go to Pearl
okay so here is the here is the link
okay so open it and show in browser you
can see we are back to that page now
back on the right window you can see all
my Emacs commands ok here so wait what's
going on here ok so we want to so this
here is a Perl code ok so I press a
button look at the right window the pink
window so I press a button the Perl code
gets extracted into a buffer by itself
right here so wait magnify it wait
what's going on with the Perl factor
[ __ ] Perl mod because it changed my keys
oh no with wait maybe I did something
wrong
okay so here's a Perl code okay I'm
gonna run it I have my own command so I
can just press two keys and the UN's
sovereign current file that's paste of
you J normally it's four seconds now
it's 11 seconds you see the answer here
it's 11 because you know my CPUs are all
maxed out because I'm doing a video
that's why so normally it's just 4
seconds so anyway here that's a code you
can copy it you can run on your machine
so let's delete it and do let's show you
in browser so back to the browser page
so you can see this is a kind of just a
CD script trying to see how long does
your computer run this script you know
so gives you some sense of how fast is
your computer so I think this one is
just doing integer arithmetics basically
and using only one CPU so you can see
the results back in since 2002 so here
you have dual paned Pentium Pro 2000
this is year 2004 ok and that takes 249
seconds let me show you some interesting
visa so for example this one blue and
white Power Mac g4 hundred megahertz
PowerPC 750 now this is that's nineteen
eight 1998 I think g3 1985 machine I
think so anyway
let me show you some interesting results
okay here we have you know I try to run
this on the server in our in our
development machine for example you have
these this 100 let me magnify okay let
me magnify you so you can see so this
106 seconds this is some plate 100 at
500 0 2 megahertz
this is ultrasparc 2 e so this is some
micro systems they are hardware those
systems are very expensive so it cost
$1000 new in 2002 but anyway this is
nothing I got a server so this one for
example this one is son ultra 5 2001
back then the Machine cost $2000 okay
let me show you some other interesting
example
so this one this one 78 seconds this is
Sun Enterprise Sun Enterprise 220 R so
this is this machine is a server rack
cost to cost it cost five hundred no it
cost five thousand dollars
no no no way it cost twenty thousand
dollars this one this Rack Sun
Enterprise 220 are its twenty thousand
dollars in year 2000 okay
but after the.com crash in year 2002 it
becomes five thousand dollars on eBay
yes 20,000 20,000 dollars become five
thousand dollars and it's you know for
doing these tests is not very fast it's
only 78 seconds so this is you know
twenty thousand dollar machine back then
then we have let me show you some other
interesting this one 56 seconds this is
HP 9000 series model a 500 okay so this
machine came out in year 2000 and it
cost you also 20 over 20 thousand
dollars but but after you know after two
years dot-com crash you know it becomes
two thousand dollars on eBay
so this HP 9000 series it's a server
rack you know I remember it's like this
big okay this I think this this big it's
a rack but this stick
yeah so that's HP server
you know I poured it our pearl programs
to the hp-ux long time ago so it's now
this is 20 years ago so that's some of
the interesting you know machines back
then so this is 20 years ago so you can
see and today so for example another
interesting result from Emily how Emily
here let me show you shall she be on her
own PC and her pc her cpu is this one
[ __ ] wait go back
okay so this ma mt basin thread Ripper 3
9 9 0 X so this one is called 64 cores
128 threat so 64 cores each coherence to
thread so you have 128 threads so this
this CPU cost thirty nine hundred
dollars you know two thousand and nine
hundred dollars that's Emily Emily's
rich so on this machine it runs without
three seconds to run this test and on my
machine I have a Mac Mini Mac Mini 2004
fourteen model so it's six years old
it runs four seconds or three sometimes
it comes out three if I quit all the
browsers in everything it also three
seconds so that so you can see to
compute this thing
you know the number of CPU or core
doesn't matter because it's single
thread also floating points or vector
arithmetic soar
you know vector matrices those parallel
parallel technologies doesn't matter you
know so anyway so that's about that one
so so what what else let me go back to
the good morning Bart
so reaper says have you run your power
tests using wsar windows subsystem for
linux no I haven't done so we are faster
CPU help me utilize monads more V
effectivity yes you know so Moniz you
know monad is Haskell Hesco is also a
single thread ok Haskell does not have
particular technology for parallel
computation
ESCO does not have ok Haskell
even though you know it's a function of
pure function of foreign language it's
you know monads especially monad it's
very see you know see sequential the
hands computation is sequential just
like JavaScript just like JavaScript
sequential computation no parallelism so
so just like this program so you
multiple CPUs doesn't help so what's up
what's the question so yeah so if you
want this to be faster you need to have
a faster CPU so meaning that the speed
the megahertz or gigahertz the clock
rate the faster it is the better but
however since 10 years ago we can no
longer produce faster chips
you know we we we kind of already
reached the limitation of this you know
the physical limits of downsizing chips
and making it faster we cannot make it
faster so three gigahertz chips
you know chips running at 3 gigahertz is
available 10 years ago since 2009 you
know we have you know for example
Pentium you know this for example this
AMD Athlon to running at 3 gigahertz and
this is back in 2011 and by the way this
is a cheap cheap PC you I bought at
Walmart you know you go to Walmart you
know you buy a PC you know the cheapest
one $500 back then back in 2011 you know
you buy it and that's the cheapest AMD
Athlon 2x4 barabra processor 3 gigawatts
you know the so so 10 years ago we have
three chica Hertz crock rate and no more
you know we cannot do it faster so so
that is why let me okay
let me segue or whatever you call it
didn't digress so that is why since
about 10 years ago people are started
started to be oh god I got
kovat knighting I'm about to die cough
so you know since since 10 years ago
because CPU can no longer run faster so
we started have do a call you know a
multiple course so and programmers are
started to be concerned about
parallelization you know this is very
interesting because you know you write a
program you know we are programmers
right most of us you know we ready
forget to read but when a CPU becomes
parallel it doesn't you know it does not
automatically make your program run
faster not at all in fact if you want to
you know if you want your code to run
faster you have actually to rewrite it
basically okay almost always you have to
rewrite your program so that they can
utilize you know the newer CPUs features
of parallelization or thread or whatever
so that means you know the CPU you know
it used to be it becomes faster and
faster and faster so all your programs
you you know you don't have to do
anything they just become faster but now
the CPU don't become they stop being
faster anymore instead they have you
know parallel more threads and most CPUs
but your program doesn't become faster
it's stuck unless you have to rewrite it
so you know imagine basically
essentially every program has to be
rewriting you know this is very
interesting you know when it comes to
programming you know a lot of the
programmer idiots you know they are
refused for example Emacs you know or
something every time you sub on Linux
you know you suggest you suggest some
improvements and they will say they we
often say oh we don't want to do that we
want backward compatibility because
otherwise we have to rewrite our program
but actually rewriting the entire
software happens motored multiple times
always you know for example let me give
you some
examples on the Mac on a Mac okay when
when Max switched to the PowerPC
architecture this is back in 1995 they
switched to the PowerPC chips you know
architecture g3 g4
out of act you know you can see some of
these jargons you know in this in in in
this article you know we are talking
about history here you can see these in
apple ads you know apple ads they are
advertising you know Apple has famous
Apple ads you can still see on YouTube
you know they they roll out a tank you
know saying that you know the PowerPC is
actually a weapon
you know forbidden to export by the US
government because they have a law when
your computer is beyond certain petra's
speed or something they they have you
know you cannot export it so back in
1994 Apple rolled out this ad you know
showing a tank you know saying that oh
you know the mag is now a weapon you
cannot it's so fast you know it cannot
export so what's my point okay so back
so back in 1984 Apple switched their
chips to the PowerPC so that means they
have to rewrite the entirety of their
operating system and every software that
runs on Apple and Apple did exactly that
rewrite every software that exists on
the Mac Apple did okay in 1995 for the
switch to the PowerPC chip now this
happened again in 2000 around 2002 when
the Mac OS X came out you know the UNIX
you know factor Linux phonetics the UNIX
[ __ ] that creates that created
everything wrong with the computing
industry they are mentality the UNIX
philosophy the sloppy [ __ ] with C
you know their design you know it's
you know the this eunuchs in C so anyway
in 2002 Apple started to you know
because they are always OSE scrap
crashes every day Apple started to you
know you know Steve Jobs
you know the Mac OS X Y X X is supposed
it's a Roman numeral X stand for
ten you know Mac OS 10 the the the you
know the next version of Mac OS 9 the
successor of Mac OS 9 Mac OS 10
but why X because why they why they use
the Roman numeral why don't they just
say 1 0 10 well because you know it's
part of the marketing ploy you know
because they are following the UNIX
tradition you know the UNIX operating
system they tend to end with the X Y X
let me explain ok you in for example
Unix Linux PASOK's hp-ux AIX from IBM
AIX I Wix you know from Eric's from
Silicon Graphics you know all these and
also Apple aux and Phoenix from Phoenix
related to Microsoft Alex you know
people were talking about it today
so all these operating systems they are
UNIX you know they by tradition the kind
of unspoken meme you know front pun the
ending X Y X because X has always been
kind of the most dramatic letter in the
English alphabet X naught a naught B
naught Z naught C naught ABCD efg but it
is X same with my name X it's the most
dramatic letter of the English alphabet
so you'll find lots of things you know
it gets called X mr. X no some X or X X
X it can stand for quite a few things
you know there's also a movie
this also there's a classification of
movie you know which named xxx but
there's also a movie title
you know the car racing idiots you know
name the xxx
so who x is the most dramatic letter so
that's what you know so anyway so UNIX
is they are in system NZXT so that is
why Mac OS X list you know they use
that's a you know that's a trick so back
to what what I was saying so when Mac OS
X came out Apple has to again rewrite
every single software on a map including
the entirety of the operating system you
know that's that's that's you know
that's thousands that's literally
thousands of software and me the billion
trillion gazillion of lines you know in
our brain system so let's rewrite so
back in 1995 PowerPC be right in 2002
Mac OS 10 rewrite again in 2005 around
2005 Apple started to switch to the
Intel chip Intel Architecture why why
because oh it turns out this you know
the weapon you know the super powerful
Mac is not actually that that fast
you're the heart of the G 4G 5g 3G 4G
fight the powerful PC failed the Apple
[ __ ] failed they were chip you know
the PC is faster than the Mac always
since since year 2000 every PC is faster
than Mac and even so today Apple
phonetics [ __ ]
you know Apple people tends to be these
you know well where to do people you
know so anyway Apple so in 2005 Apple
again they had to they have no choice
they switched to the Intel chips you
know the Intel Core i5 I 3i v i5 i7 core
duo [ __ ] whatever call [ __ ] duo so they
have again they have to retire me right
there every single software on a Mac
including the operating system so it's a
tremendous walk so that you know so
Apple went through this three times 1995
for PowerPC 2002 for Mac OS Mac OS 10
then 2005 for the Intel chips so now
remember you Emacs [ __ ] okay like
whenever I talk about improving Emacs
this or that you know I have I have 1000
articles about that then some of these
Emacs phonetics or the Linux phonetics
they will say oh no only know that we
have to rewrite the software is [ __ ]
idiots
and and the problem you know that is the
problem is not because they actually
have to is the problem is that they
believed you're almost a lot of problems
in society is that people wanted to
believe you know you just have it you
know you don't think coat coat problem
or religion problem which is by the way
natural actually
okay that's it I think that's it for
today I talked about random things one
hour and three minutes good discussion
sorry parallelism oh yeah
okay back to parallelism the change has
to be programming language like elixir
or land to see parallel yes
so that's yes exactly no not necessary
programming language leaving explain
okay then that's a big topic okay and I
have a article on that I have 1000
article on that
okay so parallel programming so actually
go go go - um let's go back okay so
let's go back to my page let me show you
some my page go to my blog okay sorry
programming block
sorry programming block and on the left
you will see a section on lease now this
is a section of all my articles rants
against the lisp phonetics the licks
Lisp [ __ ] and indeed I have I did
two talk shows about this more than two
more than two okay
and these two are good ones so you go
watch them doing the bad death you have
nothing to do but now you have watch
Sally's video and don't forget donate
okay guys donate money okay put money in
my mouth
so anyway so back to the lease back to
the Lisp so here is a collection of
lease lease articles so and one of them
we are going to talk about is get rid of
cons here this article okay so let me
show let me show you now this article is
written by the preeminent this expert in
pioneer programming language pioneer
this pioneer guy Steele now if you ever
coded in this you know he you know you
know him he is also the first one who
wrote Emacs before Richard Stallman guy
stay still okay before Richard Stallman
Emacs and he he gave a lecture and also
a article essay that tells you that says
don't iterate because and get rid of
cause you know cons is a construct in
this where I've been fighting with the
Lisp [ __ ] for 20 years they don't
listen you know that this for the dis
first the phonetics dispersed they just
like Emacs code or Perl code or Python
code or you know Python code code or
Rusk you know they they don't see things
you know Linux code they so for lease
furs especially commonly Spurs they have
a obsession with cons you know because
I'm not going to explain why but you
know I I have I have reasons why coat
you know certain things happens in code
you know but anyway so these these
phonetics especially commonly Spurs they
have a deep obsession with counts why
because basically because cars is the
consists the one of the thing that
identifies Lisp
in other words its identity of lis
because once you if you disparage cause
then least lispers gets insulted you
know they fear their language is under
attack that's that is why that that is
why this purse have a thing for cons
because cons is kind of the kind of a
unique thing that identify associated
with least the language cons okay and
and also the other things are
parentheses cons parentheses for example
let me give you some examples of this
coat obsessions so for ye max what do
you have you have lisp to miss okay
buffer okay in scratch buffer okay in
Emacs the obsessions are lisp scratch
buffer meta X okay meta meta key meta
okay so these are things that that
serves as the end and few others okay
these are things that serves as the kind
of the identity for Emacs phonetics
wherever these things are under you know
in question Emacs
you know get sense in Emacs phonetics
they will get very sensitive and they
will defend it to death okay wherever
you talk about the meta key or the
scratch buffer or the the list you know
in Emacs you know the Emacs Emacs
phonetics which becomes a very sensitive
sensitive so my point here is that I'm
trying to illustrate the code usually
codes usually they have certain things
well
let's limit to the programming things
okay so in programming community codes
Linux Emacs Python people / people list
vers codes these are codes they
typically have a few items they are
obsessed with and very sensitive about
and why my point my Memphis is he rocks
are ism he my main Jews you know
fruit pieces here is that the reason
this these particular codes or phonetics
groups they have a particular technology
that they talk about all the time is
because here's the reason is because
those things are serve serves as the
identity for that technology for the
technology that they are fanatical about
in usually in a unique way that is why
okay that I'm telling you the reason
usually in a unique way
for example in Perl in Perl usually
usually it's the like more than one way
to do it in Python usually is the the
the you know the layout syntax you know
Python will defend it to the death and
also it's also typically it's these
things it's dramatically oh you hear
them all the time like I mentioned that
debated you know all the time
unnecessarily so back to this in this
it's there's also such things so for the
list phonetics the things are cons
parentheses and the marker okay the list
Marco the [ __ ] idiotic extreme
idiotic [ __ ] this Marco's you know you
you know if you call this you know what
I'm talking about the list was we will
talk about Marco all the time and they
will necessarily always try to do things
in your marker because it you know it
looks more complex these idiots so
anyway back to the guy steel so Castillo
is saying you know so what is Castillo
doing he is doing research on parallel
computation you know he's doing research
on parallel computation so he you know
so you know he gives you some tips and
you know what he found about parallel
computation how how how should you write
the program you know because parallel
computation as we talked before is
becoming very very very important
because CPU and na
getting faster anymore therefore it's
necessary you have to rewrite basically
rewrite every program in order to for
them to be parallel so the more CPU the
more faster your program you know you
need will become and it's necessary
because CPU are not getting faster
anymore
so if you are program whatever program
you do software server whatever if your
program is like single thread you know
that if it's not written specifically
for parallel computation that means your
program will stuck with one core you
know it's just like the demonstration
we've done you know it doesn't run fast
it so imagine 20 years later ten years
later okay imagine this imagine this
after 10 years from today you know we we
might have CPU that's you know one one
1000 course but however their speed is
maybe like same like today maybe okay
actually who knows what will happen in
10 years because maybe we all have
quantum computers anyway just let's just
say for example 10 years later we might
have you know it might be common for
every you know personal computers to be
have to have 100 or 1000 course but
however each core is no more faster than
today's computer today's you know chips
so if your program like the entirety of
Linux programs today or whatever
programs if they are not rewrite
rewritten that means after 10 years they
are no faster us today they are the same
speed as today so you see here's the the
key point that you see the the the
impact of this parallelism is that it's
serious and it's true truly every
program truly sooner or later will be
rewriting needs to be necessarily be
rewritten to 2 for parallel programming
ok anyway you you go you can read this
Holika ok it's it talks about this
specific you know if you want to learn
you need to learn about these parallel
computing computation why is it
important and what can you do as a
software programmer what should you do
to make your program you know use
parallel computing computer if there's a
lot of topic to talk about on this
subject because you have parallel how
the how to write how to code so your
program becomes parallel that's one
question then so this question this guy
Castillo is trying to address then
there's also other questions such as
parallel languages you know Golan's
supports co-routine closure has some
kind of ATM another mechanism for
parallel computation Haskell doesn't
have okay Haskell doesn't have [ __ ] the
monad phonetics else car doesn't have
[ __ ] so closure has you know some they
called
ATM or something and you know go line
has co-routine : a line is the first
most famous for parallel computation
based on message passing ok so alright
so you know you have these dedicated
languages for parallel computation and
then you have elixir or other space down
over LAN or something like that so
anyway so so that's another topic how to
design a programming language such that
such that it's easy for programmers to
write programs for parallel computation
and also there's another question how
can you have a programming language
language such that when programmers you
know don't even have to think about
parallelism they just write programs
like we do normally but however once
their program runs on parallel you know
multi-core we are automatically run
parallel that's the ultimate solution
you know the ultimate solution is to
have a programming language such that
automatically does parallel zation why
Cannot it automatic be parallel why do
we have to specifically design it you
know that's a lot of questions about
this topic anyway and I think that's it
for today
which is a definition of which is the
definition an intersection very
mathematically mighty what what do you
think are the best jobs so you can just
earn enough for living and still have
time for your personal life in projects
I don't know you know well yeah you be
yours I can tell you be a cam girl okay
be your girl and do cam show you have
that the best jobs so you can just earn
enough for living and see you have time
for your personal life in projects if
you can go okay be beautiful be be be
young ppl that's what you need we are
eating fast food allow you to compute
faster okay that's it for today I think
we have
we have a Rambo and that's it for today
and good bye guys
fern is so gay
okay so yeah so
oh I have 20 viewers oh oh wait someone
gave me $5 who is it
let's check idea I didn't even pay
attention oh thank you live so do we
have more questions now today is a super
long session now it's already 1 1 hour
and 18 minutes actually so let me drink
some coffee and let's let's let's say
let's have a cool-down session 5 5
minutes or something cooldown session so
we can kind of summarize where we are
what we want so reaper says this is an
interesting theory about ending in x no
it's not interesting theory it's a it's
it's a it's kind of a fact you know do
you have a reference for this or is it
pure sound analysis it's so common
Ripper
so Ripper is talking about you know the
UNIX operating systems ending X kind of
a convention so reaper is saying do you
have a reference so I mean where do you
hear these or something like that I mean
it's this is kind of common I mean just
look at the examples I mean one easy way
to check it is you look at all UNIX
operating systems from 1980s to 1990s ok
you you you write down word you get a
list of all of them UNIX operating
systems now by the way you there's no
hard definition of what is meant as Unix
because you can go by certification you
know then some is Unix
then Linux is not Unix okay because UNIX
is actually a trademark you know the the
UNIX and Linux periods this phonetics
facts [ __ ] in including or the BSD
phonetics you know you know don't let me
talk about UNIX okay
so UNIX what do you mean by you in UNIX
that there's no one definition you can
go by certification you can go by what
the author says you know this but in
general we kind of you know as a common
you know you can it's it's like it's
like let me ask you what is a pen okay
is there a actual definition for a pen
not really you know you can look up
dictionaries you know each one may
define it slightly different so you can
have quill pen you can a ballpoint pen
you can have space your pencil you know
or your finger might be a pen you know
so but there is no like scientific
definition of what is a pen but however
we don't need but however we don't
really need such a definition because
everyone in the proper context we
understand what is a pen okay what is a
pen the kre-o is also a pain right a
chopstick is also a pen okay I can write
this on sand
you know in case oh right your blood
with it you with your fingers on a wall
circumstances requires that so paint you
know so in a same way
what is Unix there is no actual you know
the definition but anyway we don't need
it we know what is Unix
so if you look at you know you write
down all the UNIX operating systems from
1980s to 1990s write down their names
you know we have a let me repeat again a
a UX from Apple UNIX the word itself the
first you know from AT&T you know by the
way AT&T it's it's commercial okay it's
not free AT&T UNIX you know
you know you know you know so hp-ux
hp-ux from HP Eric's from Silicon
Graphics AIX from IBM aux from Apple
UNIX
PASOK's the UNIX standard plastics which
is named by Richard Stallman by the way
which is Stoneman created the name
PASOK's okay then you have you know you
basically all but there are some
exceptions also cynics you know you look
up go go go read up Wikipedia UNIX
you'll find it okay you'll find tons
tons of it and also Linux why is it
Linux why is it why not just lean
Leena's white why X because it's
following this kind of implicit pun
convention X you end with X so there are
a few exceptions the most the most major
one too is Sun Microsystems Sun OS later
on later on they change their name to
Solaris fak fak so Microsystems
they are the most evil company in my
eyes okay so Microsystems they they
created the Java scumbag within the
other the company with the most abusive
Jagan's that is some Microsystems I'm
glad they are dead bought by an Oracle
is not a good company neither but my
opinion contrary to the UNIX [ __ ]
no typical UNIX [ __ ] they will say Oh
Oracle is bad but some micro system is
good no you have to remember back then
Sun Microsystems when they are thriving
with their Java
around year to K they are actively you
know promoting Java on their Solaris
operating system but meanwhile trying to
make it doesn't work on Linux you know
the the open source of the Linux
but eventually some micro system diet
cure by open source the virus so that so
back to the yeah so that's I think you
can verify that most UNIX is anseung X
that's the I don't think it's not
anything controversial
Paul Edwards says good discussion
parallelism okay
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching join discord I have a good
day