hello guys hello guys welcome to another
episode of sound talk show so today we
are going to do two things one is we are
going to show I'm going to do unboxing
of the Kinesis Advantage 360 keyboard
oh good this keyboard fantastic I'm
going to unbox it Kinesis Advantage 360
okay I don't want to show my address
here but you can see it's a big box
yeah okay so this is kinesis Advantage
360 pro I'm going to unbox it then I'm
going to
um then let's call JavaScript live I'm
gonna show you I'm gonna code from the
ground up so if you are new to
JavaScript and we're going to code an
application I'm gonna show you later
okay two parts hello Allen and hello my
friends okay so Kinesis Advantage 360
pro that's unbox it
okay but before I do that I have so many
keyboards here so let me show you around
so here is the glove 80 glove 80. this
is my main
and uh fantastic okay I did the review
full video review and on my website just
search for Saudi glove 80 glove like the
glove
8080 because there are 80 keys okay so
this is Club 80 and over here it's
ultimate hacking keyboard version 2.
both of them are fantastic and uh
and and my old friend
here is the Kinesis Advantage 2. this is
a version before the before the thing we
are going to unbox today so I've been
using this one for about six years okay
so they are all great okay actually I
can recommend any one of them and I
cannot tell you this is better than the
other okay there are differences but of
all the keyboards these three these four
are the best ones okay now let's unbox
the Kinesis Advantage Pro okay so let's
um so I need to move my keyboards away
make some space
okay so let's unplug the you know the
glove 80 it's fantastic I've been flying
you know I've been
you know if I show you my uh screen you
can see encoding it for the past month
fantastic you know glove 80 keyboard
okay so let's make some room for the
unboxing of the
Kinesis Advantage 2 okay um plug
any questions comments post it okay
hello Reaper and the chicken pay me okay
if you like my stuff you think if you
think I'm a good guy pay me PayPal
patreon go to sally.info and pay me okay
and you can ask questions I'll give you
a deep analysis
so now let's see the box so here is the
full full box actually I already opened
it
and this is gonna be awkward because
okay you cannot see the whole
yeah
okay let's just do it this way
okay so can you still hear me okay
so first of all there's a pamphlet you
know that's for sure quick start guide
quick start guide okay
it's got three pages
quick start diet I don't need it in fact
I have already used this keyboard
before because I was a better tester for
them so here is the cables I guess so
it's not opened yet
so let's open it
up
oh this is not the cables this is the
wrist pad wrist pad
I think
oh a new wristband nice let's see
okay so it's very soft
kind of leather-ish
it's not it's some kind of it's some
kind of
um
scientific material I'm not it's pretty
comfy okay
some kind of scientific material
high-tech motivio so that's a wrist pad
and I suppose you do you peel this off
and stick it down I'm not sure Pages pad
that's these box
and here is the main thing okay so you
can see I don't know if you can see the
whole thing so here is the main thing
here is the main keyboard heavy this
thing is made of metal
you can see here is the thing
this is made of metal okay so it's
pretty heavy
and see so USB 20 two USB ports here
here and here is the wrist I mean the
the stand you can adjust by
pressing this button down
and you can adjust okay one way two way
just just two ways so it's like that
or this way okay
anyway
and on the other side
is the left hand side
same thing heavy beautiful
okay Kinesis Advantage
360. now there are two versions of it
one is just named 360 and the other one
is named 360 pro
the pro version is Bluetooth
with zmk firmware okay if you are open
source phonetic you might be familiar
zmk is some kind of a bit like qmk so
okay now where is the cable
okay this box accessories
so here is the cable
and see
indeed
so we have what is this main cable
uh
so this main cable and this is extra key
caps
okay and the key puller suppose yeah
extra keycap for your Mac command key
option key
and here is Link cable this goes between
the keyboards Link cable okay fantastic
and one more thing what is this
Bridge connector okay so this this piece
if this is a piece of black plastic
uh I presume it connects the two
keyboards so that they don't move so if
you prefer one piece
thing
you attach this so that the the two
parts do do not move around
okay that's that box
that's it that's empty box
okay so let's see let's
shall we connect it actually so there's
nothing much to it you know the
keyboards keycaps
and the main cable so this is a main
cable so let's open it we'll need to
connect it
any questions
how much that did I pay they gave it to
me as a gift
of course then I I'm going to reuse it
and do review for them
uh I am there a long time customer I
bought for example
they gave me the advantage 2 about six
years ago but I bought my own
because the one they gave me is brown
switch
some six years ago so back then I don't
have strong opinion but but I realized
because my repetitive strain injury I
need light switch so I bought that one
that's a red Cherry MX red silent okay
for the 360 you have quite a few choices
you have a lot of light light switches
Gator on guitar is very good okay I can
tell because I have get wrong keyboards
I have several keyboards with GitHub kit
around switch
okay so let's the main cable okay throw
it away throw the bag away so here is
the main cable
USB a on one side
and you know I'm always always won the
the the the the the caps for the US
Cable USB cable is kind of redundant who
needs this cap
so so here's USB a to USBC okay and it's
sprayed it cable fantastic that's an
improvement the old one the advantage 2
is not braided cable okay and they got
these wrappers velcro wrappers so you
can
manage your cables let's plug it in okay
so I think I know what to do
I don't think I need to read manuals
because
so let's just plug it in
to the back of my monitor there is USB
USB connection you have to figure out
which side goes which upside down Okay
so this side is USBC
okay now there's a question so on the
left part you have two USBC ports
on the right part you have two USBC
ports
then you have a cable that connects in
between
so let me see what questions you guys
have
so do you have are you able to do a
tutorial video about key binding via
command command line interface on
Windows
do you have a tutorial video about key
binding via command line on Windows no
you know on Windows you don't you don't
be buying Keys you don't remap Keys via
the command line okay on Windows two
major software there are several but two
major software
to remap your keys you know control
something shortcut if you want to change
it you know to make them do something
else or change the layout one is
autohar key okay that's a program so you
download it I have a tutorial just
search for Sally Auto hotkey you
download it then you can follow my
tutorial I have a lot of examples to
remap keys to disable the Windows key or
if you want the Windows key to do let's
say to do alt or whatever or you want to
disable the caps lock key or if you want
the caps lock key to do the window key
or the or Escape key Auto hockey okay
check out my tutorial just search for
sorry
then the other major
fantastic
keyboard software on Windows is called
power toys okay power toys that's
created by Microsoft a few years ago so
with power toys you can also remap lots
of key you know you can also do this and
but you use a GUI so in General on
Windows you don't use command line
interface to program his uh on Linux you
do that okay
so the keycaps and key pullers I don't
care put it away
so but I need to know which cable goes
where for quick connection oh there it
is so you know visual visual instruction
so I don't even have to read it so this
one goes to the right keyboard
put plug it in
and this connection yeah
and this Bridge cable just
go to the middle okay so you see one of
the light goes on
so there are two versions of 360. one is
360 pro
that is Bluetooth with zmk software and
the one I have now is just 360 okay and
that is so it's USB wired and the the
software is not zmk it's uh it's Kinesis
Advantage is on
it's called Smart Set Smart Set okay in
fact I think I prefer this you know I
I have many of you are open source
phonetics qmk phonetics keyboard do it
yourself phonetics you know they say oh
you must use qmk because you can do this
or that or let us know not for me okay I
like
the Smart Set software from Kinesis
Advantage 2 and over here too I think
they are fantastic and one of the
features is that they allow you to do on
the Fly key map for example let's say I
want this for example whatever key let's
say six this key I wanted to I want to
change it let's say I want to swap six
and seven I can do it by just pressing a
few keys I don't need to launch any
software I don't need to download any
software I don't need to create an
account on the Internet or I don't need
to have a internet connection I just
press some keys
on a key and they are swapped okay in
the firmware I don't need I don't need
too long chaining software that's that's
called that you know this feature is
available in some keyboards it's on the
Fly it's called on the Fly kiwi map so
that's part of the
Kinesis Advantage advantage to a Smart
Set and also part of the keyboard I have
okay so let me give you some overview
you know so this is really heavy so
these two pieces together
I think they are one kilogram almost
so again
it's it's some kind of metal uh wait uh
okay the the bottom the button is metal
okay
some kind of method it's metal okay so
the top is some kind of
it's not metal but it's uh some kind of
plastic okay
so let's since now I have you know you
see the lights on
can you see so you see right like
so uh so you can
okay I don't want I don't want so much
tinting
yeah so let me go over the physical
build quality so I can
yeah so so this button you press over
here you press it down then it goes down
but
does it lock
yeah it's okay so there are three levels
one
two
three okay but
you know once it's down it
yeah
okay anyway
so let me see if I can type something
let's see so this is by default oh it
works so by default is quality right
yeah so the arrow key works but I want
to switch it to Vol rack
no actually I don't know how to do that
because this is a bit different from
advantage two
huh
so let's check the instruction you know
all you have to do is just press some
key combination but I forgot how that is
done
getting started
separation and rotation yeah so
ergonomics optional Bridge connector oh
yeah that's a plastic
let me show you then
so this thing
that fix these two keyboards together
firmly
how do you connect that okay somewhere
here
now I'm getting old so I have to wear
reading glasses in order to see things
close
I suppose it just goes like that
oh it just snap on I guess
snap on
yeah so you just
okay
okay so now this kind of keep them
steady so you don't have to fidget like
move this a little bit to the you know
that happens when you when when I have a
split keyboard so you know let's remove
them so I tend to you know adjust the
little micro adjustments
but anyway I don't think I want to use
this
it's redundant you don't need it
okay anything else let's so let's see
the questions Okay so
yeah so I first of all I need to switch
to Black layout I'm not sure they will
explain in this quick start menu
because you know vorac what the is
full rack you know most people don't
know oh it will wait default keyboard
layouts okay uh if okay uh black hotkey
any questions ask it okay
I'm gonna read it let's see if that
function layer default layout F1 F12 so
they don't have physical F keys so if
you want to press F1 F2 you have to hold
down the function key on the left here
okay
but
right now my concern is
how do I switch to Lorac layout
[Applause]
on the Fly Marco programming on the Fly
macro recording you see that's what I
was talking about if you want to let's
say make this key to do Ctrl C copy you
can just press a few keys in
and it'll be programmed into the
firmware
onboard programming yeah smart Drive
okay I'm not gonna
yeah so
you know I don't know how to switch to
but but let's switch to Windows for rack
so let me show you Windows 4 right
so you hold down the windows key
window window space
there it is Windows 4X so let's let me
show you some typing okay magnify
okay fantastic magnify let's see some
typing uh
wait oh wait what
what key oh okay so this is escape
so the traditional caps lock position
now is escape
so I need to because I'm using emacs
that's kind of like keys
so switch to command mod Okay so
typing
let's let's hold on a second let's do
yeah switch to command mod let's go to
my init file Okay so
Escape Escape
Control G for quit
Ctrl G for quits
and the odds
space to switch to command mod Ctrl G
for grid okay now I'm back here now open
init file wait not there so you need to
open bookmark
in it there it is now go to my Emax init
now open the keyboard key binding file
and now I want to disable this
um
this remap of escape to control G so I
want to disable that
and it's hard to disable you know you
have to restart emacs yeah
okay let's not let's not
so let's go back to some typing okay
see some typing on uh wait
on this keyboard this is a new keyboard
and every time you get a new keyboard
you are not familiar
with it takes a while to get used to
especially
on a special keys like
Escape
Port windows
and so on so
you know okay so fantastic okay now I'm
gonna answer questions
so that pretty nice how much did you pay
for it I answered that
it's a gift since the surface of the
keyboard is metal is it code to the
touch okay so the surface of the
keyboard is not metal
some kind of plastic okay very nice to
the touch very very
feels very good okay
yeah feels actually fantastic it feels
very good
you know
it's very true
but the the back
this is the metal it's heavy okay this
thing is heavy
wait but it doesn't sounds like metal
but
it's some kind of it's it's metal it's
metal for sure but it's has a classic
feel to it
I don't know how to explain it's kind of
matted metal
so can you use the fourth unused USBC
for other peripherals I'm not sure I
don't know I have to check the manual so
you know so there's two USBC here to a
USB C here but I don't know if you can
plug in another USB
so the mouse is
g502 yes and it's fantastic primarily
because of the spin wheel okay you
always want the spin wheel spin wheel is
just
um necessary okay
for example on my Twitter I can spin for
for 20 seconds without touching it
uh paraphrased command line is blocked
Windows just works that's true a bit
okay no more questions now
um I'm wondering if I should do the
JavaScript coding anyone wants to see
JavaScript coding
or is there okay we got night people so
any questions about this keyboard
you know we can start to do JavaScript
coding
I can either use this keyboard for the
next 30 30 minutes or
or I can use the ultimate hacking
keyboard and let me show you okay so
pick a choice you guys who are watching
you know like we can use this new
keyboard to code or we can use the
ultimate hacking keyboard too
or we can use the
glove 80 oh yeah so you you guys
probably like to see some kind of
comparison you see the glove 80 is much
smaller lighter this this is like one
fifth
one-fifth or sixth the weight you know
this one this this this thing is
almost 10 times heavier
you know the the girl of 80 is just
elegant and neat okay
well this one is for those of you who
prefer premium feel or Deluxe feel or
military you want things made up of
metal
so
okay let's see what's uh
switches are too heavy for you no the
one I have I've you know the one I have
is super light is like 35 grams it's
skated wrong
okay yeah let's go to their website so
now
uh you see a
customizable memory to the keyboard like
advantage two
yes this is the memory building okay so
it's just like advantage two uh you know
everything you programmed is is set to
the firmware okay so you just so you
don't need to
you know when you plug this keyboard in
another computer or you bring it to work
or to a friend's house you don't need to
restart the you know key remap software
and reprogram everything is building
okay so all the key keybinding you
program come with go with the keyboard
okay I don't think that we are going to
do the JavaScript live coding so and you
know since we just talking about
keywords yeah so now let's look uh let's
go through their website and uh
and let me let me show you a bit about
their website Okay so so I have a review
so you just go to kasali.org study.info
so you can see my ergonomic keyboard
reviews so glove 80 Kinesis Advantage 2
each one's got the video review and full
detail with lots of photos and 360. now
on the 360 I don't have much info yet
because I just got it but here is a
review
um
there are a couple of reviews by other
people okay so you can watch for now and
so you go through their website
so there are two versions again you know
360 and 360 pro the 360 is wired the pro
is
Bluetooth and the pro is with the zmk
firmware the 360
is with Smart Set okay and they both
have internal memory and so on so and as
far as key switches you can see they
have they offer you
six key switches and are they hot
swappable
uh I think they are actually you know I
myself don't really care for hot
swappable hot swappable means you can
you can buy a bunch of key switches you
like and just take them out and swap
them in but it takes some work and you
have to be careful because otherwise
your damage the
the the
electronics the PCB wall
so
so now they offer several you know a
bunch of key switch choices and the one
I have is let's see
uh
uh yeah so two versions 360 pro is
Bluetooth with zmk
and uh okay so let's see all the up
order from upgrade so what key switches
do I have
catron Brown get around Brown uh
spec model comparison programmability
integrated tinting mechanical switches
there
uh
but can you actually see
what switch do they offer I mean the
details
upgrade keyboards
uh you have to
invest yourself shop so let's go shop
okay let's go shop so there it is
Advantage 360
Signature Series
professional 360.
Signature Series choose your switch
oh so the so if you want to choose your
switch you go with the signature series
okay so let's click on Signature Series
okay
uh keycap set Bora keycap set okay
all the direct from upgrade okay so you
have to order from this page in order to
choose
so you have to build it okay so
if you want to Bluetooth start with 420
if you want the non-pro version the
wired version start with 390.
Okay so
turn on JavaScript
you know again I recommend lighter
switch okay because switch is actually
the most important to me now oh there it
is so the one so
wait wait 50 grams 50 grams
uh
cater on silent Brown tactile getter get
around baby kangaroo tactile switch
there's so many these days you can
you know you don't know what they are so
the one I have is a light linear so
and you can also buy a switch tester I
recommend you do that
oh God they have so many choices now I
don't you know I have to check which one
they send me but it's a something like
35 grams
linear switch so I can type on it
okay that's it not hot swappable okay
you see okay okay so
I think that's it for today
yeah I think so that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
we're gonna shut down in two minutes
yeah I was going to call this JavaScript
thing but uh
so there is a interesting question hello
what are the most interesting fields of
mathematics for you
I like in general I like geometry and
the most interesting that would be hard
to say but in I like complex analysis
uh
that's the question not you know I like
pure mathematics in general so I would
not like statistics
but I do like probability and uh and
usually geometry okay so I like
differential geometry algebraic geometry
I'm not too you know I'm not Advanced so
I don't really know that much uh but
complex analysis but basically geometry
okay lots of geometry
and also lots of non-professional I mean
what do you call none yeah you might
call you know
um recreational mathematics is you know
like not the main
part of mathematics such as probability
Theory titling Theory
and Knots nuts and networks and I also
like graph Theory those are not
like the main stream mathematics
okay bye guys