good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's show today's 2020 may
5th and Tuesday 5 o'clock p.m. in the
afternoon San Francisco time so good
morning guys good morning Johnny
good morning Ripper good morning Alan
and Todd Jack crystal and source so what
are we going to talk about today I don't
know I don't have I we got some
questions
Alan collected compiled a bunch of
questions compilation did you know that
the word compilation came from the
etymology is stealing ok you probably
don't know but let me show you the
etymology et tu IMO lgy of compilation
and you know how I found that out
because I was watching porn you know on
porn websites you have compilation of
certain acts and then I'm wondering so
where does the word compilation came
from well it came from basically
stealing pure furring you know rampage
whatever that is the proper word okay
and you are looking at my Emacs setup
sawfly keys and on the right side you
can see all the commands I caused such
as moving cursor and moving cursor up
down left and right or left and right by
words and you see oh it's all single key
press so it's a most efficient thing and
by the way did I mention oh I think I
haven't mentioned this before so about
two weeks ago someone will he
implemented a new entire new engine for
cough like he's okay let me show you
actually let me talk about that
sapphire keys entire new engine and will
go back to a combination of etymology
etymology of compilation okay so
actually let me open another page wait
for the English and open it here and
then magnify so you can see my window
and okay and show the keys okay so add a
new section and and switch window
etymology of compilation okay
copy yet move back here and select it
and etymology so I have you know I have
a case our lookup command cuz I look up
etymology actually so so you can do it
multiple ways so for example I want to
know the etymology of the word
compilation so this is a Emacs demo ok
so there's a package jean-luc episode I
call the command meta X and type
etymology so I look up etymology that is
a command I call and you're showing
browser of the etymology website so you
can see let's magnify the words so
compilation middle 15th century that
which is compiled also action of
compiling act of bringing together and
adapting things said or written by
different persons for the X was
exposition of a subject so that's a
meaning from Old French compilation come
from Old French compiled action
something like that and compilation
collection from Latin compel atonium
compilation literally a pillaging leg
literally pillaging now of action from
past particle stem of compile errors so
pillaging tillage that's what compiled
and which so when you write c or c plus
first those idiotic language languages
you compile you are pillaging you are
pillaging some bits
so etymology so so so here is the
etymology okay thus I look up commands
okay this is fantastic commands you can
pillage you can pilfer from so here is
the the least code you can see let me
magnify the window okay wait hold on
second I need to show you my keystrokes
so magnify wait and what's going on
so magnify magnify so here is the Lisp
code Sol look up etymology and this is
part of the package Sol look up so you
can pillage you can pillage it from Napa
Emacs Emacs stuff and here we have the
website here okay we open it and show in
browser Emacs sallow Kapadia look up the
web you can look up Google any search
engine you want you can customize it
here and you can look up world
definition look you can look up
Wikipedia look up what dictionary dick
org look up Wiktionary and look up
etymology so that's one of the package
you can use so let me copy it and let me
switch window let's go to so let me go
to the San talk show page and let me put
this here so you can actually see my
comments so here is our look up stuff
Emacs stuff and let me go back to the
compilation the Emacs stuff okay so let
me show you
etymology of a compilation now we use
the command to look up the word but now
there's another way if you are a blogger
like me a blogger so you want the
etymology of compilation so you call the
command
Kassar words etymology linker fie
you see you call that command so I press
ENTER so it creates a link to the
etymology website so you can make it a
paragraph showing browser so now you can
see we have a link to the etymology of
compilation and what I'm going to do now
is I'm I'm going to peel fur steal it
copy it you know why because this is the
modern way everyone is stealing from
every other you know you know about
google image search that's a beginning
that's the that's kind of the how it all
began and you know the meme you know
know your mean website that's pillaging
you know and the most popular example is
Wikipedia you just steal from thousands
and ten thousand one hundred million
resources and put on Wikipedia that's
what you do okay so we copied we copied
the the compilation the etymology and
let me show you another command ok so
you see let's do this again so I paste
it here
that's the ethnology of compilation now
this is I want to make it what Emacs
call Emacs feel ok Cydia do see of the
Emacs feel let me show it again so you
see now if this long this is very long
line so you can call a feel command
actually my field command is different
from Emacs because it does it's more
suitable suitable for programming code
we'll talk about that on another day but
right now what I want to do is that you
see this these idiotic straight quotes
that does not match I don't want that so
core command press a key wait press ok
way first what
press a key you can see the key let me
show you the key again here so let's and
do and do okay so wait so let's do this
over again okay close the window close
reopen fantastic commands and paste it
again you see now it's there now I call
the command shall replace straight
quotes now they now they are in curly
quotes you see it highlights the places
that's that changed now let's let's see
the beauty of the curly quotes
can you see now I make a paragraph out
of it okay so let me shrink let me
shrink it okay so Nick let's make a
let's see you see make a paragraph and
make it quote block quote and the
showing browser so now you can see
etymology of a compilation and now it's
on my website not not someone who spent
10 years to create this passage but we
we want to be nice so we give it credit
here so the sauce you know now this is
related to SEO you know this this is
what all the thousands creates the
commercial websites you know they've
been doing this for more than 10 years
the CNN [ __ ] and New York Times well
place of New York Times but more this is
done by most of the news secondary news
websites such as you know TechCrunch
next web you know the next web you know
turns thousands of them they like every
time Google for example Google has a
blog right Google Google blog every time
Google has some news they talk about on
their blog then all these sponge web
sites they they go they copy passages
from the Google then they rewarded you
know they tell you so you go to their
website instead of the Google original
blog blogger Google Park website so you
know that all these websites been doing
that and that that is helped by Twitter
and Facebook Fox you know because they
want to make money and they they created
this situation and the Google by itself
is guilty
Google invented the concept of SEO which
stands for search engine optimization
you know so why what's wrong with that
you know the reason you know the problem
is at Google they are a search engine
maker you know that's how they make
money but however they want to get you
to help them that's why that's a source
the original concept of search engine
optimization it's not really search
engine it's not [ __ ] my business too
up to help you to happen to make your
search engine better but however Google
by-the-by their power brainwashing to
the idiotic open-source [ __ ] open
source phonetics you know they made it
so that every every open source open
sources you know these Linux idiots and
free software foundation they are like
Oh help Google you know they created the
concept so search engine optimization it
becomes a thing they created this jargon
and there's and they can Google has this
guy Matt you know you guys remember the
guy Matt you know he's he's you know the
representative you know a very nice guy
he talked very nice you know help we
need to help Africa we need to help
women we need to help blacks that's the
you know that's the social justice
kans thing help help we need to move
make the world better a better place but
actually what it's helping what is
actually doing is help Google and with
the search engine optimization they
created a structure kind of you know
brainwashing into you people to create a
structure so that you you create your
website according to whatever Google
likes you to do so all the websites
become set good morning Eric Chen good
morning in China okay so let's go back
to item ology and I have thousands
articles on SEO okay so but it's let's
not talk about that because they are 1
billion topics so etymology okay so we
show the two commands about retaining
Emacs about etymology so for example the
command I just used swords swords would
etymology linka fight we can look at the
source code
so let's magnify wait wait okay
magnify magnify so here is the source
code make the current word into a
etymology reference link it this is
supremely useful if you are a blogger
especially if you are into linguistics
Alan Alan is our linguistic Alan is our
local in-house linguist he is a PhD
student drop out of linguistics okay so
this is useful command
okay so let's that's about that for that
okay so this is my wordy block from the
haughty emotions of lexicon stylistic
concerns decipherment of grammar and
idioms linguistic allottee literature
and logic allottee okay that's my word
block okay so that's that about the
etymology of compiled and there's one
more thing etymology of compilation okay
copy that we need to make it a header
okay let's make it larger and need to
show you the keys okay so etymology of
compilation h3 header show in browser
fantastic okay now that's it and I'm
going to type I'm going to drop into ECL
the first fantastic email is technology
and a sink the fantastic UNIX technology
and password the fantastic technology of
abbreviation so it's uploaded on my
website and now if you close this copy
the file path open a new buffer pasted
you can see the file path local file
path and you press a button and it
becomes Sawadee blog become the actual
URL here and now you press a button
everything is single button press
operation here you go to actually you go
to my my local file but what we want we
is to show this in Chrome browser so you
call open link in Chrome that's another
command you can find on my github so you
are looking at Sawadee blog and we have
the today's update etymology of
compilation pillage
okay that's it for that topic that's the
completion of that topic let's hop to
the next topic okay so let's go back
copy that close it
saw talk-show okay etymology of
compilation and put the link here
Sawadee block okay showing browser yes
stuff like his stuff like his needs a
website stuff like he website inc so
stuff like his website let's put that
here
let's get that link show oh yeah so that
we have a new engine new engine forks
are fly keys by wheel so by we old
wheels something
thank you very much wheel you can find
his name on the unlock stuff like his
github it's a fantastic new engine this
is a great improvement because now stuff
like ease has priority over us you don't
have you don't have you don't have to
worry about minor mods you know such as
the magic mod overriding your keys
so so we done okay so that's the topic
so let's go to the next topic I have
tons of things to say how long have I
been talking and that's touch base let's
see who is here and what you guys are
saying I've been talking about 17
minutes so go back here if you have
questions put my name to it
okay put my name maybe he's not as oh
and we talked about SEO okay Google SEO
Google created the concept of SEO okay
so actually I want to show you the
article about that because that's a
important topic
sorry SEO Google the [ __ ] evil thing
and the and and by the way when Google
created the SEO website I mean the
concept this is before 2010 this is
around I don't know 2008 or something
back then Google was still considered a
ethical company you know do no evil but
this move is and and you know but this
move to me
is actually the evil it is you know it's
actually you know after 2010 Google
Google became explicitly evil lying
lying scumbag cheating and you know
showing their website because you know
some ad money they pay you show on top
of their website things like that and
also collusion with US government
government so after 2000 also of course
making AI weapons helping the government
doing AI weapons and going into China
helping China do things of course
because money money is talking money is
fuel of everything we do human animals
so actually you know deviate to into
another topic it is actually true when
you look at society the way why is it
the way it is now of course depending on
what things you are talking about there
are many reasons but you can almost
always say the fundamental reason is
money money is making things co and and
I'm doing YouTube videos because the
money to otherwise I may not have to I
may not have in part okay so so why does
Google give a SEOs advice so the here is
the article written in 2010 there it is
you can read it so let me copy the URL
and wait copy the URL and put put it
back in here so
showing browser okay so let's go back to
keep in touch with you guys so what you
guys are saying what you guys have been
saying good morning George what is the
most blessed technology that would be
well I don't know that would be
chopsticks okay the most blessed
technology that depends on what do you
mean you know like what what what what
what is the context spoon is a
technology know right so how useful is a
spoon is it is a spoon para technology
then sliced bread I would say so yeah
you know with our spoon you cannot have
soup or with you you know you use your
hands so so okay let me catch up with
the questions and also we have some
questions on this code Alan has compiled
a bunch of questions on this code and we
can talk about that but let me quickly
go through the the the the chat here see
if there's anything interesting
good morning George good morning Alan
Ripper and Eric Chen China ding dong
ding dong and let's see put my name to
it okay fantastic UNIX Tech let's see
Alan says are you using another Mick in
addition to your headset microphone
audio sounds fine to me
so it sounds fine sweep to you oh no
this is he only headphone I'm using this
is he only make the headset so what is
the most best technology that you know
that depends on what you mean chopsticks
and what's your opinion on Emacs evil
mod that's a lame question because evil
mod emo Maggie is mode oh okay
same as stuff like keys and moto is good
if you are if you can get you know you
can get used to it you know there are a
lot people who who who look at moto e
and then they go on and I don't want to
do moto
well actually the only reason is because
habit ok habit is a is a foundation of
almost all opinions habit you if you put
your mind to it chickenshits
go change your mind ok change your mind
moto is good listen to me moto is a good
thing ok you want model repeat that
every day repeat that three times every
day for a month then your love model
then you start to use evil model sucks
love like this then you will discover
the fantastic ality of such mod so so
yeah Komodo well if you are a programmer
Komodo ok and an adder has 40 theory
Allen do you want me to do a live at
live criticism of your articles is going
to be a torrent of Wrath probably I can
do that you pick one or two of your
articles and I'll do a live review free
free ok without charging
so Eric chance also Alan says in what
way are you less evil than Google me now
that's that's a touchy question in what
way am i less evil than Google in lots
of ways in terms of ways that's no
that's easy and easy easy answer this
it's not even worth answering you could
say you know because you can say
basically almost all human beings if
unless you are famous then maybe we have
to talk about it basically everyone else
is much less evil than Google because
it's an evil empire the human Empire
it's more powerful than you know you
could even say it's more powerful than
the US government it's the most powerful
organization in the entire human history
that is true Google basically you could
say Google is that what is your favorite
type of virtual seek signaling I don't
do what you're signaling [ __ ] okay
basically if you are the type of person
whose way all the time you don't qualify
you don't qualify to be a virtual signal
signaler so what did you start saying
human animals were you always such your
mark max'll marks amidst materialist
I began starting to talk use the term
human animals when I started to study to
look into human animal social issues
around 2003 okay around 2003 basically I
talked about this one time before these
these touches upon the history of my
life biography biography of sorts
autobiography human animals so why I ask
why why do I started to use that phrase
but let me give you the background human
animals so before 2002 you could say I'm
a nerd and I'm a nerd who are just like
other nerds who I don't know anything
about society I don't know anything
about politics I don't you know I don't
care much about politics oh I do and I'm
a superior nerd I'm an extreme case so I
just study computer science and math
programming math that's what I do an
etymology English vocabulary okay that's
this is before 2002 basically English
literature I have to read Shakespeare or
whatever famous American writers or
classic literature's you know Dickinson
you know tons of them the
the the humpback of note Roe done for no
damn for example I didn't read that one
by the way boy and piece you know the
big shots you know the big literature
the the Old Man and the sea so I read a
bunch of them and you know and also
study English so vocabulary so mostly I
study I'm a big nerd I study math math
is the primary primary thing you live
and dream in math up to 20 hours a day
actually literally that is true I was
younger when you when you were young you
can do that you go all night just dive
into the tech including la tech and tech
this idiotic facts you dive into you
really just keep reading keep reading
and but back then you don't have
internet as we have today you don't have
Wikipedia Wikipedia began in 2003 also
which are discovered because they link
to my website so you don't have
Wikipedia but you have encyclopedias
Britannica Americana
you know encyclopedia americana coitus
encyclopedia and around 2000 around 1997
you have Microsoft Encarta you know
encyclopedia from Microsoft I bought it
I'm the first one when cd-rom reader
came out for the computer I'm the first
one to buy it yeah this is in 1990 1993
or 1996 I forgot the first cd-rom rod
reader the technology came out with the
encyclopedia on it you know it included
you know as part of marketing so I
bought it for five hundred dollars back
in 1990
I think 1996 maybe Oh before I forgot so
I'm the first one to buy that you know
and I saw I'm also an avid reader of
encyclopedia so anyway I was saying
before 2002 I was just a big nut and and
what I read is mostly math programming
math programming psychology and
linguistics okay and in vocabulary
literature basically these five things
these five subject matters but and I
don't know anything about social science
the science is you know not much but but
after 2002 I started to go into those
directions I started to you know mostly
the primary impetus is future is what
you call these nerds idiots called
futurology okay basically you want to
know what will happen in the future to
eat to human animals for example back
then robotics is coming on strong and
back then around 2002 there's a big fear
of of nanotechnology you know they are
thinking in ten years
something drastic will happen to society
nanotechnology far more than dangerous
there nuclear bombs that's what people
say for example there's this guy Bo one
of the Sun Microsystems founder the guy
who wrote VI him he wrote a very popular
article and as a reaction from reading
the Unabomber's declaration manifesto
you know and he is saying you know this
this nanotechnology and robotics in AI
they are going to become crippling they
are going to [ __ ] humanity we have to
pay great attention to them you know
he's soaked and he's saying that and for
example so so so I started to this is
you know futurology what will happen to
human Mo's that's my that's got me
started to look into this kind of issue
study human animals human animals humor
history human animals behavior what we
do and you know back to human animals
that's I don't know I don't remember if
that's the first time I used it but
basically I started to use more more and
that term because I I explained this
before why why do I use the term human
human animal because if you don't
believe in God
okay if you believe if you believe in
God then you don't say human animals
because that's sacrilegious human are
not just animals humans are the creation
of God you know you have to you know
it's God created these beans beans okay
God created out we beans from the image
of God so we look like God we are the
creation of God human beings not animals
whatever FLAC we are human beings now
but I don't believe in God so what what
God but God so I so human being what the
[ __ ] does it mean beans be my ass being
[ __ ] yourself with your beings human are
not be you know beans beans
it's an etymology it's a euphemism it's
a fake news fake word fake fake word
human beings what what being being what
being what what's a being meaningless
[ __ ] human beings meaning that
meaningless [ __ ] okay so we what's aware
we are we are animals okay if you don't
believe in God then you are an atheist
or agnostics you know so
you don't believe in God oh you don't
believe in a creator divine creator
because there's so there's no logical
reasons to you could have faith then you
believe okay that's you know that you
can do that but if you don't if you
stick to science in other words if you
stick to science then there's no such
you know you cannot prove it or such
things we we cannot possibly know God
I've not I've not a not not God I have
speech problems now I'd knocked a
seasoned okay
that's what Bertrand Russell famous
famously said that if they asked him do
you believe in God and his answer is
depends on how knowledgeable the
questioner is about the subject if you
are fairly acquainted with the subject
matter then he would say he's agnostic
agnostic meaning that the question about
whether the existence existence of a God
is kind of a metaphysics metaphysical
question is the question that you cannot
possibly answer you don't know basically
you don't know we don't know we don't
know whether God exists or not you know
there's no and so but if you are so if
you know a lot about this subject you
know I'll say I'm agnostic but if you
don't know it's simpler to say oh I
don't believe in God I'm my atheist so
so so that's a you know that's a
Bertrand Russell said that so anyway
back to the human animals so human
animals you know human beings you know
the if you look into it and if you are
concerned you know if you have
interesting vocabulary the beans doesn't
you know and logic
you know the beans does not make sense
it's some sort of euphemism it's some
sort of fake news it sent some sort of a
Papa ganda okay embedded in the language
from religious people
and this is a good reason too because
before science is we don't have nothing
we have to believe in God or some sorts
because we fear the darkness somewhere
I'm gonna come out and cut your thoughts
and most like most likely you know it
may be a tiger or it may be another
human being so so human being you know
that that word if you know since I don't
believe it so that's a nonsensical
that's not a good word if you are you
know logical rationalist so that's why
human animals ok human animals that is
the proper term if you are atheist or
agnostics because that's what we are
animals ok now now now this is important
now if you are atheist you may not you
you may disagree because actually humor
em knows animals are different from
other animals a lot of people say that
you know including in science you know
in you know part of it because they
still believe in because the influence
the momentum you know the trend the
heavy trend of from religion you still
say human beings but partly because you
know human beings you know we scientist
an atheist scientist may not agree may
you know he may think that actually
human animals are really different from
other animals they might say oh because
we have more intelligence or we have
something something but it's all
[ __ ] but I learned in passed last
year that actually there is one if we
can say there is something different
from human animals and other animals
there is one thing that we are actually
kind of different from other animals
such as monkeys or chimps
that is we cook you know we we cook you
know you you microwave right you
microwave you barbecue we cook we use
fire to punch stuff before we put it in
our mouth we eat you know we kill pigs
and and bows and we kill you
we kill your skin you cut your meat we
eat it but however we are different from
lions and tigers and hyenas we before we
eat it we burn it you know we cook and
this habit of cooking is actually a
million years old you know I started to
read you know what's you know because
cooking is puzzling you know because you
know remember I'm I like the word human
animals but but this this cooking I
always kind of puzzled about you know
what why does cat you know when cat eats
a mouse he doesn't cook you know Kat
doesn't cook so why are we cooking I
mean so and today you know you have a
lot of Americans you know the the fat
Americans whose life is too good they
are all animal rights or diets or you
know cardio diets diets or meat that you
know they have 1,000 terms about dieter
idiots Ripper diets diets this lion diet
you know what so some of the terms of
the diets the [ __ ] diets America are
concerned obsessed about diets these
people whose life is to reach to comfort
comfortable diets and so so these all
these diets you know so so why does we
why do we cook and there's this slow
cooking this this fat [ __ ]
among the lefty California you know
people now they not just cook okay
microwave no micro very easy doesn't
taste good you know you have to care for
your palate a lotta let you know your
care for your mouth you have to go
microwave it's no good you have to cook
with the elaborate cookware and but they
also have you know this slow cooking
like normally if you cook meat you know
you cook for 5 minutes or 10 minutes you
know
or beef barbecue or whatever but they
have slow cooking that that is you put
down low temperature and you cook for 20
hours I have a article on that and
there's a French word describing that
Alan do you know what's a through or
something the French term describing
that activity that's there's a movement
in California slow cooking and
supposedly slow cooking the food come
out test spit better
okay people you know whose life is to
reach so human so cooking soso cooking
cooking is actually if you if there's
anything we can say that says human
animals different from other animals
that would be cooking we cook we have
been cooking for a million years that's
incredible
okay Alan got go so what else we gonna
okay I actually I talked about a lot of
topics I wanted to show some articles
but the trend is lost the direction now
let's see some of the other questions
here how long have I been talking forty
minutes let's see some some of the
questions and we go back to this code
there's some questions on this code yeah
so Alan's question when did you start
saying human animals so so it's around
2002 I started to use that phrase often
because I then you know there's also
some changes in my writing style because
before 2002 I am very obsessed about a
writing style that is pure logic
you know and anyway human animals that
the face so let's see what's the next
question is the nukes and flakies and
Melba yes
Clark Kaka cracks okay George show Alan
says repeat that every day three times a
day then you'll love model I got to go
in few minutes okay but you can talk
about QWERTY theory QWERTY theory okay
Alan Scottie theory
Alan has invented a theory of his own
QWERTY theory so we might read that and
you know I don't know what's up there
hannah has written a blog about quarry
theory Santa Vee it's probably better if
we do it when Alan is here sucks ass
neckbeard is getting longer a
second-by-second so let's see what else
[ __ ] yourself with your pings what is
being sung okay so do you watch yes of
course I do
Eric Chen every Chang join discord ok
join discord you and you will discover
the wonders of things
okay what's so any any other questions
sous-vide yes and I'm not sure how to
pronounce that George says sous-vide
okay that's the you know the hipsters
they doing that okay tick tick the heck
don't you think
another different different do you think
don't you think another difference
between humans and other animals that we
draw pictures no not really well drawing
pictures is a skill basically your skill
of using tools and also the skill of
having concepts in abstraction
close close and have can do that octopus
can do that it's just that they don't do
it as good as we do you know we have we
are in higher level Oh Eric changed in
this code okay let's go back to so okay
so no more questions these things are
starting to get boring let's go back to
this disco let's see what we have there
so is here something I want to talk
about actually not really
let's do 20 minutes 15 minutes so maybe
so
Alan some questions from island ends for
mother so what do you think of prologue
ok prologue is the logic language I
don't really know much about it for
Locke is logic it's a declarative
language you know and it's based on
logic basically you Prolog is very old
it's like 3040 years old something like
that Prolog I don't really know much
about for Locke I try to learn you know
someone in China Chinese follow me in
China try to teach me that you know
we've been chatting about that for a
week or so but I'd actually never
learned much from it for Locke and okay
so there's a modern version of prologue
that's called mercury so you search for
mercury language you'll find it and how
did I learn English that I'd learned a
long time ago
I can tell there's a big story actually
I did I did a talk show on that how do
you learn English words long time ago
half a year ago you might find it you'll
find it on my youtube but I did this
kind of you basically I learned English
purely purely by reading dictionaries so
I learned ten vocabulary ten words a day
accumulatively that is each day you
learn ten was well in the beginning you
learned more than 10 20 but so let's say
10 ok 10 words a day
so after month you have 300 yeah ten
right now 20 okay
tens big enough the the important thing
is accumulatively that is every word
once you learned it you tried you try to
you want to keep trying to remember it
so in in one month you learned 300 words
in three months you are know 900 words
okay in a year you are know
3650 words in a year 3650 words now now
the point about ten words a day is that
and accumulatively that is every every
week you have to be review the words you
already learned so this this is very
important critical because after two
years you are know after just two years
you know about 7,000 words 7,000 words
and that's equivalent that's about
basically what American a typical
American knows in three years you are no
more than 10,000 words that's more than
college-educated American okay if you
keep up the ten words a day and trying
to memorize you you must have a way to
always review the words you learned you
write it down that's what I did I have a
website I have tens of I have tens of
articles on that ok such such for Saudi
dictionary review such for Saudi
vocabulary you'll find it so 10 10 words
a day not too much don't be greedy okay
just 10 water a day but try to you know
remember you must remember you must
review the other words you learned in a
path in you know before so you have to
can't you know you have to review them
after three years you won't know more
words than a typical American
college-educated America that's me
that's how I learn English and back then
I ignored everything else about English
I ignored you know it's such great you
know really good advice such as learning
starting from the basics so I I was
known in Shakespeare words you know well
I don't know
ABC yet that's what I did you know brute
force that's that that's what I did it's
not actually it's a very stupid
inefficient method to learn English but
however that's what I did I don't do it
now I ask you look up dictionaries and
vocabularies but not as much you get oh
you get out
you know so and and with these 10 words
are there you cannot do it for two you
know the thing is once you see once you
passed let's say once you know six six
let's say once you know six thousand
English words the more words you learn
they they're gonna be useless like you
will not encounter such word not once in
your lifetime typically such as words in
Shakespeare words in novels you know
there's tons of words you will not
encounter at once in your lifetime
basically you know 6,000 words is enough
you know there's poetry this you know
words poetry words you know obscure
words absolute words and you know things
like that so anyway that's that's
basically higher learned English by
reading dictionaries repower thank you
Reaper for money any questions you have
Reaper yeah you know you know this this
monetization the Google invented
monetization is for super Chad you know
this is called super Chad so that you
can ask a question so do you have a
question you want me to answer
personally I answer that type it okay so
okay so let's go back so how long so are
we gonna talk about ten more minutes or
so quite a few topics here what do you
think up for dark okay so I don't know
much about forelock it's interesting you
know but so today there are so many
interesting programming languages I
actually I wouldn't you know I wouldn't
recommend prologue actually it's not to
say depending on what you what's your
needs what's your goal what's your you
know orientation if you are if you are
into studying programming languages if
that's your main thing yeah sure learn
product but it's gonna be it's likely
gonna be useless your I mean useless
inglis NC it's not practical you're not
you're not finding a job but besides
that you know lots of languages such as
Haskell you'll probably not find a job
and Julia in Mathematica and least all
these languages you know you can learn
and you will not find a job but Prolog
is even less than that
Parag you learn it you are not even find
applications even you and you will not
be able to program you know you will not
be able to write your scripting it it
will be useless the only use will almost
be the conceptual learning of a new
programming concept that is programming
by logic so you know if you are into
programming language concepts and you
know that's that's you know you can
learn palak that's my opinion about it
and also by the way in Prolog back then
in nineteen is there is
Mathematica for example in common lisp
they implement Prolog in Mathematica and
in Lisp and and if I recall correctly
one of the famous Common Lisp book you
know there are like four three or four
very popular most popular common these
books they have implementations in
Prolog as as one of their chapter I
think the book by Novick Peter Novick I
think you know AI with common least
something he you know he's written a
book classic for common list that
contains a chapter or epilogue of Lisp
of Prolog implemented in Lisp so anyway
that's about Prolog so Allan's next
question english-speaking audience but
do not know how to translate expression
wait so are there any Chinese words do
you often wish to use with your
english-speaking audiences but do not
know how to translate x-rays no you know
when you are beginning if you are a
beginner in English you do have such a
question you know often you know some
Chinese or Spanish or whatever is your
mother tongue Russian you don't know how
to say it in English you know you are
frequently bombarded with such question
when you are beginner English but I've
been living in USA for the past thirty
years I and and three years in Canada
since you know 1984 I started to learn
basically so that's what you know that's
long past me I don't I don't have any
words in
because I don't speak Chinese anymore
you know in fact I haven't been talking
or writing Chinese every day you know I
really do I still speak Chinese because
I was born in Taiwan but actually I know
far more English words and Express
ability and my writing skills is all
English in fact lots of English terms I
don't know how to say in Chinese so I
have the reverse problem so click bait
optimization so actually so we talked
about after you know click paid and SEO
a bit about that so reaper says sorry
what are your thoughts about spending
the time to learn regular expressions
oh yeah so that you can do stream
processing more efficiently and what
about incompatibilities between
different projects it's okay that's it
that's the topic regular expressions I
have one thousandth article 1000
articles on that literally actually not
literally but by the way when you say
when people say literally you know some
some grammar nazis or some pundit we all
say oh no you can you use that word
wrong because when it's not literally
you cannot say literally actually force
well you could say something literally
something something literally - as an
expression of exaggeration because I
remember we mean that the boy you know
the great writers have done that anyway
so I have quite a lot of articles on
regular expressions so let me answer
your question fully so kisame regular
expressions I have like 10 articles
about that I have I have full tutorial
on regular expressions for Python for
JavaScript complete documentation of
your graduation in Python JavaScript and
tutorial in eMac lists
and in quite a few and also I have tons
of essays about regular expression and
also a lots of problems with the about
regular expression problems in great
tons of articles about that so such folk
sorry regular expression and you'll find
JavaScript regular expression tutorial
and rejects limits or should you read
Mastan regular expression that's an
essay and Python rejects my rejects
match object that's a reference for
Python regular expression and goal and
expression : regular expression that's a
tutorial of regular expression in : how
to use it you know great regular
expression and let me finish the article
list yet first I have $10,000 other goes
on with regular expression and and I
will get to your question Swiss your
specific question so another essay XML
is not a CPS expression okay actually
this one is not about regular regular
expression so let's keep that then Emacs
rejects tutorial okay let me show you
some of these articles and Elise week
rejects tutorial because in Emacs and
eMac beast you use regular expression in
some are different ways they are you
know technical complexities
so actually I have an index of all my
regular expression pages somewhat so let
me see if I can find it okay wait what's
going on okay cancel rejects okay
rejects passing index I'm not sure oh
there it is
so it's a regular expression articles
index so I have like 30 articles or
something so you have pattern matching
versus grammar specification you have
eMac miss versus pearl validate local
file links kind of odd JavaScript three
articles okay where am I going so let me
show you some of them so JavaScript I
have regular so for each language you
have regular expression tutorial which
is quite important from regular
expression reference because you can
because tutorial for each language the
way they use regular expression is very
different okay very different from each
other Java JavaScript Python Perl
the way you call regular expression the
way you want to replace the string or
you want to find a match
string pattern the way you call them the
function or whether it's an object or
whether they return a list or whether
they return the object it's all
different
so for each language you have to learn
how to use regular expressions so I have
articles on that for example here is a
javascript regular expression tutorial a
simple introduction you know for many
programmers you don't even know what is
a lot you know beginning of programmers
you don't know what's a regular
expression regular expression is one of
the most important thing you want to
master okay you want to master it as
soon as you get your hands on you know
you started to program you want to learn
try it you know have the mindset that
you want to master regular expression
see extremely useful however don't get
into the extreme you know some people
some programmer will say oh you need to
master to such a degree you need to use
regular expression to write compilers
actually that's it
we'll get into that anyway
so regular expression is very important
you want to try to master it okay but
don't go overboard don't once you know
what is about you know you can use it
properly you can use it to find a stream
pattern in text files or you can use it
to do find and replace replace you know
for files that's good enough okay
on the other hand what what do I mean by
extreme they are certain you know notes
you know these advanced notes they think
they think you need to know regular
expression to such you know for example
when you start to hear automaton you
know here's a dividing line when you
read the article they start to talk
about how regular expression is some NT
a nonterminating some jargon the
automata okay
Oh NFA or you know something like that
when you start to see that I have
articles on that okay we just have to
find it it takes time to you know show
the article but anyway when you started
to hear those jargons in what's what let
me let me find it okay jargons ND a
regular expression let's see if it's
here automata okay Rick jargons automata
yeah here's the thing when you start
when you learn some website about
regular fresh expression just read my
website or we have Frankie Argos for
Python for JavaScript for email is for
for you know for those so when you hear
the word finite state automata okay when
you when you trying to learn regular
expression and you start to hear the
word finite state automata okay
that means that Arco is crap crap okay
don't pay attention you are wasting your
time
the only time those article becomes
useful is when you are actually writing
a parser or compiler now parser is the
is a word that's very abused basically
when you are ready when you are actually
when you are actually working on writing
a compiler then finite state automata
the concept and the you know the the
technology you know what they they are
is important how they relate to regular
expression regular expression is a
automata okay yeah the arrangement of
regular expression came from compiler
theory in NFA and NDA okay that's a
jargon NFA and NDA okay so anyway so let
me summarize regular expression is very
important as a programmer is extremely
practical you want to know it well okay
but but then once you know it well you
know and then you'll come across
articles that talk about finite state
automata in relation to regular
expression with the abbreviation the the
jargon of NDA NFA typically don't pay
attention to them okay and and most of
the time often okay more than 50 percent
of that those are article are just wrong
okay those are like oh are technically
wrong they are garbage information they
are written by people who don't know
what they are talking about but they
want to talk of jargons about automata
about NFA or body okay they're just
wrong most of the time they you know
older articles with those those words
are just incorrect okay technically
incorrect
okay that's that's what I want to say
about that so don't pay attention to
that but however learn regular
expressions that's the most important
thing okay so we have JavaScript regular
expression tutorial let me show you so
we got JavaScript regular expression
tutorials we got then a complete and
complete reference about regular
expression in for JavaScript let me show
you my holocaust so you go to javascript
javascript object reference then you
have a regular expression object you see
as I mentioned before regular expression
is the syntax is basically the same in
every language you are almost the same
in every language but however the way
you call them and you know the way you
work with them is very different between
languages Perl Python JavaScript very
anemic beasts all these for Perl Python
JavaScript
emac beast there the way that you use
regular expressions is entirely
different in each one of these languages
so you have to actually study them but
however the the regular expression
syntax is the same for javascript perl
python but however for eMac this is
varied it's different is slightly
different from the other three
so anyway javascript okay so now you
have the reference javascript reference
for regular expression object and
regular expression syntax in which let
me show you where you know i have
articles about them yeah I have like
five pages about regular expressions for
JavaScript you can you know if you are
JavaScript code and learning it so let
me show you the Python one
so here the Python this is a you know
Python regular expression object match
object that's what it paid on returns
when when you call a rate regular
expression function it returns a match
object so I have like several pages on
Python tutorials and reference you can
just search for Kali Python regular
expression you'll find it then I have a
tutorial for : okay now colon has a
perfect documentation so I have a simple
tutorial that I introduce you how to use
regular expression in colon then if you
want to know more you know go through
the regular expression the colons
official documentation for the regular
expression packages you know again each
deep language to a different view some
the regular expression is a package you
have to import that is a case for Python
and colon but not JavaScript and eMac
this so this all these differences so
anyway my articles okay and Emacs
regular expression to tutorial and I
show you some of the most frequently
used patterns so anyway so that is the
the answer where the regular expression
is important yes very much
yeah so what about incompatibilities
between regular expressions yes
now the regular expression like I said
the regular expression syntax is
basically compatible across JavaScript
Java Perl Python like 99% compatible
they are slightly slightly different
differences but almost you don't run
into them unless you are going to do a
very advanced regular expression so they
are mostly comparable but except eMac
this you know eMac this is kind of
idiotic except all based not just
similes or this with Common Lisp Common
Lisp and eMac this this too I can say
for sure I don't know about skim dis but
however common is an eMac this their
regular expression syntax is quite
different from from the others and it
quite difficult is you got problems you
got toothpick syndromes I have a lot of
cosas on that you know I have a lot of
articles you got toothpicks syndromes
like this okay let me show you
we are about to shut down so where's
show images
we're doing show images anyway let's
just magnify the page though I remember
on the Mac it's different [ __ ] Mac so
you can see you got toothpicks syndromes
regular expression economic magnify
toothpicks syndromes okay I think that's
it that's about it for today how long I
been talking one hour and eight minutes
okay we are over one hour
oh sorry the rejects max master okay
regular expression shell scripts sqi and
see we are live everyone here Jorge is
most likely to correct me a statement
break the loop good morning break the
loop says sir is there a program you
have made in the past that you are proud
of
yes quite a few or an interesting
program you have developed yeah kind of
you let me just Oh Ripper you must have
heard of the expression toothpick
syndrome right anyway so regular
expression I have a lot of Arcos on that
I mean each one I could go into detail
for example this one rejects regular
expression limits or should you read
mastering regular expressions you know
there's this famous book Jesus I don't
have a screenshot of the cover mastering
regular expression so I read that book
back in 1999 do I recommend it yeah it's
kind of year saying no okay
typically you know but I have rants
about again it's people who recommend
this page this book you know this book
is one of the this is a book okay I have
Larry war the creator of Pearl signed it
there's more than one way to do it okay
signed - brain power because I was
working for brain power estada back in
you know so that's my that's my book he
signed it and I took this photo in 2001
but but the signature is actually from
1991 okay so so typically the Nerds
you know the extreme nerds such as on
Hacker News us that you are fine tip you
know you'll find their opinion an
anonymous opinion that tell you oh you
should find a book oh you should read it
these idiots regular expression you know
the UM you know the book is this book
mastering regular expression let me show
you the website okay where's the you
know they have the our picture the
famous our picture let me show you so
let me show so I can remember to i will
compile all these links into microsoft
actual page and later on i'll put on
youtube so you can see all the links so
here's the book mastering regular
expressions very you know alrighty you
know very popular this book is divided
basically into two parts the first part
is teaching you how to use regular
expression in different languages very
popular by the way this book is getting
old so the last update is 2006 15 years
ago so you don't need it you know today
if you code in javascript you just learn
the regular expression javascript if you
code in Python you know you just learn
it you don't need necessarily need a
book practice really you know Rick make
regular expression is one of the such
thing that it's kind of confusing it's
quite it's really quite confusing
because it took me several years to
really feel comfortable know exactly
what's going on it is true you know I
begin my career programming Mathematica
which is very very advanced
you know symbolic Fatima in language
then I mastered power
but even you know but regular expression
really took you several years of
experience to
really sinking to nowhere what's going
on what you know what are these it is
true so take time to learn it okay so
this book is divided into two parts the
first part is teaching you regular
expressions the second part is teaching
you about the theory of regular
expressions that's when you will
encounter the NDF the NEF you know that
you know those jargons the automata
joggins and it's I think part of it is
trying to teach you how to implement
regular expressions and also the history
of regular expressions those part are
not useful and also there's a famous
article from this guy who is working for
Google who is on the team of : now okay
I can you know it takes some time to
find out how come I have links for my
articles so dress code you spend a few
hours reading my articles on regular
expression you'll find all the links and
law of computing history of these people
and you know this guy he by the way this
guy Jeffrey EF fender he lives in Japan
he has a blog he married a Japanese girl
he lives in Japan now in the tranquility
of Japan he has a blog with the photos
of his gardens you know Japanese gardens
and so on you know and you know today
it's probably not worthwhile to buy this
book or read it you know it because it's
in part is old it's 15 years old not
updated today do they have a new version
yeah I don't think they have a new
version you know buk buk kind of died
out you know today in especially today's
program as Millennials they don't care
they don't they don't care of mass
mastery nothing it just you know job
from job language from language you you
work for this company today you just do
this
tomorrow you move on it's a different
language that's that's a situation of
today you become a you know you
corporations can fry you about okay
actually I think that's it for today
I've been rambling quite a lot and let's
see let's go back and let's wrap and
wrap up in close down okay so
so that's a that's my answer about
regular exhibition oh yeah so
what'swhat's the program I've made that
I'm proud of is quite a few actually
let's talk about that next time because
now it's one hour in 15 minutes
thoughts on USA erection and its next
time
oh you haven't got God Jesus guys Jesus
you guys young people and River
you guys have not heard of the
expression toothpick syndrome Jesus
especially you Reaper you should know
well you you you know the concept but
you that I'm surprised you haven't heard
of the term toothpick syndromes like
that that's eMac B's that's regular
expression uni Magnus you know you got
you know other slash in back slashes
escape it escaped escapes and you cannot
you cannot know which one is which
actually I have you know I have quite
you know next time we're gonna talk
about regular expression for one hour
because I have quite a lot of articles
that talks about different issues with
the regular expression I think you would
be interesting
toothpick syndrome okay thank you guys
for coming for the show I'll see you
next time bye
and good morning Kaffee
Google Chrome just crashed I guess I'm
still alive I have to reopen Google
Chrome and end livestream Google Chrome
just crashed and now I'm hungry
I'm gonna get something to eat and hope
you guys are doing well of the
coronavirus of the bad death and because
of the bad death Google now I noticed
that the video we all become available
on YouTube after I think two hours but
however you will not see the live chat
the live chat will become available
after one day until tomorrow so let me
close now have a good day bye guys