welcome to another episode of talk show
so today the
topic is
randomish actually i'm going to code
emac lisp
and uh
so this is a live coding section session
and i'm going to work on my
um
working on my website i'm going to write
you know so you are going to see my
emacs workflow
uh let me show you what i'm gonna write
to uh write about so
so show
sauce talk show so you are going to see
my emacs workflow so
star talk show
i'm going to work on this page
this is emac lisp stream functions
so you go to
you know just search for practical emac
list then you can see my tutorial
you can learn emacs from the ground up
and emac this from the ground up the
most efficient
introduction the least time you spend
and the most
emac lisp learning your get
that's what i say about my tutorial
practical emac bisp so in this uh
tutorial there's a section on all emac
lists string functions so let me show
you where
so writing a script writing a command
interactive form and basic functions
string functions so click on that so you
can see this is how you find the length
of a string
how you find substring how you
join string how you split string
and about five years ago emacs
introduced it
added
about
10 also more string functions about 20
more string functions so this is
somewhat new
and not that many people know about it
so
so i added them here
stream functions for emac bisp and uh
but as you can see most of them are not
fully documented you know i don't have a
documentation here on my tutorial as
opposed to
my documentation for other string
functions for example there's an inline
dot for split string how you split a
string
then you have string two number convert
string to a number or convert the number
to a string or format string so i have
them
uh documented somewhat
but not these new functions
so i've been coding emac these you know
you know in the past week i you know i
code emaclis for the past 15 years but
you know but i started to use these
string functions in recent months so i
want to document them document them so
i'm going to walk through
these and write the tutorial as you can
see how i work in html
so that they become
more you know nice
so you are going to watch my emacs works
workflow and maybe learn something about
emacs hello luis bro
good morning
so if you have any questions about emac
baseball emacs or any programming
related or any
you know
yeah just type any questions okay maybe
i can digress uh past you know maybe
i i'm not sure myself because i i need a
chaotic life
like sometimes someone asked some random
question nothing to do with today's
topic and i spent 30 minutes talking
about that
and sometimes i thought i should be
focused any anyway so if you have a
questions post it there okay love to see
it
so
so today's talk show
and uh of course you are you know this
you are looking at my keyboard this is
kinesis advantage 2 and this is ultimate
hacking keyboard on top i use it as a
macro i talked about that
many times almost in every one of my
videos you go to xrd dot info
and you go to the keyboard section
keywords
and
you know i've done many videos on that
keyboards and you go to
other keyboards ergonomic keyboards and
you can see my reviews of the kinesis
this one
and the ultimate hacking ultimate
hacking that one
and also um
you know many of these are great okay uh
you go buy them
and i specifically i want to shout out
for ex-spouse okay because they sent me
a unit for review but they they sent me
the wrong key switch so i cannot use as
my main i need a light linear switch red
switch but they sent me a brown instead
so anyway this keyboard is also
fantastic you can see
okay you cannot see it you see over
there on the on my bed that's exposed
typically i use it when i'm lying in bed
so you are looking at my keyboard
and uh
and okay let's let's let's do emacs okay
on the pink window is all my emacs
command course
you can see as i move cursor
or
or delete the paragraph delete the
paragraph
you can see the command there all the
commands and keys i press undo undo
you can see undo two times
i'm using soft light keys
and which is a package you can search it
start fly keys
that's a package for emacs keybinding
and i'm using a borac
layout so the keys here is borac
okay let's
okay let's um
let's start to do
any questions comments
okay no
let's start to do
[Music]
emac this okay so i want to document so
this page is about emac these string
functions okay and i'm going to so here
is a nice documentation
um
[Music]
basic stream functions so i'm going to
work on this page copy the url back to
emacs
open it
make a backup show the ping window make
a backup and you need to update the date
you can see here is a date 2021 august
29th and i want to update it to today so
i press a key that calls the command my
personal command
excel update article timestamp
so you can see now the date is 2022.
february 4th today's date
and you can see in browser
it's not refreshed yet let's magnify
now refresh now you can see that's
today's date
so we fixed the date we made the backup
and let's
start to
[Music]
modify
and add documentation for this page so
so
i want to for example move this code
block into this
definition list
okay this this page is not too
consistent
because
because in my early days of writing
emaclis tutorial i do not have the full
documentation like that you see where is
the function name then you have you know
the documentation for that function
but in my so this is later this i added
this kind of
two years
i mean uh two or three years ago for
example let me show you some other
example so you go to emaclis advanced
you can see
list
functions okay let's go
sequence functions okay so these are
this page is a collection of all
functions that works on the sequence
type now sequence type in emac list
means it's a list or a vector a vector
is like a seize array in in
any way so
you know i have i have tutorials about
this
vector anyway sequence function so this
page is a documentation of all sequence
functions and you can see they follow
this format which is a definition list
okay so copy that
open that so i can show you search for
car
search for car
so you can see magnify magnify
so you can see that start with dl dl
means definition list
you see this block that block of code
correspond to these
it's magnified
correspond to these in browser so that's
the format i adopted adopted about two
years ago but before that
but before that i just have code
examples okay so let's go back let's go
back let's go back
let's go back to stream function so you
can see
it just um
close that it's just a
sample code without these uh
kind of formal documentation
so that's why this page is a little bit
not too consistent so i'm wondering
should i started to add you know the
formal style documentation to each and
every one of this function or not
uh let's not worry about it for now okay
because the main thing i want to do is
to add documentation for these okay
and but first of all let's
move this code block into the dl list
okay so
search for substring
there it
is
so here is the code block
cut it
move it here paste it
and back to browser now if i refresh
you'll see
this code
moving up
refresh you see so that's better
so
you know makes it more
uh the structure of the page more clear
any comments
okay no comments okay
so let's start to do some of these okay
let's begin so
stream blank okay so
string
search for blank
so i need to so in so all these are
list you can see they are at least
[Music]
um stream function reference okay so
there's a lot of them i need to do
so
even though they are not documented
documented on my page but i give a link
reference to the official documentation
you can see this is the e-max feature
documentation but now there's a problem
because of the white background okay
that's a problem
you know that problem
let me fix that okay so let's digress
let's go into powershell
powershell the most fantastic shell much
better than bash and let's say xsa
toggle
you know
toggle dark theme
okay
do it
yeah you can see
the power the power of the power shell
you can just call this command your
toggle back theme you know back theme is
one of the controversial topic lots of
my readers you guys demand demanded you
know they people ask me sir when are you
going to have dark theme
i resisted it because dark theme is one
of the fad
but a lot of my you know my readers want
it so i
turns out you know i you know
technically it's trivial to do dark
theme
you know takes 30 minutes just all you
have to do i talked about it before all
you have to do is uh
let's see
theme okay let me show you
dark
let me show you where okay
there it is
so magnify so you can see
this section
let's um
so you are looking at some css smart and
i want to reformat them to a readable
form
so i can do
f9t which caused
css format expand so let me show you so
a little digration okay so so basically
you that paragraph okay
now if i
so that paragraph i want to reformat it
so
to c
here
anyway that doesn't help much but anyway
so this
this section is how you get dark theme
to work so
media is kind of a query so if it says
prefer color theme
now prefer colors theme is the one you
set up in operating system for example
on windows i press windows i
you got these you know windows settings
then you go to personal vacation
then you go to colors and you know
window is idiotic you know all the names
are not consistent so you have one
part about themes but that's not really
about dark theme then you have another
section about colors now this is where
you change the dark theme so you can see
if you set it to light
you know then everything is light
so if you set it too dark
then everything is stuck now if i press
my marker button to go to the powershell
i can call this command you know it
changes that this is my custom function
in powershell and how is it written let
me show you so a lot a lot of equations
but let me show you let me get to it
good
get to it one by one
so powershell okay let's go to
powershell
uh what
that's uh emacs bookmarks so that's that
command is
open file fast
you can find it online
just search for that
then your your you'll find the source
code that
command allows you to open any bookmark
by a simple a few keystrokes
so that's what i did i opened my
powershell bookmark
you know let me do it again so
code press three key to correct then
type pow then there it is my bookmark
open bookmark enter that's this page
then press the button
show it in browser so you are looking at
my powershell tutorial
if you like it
pay me okay this is uh you know this is
i spend a lot of time you know this is
one of the great tutorial because i love
powershell
okay then you go to miscellaneous
examples then here
uh wait where is the
set doc theme
uh let's see
backup script set dark thing yeah so at
the bottom you click on that so here is
how you set dark theme
essentially
essentially you use powershell
to change
values in the
windows registry so this is the line you
need
you know to turn it on or turn it off
then you can encapsulate
it into a function
so
this is the function
toggle.theme so that's how you do it
okay
read it and use it fantastic now let's
go back to
talk show again
open file fast go to
using the bookmark and let's just paste
what we talked about
here
okay and make a link
show in browser so we have it there
now the things above are kind of things
i
want to talk about but we're probably
not going to cover it so anyway so
wait so here okay set dot theme that's
how you do it
now let's go back to
let's go back to our css file so
remember this section is how you do dark
theme
now again
open file fast
type css
then there is my bookmark css index
press enter
show in browser
this is my css tutorial
now
now you go to do i have a section on
dark theme so search for
press this key a key marker search
t-h-e-m-e
oh okay so i don't have a tutorial for
that
which is one of the things i need to do
to write the tutorial for dark theme
so what are you guys here for
do you prefer me to go on with the emac
baseboard am i doing okay random
can you control powershell from emacs
yes we can
that question has been asked before
uh
let me show you okay then okay so can
let me answer that question can you do
it in emacs yeah
so you go to e xiao e show is building
in emacs in every emacs okay then you
just type
pwsh now pwsh
okay
oh invalid argument okay so you need to
um
let's just type
p-o-w-s-h-e-l-l powershell okay now you
are in powershell
now
toggle
now you know you don't have completion
so
let's say xa
t-o-g-g-l-e
theme
okay call my call my personal function
do it
ah object not found because it's not
loaded you know why
anyway so you are looking at powershell
so let's do another command de okay duh
which list directory so you can see
that's the let's do it again
okay the
these directories right that's
powershell uh
version history now there's another
powershell let's magnify
partial variable
which is
i think that's that
no
i don't remember anyway i don't
i haven't set it up properly you know so
so what i'm saying is that
with emacs by default you can run
powershell without installing any
third-party packages
so
powershell comes in two versions
okay i'm digressing over so powershell
you know to explain all these things
so powershell you know if you follow my
tutorial you can see powershell comes in
two versions one is the full name is
powershell the other one is pwsh
basically powershell was
microsoft.net powershell that's for
windows only
but beginning
around 2016
microsoft made powershell open source
and microsoft also made the entire.net
framework open source that includes the
c sharp language the f sharp language
with f sharp is the derivative of o
chemical
functional language like pascal
and our camera is derivative of
ml meta language or standard ml
okay you know
you know you know
originally you have meta language
then you have standard
mental language sml then you have object
meta language oml then you start to have
then you have
[Music]
and categorical object
meta language something that's ocamo
okay so ocamo is analogous it's very
similar to haskell
and it's
much more applications has has been
written in camel
so and then
f-sharp is microsoft's version of ocamo
okay microsoft
you know created a version of ocamo
that's called f-sharp and that's part of
the.net
platform.net you know c sharp f sharp
among other
things like visualbasic.net
uh
so
so that's digression so so powershell is
also based on.net okay but before 2016
it's all microsoft only you can only run
it on microsoft and it's proprietary but
beginning in 2006
team
microsoft made them all open source so
the entire.net and c-sharp
f-sharp powershell
and dot-net libraries and and and the
runtime system and the
anyway it's all open source
so that is why now you have two commands
now
every window opening system comes with
powershell the original windows only
powershot
okay i explained them in detail here
but beginning with powershell version
six
you know
it's called powershell uh core
which is the open source version they
microsoft no longer developed the
microsoft only version anymore but
however every windows
comes with powershell for example gcm
okay gcm stands for get command okay for
example i type gcm
powershell
you can see
that is the
executable name of the powershell and
that powershell is original microsoft
only powershell comes with any
every window 10 since windows
7 or something
since basically 2010
something like that
but now if you want the cross platform
powershell the command name is is pwsh
okay so that's why you have two versions
one of them the open source version you
have to install it runs on linux runs on
mac
you know
cross
platform and
so
i was showing in isha in emacs issue
so you can launch um
[Music]
you can launch um
you can launch you know like uh let's
say exit okay exit
so right now i'm isha so you can launch
powershell
but so you see
it run powershell but it doesn't know
it wasn't able to find pwsh
so
what i need to do is i need to launch
that
via the full path so how do i find the
full path so help gcm
so gcm is an alias for get command okay
which is equivalent analogous to the
unix
which you know the unix which command
so you're looking at gcm so let's see
the documentation i want to see the full
path of the pwsh okay
so let's see
yeah let's see
uh where is it gcm okay gcm get commands
named
too much to read
but i believe i think it's um
option wait wait gcn
pwsh
pipet2
uh
full name
i don't know yeah i'm not
okay does that work no
let's try that okay
i'm not
expert at powershell yet okay so
okay
so right now i'm trying to find the full
path of pwsh
via this way
we are the get
get command
command okay but there's an easier way
the easier way is to just um
just do this
version table ps version table okay
ps version table okay
then it shows you version edition uh
yeah where but where is the full path
okay version table
okay i want to know the full path of
pwsh
um
you know this you know
so um
okay so yeah anyway anyway let's skip
that you know i can find it but it takes
me two minutes or so it's kind of boring
so
so anyway so you can run in eshop
without installing any package now there
is also a package for running powershell
you can install for mailpad but
i would recommend just stick with uh
um well not
okay so it's i mean it's up to you you
can stick with you know
each other and okay
so i can i can run powershell but do i
have um
no completion okay d-o-g-g-r-e
toggle
let's see toggle dog theme right
there it is okay so yeah
okay so here is uh what to do okay
now i know now we found out okay close
this
cure it yes okay let me show you how to
do so
first of all go to e-shell each issue is
building
then start powershell
okay now you are running powershell now
once you are in powershell then it it
knows the path to be pwsh now you start
pwsh
okay now
now it loads all my you know functions
now you can i can cook star dark theme
um
you know
copy it
paste it
there it is
fantastic run it again dark theme tagota
nothing fantastic
power of powershell in power of isha and
power of emacs
of course who you have to write that so
that's the power of emac this today's
topic so powershell so we talked about
dark theme dark theme
you know
toggle dark theme and but we need to fix
this page this emax
manual on my website that's one of the
problem of dark theme okay dark theme
let me let me get back to the css
uh
let me get back to the css
technology again so top theme in theory
this is all you need you know just
check
check the system preference if the
user's operating system
is set to dark then all you have to do
is body background color black and color
text color white that's all you have to
do and also change the link color
because normally a blue link is hard to
read
when it's when the background is black
okay that's all you have to do basically
just this
you know five lines of code
to make your website dark thing
but however
then you got this run into lots of like
little problems such as
let's make it dark such as these
you know
text disappear
sometimes it's
sometimes it's images that disappear you
know image with transparent background
that just disappear so you have to fish
them out so that
so it takes 10 minutes to create a dark
theme css for your website but if your
website if your website has 10 000 pages
like mine written in the past 20 years
then
lots of those pages will have this
disappearing text so you have to
actually find them each you know so it's
takes me a week almost yeah
to
fix lots of them and now we are running
into another one
okay
so but before we do anything let's
return the format here okay so okay so
there that's my
that's my original format
close that okay close that
so now let's show the talk show wait
what page am i on show the talk show
close that
copy
css back to my talk show let's
paste the topics we talked about here
okay
powershell copy that
paste it here
and
back here
emacs page
emacs this documentation
on characters and strings paste it here
we talked about
and this keyboard you know someone was
talking someone was talking about this
keyboard this is a japanese
keyboard very popular in the 1980s
but mostly in japan although it's
specified by microsoft you know very
interesting this keyboard is interesting
because we get to see
the different historical arrangements of
the arrow key to say the least okay you
can see the arrow keys
arranged in in kind of a cross way
and you can see another one here
and here it's a bit different you know
it's like
you know it's side by side left and
right arrows and above and below them
you have up and down arrow
so
here same thing
okay
then you have a cross then you have you
have this arrangement you know
different arrangements of the arrow key
that's another topic i have an article
on that
um which is what is the most efficient
arrangement of the arrow keys
for example normally it's like
inverted t that's a standard version
inverted t then you also have in a row
like the
like the vi you know hjkl
i have an article on that and i did a
video a year ago about that
okay so anyway so
we haven't finished about the dark theme
yet because we need to fix that website
okay so hold on a second so
so this page is wrong
this link
let me just fix it
okay
so anyway we
so we want to fix this
emac lisp
page okay so let's do that
so what is the problem here so the
problem we need to find so what is this
say char equal so go to the top search
for
char
equal okay so here is the line
um
and the d l so d l that's that and where
is the code that's the example part okay
pre
pre-class example
okay pre-class example so
now let's go pre-class example
let's go to my css
group style css
that's the the problem is caused by this
gnu free software foundations css okay
so
let's comment that out
refresh yeah
so
i don't want i don't want that
so you see this line is a problem
this is gnu you know this is
you are looking at the mirror of the gnu
free software foundation's
emac this documentation on my website
and uh you know so they have their
custom css
and which is incompatible with doc theme
okay so i'm going to fix it how are you
gonna fix it just by removing it
because
you know i because i i spent an hour the
other day looking at their css
uh you know
so
i
i'm going to remove it so what i do
so now if you drop down to the diode
directory you can see
here's here's the files
so there are 1000 of them
so for each one of them you open it
search for css you can see
it's
loading that gnu css
open it so that's a gross css so you you
so what you want to do i want to remove
this line of code for all these 1000
pages okay
so what i do is
i'm just gonna do it okay
so
call this command
find replace
paste that line
enter
replace string enter blank
in this directory no emax menu
yes enter
file path regular expression html
enter
minimal depth
0 max the depth 99
right changes to file yes
fixed case in search yes
fixed case in replacement yes
make backup yes okay it will take 10
seconds to do the all the replacements
so this is one of my package start find
and replace okay very super convenient
okay it's done so you magnify so you can
press left right arrow to see
the replacement you see now you are
seeing
now you are seeing empty bracket because
the replacement is empty you know we
simply deleted it and each of the pink
line is the file name so you can scroll
down all the way you know it takes
there are a thousand basically a
thousand replacements so a number
a number before the file name means how
many changes occurred so it's one so you
just scroll down you hold down the right
arrow key you just
go to the next occurrence next
occurrence of this you know mini so you
can see
so now if you
move to any one of them press enter to
open the file you can see
that line is gone
now when shown in browser you can see um
you know that's how this page looks in
browser so that's done so that's how i
change
actually more than 1000 because if you
go to the dial directory you can see
this is emac this manual go up one
directory you can see
i changed both the emac this manual and
the emacs menu so let's open the emacs
manual you can see it also made the
backup
you know all these are
let's magnify
remove hide the hide the
irrelevant information
you can
and again you can see all my commands in
the pink window you see diode high
details mod that's how i hide the
the date the own the the unix thing you
know owner group
permission you know 666
[Laughter]
this this w
rw
rw that means 666 my friends
which has significance
in white men society but i don't know
that you know because i was i'm chinese
when i came to usa i didn't know what
what is 666 why are these people talking
about it all the time
what's a big deal
but
all the white people knows about it
because that's part of your history
i didn't know you know in chinese six is
a lucky number six six six in particular
is the luckiest number like when you
thought that is the only six six six
because that the pronunciation of the
number six
corresponds to
the word for luck okay in chinese
like longevity but
like live long and prosper prosperity
that's what 666 means different culture
different meaning okay so that so we
happen to upon the unix
final name permission 666 okay
which i need to show
linux practical linux tutorial
you know just go to my website you'll
find it xrd practical linux tutorial and
scroll down
and you'll see a page about file
permissions the unix cryptic file file
permission system
there it is sys file permission you know
the permission the root wheel group
owner group file name and you know root
you know pseudo
esoteric
crap the worst design possible the unix
file name system the unix uh permission
system the worst hack possible of the c
lineage
the grand daddy of everything that's
wrong
in computing industry
unix okay
unix file name permission system okay
let's go back to talk show let's we
digressed
and digressed okay hold on a second unix
file name permission system and go back
linux tutorial
copy
so i have a record what we talked about
we're gonna get into them one one one
and one one by one okay so now we
show this in browser so you can see
there okay
uh now we go back to fixing this page
okay so we go back yeah so let's let me
show you the
find and replace okay
so first of all i
if you look at the pink window you you
can see
now i call describe key
by a key then i press the command okay
wait
i call what
yeah
i call describe key then i press the key
to launch
find replace okay which is
that okay so you can see this key runs
start find replace text and tab
to the source code enter
you are looking at the source code of my
package xsa find
which is find and replace and grab and
set
in emac list so 700 lines if you like it
pay me to get it okay
show in browser so this is a home page
for saw find replace package which i
demonstrated many times and you have
just seen
paste it here
okay so we have just fixed
let's go back here
yeah so
we should you know now if we refresh it
should be fixed let's refresh this
finger okay one key button one button
press
do it
fantastic
dark thing fixed a dark thing problem
for
800 pages
so you can see go back to the uh
yeah
we read from disk yes you see
that gnu style is gone
that's good
uh and
if i were doing this on my own there's
more things to need to fix because you
see
you see that that part of that is hidden
so i need to add um
i need to uh change my css and add a
little bit um
okay so anyway let's i'm gonna fix it
offline okay
so now we started to have more people
something like witch command that's
right
tong tong gossat
you guys the weird names
luis says who has unix culture still
gets excited when emacs every day
yes
that's you know that's a big history
about that topic
you know remember
where does emacs come from emacs came
from
free software foundation free software
foundation foundation's gnu project
and what does gnu means gnu means gnu is
not unix
you know that's history very interesting
why because richard snowman
hated unix why because unix was
the proprietary corporation run by the a
t and t empire the death star
okay we digressed so much you know
as time goes on history gets twisted
nobody knows what's going on
and think that oh gnu you know emacs is
part of
unix you know actually it's more you
know nothing could be further away from
that
emacs
is which is so much foundation you know
gnu is not unix they make fun of unix
because they are not in the same
community
richard stowman because unix is
proprietary you know they they they
making money and stuff
and
also the e-max camp
is part of the lisp
community
this community is the enemy of the
unix and sea community the you
know i mean this community camp
you know eunuchs and c
the criminals of the computing industry
on the other hand their enemy you know
the mutual enemies is the least they
think about things differently
differently
so emacs is part of the unix i mean the
part of the glue the lisp
uh camp
nothing to do with unix
but you know but then you know you just
don't you know anyway
uh so we
so now we let's uh refresh the directory
so you can see all the back backups that
saw find made you know for you know
a thousand files uh
okay close that so let's i mean i want
to double check
the changes i made okay so
back to here
okay
uh yeah so let me mention okay so since
we are talking about that let me mention
a a few more things okay but before we
do that let me fix
this um
you know there's a
there's a
bug in my html file i need
some html mod i need to fix because it
doesn't link the
uh let me do it now okay
yeah okay now it's fixed so
okay show in browser let's
show in browser
so this is what we talked about
powershell dark theme
toggle
the toggle command
uh powershell install print version
learn how to run emacs yeah let's write
down what we did
because it's better that way for people
who are not watching me online
in real time they can see this is
what actually
i talked about instead of just a bunch
of links so dark thing
how to do so let's you know write down
what we talked about
how to do
dark theme in css
five minutes
one
minutes of five
lines of code
but
if you
if you have a thousand html pages return
in past 20 years
you have a lot to fix
disappearing inks
okay
that's what
and this powershell
a function
in powershell to
toggle
dark theme
okay that's a function in powershell to
toggle dark theme
uh what
okay i think we have some way
go down
now
this i'm not gonna do today so let's
i need to remove them okay so
a function in powershot to do to toggle
dark theme how to do dark theme in css
in one minute but lots of disappearing
inks
now how to and then how to run
powershell in isha okay
how to run powershell in emacs okay so
that is that
about
then we have visual css
let's move that
here
refresh
visual css how do you do dark theme for
your website for your blog
okay then
we were talking about
emac this so we haven't started to talk
about that yet you know the stream
functions and i was working on that
and find and replace package of xar
you know find replace package buy it
okay pay me support me sponsor me
paypal patreon and you guys you know if
you like my video buy me a drink
however how much however much that cost
in your
abode in your trading place in your
location in your country
so
find replace package then we have
practical linux tutorial which we are
talking about linux file permission okay
yeah so
but
um but i want to show you something else
something else something else
you'll see it here okay just give me one
you go down the eunuch's pestilence
okay
it's almost like every
um i need to show that in every one of
my videos unix pestilence okay the
history of unix so why why why why show
this page because
we traced back to the
history
of unix you see a t and t
here is where a t and t came mean where
bsd is poking a hole of the atnt
death star
so a t death star we talked about
yesterday so let me show you
okay so go to hacker code
hacker code
then you'll find a page about logos
design in software industry open it
you'll see
all the greatest logos in the history of
software you know some of them great
such as the sgi logo the company
the company no longer exists
bought by oracle
samba samba you know the grand daddy
that's file sharing between windows on
the mac between windows and mac that's
what you it's what you need samba open
source
but it's microsoft technology thank you
microsoft since 1990s samba fire sharing
network technology
so if you have a mac if you have a
windows you need to share files between
them that's samba that's behind the
scenes you know
you know apple also you know um
you know
ported it to the mac you know
and and on linux you know whenever you
need to share files
files with windows that's what you do
so but we are showing this page because
i want i wanted to show the a t and t
death star
which which is one of the greatest logo
design
in the logo design history
you know logos you know you guys don't
know you may not know because you guys
are notes you know logo is one of the
big things uh in in in graphics design
you know in general it's called
communication art okay so
the f-sharp logo for example is the
worst idiotic crab so there's a there's
a madness to it there's
how to design logo what constitutes a
good logo
what is a bad logo you know many of the
people they don't know you know the
coders for example they yeah so i want
to okay so purpose of logo and principle
of logo design
so you can see
here is an example of the greatest logo
okay java
gnu you know this benevolent gnu
you know
means an animal you know that can some
kind of antelope you know in
wild beast in in africa that's what gnu
is so glue the the free software
foundation their project new their logo
is the gnu head gnu's logo is a gnu
so this is one of the
great
elements of a great logo design you you
want to
remind people of what it is
and also this smiling
gnu you know that's what that's kind of
the mentality the attitude of the free
software foundation
communism sharing you know benevolent
that's what it is so java you know java
is a drink you coffee coffee drink
microsoft windows you can you can see
this kind of window you know microsoft
windows you know then apple all these
are great logo designs
except maybe except this pearl
the pearl idiocy
so you know in mcdonald's everyone knows
xiao honda yamaha you know taco bell
wikipedia the puzzle you know the
jigsaw puzzle of the words
languages you know
wikipedia um
let's see this is svg right so let's
magnify
see them in glorious
magnification
wikipedia logo great design you know it
takes it takes designers to do that
uh but
then there it is a t and t death star
nicknamed death star by people at t oh
it's png i don't have the svg so
so
you know i mentioned at t from unix you
know that's what
that poking at at t that's what you know
that's a t's logo you know atnt was the
greatest empire
in what in 1970s to 1980s
could the biggest empire like
what you might think of google
running the whole earth kind of they
what they do they do communication they
control communication just like today's
google and facebook at t and they the
unix unix came from at t you have to
thank at t thank you at t for creating
linux
for us
you open source it
so att and ati ati is dead ati is bought
by um you know this company ati is ati
is bought by amd you know 80 i became
amd then amd became china
i think
wait i'm not sure anyway so
so that's you know apache and like the
lying scumbag apache you know apache the
name
they came from a patchy patchy you know
patch you patch your server you know
like the open source spirit you know you
write you know lots of bugs so use
it doesn't work and you look into the
source code you fix it and you patch it
you know today you don't use the word
patch much anymore because you use
github or before that mercury and and so
on
but but before the you know that osvn
you know
but even so in the 90s and 2000s
patching is common you don't have a you
don't have a you know you may not you
may or may not have a
version control system for your software
but you use patch you know you make a
change you send the patch to someone
that's that's the origin of the name
apache
[Music]
but now after 10 years after 15 years on
their website apache
they say oh
you know they have a faq frequently
asked questions why is why is apache
named apache oh oh that's because we
respect the american or you know the
indian people
where the white people massacred
genocide
now is the time for google to ban this
youtube
the white people general wiped out clean
wiped out the red skin people
but we respect them we respect they are
the greatest people we must respect them
apache the tribe the indian the risking
therefore we named our software apache
[Laughter]
sari apache
name okay search for it i have an
article on that
apache we write history you know so
here's a version from 1997
they're a fish from their official
website why is apache named apache oh oh
that's because it's just a cute name
you know let me magnify so you can see
oh it's just a cute name which stuck
apache is a patchy server
it was based on some existing code and a
series of patch files you know patch
files that's what what you do
then
fast forward to 2013
why the name apache oh the name apache
was chosen from respect for the native
american indian tribe of apache
the open source that's
you guys
those are views you know open source you
need to open those it
nobody knows you know like nobody oh
that's okay you know then then this
article got you know i how do i know
because
back then 1997
apache is one of the technology i'm
deeply
involved with you know i'm doing you
know the dot-com days you know we we
we write the
one of the first
e-commerce software like yahoo store
like amazon we write the first
e-commerce software system so that
third parties such as yahoo or verizon
they can run our software and
create a e-store and with lots of
merchants you know they can sell like
you know
like
adi expressway you know adi expressway
you know like amazon
so i was writing that then back then
apache we use apache so i know a lot
about apache 20 years ago i woke up you
know
and i was
kind of i'm part of the unix open source
spirit i'm for richard stowman i'm for
you know the ethic you know the you know
the
not open source but the free software
foundation that's a proper you know not
just oh it's this oh just it's not let's
forget let's don't talk talk about
ethics let's just say let's just make
them open open source focus on that so
that corporations can feel at the ease
you know i was against that
so i was more for the rich assortment
but you know as you get old you realize
uh things are not they weigh the way
they are and you know it got worse it
you know after 20 years it becomes very
bad and now you have this apache openly
lying about the you know the openly this
what what are these people
malenchen programmers and all today's
you guys zoomers the
you know you have this situation they
openly
lie on their website oh because we
respect native americans and back then
in the 1990s
the that
native american tribe apache you know
there there's a fight for the domain
name okay apache
see now it's like now it's beautiful
apache the apache so for your foundation
established 1999 oh
this age respect skunks
you know with you know apache kong with
the heart of the heads these these
these are the people the white people
that genocide
the redskins people and they say oh you
cannot say red skin that's oh that's
that's that's
that's that's something
the heads it is these social
justice warriors and and and apache oak
you know back then two
20 years ago
the tribe
was fighting for that domain name
because apache that's you know what's
their tribe's domain but apache
uh i forgot what they do but they
basically i think the tribe sued apache
you know they want the domain back but
apache says no go yourself go
yourself we have apache we are a bit
so today's generation you guys you know
don't know you know history you know
it's forgotten now you have new
generation and and you think oh let's do
open source let's help humanity
oh look at that there's a guy he's a bad
guy he doing what the he's like uh
evil
okay so that's a lot of digression into
this uh
angry stuff typical you know it's
fairly common in my
talk show
these open source skunks
you know i you know remember i was open
source i was pro not open source i was
pro richard storm and free software
foundation you know i've been banned
for you know for for for saying good
things about richard someone and stuff
i've been banned in you know many places
but you know things turn around and you
know like
and new generation and
massive brainwashing you don't know what
you're talking about like a lot of you
people you know don't know what you're
talking about using you know
and i suppose
that happens a lot in history that's how
you know the generation the cycle turns
that's that's how things are
okay so i talked about
an hour over hour already
and i don't think we started to do what
we originally began to do
uh
yeah so unix pestilence apache we write
history
so here is the documentation of it
and it's been on hacker news okay it's
been posted to hacker news um and a lot
there's a lot of stories you know a lot
of this controversy or the many of the
open source guns doing things
um
turns up but you don't know it you don't
know it because google don't want you to
know google facebook they don't want you
to know and microsoft today
they are all pro open source they they
are the they are the blood that runs
open source they without their money
open source dies right off
and ubuntu and red hat you know google
is putting money into them
so that google so that
so that if you are a software programmer
the only way to survive is to work for
google or microsoft or facebook
if you make a complaint if you say men
are not women or they are not the same
thing you know you'll get wiped and
there's nothing you can do that that's
the power of open source
okay so another open source rent
so what to do next i think i'm going to
read comments
i i'm going to read comments and
originally
so i'm not i'm i'm going to shut down
okay so
see i talked about that today i talked
about logos
we talked about logos and
do i have this here
logo design okay no so add it there
close it i'm about to close i think
so i'm gonna read comments answer some
questions and close so here is the gnu
emacs website
refresh i need to fix that part okay so
what else css we talked about
how shall we talk about close
ms
msx computer okay let's put the page
here
uh
yeah
close
notes close
okay that okay
uh
so i'm gonna just read comments and we
shut down in three minutes i think
so originally
i was doing yeah this page
yeah i was going to do some workflow but
msx in brazil okay cool yeah i heard
that mxs
computer i mean is also popular in
brazil
justin scarfie just in scarf i say
something more than how are you
hello cortes fantastic cortes
talent
kekma
okay kekma kik
uh
you've seen people who love both see and
this well
not really i mean yeah of course you can
they are just they are always in the
opposite camps okay
uh
ng
engines okay yeah so makes you wonder
what you will brainwash into your
generation no
okay not much comment uh i think that's
it
okay bye guys