good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa show
today's 2019 October 17th Thursday 10 o
clock a.m. in the morning San Francisco
time good morning Bart so Bart says
topic number seven lady let's see what
is number seven have it keyboard a great
choice part in my life are you alive so
okay topic number seven have it kibo
fantastic keyboard actually I was going
to show you guys you see now this is my
usual Kinesis keyboard let's try this
hold on second let's try the full head
if that works easy so this is my
Canisius keyboard
so I'm alive and you are like and I was
going to show you this ultimate hacking
keyboard I haven't done I haven't shown
it showing video I I have I haven't
shown video of this keyboard for a while
last time I showed this is almost half a
year ago so so but actually have it
keyboard is a great choice so let's do
that then so let's unplug this and let
me get my Harvard keyboard okay now over
there that's my bed you see as I live I
live like I am a ascetic and I live like
a hermit in in the city okay
a cyst City metro prolly Metro palace
city hermit and like a monk so I sleep
you know it's like you know you see we
just sleep on the floor and in fact I
have been doing that for the past 20
years since since year 2000 no TV no
nothing oh of course I still have the
ultimate hacking keyboard but I can i
it's not proper for me to savor it
because they gave me a copy for review
you know I'm doing every bit for them
okay let me get the the other keyboard
[Music]
that is the habit keyboard you cannot
see it let's see if I can figure out
some way so that you can see it
good morning Green deck in only webcam
scene he uses different make probably
from the webcam oh okay yeah so let me
try to hold your channel audio input
capture Archie tech headset now is it
better is it me or does not have was
sound quality yeah it is it is it is the
latter okay there we have it you know
it's a let's just check it out and there
it is let's see this camera sucks
okay this logitech camera sucks so it
cannot focus closely let's see if I can
do that is it focused I think it is so
this is a hobbit keyboard but actually
it has lights and this is just about
nothing special to it and that let's
plug it in so it's USB okay the smaller
one is USB I don't know I don't know how
you code but it's like that
it's standard plug and you plug one side
to it and let's see and the other side
is like that yeah so there you have it
Oh lights come up yeah Mac says keyboard
setup assistant no thank you
so it's shiny it's it's bright it's you
know it's showing the lights actually
let me turn off let's try this new way
let's put that away
and let's put this here so you can see
they are actually about the same size
you know as far as the width goes but
let me turn off the lights I mean close
my window
so this keyboard is fantastic this is
not a keyboard I can use because I need
economic keyboards like that so I do not
use this you know but it's a great
keyboard and it's got faint mechanical
keys same and kind of go keys let me
show you some typing actually so I have
to you know I need money to buy cams to
buy quality cam stuff in the stands and
all that
and see how do I do
okay and okay now if I do some typing
you cannot see my to switch to Emacs
okay
switch to Emacs oh you know I am used to
them being separate so this is gonna be
oops incorrect good this is corty ok
this this I do not think it's
programmable but actually I have a
website about that hold on a second it
Scottie but I'm using a lower class so
now I have to go to my I have to go to
my Mac to change the keyboard layout to
quote e I don't even have it there pain
is simplified okay comments monk food
yeah what Amir India I it's the only
kind saying is use different make a
properly from webcam it's me over the
sky well that's better okay better yeah
so you go to Mac you want to add a black
keyboard layout okay so you go there and
you scroll down and you pick English and
English for rack okay add okay now close
this there you have it now you go to the
top switch to ball rack now a mean ball
rack now I can type with Safra kissing
Emacs one second it's your us because
because I have application dependent
layout okay now it's for rack okay so
you see first so let me show you my
Emacs command taps lock
I don't want caps lock so
okay so you know it's I haven't been
using this keyboard so everything is
wrong I need to set my Emacs up now
where is the maitake I think it's this I
[Applause]
want to press w you see what's going on
okay Roy RAK ah over this window now is
it Scotty again stupid now I'm gonna
have a major problem when I totally
confused okay now I need to press escape
escape ass and defined ctrl G then I
press the wrong key because I was typing
Vorik ctrl G you should be caught he you
okay now I'm good now switch window you
see magnify and split window okay and
oops I didn't see window what
okay I want to split window wait wait
what is that key doing
that is doing previous user buffer why
is that
oh okay so what what key am i typing now
okay so and you see it's gets very
complicated because the vorak and let's
launch Event Viewer so that way I will
know what qiyam I'm pressing so what is
this key this key is what okay so I know
what's going on because you see it's
fairly complicated because I mean it's
because there's an issue of Warrick they
are versus Cortile out I don't know
which one I'm in so you then then there
is the issue of me you see this I'm
using this this is a numerical keypad
okay and now I have programmed that so
each key on this keypad is does
something like switch window last window
previous window next tab close tab
magnify zoom out things like that so in
order to do that because that is not a
program programmable keypad so in order
to program keys on that I use this
application called carob carabiner on a
Mac okay so now this is getting
complicated now this is a numerical
keypad now this is made by truly
hoggonomics okay however there is
something special about this keypad
because this is not just a average
numerical keypad okay you take uh some
explanation so let's do it then let me
explain what's going on so keep at you
go to keypads and my my webpage you know
keypad these are programmable keypads
that means they have memory inside you
can program the keys but however the
truly organ AMA keypad and
using is a normal numerical keypad like
this cheap like you can get them for $10
or something $15 okay so this okay so
let me actually use my Kinesis keyboards
and now I have to switch the layers this
is getting very complicated
I don't want scratch password it not
hurt what what okay
close that go to the South talk-show and
open a new buffer that's so copy that
and go here and paste okay now let me
explain what is going on
okay
bubblegum okay bubblegum throw it away
because I didn't pay attention that's
probably annoying to you you probably
are hearing it so how do you get
efficient with so many keys
you see if every key has very long
command marker became pretty pretty
efficient well this keyboard has has
buttons okay so anyway so let me
explain what's going on so god this is
so much to do so much to do to do a
professional videos livestream like like
what I'm doing professional okay so this
remember this is truly organ ohmic
numerical keypad it's not programmable
but however it's a bit different from
normal the miracle keypads now this one
you buy you see on a PC key keyboard you
have the numerical keypads on the side
you see on on the right side typically
and they send different signals they
sent number signals different from the
numbers on top row of the keyboard they
are different signals okay so when you
buy a numeric keypad they send the
numbers on the numerical keypad those
signals not not you know not the top row
of the numbers but however however on
this truly economic keypad they actually
send the same signal as the as as you
know as the number keys on top of the
keyboard okay they did that
intentionally because this truly organ
ami keypad is designed let me show you
actually best numeric keypad okay you
have wireless mechanical keys you
have missed oh this is all so while I
don't know wireless or not but it's got
lights and you have these Scott lights
and okay so this is the truly economic
numeric keypad I'm using and they are
sending this they are not sending the
keypad numeric signals they are sending
that number key you know or the standard
key signals they do that because they
designed they designed their numeric
numeric keypad to be used with Excel
they think they think it's better that
way okay because that way you don't have
to worry about toggling the number lock
number lock button right so our normal
keyboard you have the number lock key
number lock you know like like over here
you know this key number lock you know
if I press it that's going on wise right
not lighting up so anyway they are not
you know the numerical numeric keypad
signals there for now because this is
not programmable and but I need to
program it to be functional keys
therefore I use the Mac carabiner
carabiner Jesus I cannot talk anymore
carabiner elements okay this this
software allows me to program the
keyboard but I have to do some tricks
because because when I press the number
six here it needs to be different from
the number six key I press on my main
keyboard so I have to do some tricks
there
therefore but now since now since you
know normally I'm using this keyboard
but now since I just plugged in this one
and I have have not prepared this
keyboard so now when I press the number
6 key it's actually doing some kind of
mock Wow
you know it's it's actually doing Marco
the same thing I programmed on this
keypad so that is very confusing that is
why do you see so do you guys is it
clear do you understand what I'm saying
so therefore now I'm going to do some
typing demo on this keyboard the first
thing I need to do is I need to quit
carabiner carabiner quit so that when I
press the number keys on this keyboard
will not do weird things so now we can
go back here and now we need to switch
back to Borak okay and now if I can you
have to you know we have the key keys
now when you use a normal keyboard I
feel like you know I'm kind of crushed
into this bit of space okay split
it's what and what is it doing
Clara thoughts extempore that's about
something anyway yeah it's too you know
I guess I don't think you guys are too
interested in this are you what is key
what I said I just quit Carol by now
it's it didn't yeah it's not quit
okay now quit are you sure yes shut the
up
okay now let's split the window now it
works you see split window unsplit okay
now close this buffer close this buffer
you don't need it now switch back to our
talk show why are you doing that
okay now just go to a talk show there it
is this is today's topic open and oh we
don't have it anything here so anyway so
there is there it is I'm typing on this
keyboard and it's got okay so it's got
lights you can the lights you can turn
off actually
okay this is fantastically bad I don't
know what I'm doing
how am I gonna do this I'm gonna show
changing the lights to uniform color but
but first of all I need to get the
camera okay there and you cannot see the
food theme but anyway press f1 function
1 ok function to a function f1 ok now
now you see only some of the key slide
up I'm not sure why exactly because I
think it's for gammas you see this 1 to
6 are light up now let's try F n F 2
then different set of keys light up I
guess this is for first-person shooters
then F n f3 then some other weird thing
ok FN f4
ok bad weird FN f5 now f n f6 now we are
back to the rainbow thing I don't like
the rainbow I don't want them to move so
FN f6
okay it's like this ok too flashy F n f7
ok now it's like a bomb okay anyway
that's about you know there is you know
there are several pre-programmed effects
I don't think you can program them I'm
not sure I
so what are we doing now but anyway it's
got you know this thing mechanical keys
which are very good and we can take it
off to show you so let's do that
this I got from a keyboard needed you
know this is parks parks switch from tie
off and this is a keyboard puller
it's okay there it is so that's the
mechanical that's that that is the
mechanical key oh that's nice June June
okay I think that's it for that so any
questions for this keyboard it's for
this back
I want to go here I want to open a new
Emacs window and and press this key down
let's see if I can type okay
something something in the water does
not compute
Oh does it and we decide what is real
and what is an illusion okay let's get
back here oh you didn't see my windows
yeah so anyway so that is about that
keyboard I think no I think I switch
back to vorak unless there's more I mean
a switch - am I too quiet
am I too quiet now I don't I'm good
right congratulations
you won't bathroom you thanks among
everyone we greetings Derek Derek just
ingredients Justin
Derek morning okay so no questions okay
so let's put back switch everything back
to my usual saw mod unplug the unplug
this
and now I'm back to my Kinesis advantage
and in fact go to the keyboard
preference and remove the vorak layout I
don't need it because I have hardware
for ranked it does not hurt to have an
option there but actually does because
whenever you switch sometimes I need to
switch to Chinese input and borax
varrock gets in a way you know you have
to switch between them so close that no
safe so santoku index and that that is
about that so let me get to the
questions comments
oh it's Verena okay so so it's just copy
and now I need to turn back
the karabiner elements so that my so
this keypad will become Marco keys again
okay so you guys go buy it okay bye
stuff bye to help the economy
okay bye it you guys go bye
okay close that what is this Oh run this
is interesting
so Mart Matt Matt says what's your
opinion on staying on the home row on
the keyboard that's so good well if you
do touch-type that's what you have to do
I tend to have my hands spread further
than recommend it spread like what do
you mean like like what well I guess you
need a keyboard with large sized keys
something like that like what you mean
spread you you do you mean you put your
you rest your hands on the upper row
instead of the home row okay
Bart says I really like neo2 home row
neo2 that well that's that's a German
layout so what they are are you using
part
okay so Matt says my index fingers are
not staying on the F and J keys okay now
I assume you are using a normal keyboard
okay so there's many many interesting
things about keyboard but it's let's
look at them
so surely okay so yeah so you are saying
I'm assuming is that correct Matt you
are using a normal like PC keyboard like
these so you are saying your hand do not
rest on index finger do not rest on the
F&J keys I have heard that other people
say that because first the reason for
that is mostly because the standard PC
keyboard they are not economic they are
not designed for it I mean they do not
they are just right so you are using a
Mac you go they are you know the PC
keyboards just a flat very good slap a
fat a slap slab okay it's just a piece
of flat surface it's not economic so if
you use you know if you use a economic
keyboard like this then it will probably
be different so Bob says I want to
switch to neo2 but I still didn't get on
a proper solution on how to change the
key caps or annotate them I have a side
keyboard I changed I changed to neo 2
but the keyboard is not as good what do
you mean you cannot change well if you
have a mechanical keyboard with Cherry
MX switches then certainly each it's
trivial to you can buy key caps and it's
trivial to change them so
right our normal keyboard of course you
cannot normally normal you know like no
mechanical keyboard keys you can easily
change the key caps so so yeah you have
to buy a you have to buy a
mechanical keyboard you know of all
these actually are all mechanical keys
most of them are Cherry MX switches
meaning that you can easily trivially
buy keycaps to to whatever layout you
want for example look at this one you
know you can actually this one is oh
yeah special made keycaps you know this
one is from South Asia now you may you
may not recognize these artworks and
characters but if you are in Asia you do
recognize it this is Phoenix this is
that is a Chinese Phoenix actually you
know Chinese mythology and Chinese
dragon then these are Chinese style
clouds very famous and so anyway so you
buy keycaps such as they are so many
cute key caps you can you can buy this
these are artistic keycaps you have
mushroom you have this Buddhist palm he
says you stop here you stuck here it's
talking to the social justice scan and
also the UNIX philosophy people okay and
then you have this lion head ok this
lion head is also again another Chinese
characteristic thing in China you have
these over the place
sculptures stone made of stone then you
have pang gaudiya how wonderful it is
you have pang Gorion keycaps
you know it's wonderful pan goli and his
is kind of a weird creature and puke and
beautiful and then you have turtles then
you have this beautiful thing then you
have these gears now this key is
actually move you can move them there's
a video if you go to my website
sorry keyboard you'll find it it's a
video then you have this 3d printed
do-it-yourself Halloween key cap you
know this is Jack jack-o-lantern thing
and you have lots of others cute keeper
q caps superhero keycaps you have Iron
Man you have saw the hammer you have
over watch the hog you have the ass of
tracer you have Captain America and
agent of the shield idiotic then you
have the stone troop stuff so neo to
Kibo yes changing that changing is
trivial but there are no neo to keycaps
as far as I know and neo 2 has 6 layers
like what do you mean like neo 2 is just
a normal let's look at neo - okay it's
got to lay out let's go to German layout
German German and German economic we
want to go to German economic so this is
neo layout okay so so so neo 2 is new
huh I didn't know about neo 2 what's
what's the difference between you and
neo 2 so this is neo layout so if you
want to change key caps
you know it's just letters you just buy
a set of key caves it's on Amazon or
wherever wherever you buy shop at in
Germany you buy it you just put it on so
I'm not sure what you mean
yeah so I don't know what you mean by
not you cannot change keycaps reeks of
New Year's except ultra-slim keyboards
like laptop oh let's have hot you know
if you are in this level of things like
doing you know for a cornea or thing
this kind of things you need to get a
mechanical keyboard you need to buy it
of course you cannot change key caps are
normal you know Apple keyboard or
Microsoft or Logitech except the
logitech gaming keyboards yeah neo has
lots of layers okay my opinion on layers
is that don't use layers oh hey David no
never use layers well unless they are
model like typically the way they have
layers is that you pressed for example
you press the Alt key then it's a layer
you know you have to hold the Alt key
then press something then release that
kid and release the Alt key okay it's
idiotic its code let's go to keyboard
key binding okay key binding the science
the art and science of key binding which
is acha keyboard shortcut okay
Cavani and keyboard shortcut they are
actually they are also layout they they
are so so what do you want to do is you
see this combo breaker you know in
karate if they do some moves you know
keep punching you you need to employee
you need to employ the technique of
combo breaker then you defeat your
enemies okay combo breaker so so this
alcohol is bad key codes okay you want
to ban them they control out something
metal something shift bad band shift to
that pendant you don't want to them you
don't want them because they are
inefficient they they they they are
repetitive strain injury inducer okay
they if you do them a lot for example
you if you are a professional Photoshop
user using a normal keyboard you have to
press all this keyboard shortcut all the
time like switch switching to like in
Photoshop you it damages your hand
faster than just no more typing okay and
in fact if you are programmer I've done
statistics you know just search for
sorry Emacs key statistics you'll find
my report you have key lots that that
gathers the ticks statistics about how
people use keyboards okay so if you are
a a verge programmer
chances are you the keystrokes you type
over a month more than half of them are
related to related to key codes like
control something you know things like
that so this is actually so this is more
important than than letter layout I
talked about this before so so you so so
you don't want to use any this modifier
key concept okay it is it came from
historical reasons it's no good but
anyway this is something to consider
okay because for most people you don't
touch
you don't type that much even if you are
a programmer you don't really type much
okay you know get the key lock measure
your actual key number of keystrokes
then we can talk about you know things
so for the vast majority involved
majority of programmers you don't really
type that much and you don't have
repetitive strain injury you don't have
hand problems okay then for you whatever
is okay you know you can use PC keyboard
you can use it's fine but if you have
you know
if your hand hurts if you use emacs too
much you have pinkie problems you have
you know you started to have problems
then pay attention to this article okay
bad bad this modifier keys you don't
want to use it but what can you do well
you have a lot I talked about some
techniques how to not how to avoid
pressing them because you then you need
chemo Marquess that's this is when you
get into keyboard layout key binding
layout mechanical keyboards economic
keyboards you know you have to buy and
you know solve these problems so but so
you so if you are you know going you you
are using these fancy fairly of advanced
you know like you are high up there
neo layout then yeah you don't dance
natural you would consider you know help
you know have a mechanical keyboard so
you can change key caps okay so yeah so
we were talking about layers now these
these keyboard layouts they have layers
okay in my opinion it's idiotic you know
I don't you know like many layers they
are you know it's like this it's their
marketing probe they will say oh we have
ten layers oh oh oh go ducks we support
six layers we support semi layers near
they are supposed else supports 100
layers we we have by default 100 layers
it's the idiot okay when you so to them
they are like they are trying that you
know they look so nice you know these
layers when I see that okay you know to
me so we are never used this layout
because it has hundred layers it's
idiotic
so don't let is don't use layers I mean
again like how depends on how much you
actually type what what kind of level we
are we talking about if you if you you
know this is truly a difference of
levels like for most people if you are
not a programmer it's
your mom okay when your mom see you
doing programming they think oh you are
God you know like when you look at you
know but actually among programmers
they are programmers like me okay who
just to Emax and they are the super
programmers who wrote the Google search
engine okay among programmers there's a
big difference between even but if you
are not in the programming community you
have no idea you think you look Oh you
think they are all you know talking
about you know nouns you know
Incredibles things like rocket science
you don't understand you look at all
programmers the same but actually you're
my programmers you have those who just
graduated high school you know college
versus who you know some of the great
programmers right in the same way like
mathematics like if most of you don't
know mathematics and you think you look
at me or someone you think oh they know
math you know they about me but actually
this there's a big difference between
the levels of expertise so in the same
way what what are we saying so so you
are using your layout yeah so I mean so
yeah if you it depends on how much you
are into it okay so so layers they are
fine okay they are they work they are
fine but if you are really really really
into efficiency like you have to you
start to measure key logs you have to
compare you have to find out which is
truly the best then then your if you do
study that you may agree with me that
that modifier keys is no good okay now
layers layers the concept itself is is
fine because it's fine but you don't
want you don't want the activation
method to be modifier based like holding
down modifier key then pair something or
holding down this
you know old control then then they
impress something okay that's not good
so that's what I'm saying
so do I make sense do I make sense like
you know the I need to improve my
articulation at yesterday yesterday we
were talking about I was doing a great
rent again it's the UNIX philosophy of
the aspect lying lying truncation lying
based programming languages counting
software by lines of code counting
software complexity by lines of code and
all that I mean basically I'm talking
about how how the line based philosophy
of UNIX philosophy created a everlasting
damage in computing industry and I gave
several examples for example I gave you
examples of email specification where
UNIX tells everyone everyone else to
truncate lines because they cannot they
cannot deal with long long lines they
are UNIX idiotic technology they cannot
deal with long lines so so they create
the email spec and force everyone force
everyone to truncate their lies you know
you have to do it too because we cannot
you know funky Unix
so I gave several examples why it's a
tremendous harm to industry email SPECT
then the quotation McCann is I mean
emails which is all up you know
you have you know you you quote
something by by appending a character to
the beginning of each and every line so
that so that's another example then we
talk about you know several examples I
talk about programming language syntax
the concept of syntactical unit in a
programming language how that is wiped
out by unix you know by the unix line
based thing
and I talked about I talked about what's
the solution I talked about Sofia
marching I talked about how UNIX trust
me they form a coat and so they stop
people programmers from thinking so I
gave several you know I give like half
an hour rent on that so I won't I'm
gonna into it was am i clear
caffeine good morning Kathy and and but
so yesterday when we when you hear me
ranting philosophy half of the half-hour
is Unix
but but do you are do I make any sense
at all anyway so part says what about
layer six you should love it
so but what's the difference between neo
and big neo to you know I
Sonia website they are like in German I
don't understand German
so he says Neil is I nine ago most nish
Tata smuggle a gun
welcome Verdi did Juche smash atomizer
East
so you never use new one so the page I'm
looking at is this neo 2 on your one so
I guess you are just calling your Neil I
mean I guess they just changed I mean
it's the same thing basically yes I know
that but you should know I know that neo
is an ergonomic keyboard layout which is
optimized for the German language I
wrote a article we were talking about I
wrote a whole page about it the history
of ergonomic keyboard layouts of design
for German language you see okay so it's
neo too so it's just just just Courtney
oh wait why do you call a neo to me on
their home page they don't say neo to
Sony oh you know Sony oh let's see
layout epping 6 ok this we need to go to
a JavaScript
translating the whip in translating the
webpage okay let's go to neo layout org
a being may out yeah so let's click on
Epping six okay yeah okay math it's it's
math you know I don't recommend it I
don't recommend all this layout okay
it's I I studied this issue in detail
for example let's go to layer six okay
you cannot you have to you cannot make a
stick I want to stick and it doesn't
stick this stupid website
okay Sonia Sonia six ok so actually let
me do a screenshot okay now let's go
back let's demo some power of Emacs okay
and show in browser okay this this is a
page and we are gonna call this command
okay hold on a second let me show all my
Emacs commands on the left window okay
and how long have I been talking let's
see we I think we are about to end the
end of sorry for today okay the night is
young we only talked for 15 minutes so
anyway so back to Emacs so I press a key
I press ENTER I press ENTER I press
ENTER then show in browser then Wow
suddenly you have this screenshot
fantastic the I just store the new
website into my blog
now now this is actually not the
screenshot we want because you know the
Audis got wide spaces so I press a key
it launches the my operating operating
systems viewer and I just do that that's
what I want okay and I press a key crop
okay now close it back to Emacs it
automatically refreshes okay close it
and show in browser perfect actually
this is this is not perfect because
because previously you see let me
magnify okay previously you see you see
this width and hate with 1293 hate 995
okay that's the previous size but
because we cropped it so there's a new
size now we need to redo it so I copy
that copy paste okay then I call command
now this is new okay so the new width is
560 and the new head is 291 show in
browser see there's the difference back
in Emacs cut out that line okay and wait
oh I could out yeah cut out the line so
but but this is still not good enough
because okay so anyway I want to I want
to extract or URL all URL in this block
of text so I call command it's done now
I move the cursor down paste you see the
you that's the full path of the URL and
I press a button it becomes the image
tag for me you see the difference is
actually there's no difference actually
yeah there is no difference between
these two but there is something I will
get to so so you see right now this if
I'm writing a blog about this knee or to
let's say the the NiO layer six you know
I need a screen shot but this is not
good enough because the image file name
is screen shot something that's not what
I want I want the proper name so I press
a key to rename it okay now you can see
in in at the bottom now I type a new
name
I say Neal layout layer six okay enter
you see it it does multiple things if we
look at the file we go to tired here is
the file actually so here is a file you
see it actually renamed the file on on
disk without me going into the directory
you know it actually renamed that we
named it also relinked it here you know
it just works so in browser it works
back to Emacs there's something else we
need to do we need to do because now the
name is a screenshot the proper name
should be near layout layer 6 so let's
extract the URL again now I move cursor
down paste and enter add newlines so you
see this is the URL and press the key we
do it so now showing browser so now you
can see it has the name based on the
image file name it's all automatic ok
now I can delete that so Neal Neal
layout layer 6 you see those characters
I can type those characters without
those layers let me show you
ok let me show you ok open a new buffer
magnify Mac ok magnify so you can see so
let's say I want to do Sun Sun let's try
again
Sun there it is ok now let's say I want
to say for all for all there it is I
want to say exists there it is I want to
type the symbol for natural integers so
for for real number let's say ah there
it is
magnify magnify beautiful I want to type
in something like for example X is in s
ok that's a typical math phrase ok the
way you say it you want to use symbols
okay in there is you see and all these
are turn without holding down a modifier
how do you know ctrl alt shift something
I get there spring your fingers the
tomorrow you go to visit the doctor ok
that's what this you know that's this
layers to to you tomorrow is visit the
doctor so but you can see my key strokes
on the left panel here there is no
control or something and this is
extremely it's actually much more
efficient let's say right arrow ok
double right arrow ok so you see right
arrow RA now if I use some of these
common you know if I use them frequently
I can make it even easier let's not do
it it's you know Emacs is called a brief
so I did a tutorial on that I think
twice so you just go to my YouTube
search for go to my YouTube
YouTube channel search for Emacs a brief
I have a like one hour tutorial on that
so this is how you do you know this is a
efficient alternative to these typical
layers thing okay
and in fact I have a article that you
know I spent like a month study all
possible ways to input basically when
you study this kind of things the proper
subject matter for this category is
called input methods okay
input methods a specific type of input
methods for example let's go okay so
let's go to keyboard section let's go to
key binding section so in this page is a
index - or articles related to key
binding and input systems actually input
systems is is in the layout section
anyway if you go to the key bindings
section there is a section there's
article called math info design so the
title is design of math symbols input
system so this page discussed so if you
want to type a lot math what is the best
way what is the best method is it by you
know maybe using a lot modifier key or
is it by using a key sequence or is it
by maybe using some kind of abbreviation
that automatically changes to the symbol
you want things like that and by the way
this is not just math symbol C it can be
any emoji okay so I studied you know
so-called research most people will just
caught research I researched okay I am a
researcher I research this issue I look
at you know you spend you know days a
month to study it so I have conclusion
of pro and cons of various methods and
and I devised the best methods so what
you have seen for example and info
natural numbers you see okay so let me
show you how this works
so I want to turn this end to a double
stroke in so I press a key twice
FK of 10 f10 is actually my thumb key
you see normally on this keyboard you
don't have big functional function keys
it sucks okay you don't have big
function keys you have this tiny thing I
don't like that so so this key is
actually f10 on my keyboard okay so
let's try to do it again okay let's so
you can see both my screen and my key
undo okay yeah hold on a second let me
show this window as well so I want to
turn this character this character into
into the double stroke end so what I do
is I press this key once twice you see
so which one is easier you know hoedown
out you know control out the layer six
whatever you know ctrl shift
Windows key then then you press in oh oh
you type one character well two
characters shift in okay shift and two
characters then another two characters
f10 f10 you know one two three four so
anyway that's about that oh and this mod
this is stunning
Emacs and this mod the command I just
scored is some math input change to
symbol that's the command name and we
can go to the source code and here's the
source code
it's eMac Lisp and you go to the top you
can see the webpage URL in this line and
show in browser show it so I have a web
page you can go there
you can download it it's free don't
forget to buy my Emacs tutorial ok it's
it's the best tutorial it's one of the
best ok
so buy my Emacs tutorial and or go to my
website you can patreon me PayPal me
thank you for support so so this package
is free you can type like 500 symbols
you can also trivially add your own well
if you actually if you are Emacs user
you know on my page if you read this
page I have lots of links you you can
read about all kind of details like how
to do it what package is you know what
software to use to create how to create
your own layout things like that you
know you are low on your own Unicode or
emoji layout on Windows Mac you know
Linux so full of details you can you
guys can check it out so comments guys
comments so actually I think I have some
discord comment we failed we didn't
mention discord today let's go to
discord but but are you on this Court
Joe enjoying my for one piece so discord
let's see because some some people I
think they don't go to YouTube comments
they just go to discord
what oh and you need to turn on
JavaScript turn on JavaScript please
okay I need a drink a break in the drink
so today's juice enter
today's juice is grape juice okay 100%
natural juice juice for human animals
you know modern society you have these
juices you can go to a store and you
have aisles of it like the matrix guns
you know whoo
I also ten thousand hours and on the
rack you have 10 racks top row second
row third row do 10 racks on each side
and you have juice grape juice white
grape juice
paavo juice orange juice prune juice
raspberry juice fascinating you have all
these juice you know what does it take
to do this if you don't have modern
society you have to pick them it's it's
tremendous work okay it's tremendously
tedious it's tremendous work okay so you
can make a paid course yeah that's what
I'm saying
King herring I was saying you know I'm
trying to make a paid course so how do
you pronounce your name my my crowd work
my co-op work so micro bug is asking me
whether possibly I can do I can teach
eMac disp like advanced and my answer is
pretty much yeah yes I mean if you have
have have you have you ever written a
email is packaged for the public have
you ever if not then 100 dollars to me
for three hours I teach you eMac this
you probably can benefit it's probably
worthwhile okay so yeah so pay me you
know I can teach eMac list and
JavaScript okay so what what we all get
for $100 for three hours you know I can
do four hours you know once I start
talking you know
kind of it's tough but I can do you know
four hours for you guys so you pay me
$100
so for Emacs B's Oh or just even Emacs
you know questions you can ask me o
JavaScript I can you know I can make you
I can make you an expert okay
because in these three hours if without
a teacher you will spend like you know
30 hours you know is something like that
actually that more than 30 hours if you
study by yourself you have to spend you
know if you do two hours a day it takes
you several months because well because
i-i've been coding eMac this and you
know and you know four years 14 years I
know I can tell you what to do otherwise
you've you otherwise it's like if you
don't have a parent then you know if you
were an orphan you're you don't have a
parent like James pound you know James
Bond James Bond okay if you don't have a
parent you learn things the hard way
which is extremely inefficient you don't
have a guide you know guide guy a good
guide is actually quite important
because it saves you tremendous time you
because otherwise you are running into
dead ends all the time okay so any
comments do the same with our Emacs what
I forgot to add the elixir of modern of
modern maternity elixir okay
in short this is called condensed coffee
okay it comes out crystal clear you can
see transparent in color of afar chant
alpha channel value is zero
acha condensed coffee
so Matt's say stop drinking that
that is correct that is good advice but
you know in other life we have we have
our problems speaking small you know
like you know some people smoke
cigarettes which I do I'm trying to quit
and meanwhile I know many of you smoke
drugs you know the the you know the by
the way it's legal okay it's legal in
California the Majah wanna you know many
of you do that you know it's a you just
modern life okay so I missed some
comments I think what actually there's
not many comments I think maybe that's
it for today I hope you guys have fun
had fun you see I'm doing my video as
part of it for motor tooths multitudes
of reasons part of it it's a Captain's
Log its Sally's diary
it's my periodic passage I enjoy
masturbation okay it's a record of it so
when when when when you know when I'm
dead you can see oh so sorry looks like
that and maybe they'll stop some rumors
you know when you are dead all the
rumors will fly and then then the other
thing is you know when you do video well
you know I'm a Explorer so I explore all
kind of things so one thing I'm learning
about video is that one of the things
one of the things he said I can hone my
articulation skill and I can home my
oration skill as well in real time you
know I don't want I don't like the
scripted way like again yeah I can
improve my videos bye bye you know
preparing you know maybe rehearsed you
know then do a nice video for ten
minutes you know that's one possibility
but that's not what I want to go it you
know that I don't really have to have to
be in some way but anyway right now I'm
just doing real time real time is great
because so so I'm learning you know so I
can talk about any topics any topic that
I know and I became better at that so
one day I imagine I'll have the great
debate you know young political stage so
okay so Bart says part says bar says
it's neo2 it was trans translating I was
translating from what no that was just
you what you read saw that was just what
you read okay chill I was translating
the webpage but I don't I don't get it
why is it it doesn't mention neo2 on the
webpage or maybe they said somewhere
here in German I don't I don't
understand so leopard that neo2 is also
usable for English yeah I heard of that
contrary to near 100 K so the question
to me is that I don't know what's the
difference speak between knio knio one
or neo2 I think it's just a new version
with major changes right that's what I
think it's not it's not like someone
else forked it and we named it neo to
you know sometimes that happens you know
but I think I'm guessing here they just
refer to the same project it's just a
newer version with many maybe major
changes so contrary to neo one so yeah
you can so this neo you
they don't have a English version so I
suppose that that means their project is
focused on German people so so you don't
get much exposure you know for example
if they have an English page then I
would read in detail but it's it's
German so I just okay I just look at the
pictures okay so that's it
maybe somebody cares enough that T Co is
missing what is T Co so do the same
without Emacs through the same you can
do that okay part so I think you are
saying creating you know these layers
without Emacs okay so that would be more
difficult you see this there is an
interesting question about keyboard
technology like when you want to type
these Unicode characters does no matter
how how advanced is your programmable
keyboard like the one we've we've shown
today you know the automat hacking
keyboard or the kana my Kinesis keyboard
they are very advanced programmable
keyboards but however it is basically
technically impossible to program the
keyboard so that it types any of these
Unicode characters you see this is very
interesting you know once you started to
study keyboards you start to discover
lots of weird weird illogical things
okay so it's see it is impossible
doesn't matter how advanced is your key
key programmable keyboard it is
impossible to make it's well technically
impossible okay that's there's a
difference it's technically impossible
to create a shortcut or program a key to
type unicode characters why because the
keyboard protocol you know the USB well
you have keyboard protocols that that
says you know how the keyboard what
signal you know electronics you
electronic signal represent what key
things like that you have protocols you
know and they so what the keyboard sent
is actually it's not characters
no is it s key you know code for the
characters it's actually sending it is
just sending some a bunch of numbers
okay and and there's no way okay anyway
so your your keyboard send sends a bunch
of numbers when you press a key it's a
number so each key is just just a number
and on your hardware on your firmware
when you when you boot up the computer
there's a firmware you know very
low-level firmware that that understands
those numbers it's hard coded okay so so
those numbers you know they don't is
hard-coded to ask you know to the court
if they are then you know that's when
your operating system made the Windows
Linux or Mac when they put up okay after
they put up they load the operating
system then you started to load the key
binding you know the system-wide key
binding you know on a Mac or Windows or
on Linux you know you you started to
load a keyboard layout you know kind of
map keyboard layout map for your console
on Linux for example then the x11
windows system comes up then that itself
started to load its own key map so you
see this is very simple complications so
on the Mac for typically two levels when
you put up then you load the operating
system the operating system then loads
the key map you know kind of a higher
level key map then you can choose for AK
of Corti you know then the OS decides
what number correspond to 1 later but
still even with all this trouble
the letters are just asking Keys you
know so so okay so
so once the operating system notes the
the key map loads then the operating
system knows you know which number
should mapped to what character but
actually it's not character because
because then this is sent to the the
operating systems keyboard framework you
know the input system yeah input system
framework and in that system there is no
such thing as Unicode characters I mean
something like that okay basically
basically what the bottom line is that
it's technically impossible to to make
your programmable keyboard same actual
Unicode because the signals are not
Unicode are not characters they are just
numbers so so but if you want to
actually do this kind of thing you have
to go through hacks
okay hack we back to hack in fact
engineering if you actually study
engineering you study or aspects of
engineering most of it it's like like
like ninety ninety percent of
engineering maybe a machine hardware you
know a truck or a tank it's all hack
it's a whole like hack but on the
surface it works you know you don't know
the details for example if you install
neo it's probably oh you just have
layers you'd press this key and you get
these math symbols but actually there's
a lot of hack going on so how they do it
I'm not sure how they do it all so these
days you know this more advanced
technology these days but anyway that's
another topic we're getting complicated
so it so anyway so anyway
so what I'm saying so so but a easy way
okay this is here's a practical tip easy
way if you want to type math symbols and
you want a keyboard key to do that one
easy way is to read rely on an app an
application ok such as Emacs Microsoft
Word okay because when you are in your
app the when you press a key the
operating system going through several
layers we will send that key where we
will send a character to the application
for example in Emacs or in Microsoft
Word okay he will send the letter to the
application then the application can
take that letter and do something with
it you know change it to something else
so so so this is this is the most easy
and practical way to make a key to
actually type a unicode character or an
emoji you rely on a long app such as
Emacs or or Microsoft Word you can
usually they have a fixed you know I
have tutorials showing you how to do
that in Emacs but but on Microsoft Word
they also have a brief feature like that
you can find it easy and similarly for
the editors okay I think that's it for
today so no comments I guess 18 people
every time they were in Slate I got more
people watching it's kind of annoying so
let's back to discord T Co means tail
call optimization oh yeah oh yeah all
right that's why it sounds so familiar
so what's the context of that meow cat
or card male cat me or casas can TCO be
easily transformed to loops
yes if you are a compiler writer yes of
course
telco optimization yes if you if you are
a compiler writer yes that
can easily be done but if you are not
for example I am NOT then you don't know
how to do it I don't know how to do it
you know I don't know even how to how to
write a compiler yet okay I know I know
I know how to write a parser which is
the first step of compiling I kind of
know a bit of that and then then you
have to take the bytecode or whatever
you know then you have to you know
convert the the process output into into
the compilers target language such as
machine language or C you know
JavaScript you know so I don't know how
to write a compiler but you know you're
talking about can can tail call
optimization be easily transformed to
loop okay that okay the the proper way
to say that request that doesn't make
sense okay the proper way to say that is
that tail call optimization by
definition is a loop okay almost by
definition telco optimation by
definition means you turn a source code
that's using tail tail recursion using
you know function calling itself you
know calling yourself because if you
know call a function at the end you want
to turn that code when you write a
compiler you when you see a you know
because and you have tail recursion you
you want to convert it into a loop
that's every compiler - that's what it
means
you know telco optimal optimization
that's the optimization part of the word
so so I I think you know if you know
compilers you you you know then I don't
know what's a what how difficult it is
things like that so you have to be your
compiler writer to kind of and and
typically it's not something important
ok tell recursion you know
recursion is something it's another
dramatic thing among programmers among
foreign languages such as monad tail
recursion release Marcos Marcos okay I'm
starting to read I talk about this often
every Tomas a video of my videos so you
got this so it's one of the dramatic
thing telco recursion recursion is
actually not not not really practical
and thing okay I think I've been talking
too long and there's no more comments
okay so okay that one more minutes then
that's it for today
okay one more minutes and we shut down
Bart says doing it your way to counter
layers is like thinking hours on UNIX
which use us v8 tinkering hours on UNIX
no it's not like that which you suppose
we hate be consistent with your opinions
no it's not to you it may see me you
know he's like I suppose okay let me see
what you say what do you say UNIX just
does not work Mac just works yes then I
answered layer six just works making
down making own alternative does not
work it sucks okay if this none day okay
so I guess I see what you're saying no I
disagree I see what you're saying is
because you are seeing okay let me
characterize what you are saying which
is you know since I'm talking because
it's probably favorable to me and you
have no way to counter you see what you
are saying is that
you see me rent again his UNIX and Linux
all the time and part of the reason is
because I blame that UNIX and Linux you
know they are doing hack you know
extremely complicated hack underneath
- maybe you achieve something then you
see me talk about you know the keyboard
the layers you know on one hand you have
this neo 2 layout which just works you
know you download it you just walk so
you can type the Unicode on the other
hand you see me talking about how you
know I'm getting like complicated ways
to type math symbols and I'm saying you
know this is superior but actually it is
complicated because yeah it's
complicated because first of all I have
to implement it you know is Emacs and
Emacs and you know the tools and most
people don't can use it you know they'd
rather they'd rather just download this
neo and in there out of a box it works
so you think there is an inconsistency
you know thank you
I'm flaming UNIX but meanwhile when it
comes to keyboard layers I'm like doing
hack myself and not not know it okay I
see what you're saying but I don't see
it that way you see the way I see it is
that the UNIX hack is truly a hack okay
it's truly I mean they they were there
so I'm saying the UNIX you know they
have they are hacking not just that but
I think there are concepts ideas are
just stupid in the first phase and they
are not even hacking they are not
hacking to try to achieve something
rather they are beginning with brainless
Ness like they don't think about
anything they just whatever is the
easiest way the the the easiest way to
do something called something they just
do it then after 10 years 20 years 30
years things just pile on pile on that's
what I think of Unix
then they try to fix something then so
it's extreme complex okay that's
your neck that's my opinion but
meanwhile what why can I say I'm doing
the same thing for the keyboard input
system well no because what I'm you know
the to me okay um
this is thinking this is not unthinking
like the UNIX people this is thinking
analysis you look at all for example I
study odd all the possible input systems
Chinese how you type Chinese how do you
type Japanese their history of their
employers input systems very complex and
also how you type math symbols you
survey how Mathematica for example type
math equations how tech latech they
their way of typing math equations and
Microsoft Word how they you know how
they dead people was their method for
people to type these Unicode characters
you know math symbols so you look at
them you lose you study them and you
also study they are different ways okay
you study them you find okay this this
Microsoft is doing using a brief if you
know then Emacs is using this way
something something Mathematica is doing
that way la Tech is doing another way
which actually doesn't input Unicode
rather you render you know you rented
okay anyway so you study other ways you
compare then you analyze the the key
efficiency you know how many keystroke
you mean to type economics of using
modifier keys you know string on your
pinky things like that so that's the way
so so then you come up you know with a
way that's better better than out there
let's say then you implement it okay so
yeah so it's true if you want to use for
example my way you have to download
myself maybe no Emacs you know kind of
complicated but is that's because
you see what I'm saying I don't see
these as us being inconsistent you know
oh my god I'm going through all this
hack and not even realizing yet this is
actual design thinking not the UNIX hack
okay no more comments okay so that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
Cathy says Cathy says the way you
program the keyboard looks very
efficient and mouse automatically
clicking we're moving outside browser
yeah that's a huge hand saver for me I
actually agree line truncation destroyed
me again again okay so we have a new guy
weenie weenie or winey winey weenie
should be Winnie TBH tbh means to be
honest okay to be honest despite
starting with the Kinesis advantage
quota for a payout with lorac Legends
it's not very useful to have lay out
specific key caps since when should
touch type always and mentor map them
that's true actually I have a big gripe
with that attitude because when you are
in the keyboard nerd community you know
often well the dramatic thing you know
just like programming they also have
their dramatic dramatic things one of
the dramatic thing in kpop nerds is
blank key caps you know they like he you
know keyboard without playing you know
no no labels at all and they show of all
the time you got because then it's
traumatic because every time you post
pictures of that they're no more people
they all say wow wow how do you type you
know oh yeah because I touched I've and
so on yeah that's true but actually if
you are but actually a keyboard with key
labels is actually much better because
you don't want key labels especially if
you research
if you research keybinding you know if
you are designing like me I mean I've
been changing Mikey's designee my logo
Emacs mod and soft like his mod I have
to you know find which one is more
efficient tea logs and all that so I
change you know I used to change
keybinding every week every week you
know go to my Emacs it need for like 10
year over 10 years I haven't done that
much in the past 3 years I think but
before that everything in for 10 years
every week I changed my key bindings one
out you know two or three of them and
it's very frustrating because every time
you change you have to change the habit
again every time every week every two or
three weeks so so so when you are doing
research when you're designing key
bindings and also when you are writing
keep earning programs like Microsoft
like this you have to for example you
you have to write converters between
Borak and quality or Commack you know
you have to convert them but then if you
have a blankie thanks father because you
okay so if it's work I can type you know
I've been typing for work for 30 years I
can even hunt and peck for work without
by using a quality lay board keyboard I
can actually hunt the mpeg-4 rack so
when I see code here I know what what
letter it is actually work so I'm very
familiar with it but however when you
are doing you know keyboard key key
research and you got a blank keyboard
every key is you know blank it's a
problem because you know it's like when
you go to a forest you you saw 100 you
know 1000 trees every tree looks exactly
the same it's a problem identifying
which one is which quickly you know this
says so so I would always prefer
keyboard with key labels actually I have
article on that you can find out by
going to okay I'm gonna shut down in one
minutes
wait no Monsieur yeah okay so you can
find out by going to key labels yeah so
key labels you go to keyboard design key
label tech actually that's not it
actually you go to layout I know how to
find it you go to layout you go to vorak
layout okay oh here so alright so here
here's article blank key caps versus
labeled labeled keys so in this article
I detailed my analysis what's you know
Pro and cons of each I saw I would
actually so even if you touch type I
actually recommend you do not buy these
blank key keyboards you you want labels
it doesn't matter what label you want
just some pictures even just pictures
like random pictures on them okay thank
you guys for watching that's it for
today thanks