Hello guys, good morning. Audio check,
video check. Welcome to another episode
of Kasan Talk Show. If you are watching
this offline, play at 1.5 speed because
I ramble just like Joe Rogan monkey. So,
we are going to do uh Emac Lisp coding
pure Emac Lisp technology
make America great again. tech by
technology and that's the only way and
the emac bisp. Okay. So if you are here
say hi.
Okay. Let's begin. So let's begin. Uh
someone here. Nobody is here. So let's
just let me just code. Okay. So we are
going to solve this algorithmic problem.
So let me tell you about it. Uh complan
search for.info
compar programming blog. So there is a
fascinating question. So let me show you
what is a question. Okay. So you just
search for find and replace
feedback
loop problem. Okay, find and replace
multi-pairs feedback loop problem.
I had this problem for like 10 years. Uh
basically the problem is if you want to
do find and replace text
uh and you want to do it multiple pairs
you cannot do it sequentially
because then you run into problems
you'll get into a situation where you'll
find string that does not occur in the
input text. However it get replaced by
the replace string. So that is a
situation. Okay, let me check one more
time. So, audio check, video check.
Where where is my uh audio check, video
check? Okay, find replace multi-pair
problem. So, we I talked about this two
days ago in last episode. So, but let me
tell you again. So if you have a text
you want to do multiple pairs of find
replace for example if your input text
is a b c d and you have two pairs a
replace by c and cb replaced by x. So a
occurs once so it becomes c. So you got
c b c d
and cb does not occur anywhere. Okay. So
cb2x does not happen. So the result
should be C B C D. However, if you do
this you know uh replacement
sequentially
then you will get X C D because A
becomes C and C interact with the
subsequent character they are CB then CB
becomes X so you get X CD so that is a
problem find replace multiplayer
problem. So I had this problem for like
10 years be because uh this happens in
real life as uh especially when you do
you know the amperand encoding.
So you know it happens in in real life.
So
so I was talking about this two days ago
in my live stream and I was wondering
you know today we have AI so let's ask
AI this this problem must have happened
before uh is it a known problem must be
a known problem. What is the name and AI
answered? Uh, so let's see. Can I can I
find my tweet?
Uh, oh, just search my programming blog.
I blogged about the situation. So, age
of AI artificial intelligence. That's
interesting. I saw I've been super busy
writing a lot articles. If you are
watching here, say hi. Okay. So, coding
font review. Lots of work on font
technology review. Wuam language ws uh
state of AI multiple stream replacement
problem. So I was you know posting on
Twitter and live stream about the about
this problem and I was wondering you
know I'm pretty sure this is a known
problem. Is there a name for this guac?
And Guac says, "Yes, this is a known
issue in string processing commonly
referred to as the multiple stream
replacement interference problem or
cascading substitution feedback. It is
often solved using simultaneous
replacement algorithms like a whole
quasassic to prevent order dependent
errors.
Amazing, you know. So AI told me I had
this problem for 10 years. AI told me
the name. Then I I search for the name.
For example, this another AI. This is
Brave browser. Brave search. I recommend
it. Okay. Don't use W Google. Don't use
Firefox. I mean I recommend Brave
browser. It has um add filter building,
add blocking building. Okay. Brave
browser in Brave search. I searched for
multiple string replacement problem and
Brave answered. So Brave gave you two
solutions. One solution is that you
um you do uh you you use a regular
expression to join all the fine strings.
Okay. So all the fine strings you know
you want to find this or this or this
you know regular expression. Then you
put uh then you put the find and replace
pairs into a hash table or dictionary
also known as diction dictionary. So so
you search for the regular expression
for all the find strings. Once you find
it you check which one you found. Then
you use the dictionary to find the
replacement for that found string. Then
you replace that. Okay. So this is
fantastic. this is doing fine replacing
one shot using regular expression or
so you don't have this feedback loop so
that's one solution I haven't thought of
okay so that's one solution so I learned
something from AI AI is you know it's
like 100 professors around the clock
serving you uh that was one of my uh my
fantasy when I was younger you know is
it you know can I have I you know I I
I'm deeply obsessed about knowledge. So
I want to know it would be great if I
have all the professors around me who
can wherever I have whatever question
math question the math professor will
answer it. You know the let's say the
world's top mathematician he'll just
answer it. I have a a question about
chemistry, about society, about whatever
programming computers or CPU, all the
professors will answer it right away. Or
about plants, you know, the
plants or flowers, you know, or English
literature, history, linguistics,
it would be amazing all the professors
of different fields, you know, hundreds
of them evolve around me whenever I have
a question. So you have to be very rich
to to to do that. But anyway, today we
have that that is AI. So I have I've
written about this uh age of AI
professors on demand. That's exactly
what AI is is pretty much you know
basically you ask anything you don't
know like anything in history in
academia you know any academic topics
history of uh let's say history of sort
you know can you pass the sort you know
history of sort that's a there's a
history to that or the history of pi you
know the mathematics pi the number pi or
the history of uh you know any math or
any mathematics or history of or any
linguist you know you can ask the
history of Mexico how many races are
there you know things like that you know
like things you never you don't know a
thing about
you can ask that's AI today okay so
that's AI then uh there is resistance to
AI okay so typically the European
Americans like they you know they they
got a problem but it's interesting let
me let me finish talking about this and
let's we will get back to Emacs this
coding. Okay. So be because you know
there's a resistance to technology and I
personally see it. So for example when
there is uh graphing calculator when
became popular around 1991 that was when
I was in college there's a huge debate
whether you know you should allow using
graphing calculators.
Oh, that's like you know if you are
student these days are too uh lazy you
know because graphing calculators you
don't learn anything anymore you just
you know punching the numbers and then
there is then I learned you know through
lots of readings of diverse uh random
readings that happened the resistance to
technology happened in typewriters you
know for example when when mechanical
typewriters were invented 200 100 years
ago people are saying oh no no thank you
I can I can I'm capable of writing you
know handwriting you know like they are
resistant like what the yeah I
don't want I don't want it I don't want
mechanical type you know I don't want
typing machines I can I can be hand you
know writing by hand beautifully that
happens to typewriters that happens to
credit card when credit card was
invented people are like no no I can I I
you know I'll stick to my checks Thank
you.
And when calculator were invented there
are a bunch of you know engineers there
no thank you I'm capable of using the
slide rulers you know they used to use
the slide ruler so then graphing
calculator and instant messaging I
personally experienced that's around
year 2000 when all of a sudden you have
the instant messaging you know a a
online you know like like
of of Because today we have Twitter and
and so much others. But when instant
messaging came up, you can instantly
chat to someone on the internet. Maybe
you know uh uh you know your friends in
another states or in another country,
you can do that. Then also when
Wikipedia began around 2003,
you know, there's huge resistance to
Wikipedia for like a decade. you know
all the tech nerds you know like they
refuse to link to it or and and still
and there's still some of that today.
So, but eventually technology you cannot
stop technology. Okay? Like today a lot
of people are you know like you know
especially the white Americans they got
problems you know they they are
resistant to AI you know oh you know the
AI is just all fake news uh it's
controlling your thought and and all
that they make people stupid you know
you know some research look the
scientists they did the research all the
people students who used AI they are
unable to think okay those people who
say that they are idiotic. They are the
Ludats, Ludetss,
you know. So, there's a story about
Ludites, however you pronounce it, you
know, uh
they are resisting to the invention of
the weaving machine and they get angry,
they start to burn or break machines,
you know, uh the most uh uh famous
story, Ludites. Okay. So there's strong
resistance to AI and then uh Wikipedia
and then but eventually the uh you know
the resistance fold because you can
never stop technology the progress of
technology for example chopsticks
you know you know what's a chopstick or
fork and spoon or knife or the wheel you
know the wheel the greatest invention
the wheel or the fire you know you can
never stop it okay or you know today the
internet and cell phone
uh the internet I remember when when
internet began around let's say 1991 I
began to kind of start to use internet
in 1991
you have to connect to modems you have
to buy modem any anyway so but then then
there start to have email and a lot of
what you know at back then you know oh
that's cyerspace what is email a lot of
people refuse of course but today we are
beyond email of course everyone is on
Twitter everyone is on Instagram doing
their whatever posting and
whatn not
so technology you cannot stop it okay if
you don't use it somebody else will keep
using it and you'll be like dead
such as nuke
Okay. So in AI, you know, so anyway, so
that's a digression about AI. So
we got into that story because we were
talking about you know I asked AI an
programming issue algorithm alorithmic
problem and it answered superbly
uh a question I had you know I actually
I didn't look into but it's a question I
have for 10 years and AI just gave me
the the answer.
Okay so there are two solutions to this
problem. One of them is the um uh where
is the article? One of one of them is
the uh where is my uh blog? Okay. So,
okay. So, I need to go to uh
show that article again. So, one of the
solution
um is you create a hash table. You know
you use regular expression or expression
to do them one shot and each time you
found one item you use a dictionary to
find the replacement and do it. That's
one solution. The other solution is you
can you see it? It's kind of small. So
the other solution is uh the the the AI
from Brave search which is called Leo.
Leo answered is that the other solution
is you do a twice substitution. You
substitute twice. So the first time you
replace them with replace each find
string by some uh kind of random number.
Okay, that that will not occur anywhere.
Basically you identify all the fine
string spots. Then the second pass two
pass solution. The second pass you you
you use your uh newly random identifier
to replace with with each of the fine
string. Okay, two pass solution and that
is what I was doing. Okay, so that is
the like the prelude to the problem.
Okay, so today so let's begin to write
the write the code. So we uh I started
talking for 15 minutes. Okay, so what we
want to do? Okay. So what is this
programming blog? Uh okay. So today's
talk show. So let me show you a um the
the the code. Okay.
So I got this command. So describe
function replace squeak letter name to
symbol. Okay. So let's here's the
documentation. Let's go to it. Uh so you
can see you have bunch of so let me
demo. So here's a source code but let me
demo. Okay. So open that. Close that. Uh
let's start to demo
text. Okay. So let's uh text.
Okay. So you have some Greeks,
Greek letters
uh
such as
alpha and beta.
Suppose you have a angle of theta
mathematics. Okay. So now you copy that.
So but you want the real Greeks. So what
you can do is Greek uh what is this
command name? Kasa replace Greek letter
name to symbol do it. So you can see
they become alpha and beta. Okay.
Actually you do need to do this on this
line too. Uh oh theta eta. Okay. So
actually I need to fix that. So you see
there is theta and there's eta.
So but when you call this program it it
didn't check the word boundary. So it
all became eta.
Uh and actually I think eta is not in
modern Greek. ETA is a uh is it am I
correct Asian Greek or something? Okay,
so let's look up.
So now let's go to Unicode
block.
Okay, and there is a section on Greek.
Of course, you can go to Wikipedia.
So uh so there's eta bold itallic cancel
translation uh Greek archaic Greek
letters. Okay. So you got the final
sigma
uh cancel that
cheers red wine.
So ETA where where is ETA? So
God is anyone here? Hi Rohan. Why the
half keyboard in the middle? That is for
my keyboard Marco. That is ultimate
hacking keyboard.
There are two parts. You can you can't
see them but I can you know. So you can
see the other part is here here. So I
use them as a keyboard marker.
Okay. For example, so I'm in uh for
example I in my browser. So this key
switch to the last tab, previous tab,
next tab, previous tab. Next. Next,
previous
previous. Next, next. Pre previous.
Doom. Close it. Reopen it. Oh, wait.
Where is my reopen key? Uh, wait. Oh, I
I think I removed it. Okay. Tap shift
controlT to reopen.
Okay. Where's my uh reopen? Last. I
forgot. I I I probably removed it when I
changed my keyboard layout. Okay, that
is the answer.
Uh yeah, so I've done like hundreds
videos about keyboards uh in the past
few years. So it's all on my YouTube.
Okay, so let's go back to Greek. Yeah,
so we were we were wondering what is
eta. Okay, so let's check on that
now. Is eta a archaic Greek? I thought
so. Does anyone know actually? So
archaic Greek letters uh mass symbols
derived from Greek.
Wow. Okay. So let's check Wikipedia.
Greek
Greek alphabet.
Okay. So we are looking for ETA now does
it? So it says here, search for ETA
beta zeta. Oh. Oh, that's H. I mean
that's corresponding to the English edge
or looks like. Okay, that's why
uh Greek capital. Oh, okay. So, it so
anyway,
so you can see. So, go back then. Go
back here. Go back here. So we got this
ETA ata. So we need to when we do
replacement we need to have a boundary
check. So we you know theta would not
become tha.
Okay. Can you see that? So okay so let's
back to the command. So we want to
rewrite this command. Okay. So let's do
that. Let's do that. Okay. I think um we
talked too much. I mean not be able to
finish this. Uh okay. So we start the
eac list this code. So let's start
coding it. Okay. So right now it's
calling my uh custom function which I
talked about before. You can you can
download it. So this replace pairs
region. So you can see how easy
convenient. So you just say you know
give it a list of find replace.
And this function is available online
uh by just go to uh uh describe function
go to the source code go to the top so
it's on this URL open it showing browser
uh wait undo
this key showing browser okay so you can
so the source code is here you can grab
it okay you can use it but I want to
change it because
close uh Close. Close. I want to change
it because I don't want function
dependency,
you know, because to enable to use this
function, you you know, you need to get
that library. So I don't I don't I I
don't want that. So that that's why
let's rewrite it. Okay. So
Okay. So let's do that. And also we need
a boundary check.
How many people watching? Two people.
Okay. So, let me just uh focus on this
and get to work.
So, uh so do we have the algorithm
outline? Yes. So, all you have to do we
I have written it here.
uh we want to find do find replace
multiple pairs each find string is not
regular expression now remember we don't
you know the fine string are not regular
expressions okay because when you have
regular expression then then you don't
have this sequential replacement problem
because each regular expression can
match arbitrary kind of thing. So if you
have a multiple pairs of regular
expressions like find replace pairs and
each find is a regular expression
usually we just want to do that
sequentially. Okay. So but in our case
it's not regular expression. Okay. So we
want to do find replace multiple pairs.
Each find string is not regular
expression. Input is a list of pairs.
Each is a find replace string. Okay.
Convert the fine strings into a list
then call regular expression quote on
each so that they become they are not
irregular expression you know then
combine into a single regular expression
uh using all okay so that is outline of
the algorithm
uh let's uh
with all
with all operator okay then call regular
expression search uh search for what to
replace them in a while loop for each
found replace it by the corresponding
replace string uh by checking what's
match string. Okay, so that's that's the
outline of algorithm. So let's kind of
type it. Okay, so um so where is our
code? Uh here is our code. So let's
describe the algorithm here. Um
okay. So let's um
yeah
something like that. Okay. Now begin uh
begin that's beginning and end that's a
position the cruiser position of the
region we want to do the change. Okay.
So in this case you know so it you know
so if there is if it's given in the
argument in the parameter then use them
otherwise um let's do something okay so
actually so let's let's set Q
uh set sequence okay so actually we have
written this before so let me
uh grab the code okay because we don't
want to waste time to write this. Uh, if
you don't know, I've written this in my
live stream a thousand times. So, we
don't need to do it again. So, let me
just grab it.
Uh, so what is this? Um,
let me let me find where I can find that
code. Okay. So,
oh god. So this is not actually um
let me uh let me just find it. Okay.
[Music]
Okay. So that's one of these. Yeah. So
let's copy that.
Okay. Close close.
Okay. I'm going to explain. Okay. So
close that. Close that. Okay. So that's
what we want to do. Delete that. And I'm
going to explain this. Okay. If region
uh this formatted
pify the code. Pify the code.
Prefy the code. Okay. So we have a local
variable x begin and end those are
integers that's a beginning position and
end position of the cursor
of the region we want to do this
replacement. Okay so if region is active
that means if there's a selection then
set them to the beginning and end. Okay.
Uh but also actually so uh but we need
another if statement. Okay. If and if
they are defined given in this uh param
in you know the argument if they are
given then all you have to do is just
say list
um
just return that. Okay.
Then otherwise.
Okay. So
if they are given as argument just use
that. Otherwise if region is there's a
selection then use a beginning region
beginning region end the selection. If
there's no selection then what you do is
you um you search backward for the blank
line. So that is this search backward
you know the new line you know you
search for two
new line characters okay then you return
that
that's a beginning position then then
you search forward for again for two
line two uh new line characters. So
basically what that does is select the
current block of text. Okay. Separated
by new lines. Okay. So that sets up the
beginning end position. Okay. So then we
don't need this. Uh yeah. Okay. We want
to if there's no selection we just do
the current block. Okay. Then here is
the what we want the find replace. And
here the let's um so this is where our
algorithm is interesting the algorithm
outline. Okay. So we so remove that uh
remove that remove that. So this is our
list of pairs. Um
so let's see. So can we actually so let
me do something. Okay. So um let's make
the let's make it um kind of one
okay one is lower case one is uh one is
uh
capital first word okay so this is a
list of pairs so what we want to do is
now again check
convert so this is a list okay so
actually so Um
okay
when let's define the list locally. Okay
so case for search
um
so that's a list. So you need to uh
uh
find replace map.
Okay, that is like the dictionary you
want to um do. Okay. And and um find
replace map map you can set them
by this list. Okay. Now purify.
Okay. That is your find replace map.
Okay.
Now how do you deal with the lower case
or capital case? Right now I'm saying
you know make it case sensitive then
manually you know you have this group of
capital
letters um
yeah let's do that you know no case for
search set it to neo means no smart case
it's just all case sensitive
okay so that's that and so what's the
Next. So, you need to grab. So, let's
see. Uh,
let's That's too many words. Okay. So,
let's just say
FP map. Okay. That's our find paste map.
Copy it.
Then we So, algorithm outline. That's
correct. We want to change them. Uh so
uh find strings. Okay. Uh you you you
need to get all the fine strings. Okay.
So
find replace map find strings. Okay. Uh
okay. So
you want to gather all the fine strings.
Okay. So what can you do is you uh map
this is how you do uh not map chart. So
you want to map car
that means go uh basically that just
means map like Python's map or
JavaScript like JavaScript map. Okay. So
you want to map to this sequence and
what is the function? The function is
just to get the first element.
Uh
actually you need to turn this into a uh
hash table. Oh god, there's a lot to do.
Oh god, there's a lot to do. Okay, so
let's do it. So
okay, find string set the all the fine
strings. Then uh what do you want to
save them to be? You want to set them to
be a list. Okay. So all you have to do a
ref
uh because th those are arrays. You can
see those these are arrays. So that you
want to get the first element
uh array
which is x
uh wait so
yeah each pair is array so array index
is zero. Okay.
So that that that that that that that
set fine string fine string is
uh you can actually print it.
Okay. So wait not wait
you want to print fine string. Okay
that's a fine string. Uh
actually so let's see why is this um
so that sets the sequence. Oh god.
Oh god a lot to do. So
we need to finish this quickly. So why
is this indented one level to the left?
Uh let's increase the uh
that's the let. Oh yeah. So that's why
so this don't want
very you need to be very very careful
about this because this is the let block
local variables you see. So this this
needs to be inside. So uh prints that.
So basically it's a list of find
strings. Okay.
And also you need to turn this into a
map. Oh god.
So right now it's a list of pairs and
each pair is an array data type. Uh but
for this problem, it's better if you
turn them into a map like hasht.
Okay, you need to turn this into hasht.
God. Uh oh, So, let's go to Emac
Lisp tutorial. Uh hasht is a data
structure in EMAC lisp. Emacs
efficiency. Uh wait, this we need to go
to lisp basics. Uh so sequence data type
hasht there it is. So that's your hasht
and you want to create a hash table.
Okay so what you can do is make hash
table. Okay copy that
uh and close that. Okay so this right
now it's a list of arrays. You want to
make them into a hash table.
Um
so there it you know first of all there
is a design issue. Do you want it to be
hash like manually hardcode the hash
table to begin with or you can begin
with this a list of arrays which is easy
to read then have a function that turns
them into a hash table. Let's do the
function. Okay. So
that so okay so then then then you need
another variable let's say hash table
okay so yeah so
so this hasht is actually hasht make
hasht okay then you set
hash table you want to turn this into to
a hash table. Okay. Can you do that?
Yeah. So, okay. So, you again, so you
want to turn it into a hash table.
Okay. So, you do map C. Um, then what
sequence you want to map to? Uh, you
want to map to
this map. Okay. Then in the body, you
say put hasht each for each item you put
hasht. Okay. Create hash table with
symbol keys with integer keys. Uh in our
case the keys are string keys. Okay. So
literal expression for hasht length add
entry. There it is. Add entry. Put hash.
Okay. So the the body of the function is
going to be put hash. Okay. Uh no make
hash table. Wait. Uh where are we making
hasht? No, just put hash. So put hash.
Uh the key will be the
you know the first element of the array
that's called vector in magis. Okay. So
the first element of a vector how you
get the first element be that would be
array f. Okay. So array would be x. The
x is a pair you know because we map it
to that the index is zero. So that is
the key and the value would be not nine.
The value would be the first index of
that array. Okay. Then here is where you
say the hash table put it to a hash
table. Okay. So
pify the code. So this line, this single
line will turn this list of
vectors into a hash table.
It populates the hash table. Okay.
Convert uh list of vectors to hash
table.
No expansion found. Interesting.
Okay. So hasht. Okay, that's this slide.
So we got the hasht. Let's highlight it.
Okay, so this map. So we got a hasht.
Fantastic.
It's like I've been coding eag this so
much. I know what to do. I don't Okay,
so anyway, uh we got a hash table
and uh okay, convert fine string to a
list. We did that. Okay. So let's move
this part to
cut. Okay. Uh yeah. So common dial.
Okay. We convert it to hash table.
Convert. Okay.
I mean the it's at least a fine string.
Then we also convert it to hash table.
Then we need to turn this fine string
into a regular expression of all. Okay,
how do I do that? Uh, well, I
uh you can call a function called
rejects something
but I forgot. So, let's look up my I
know where to find it.
Uh, create a major mod. Okay, but if we
don't know if you are not familiar with
my tutorial, how do you find it? So, I
can we can do um a propose to search for
it. Okay, for example, let me show you
the command. The command is called a
propose command which will list all
commands containing certain regular
expression.
Okay, but right now you don't want just
command. You want to find
in the space of functions. You want to
find a function. You are looking for a
function that will turn a list of
strings into one single regular
expression. Okay, there is such a
function. So how do you find well that
so you do what you do is uh you give a
universal argument. So rejects
okay let's just search for it. Okay. So,
uh you know, I'm not talking about all
the things. Um
you probably don't know what I'm saying
because I was not too careful in
explaining. But anyway,
so you call universal argument which
which means you press control u then you
call the a propose command that will
list all
command n functions that contains the
word rejects. Okay, that's what we did
for example close it. So press controlU
universal argument you can see in the
bottom control U. Then you press the key
for a proper command which is that.
Okay. Then it asks you to type. Then
let's type rejects.
Oh what? Uh let's do it again.
Oh god. Uh wait wait wait.
Didn't wait.
What list or rejects? Okay. So you have
to type rejects. Okay. So there it is.
So you got all these functions. We are
looking for a function that converts a
list of string to
to one single regular expression with
all. Okay. So something so there's like
you know hundreds of them.
So if you are coding EMAC this this is
how you find um the functions you need.
Okay.
Cheers. Red wine.
Okay, there it is. Can you see that you
got rejects builder regular expression
builder and rejects opt funky name? So
function. This is a function return the
regular expression to match a string in
the list of strings. Exactly. That's
what we want. So go to it.
uh return to open it. So here's a
documentation of this function reject
opt
return a regular expression uh to match
a string in the list of strings. You can
can you see that uh wait actually uh
what let's do it again. Okay so let's
highlight this word. Okay. So each
member of strings is treated as a fixed
string not as regular expression. That's
exactly that's what we want. Optional
parent specifies how the return rejects
be surrounded by grouping construct.
Okay. Uh in this case so let's just do
that. So we want it to be um grouping
construct. We do that's basically means
boundary. Do you want boundary? Yes,
because we had the ETA versus theta
issue because ETA occurs inside theta.
But if we add boundaries, then you know
that's not considered um the same
when ETA is inside theta. So anyway, so
uh so words or symbols. So let's see um
uh okay so let's uh words or symbols you
know that's always a bit confusing
symbol basically means including uh
hyphen usually not always
um
let's let's use symbol for now We can
always change. Okay, let's do trial and
error cuz you know so anyway. So what?
Okay, let's try again. Describe function
rejects opt. Okay, so what is a function
name? So let's just copy that. And uh
optional paren is going to be that.
Okay, and strings is going to be xfind
strings. Fantastic and beautiful. So
actually we can print this. Okay. So
let's say messages and and just print
it.
Okay. So this is uh rejects. Okay. Find
all these strings you know in a uh
regular expression. Okay. So what is so
we need to set it uh wait
uh this is a list. Okay. So actually
this is not a good name. So this is a
list. This is a string. Okay. Okay. So,
let's change the name
uh
replace strings by
find
this. Okay. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Okay. So, you need to
set that
by that. Okay.
Fantastic. And we print it. Now purify
the code. Fantastic. Now make a backup.
Go to the directory by compile. Is there
arrow? Yes. Lexical binding directive.
No lexical binding directive. So let's
add one. use the abbreviation feature
SAR UTF
and it adds this declaration code UTF
coding UTF8 encoding and lexical binding
true so make a backup go to directory by
compile it yes
uh warning unused lexical variable x
begin and x end that's is that correct
yes that's correct because We haven't
used it but let's ignore it. Okay. So,
open the bite compile file. Delete it.
We don't need it. Uh we just haven't
used that yet. So now the algorithm
outline. So we let's see.
Okay. This is uh fairly technical and
boring. Okay. So let me finish it. Uh I
find list um
so convert list of vectors to hash
table. We did that. Yes, that's
required. Uh and we need to So what is
Yeah. So evaluate the buffer. Now let's
call this. Okay. And let's just call it
on this uh kind of here.
Let's see what we do. Do do it. Okay.
Now go to the messages buffer. Here is
what it printed. Fantastic.
So you can see uh regular expression it
print you know it generates this string
this long string of or you know that's a
regular expression or and also with the
you know so alpha beta ch that's
fantastic close it
yeah exactly so so far so good yes next
so next we need just go to um now Let's
let's start to use um go to char
uh x begin that's a beginning position
we defined here go to char x begin then
do a while loop
while
we want the regular expression search
forward. So research forward regular
expression when whenever this is true.
So what we want to search we want to
search for this uh
right this uh this is a fine list. Oh
this is uh this should be fine string.
Okay. So wait. So that is fine list.
This should be fine string.
I can actually uh copy that.
You see remember we are turning a list
into a string. So this is a new
variable. We need to like put it
you know. So we begin with a map of list
of vectors. Vector each pair is a
vector. We create a a list of just a
fine string. We also create a string of
regular expression. Uh so let's change
that to find rejects. Okay.
Do that. Do that. Do that. Fantastic.
Now it's more sensible naming.
So we turn the list into a list of
strings into a one single string of
regular expression. Then we print it.
Then we go to the beginning position.
Then we start to do the search. And what
is the reg regular expression? That
would be this
rejects. Okay. Bound. Yes, we want the
boundary that is don't go beyond that.
So the boundary is X end. Okay. Whatever
the region beginning and end. No error.
True. In case you know any of these
alpha doesn't occur you know we don't
want it to say oh error cannot find
alpha omega
okay and count we don't care okay so
so okay so the no error true we can make
it a symbol easier to read okay which
zero means true okay so while that is
found you replace it now what you want
to replace here is the new text okay
what we want to replace is that you want
to find out first of all what is a match
string.
So match string you find the exact match
string. So zero. Okay.
So that is a match string. Then you want
to get from the hash table to find the
corresponding replacement string. Okay.
So what you do is um
so hasht let's go to hasht again. So how
do you get a key the value of a key from
hasht? So that would be
uh get hash. Okay. I'm pretty sure it's
get hash. There it is. Get hash.
Okay. So get hash.
Exactly. So the key is
the match string and the table is
uh not m hash table you know so from
this hash table and optional means if
it's not found what do you want it to
return we don't care just return neo
okay so if that is true So
when it's found it we you know there
it's going to be there for sure because
the way we uh worked on this. So replace
match
replace by this string. Okay the value
of the corresponding replacement
then new text. Um then what is the other
option? New text.
Uh what? Let's check the documentation
for replace string.
Oh, new text. Yeah. So, new text is
that. Okay. Then optional fixed case
true. Wait, it's just that literal true.
And this we don't care. Okay. So that
so
that Okay. So purify the code. So there
it is our code. Actually,
I think we done. Oh, Did
we already do one hour? Yes, but it went
smooth. Uh, you know, so actually I
think I'm done.
So this message we don't need anymore.
Uh such you know remove the message the
uh crust. Okay. So actually we don't you
know the algorithm outline we also don't
need anymore.
Uh let's kind of delete it. Okay. So
that so that so that pretty the code. I
think that's it. So you can see our
beautiful code.
Replace Greek letter name to symbol.
Okay.
Uh you got beginning end position. You
got you know don't you know make it case
sensitive. Okay. Then you got the map of
what you want to find and replace
capital letters and lower case. Then you
have a local variable of the list of
fine string. Then you have a regular
expression for all the fine strings in
one string. Then you have a hash table
of find replace pairs. Okay. So you
begin by set the beginning and end
position
of the you know if there's selection use
that otherwise do the current block of
text like a paragraph.
Okay then you set up the fine list. So
it's fantastic perfect coding find list
that's all the find strings in a as a
list. Okay. Then you do convert the list
of vectors to hash table. Yeah, you
create a hash table.
Okay. Then you create the regular
expression. The all regular expression
all connectives. Then go to the
beginning. Then do a while loop
regular expression search.
If you found this regular expression
found
to the end of the position
no error then then you replace it. Every
time you do it found it you do the
replace by the corresponding entry in
the hash table. Am I correct? Double
check. Yes, I think. Okay. So back up.
Go to the directory.
Uh compile the file. No arrow. Open the
compile file. Close it. Delete it. Close
it. Evaluate the buffer. Now we can test
it.
Okay. Describe function. This function.
Fantastic. Now this is in our temp file.
Fantastic. Yeah. So now let's go to uh
let's go to some file where we let's do
you know let's go to some talk show uh
there. Okay. So
copy that, paste it and let's call the
command. There it is. Meta X. Let's do
it. Let's see if it makes error. So do
it.
Wrong type argument hasht P. Okay, we
got a problem. Go back to our code. Go
back to our drawing board. Is this our
code? Yes. So wrong type of argument.
What is the error? Replace match wrong
type argument hasht P.
Oh, right. So, we need uh wait get hash
wait hasht.
Oh, right. So, wait.
Oh, wait. This is not how you do it. Uh,
so you don't set it. Okay. Because the
because this is not functional
programming. When you use put hash,
you know, you map a function, you map
this function to this
map dictionary of find replace pairs.
Each time you map it, you have a
function, you put add to the hash table.
So you don't actually do this set
because the result of this map C is
Neil. Okay? So you don't you don't do
that. So so so
the code here is correct still correct.
You you just don't set. Okay. This this
is a part of lisp that's not functional.
Not not exactly functional programming
because you see anyway
evaluate the buffer.
Close the message buffer. Go back to our
testing page. Code the command.
do it.
Fantastic. You can see you see it
changed the theta character to the Greek
theta and did not make a mistake like
before where it changed the eta to you
know the eta part of theta to the eta
you know let's magnify can you see it so
this is
fantastic and beautiful so let's do it
again one more time copy it paste it
here. So you got alpha here, beta there,
and theta. Let's add omega. Okay, and
pi. Okay, now let's call the command.
Now don't highlight anything. It'll
automatically work on the current
paragraph. Okay, call the command.
Replace Greek letter name to symbol. Do
it.
Fantastic. Theta and omega and pi.
Okay, thank you guys for watching. That
is fantastic. ACP says, "Hello, just got
here. I'm almost done." Yes. Can you
explain the regular expression search is
Xfine rejects list? Okay. Okay. I
I I actually explained them in detail
but quickly.
So we
So the regulation Okay. So, so we first
of all we got this find list
that is a list
of strings of all the fine strings.
Okay, how we get that? Because we just
map map over the map. Okay, you see this
is the original input you know list of
pairs. Each pair is a vector. Okay, that
is
that is the
map. Okay, so so we but we create a fine
list of list of strings of just the fine
strings. Okay, then let's highlight it.
Okay, so wait highlighted pink. Okay,
then here we create a one single regular
expression string. This safety rejects.
How we do that? By calling this reject
opt function, it will take a list of
strings and we'll basically construct
one single long regular expression of
all the words.
So that is that. Okay, let's uh let's
color it.
Okay, so it's green. So now we just
search for word. This reject regular
expression is like one single huge
regular expression of all
words.
Okay. Thank you guys for watching. Uh if
you like you know let's put it back.
Showing browser. So that's today's talk
show. That's the code. This is supreme
code. Uh wait syntax code show in
browser.
Scroll down. So here's a code you can
grab it. You can do so this specific
code does the find replace of Greek
uh letters fully spelled into actual
Greek characters but you can change it
to
uh lots of use. So let me show you for
example uh so let's uh this matching
lines defend. So you can do lat to unic
code. You can do tech text to latex you
know convert you know or math symbols to
wam language or or Greek letters name to
symbol that's what we did or you can do
also remove vows English vows a e i o u
or you can replace all a brief you can
replace all profanity for example for
example let's look at the code you know
ass you
You know so that they all work in the
same principle
but you see my functions they are
calling my custom function
replace pairs region but now you don't
need the dependency
you can use that you know you know too
but now but we have this algorithm
concrete version worked out.
Okay, thank you guys. Yeah, so if you
like my stuff, you can, you know, donate
me.
Please go to kasi.info.
All the way at the bottom, you can see
my Patreon, Amazon gift card, PayPal. If
you work in a job, pay me $100. Okay,
bye guys.
Yeah, this is fantastic because
Okay, let me talk for two more minutes.
We're going to shut down. This is
fantastic because because my code uh
let's go back to the code you know this
replace pairs region they are
inefficient
you know because what I was doing is the
two pass solution so I was doing for
each pair I'm basically doing the first
replacement
but replace it by a unique random
identifier here. Then I'm going to do a
whole find replacement for the second
pair like going through the entire input
text. Then I'm going to do the third one
then then the fourth one and so on for
so I'm doing find replace like multiple
times.
That's very inefficient.
uh then once it's done then I go through
each pair again by finding the unique
identifier randomly generated basically
a random sequence of you know numbers
then then I replace them with a real
replacement character. So my code this
is a two pass solution is actually
compared to this solution we are doing
today is inefficient.
So that that is why I'm doing this today
to first of all get rid of the
dependency
you know so this you know this function
there's no dependency of my code but it
also prepares me to fix my code so that
we so I will be using this new algorithm
uh in in my package so this package let
me show you again so this is find place
payers eel.
It's it's great very useful because
instead of writing you know instead of
manually writing this whole thing you
can just simply say you know just give a
list of find replace you want and we
were talking about earlier today I
learned this because by happen stance I
asked AI AI just gave me the solution I
mean I already have the solution the two
pass is one of the solution but there's
another solution which is using the
using a hasht dictionary and using the
regular expression of all. Okay, bye
guys.