Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Son talk show. We are
going code going to code Emac LISP
today. So this is for you people who use
Emacs and who like to learn about Emac
Lisp.
So let's begin. If you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed. If you are
watching this live, say hi. Okay, we're
going to code one command called lookup
goipedia.
That's one thing to do. The other thing
I'm going to demonstrate is go to char
and go to line. That will go to a
character
um
in in your next pen. Okay. So for
example, go to a character the line
number or the position under the cursor
in the other pen. For example, if you
are coding something and you got error.
So error at line number let's say 29
39. Okay. So if you are coding here
something something and you compile or
run it and you got the error then you
want to jump to line number 39. So, you
press
I believe it's this key. This There it
is. Wait. Uh, okay. Wait, that's not the
one. Uh,
what's the key? Press uh describe P.
Press press.
That is go to line. Okay. So, go to line
39.
Oh, there's something I need to fix. But
anyway, it's supposed to jump to uh line
39 in the next pen. So, so somewhere
here. Okay. Yeah. So, anyway, so go to
line number go to line number go to line
or go to char. So, that's a two command
I'm going to show you and fix it. So,
first of all, we're going to write
uh guipedia. Hello NASA.
So Gipedia, if you don't know, it's like
Wikipedia.
It's created by Elamusk.
It began about a week ago. So there is a
guipedia right now. So let me show you.
So actually we we just going to start to
write the command. Okay. So emacis
uh eac list define define function and
show the pink window. The pink window
shows all my command calls and the
keystroke on the left. I'm using a VA
keyboard and and I'm using Safly Keys.
Let me de demonstrate again Safely Keys.
Let me show you uh if you haven't seen
it already. So Keys is the most
efficient
editing system in the universe. More
efficient than Vim or Neo Vim, but it's
for Emacs. Okay, it's like model just
like Vim but it's more efficient design
based on frequency of the command name
course and the ease of the finger. So
you can see this is a homepage of Softly
Keys and there's a video introduction.
There's lot like tens of videos in past
five years and you can look at it. Here
is the the actual uh cheat sheet diagram
for the keys. So you don't have to press
control
uh like you almost never have to press
control or the meta key or the old key.
So it's just like Vim but it's more
efficient. Okay. You can measure that
scientifically by counting your
keystrokes. For example, if you go to
the Vim Golf, you know, there's a
website kind of like who can who can
type the shortest number of key strokes
to do something you know for this is for
uh mostly for coders programmers. Okay.
So Safa Keys if you have not tried it
already try it. That's one of my best
work in my life.
Okay, it's on GitHub for Emacs users.
Okay, so that's Safly Keys. Copy uh copy
the file path. Close and uh put this
back. And let's just link Safarly Keys.
Now go back to the code. We're going to
write a command uh called Kasar.
Uh what is the command name? Guipedia.
Okay. Look up Guipedia. Copy. Go back
here. Paste it. Okay. Uh, look up
Wikipedia
of
current word the word under kuza. Okay,
created today's date version number
today's date and uh we can start to
write it. The first job is grab the
current word. So let me tell you guys
what is guipedia the nature. Okay. So,
Ela Musk, the the world's richest guy
who created Guipedia and it uh the beta
version came out last week.
Uh in fact, we can just go to it. So,
for example, let's select uh let's
select just that what and look up the
web. Wait, press press lookup web.
That's one of of my packages. So, let me
show you that. Okay. So wait, put it
back. Wait, put it back. Now describe
key. Look at the pink window. You'll see
my command core names. And uh describe
key. Press, press, press, press. So you
can see if I press those keys, it's
going to call lookup web. Okay. Now jump
to the source code. There is a source
code for lookup web. It's very short, 10
lines of code or or just five lines of
code. So and we can we're going to write
that for Wikipedia. So if you look at
this package, this is my package. Uh you
can go to the uh homepage that URI I'll
open it
lookup web. Okay. So you can look up
Google specific search engine Google
Yandex by that's for Chinese when you
want to look up some Chinese characters
in China. So there's look up Twitter
when you want to search the vast amount
of information on Twitter. Twitter is uh
very rich with information you know of
of some special kind you know different
type. So that's my Twitter. Follow me
Kasa Lee. Okay. So today's talk show uh
you know so I announced on Twitter. So
why do white men use their hands to eat
food? It's so unhygien
hygienic. [laughter]
You know in in in the past few months
people are trying to the white people
are making fun of Indians. all sorts of
Indians you know they they kind of poor
also but this is very fun video you know
she is not poor you can see their attire
you know they are like elite class or
something so but they but it's cultural
tradition kind of habit where Indians
use their food to eat you know in in seo
anyway that's digression okay it's just
something fun So my Twitter. Okay. So
you can look up Twitter, you can look up
Google, look up Yandex, that's when you
want something of Russian interest
because different search engines, then
they censor different things. Now Google
in America, you know what kind of things
it censor. Now, if you want to search
for certain things, especially if you um
like Russian related information, then
you want you might want to use Yandex,
especially if you search for girls, you
know, Yandex will return uncensored
information like pictures. But Google,
that's a different story. Okay? So you
can search BU, you can search Twitter,
you can search Google Street Map, you
can search images via Google or you can
set up a different URL to search images.
You can you can look up YouTube, you
know, just search for example, let's
search for Kali. Okay, so for example,
wait, copy that. Look up. That's that
page. Uh, and paste on today's talk
show. Let's just paste the link so you
could look up. So let's search for
okay now I don't remember what is the
key so let's just call the command
lookup YouTube
space hu okay cancel space hu there it
is actually I you know lee it just
search for lee so actually if you put
the cursor at the beginning of the line
it will search the entire line so space
space hu
there it is Google YouTube results
you can see my videos today and
yesterday this one yeah yesterday and uh
you know I by now I have like 400 videos
so 300
oh keyboard beautiful hour fantastic and
I'm not dead yet
uh that's a bad situation anyway Anyway,
so
that's demonstration of that command.
Look up YouTube and look up Wikipedia.
Look up internet archive or look up what
definition or look up synonyms or look
up dictionary or a specific dictionary
uh or you can look up wictionary
wikary or ethmology or Chinese character
Chinese character definition. So all
this you just press a key. For example,
let me show you uh press press and uh
press that key and you can see all the
commands in their keystrokes.
The backspace key you see there is right
under my hand under my left thumb. Okay.
So you can press space or or start with
backspace. Same thing. That's my custom
se setup. Okay. So this package provide
all that. So you don't have to uh go to
a spec, you know, you can just press a
few keys and find what you want. Today
we're going to write
look up guipedia. So what is Gipedia?
What is the nature of Gipedia? So you
got all these website Wikipedia.
But Wikipedia became corrupted in the
past 10 years. When you look up any
information that is
power sensitive,
also known as politically sensitive
involving power. For example, if you
look up on election, on Trump, on social
justice warriors, on trans issue, on you
know men in women's bathroom,
if you look up on gun, on gay, on um
[laughter]
you know that's American thing. You look
up those things, they will have fake
news. Okay? And also when you look up on
China and today Venezuela,
you know, a country who's got the
biggest oil in the world on earth more
than Saudi Arabia, Venezuela and Trump
is like doing things to them. So you
look up all these issues, current event
or all the other wars going on or or the
people you know uh different people in
different countries as long as they are
in the current news what you get on
Wikipedia is fake news. Okay. Especially
also if you look up on Ela Musk, if you
look up on you know besides Trump bidden
or any of the political figures,
uh if you look up on any like
popular political commentators
or activists,
what you get is fake news. beginning
about about 15 years ago, let's say
2012,
something like that. Okay. In some
cases, extreme fake news.
Uh and also on China, of course, because
China, China, you know, Trump been
saying China since 2016.
Why? Because China has become powerful.
That is why. So when you look up China,
you'll get lots of fake news or World
War II or certain country in World War
II, it's all fake news. Okay, that well
actually to some degree. Okay, the
important thing is to some degree. Of
course, when you when they uh when it
comes to propaganda,
you know, it does not imply 100% fake
news. propaganda, you know, the best
propaganda is actually, you know, they
report it with a trrist with a certain
perspective. That's how effective
propaganda works. Or they just show you
certain, you know, they they so-called
according to white men that they say
cherry pick. You know, every day on
Twitter, the algorithm show you certain
things, but other things they never show
you. Okay? So all those are considered
propaganda. In other words, propaganda,
you know, propaganda is like academic
mumbo jumbo jargon. In other words, they
just influence your thought. Okay. So,
Wikipedia became fake news since past 10
years or so. So, Ella Musk, you know,
the richest guy, he has a thought. So
you know we're going to write Wikipedia
the entire Wikipedia they call it
Guipedia based on AI you know because
today AI is becoming amazing so they
just going to generate an entire
encyclopedia in one day that's what they
did okay so now it's available online in
fact let's look up um let's look up some
let's say um
controversial topic you know There's gun
control, there's abortion, there is
different abortion organizations,
there's lots of political money
organizations. What what should we look
up? You know, we we need some example
that's simple and everyone understand.
Uh well, let's look up, you know. So,
what what's some examples? Uh
and you can look up censorship, you
know. So
uh or you could you can look up gamer
gate. Okay, that gamer gate is one of
the
you know one one of the big um
event
that influenced USA culture and politics
in past 15 years.
Okay. So game is one of the sensitive
topic. So you can look up
Wikipedia
uh Wiki Wikipedia. Okay, let's do that.
So there. So you got one version of
information. It says it begins Gamergate
or GG was a loosely organized
misogynistic
online harassment campaign.
motivated by a right-wing backslash
against feminism, diversity, and
progressiveness
in video game culture. Okay, that's a
introduction introductory sentence. So,
it's about lose the organized
misogynistic
something something. Okay, so that's
Wikipedia say now Guipedia. Okay. So I
don't have Guipedia. This command is not
written yet. So we have to go to
Guipedia first. So
go to Guipedia. Go to it.
Press that key to go to it. Okay.
Okay. Then type gameate. Okay. You need
to turn on JavaScript.
Uh, dark mode. dark mode.
Okay, now gamer gate.
Let's go to it. So, there's many
articles. Skimagate Gameagate Ant Gigi
Zo Queen
Anita Skax Sakisian
[laughter]
Briana Woo or Brian something okay this
you know those are the main uh
characters okay so let's click on
gameate
so game says gameate was a grassroots
online movement that emerged in August
primarily focused on exposing conflicts
of interest and lack of transparency in
video game journalism.
initiated by a blog post detailing the
romantic involvement of indie developer
Zo Queen with journalists who covered
her work without disclosure.
So you see so Joe Zo Queen slept with
some writer
who published talk about games. So they
slept together then other people exposed
it. So game was a grassroots online
movement that emerged this way. Okay.
Exposing the conflict of interest.
That's what Wikipedia says. Compare
Wikipedia. Game was a loosely organized
misogynistic online harassment campaign
motivated by a rightwing backslash
against feminism diversity.
Okay. So you see their take is sharply
in contrast.
So that is that is why I like to have
look up Wikipedia.
Okay. So that's on political sensitive
topics. Guipedia is very different from
Wikipedia and that is the reason
Wikipedia exist. Okay. That is a stated
goal to according to elements provide
the truth. Okay. Now, however,
Wikipedia cover lots of things including
nonpolitical sensitive topics such as
programming, mathematics, chemistry,
physics, engineering like tons tons. So
on those topics, I have I' I've done
review. If you follow my Twitter, you
might know. So let's go to my Twitter.
Let's search Kasari.
Uh
so let's search for
search Kasari. Oh yeah, you need to
click on here then search.
What do you want to search? Oh,
so I did a review uh beginning beginning
review on
on technical topics Guipedia
uh on physics on mathematics, you know,
computer science.
So it turns out Wikipedia on these
topics is basically a copy of Wikipedia
but without any illustration without
interconnection interlinks
basically just a plain text version of
Wikipedia word for word when you look up
anything on physics math topics or
programming languages. Okay. So in that
regard, Wikipedia is not good because
especially when you study math, you need
illustrations, you need the interlinks
because so many jarens you forgot. Okay.
So Wikipedia is not good for now.
Basically not good. It's the same thing
as Wikipedia. But even without pictures,
but for political topics, Wikipedia is
better. Okay.
So that is an introduction to Guipedia
and why it's there. Okay. But and now
let's just write up a lookup Wikipedia.
So So first of all, what we need to do
is grab the current word.
So uh let's see comments. Don't forget
code war the fakest.
Uh that's questionable take. Okay. I
don't know about that. Well, I mean
yeah. Okay. Let's not digress into that.
So,
okay. So, wait. So, okay. So, let's see.
Uh, Alexa, hi.
Are you not using a multi keyboard setup
anymore? Is the new keyboard that good?
Okay, so this is about the ultimate
hacking keyboard 80, which is which is
what I'm using. So a week ago I did a 1h
hour in-depth review of ultimate hacking
keyboard 80 on YouTube. So you just go
back one week you'll find it. So why am
I not using multiple? Because
because uh for one reason you don't need
it because this one is got 80 keys then
press the key cluster then I got several
mouse and track balls. Can you guys see
it? Uh let's show. Okay. Ultimate
hacking keyboard 80.
Watch my check my review. Okay. Last
week in depth and cheers. This is red
wine and pom pom pom grenade
juice mix.
The other reason I'm just using one is
because it turns out if you have two
ultimate hacking keyboard
and if you want to use the um the UHK
agent which is the greatest software
for keyboard for customizing keyboard
they only allow one. So if you want to
run you you you can have multiple
ultimate hacking keyboard at the same
time, you know, plugging or this one
wireless, you know. However, if you if
you want to run the software to change
some keys, they say, you know, you have
multiple UHK plug in, you know, it only
allow one at a time.
So when you have multiple UHK keyboard
plug in it's, you know, this won't
start. So it's kind of annoying. So I
just remove it and I don't need it
because the ultimate hacking keyboard
is, you know, watch my review cuz it got
so many modifiers and you know, I don't
need it. So anyway, back to the code. So
first first thing you want to do, so
let's get back to u
uh let's get back to the uh code. Emac
bisp. Okay.
So, we want to grab the current word.
Okay, let's just say let's just
get this to work quickly. Okay,
so so current word. Okay, so
word. Okay, so
this is a local variable x word and this
command current word will grab the word
under cruiser. Okay, then you just look
up. Okay. So, uh then you just look up
the URL. Um so, Guikipedia, you need to
find what is the URL. So,
okay. Uh this is Wikipedia. Let's go
Wikipedia. So, go back. So, copy the
URL. Paste. So, this is the format of
the URL. Okay. So,
Okay. So you got the current word x URL
and uh set x url
equals to
that basically that string and uh that
concat x
x word okay so you need concat
that into one string okay and cut it and
that's the URL
predify the code.
Okay, so you got the URI, you got the
word, then you just browse uh browse
URL.
That's a command that lets you browse
the URL and you just type the URL here.
Okay, predefine the code. That's it. I
think that's it the command. So let's
evaluate the buffer so Emacs know the
command. You can see. So now just put it
back. Syntax color show in browser.
Fantastic. We got we got our code. Now
let's look up gamma gate.
Okay.
Look update.
There it is. Beautiful. Now let's look
up another words. Okay. Uh, let's say
China.
Do it.
[laughter]
Okay. So now there's a issue. Okay. So
when you do it this way,
it returns a list of, you know, items.
Can we like try to just go to article
directly?
So what if you have
what if you have some page that's not
available? Okay, so for example that's
valid. What what if you have some
X YZ? Okay, what happens there? So look
up go to the URL. So it just says
uh doesn't exist.
Okay.
So the question is should you use which
one is more convenient?
If you do the search like you know if
you do the search way like search
question mark Q equals true then you
arrive at a page that's list of key you
know list of entries but if you go to a
page directly
then um well now let's just use the
search like what we have Okay,
just what we have. Okay, that's one
command done.
Anything else? Is it interesting?
How did you transform the string current
word in
to its function form with arguments?
It it doesn't it it'll just grab the
word. Okay, so this is a function. For
example, we can call it here. Let's say
something. Okay. Now, metax
current word. Now, that's not a
function. Okay. So, you cannot call it.
You cannot call this function
interactively. Current word because it's
not a command. It's just a function. So
it takes two optional arguments strict
and really word which basically is about
whether hyphen or underscore is
considered part of the word something
related to that. Okay. So you don't
really care for for us we don't care. So
basically consider it as a function with
without any argument. Okay. So what it
return is whatever just the word under
the cruer like if the cruer is here you
just return the word return like that.
Okay. How do we know? Can we can we try
it? Yes. Let me show you. Okay. So for
example copy this line then put the
cursor let's say
here. Okay. Now let's call
eva expression. Okay. that allows you to
evaluate a edisp expression. Okay,
do it. And now type your expression.
Let's say okay. So just current word.
Okay, do it. You see you see at the
bottom it says otherwise
a string. So it b it basically just
return that string. Okay, let's do it
again. Let's put this under here
anywhere. Call it eval expression
and the last expression current word. Do
it. It return anywhere.
Go to the messages buffer. Can you see?
Can you see? Okay. So, that's that's the
function current word. It just return
the current word. Close it. Okay. So,
and that's it uh for our command. Now I
just going to So for you guys watching
this, you can just copy it, put in your
Emacs in it. You'll have it. Okay.
But for me, uh I'm going to copy it and
put into my Excel lookup,
you know, uh packages and then give it a
key.
Uh okay. So that's that's it for that.
Now
what's the yellow command? So go to
child go to line. Let me fix that. Okay.
So describe key.
So go to char
describe key
space tg on vorac layout. Okay. So go to
line. Go to the source code. There it
is. Cuz I go to line. There is one error
I need to fix. Okay. Here. So instead of
go to char, it should be go to line.
That's it. Okay.
Uh now evaluate the code. Okay. Now
split the window. Now new buffer. Now
let's say line 200. Okay,
200. Okay, now call the command. It will
go to you know let's let's say uh error
let's say
compile error.
You have something bad at line
200.
You know when you do something it says
that. So move the cursor to the 200 and
then call
s go to line. Do it. There it is. You
see it moves right to the line 200.
Okay. So that's why this command is
useful. You don't have to type 200.
Okay. But if you want to go to you know
let's say you want to go to line 500 you
can do so by
caller command go to line it says no
number under cursor go to position so
you type 500 enter there you are okay so
this is a generalized command it
generalized the build go to fine and the
other one is go to chart so sim they you
know you can so it's
uh generalized fantastic and and it's
part of the
it's part of the safely keys okay I I
showed you before so you can download it
it's the most efficient key binding
system by now it's 4,000 lines of code
okay get that use that tell your
friends. Okay. Like my like my YouTube
like my post. Okay. Stuff.
Okay. Showing browser. So we
demonstrated. Go to char. Go to line.
New ink safely keys. Fantastic.
And I think that's it for today. Any
questions?
Did I answer the questions? ACP Junior.
So, no more questions.
You use Brave Search in a Firefox
browser. I don't know why, but it's kind
of strange. Okay. Well, that's the
reason for that is because I use
multiple browsers. So, you can see
I'm using Google Chrome here for
everything that has to do with Google,
such as YouTube, where where you need to
log in. you need to have a Google
account. So only for Google related
websites I use Google Chrome nothing
else because Google has been very
corrupted. Okay, Google Chrome
uh Brave is I use it basically just for
Twitter. Okay, Brave has automatic uh ad
blocker
among other things. Okay, brave. Now,
Firefox I use mostly for my dev. For
example, you you go around, you know,
right now there are about like 2,000
tabs open. They are all sadi websites,
okay? Like 2,000 tabs. So, how can you
tell how many tabs you have? Well, you
have to do
uh but anyway, so you can see,
you know, I can show you. So it's all my
websites. I have a total of like 10,000
articles written in the past 25 years.
So when I work on emacs on emac this on
buffam language on whatever you know
auto hardkey saw talk show universal
argument in emac this and uh you know so
lots of things including my political
comment commentaries
death of a troll you know a famous
online guy Python doc problems you know
so they you know there are 1000 um tabs,
but there's no easy way to show how many
tabs there are. You have to
uh you have to select all then then try
to close then you'll say how many tabs
you know like very inconvenient. I I
learned it from asking AI. You know, you
just ask AI, how do you know how many
tabs you have open in Firefox? AI will
tell you, but there's no easy way. Okay.
So, anyway, so Firefox I use it mostly
to do dev on my websites. Okay. So, and
uh the question why do I use multiple
browsers? I answered many times like
since 20 years ago for lots of reasons.
I always use multiple browsers since
since like 199 uh 1997.
So almost always three browsers minimum.
at some period period of years there's
four or five because back then you got
you know there's lots of they come and
go there's also opera there's also uh
you know today Microsoft edge browser
and many many var variety and many
okay so there actually there's a video
talk show where I explicitly explain why
do I use multiple browsers like
maybe five month ago go uh YouTube.
Okay, just just search for YD
multiple browsers. The the Brave search
will probably tell you, the AI will tell
you and give you the article. Okay, so I
think that's it for today.
Sorry, I was not clear. I meant that you
typed current word then transformed it
to current word TT somehow. Oh, that's
part of the Emac list mode.
Okay, so um let's see EMAC list. Okay,
copy it out. So you can see Emacs mode.
Okay, or put it back. Delete that new
buffer. Now, right now it's HTML mode.
So how do you how do you know? Describe
variable. Wait, let's show the pink
window. Okay. Now call describe variable
and say major
mode. That is a variable whose value is
the current major mode. Okay. Do it.
Then you say it says major mode is a
variable defined in C source code. Its
value is kasa html mode. Okay. So close
that. So that tells you right now in
this buffer is kasa html. So now now
let's switch it to kasa el this mode.
Okay, do it. Now I press d
space it became different space it
became the full template.
What about current word? So current word
do I have a abbreviation? No. Oh I do
actually. So press enter. It became
current word. Press enter again. Wait.
So, uh, press return. Then it became the
full template.
So, I think that answers your question.
So, if you want that, you can pay me and
get ed. Okay.
Describe uh function. Describe function
ed mode. There it is.
uh open uh you know make it full window
jump to the source code expand the
window go to the bottom 2,000 lines of
code go to the top and go to the
homepage URI open it showing browser
emac this mode and if you click go to
back to kasar emacs packages so you can
see all my packages or over here source
code jump to the directory. So, and hide
the permission and all that and delete
the backup.
Delete them. Yes. Okay. So, you can see
all my packages I wrote in the past 20
years.
Uh, it used to be free for like 10
years, but then people don't give a
This opensource opensource
fanatical you know, they
don't give a And then I was dying
of hunger around 2012.
So today they are not free. You click
it, get it by donation. Go to PayPal,
pay me 32 bucks. I send it to you. I
email it to you and it's open source,
you know. I don't make I don't make
money out of this. So, but it's just a
gesture, okay? If you like it, send me
some money, I send it to you because
when it's open source, anyone can
republish it. You know, they you can,
you know, you pay $32, you get it, then
you put on GitHub. Open source, that's,
you know, legally allowed, you know,
then you make some tricks, you know.
then then you put put it on on on mail
power whatever then basically you took
over okay that's the nature of open
source
uh very harmful actually it turns out
you know so 30 years ago I was a fanatic
of Richard Stman's free resoftware
foundation but it's very bad it's
I don't support it since like since like
15 years ago Well, it's in fact very
harmful.
So why do I why are they my code still
open source? Well,
partly because I mean Emacs environment,
you know, Emacs itself is the Richard
Stoman's baby, you know, and the whole
Emacs is uh open source. I mean it's
actually not open source. It's free
software so-called according to Richard
Stman because he and open source there's
a big war. If you say Richard Stman
thank you for open source he gets very
angry. It's on video you know he gets he
he say go yourself. You know
there's two fighting kinds. But today's
zoomers you know today's people they
don't know a thing it's all being bought
out and forgotten. You know the zoomer's
brain got washed. They don't know a
thing. So rich. So so basically Emacs
environment is all open source. So
that's kind of why it it doesn't make
you know it's not it doesn't feel right
you know if I you know the whole thing
in EMAC this I say it's not open source.
And also
there's no way I mean I mean there's no
way to sell it you know like if I if you
if I make it close source and you bought
it
in what form do I give you the file you
know it's just the source code or I can
bite compile it but by compile it
doesn't do much you know like press B to
bite compile
you know you and decompile it. Right?
So, um but but I do have the legal claim
that it is not open source or free
software. So, if you actually publish
it, then you are committing a crime.
But in practice, nobody give a you
know, like [laughter]
you know, the value is not that great.
So anyway, unless you are Google, then
you can do something like Google,
Facebook, they are all doing that, you
know, the idiotic open-source and free
software idiots. They've been
brainwashed to a degree they don't know.
So that's the situation today. Okay,
that's it. That's it for today, I think.
um
because at F mod uh you know I'm
learning F so I just started the mode
but it's not good so but on the other
hand my EMAC this mode and my HTML and
many others had they been I've been
coding them for over 10 years so it's
very good better than GNU better than
whatever you have in default Emacs. In
fact, better than any Malpa, you know,
the very popular. Oh, million downloads,
HTML mode or whatever the eagle
enhancement or whatever company mod, you
know, million, two billion, trillion
downloads. Mine is better than them.
technically superior in speed, in
functionality, in correctness and in um
speed, functionality, correctness in
feature reach, you know. Uh so anyway,
so you have to pay me to get it.
Meanwhile, just use go use Safly Keys,
okay? Because that's a mother ship and
it's free. You can you can use it.
Okay, that's it for today. So, if you
like my stuff, you know you know where
to pay me. Go to kasali.info
homepage without s in http no s. Then go
to the bottom
then pay me, Patreon me, Amazon gift
card, PayPal me. Okay.
Okay, that's it. So, what is this page?
Close show in browser. That's it for
today. Bye, guys.