good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is 2020
July 15th Wednesday noon San Francisco
time and we are going to talk about
Emacs and Emacs Lisp I'm going to write
a command I'm going to show you how to
write it and and if we have more time we
are going to do some keyboard stuff lots
of fancy keyboards this is gogo
keyboards I'm gonna show you quite quite
a lot news about keyboard on my keyboard
knock so let's begin
well so so this the the background image
you see on youtube today
is this Lisp stickers someone send me
someone made this sticker about 10 years
ago
Duncan home and he sent a few to me and
I send a few to others so we have Jacon
Jacon x' this is Jagan's photo and we
have troy Fletcher's photo and by the by
the way jaqen is a lisp skin expert and
in functional programming expert and
Troy Fletcher is a do-it-yourself
keyboard expert let me show you ok
digressions so Troy Fletcher made this
keyboard am I am i alive am i doing okay
hey guys hey George and info Matic and
Danielle
so I'm going to show you this guy's
keyboard okay George Fletcher I mean the
top Troy fetcher just let me show you so
he actually made this keyboard he is the
author of this keyboard Signum 48 now
this is few years ago he probably have
new versions so anyway he's a guy he's
got a video
he's got a YouTube doing video talking
about keyboards okay so let's begin with
Emacs and Emacs Lisp so what we gonna do
today so let me show you today's
keyboard
today's keyboard today's talk show so
this is my Emacs window on the right
side you can see all the Emacs command I
call and the key press on the left side
of the pink window and I'm using a very
key board and and I'm using some fly
keys okay so what are we going to do so
he so let's magnify okay so you see in
let me show you the chant okay so I can
see hey good morning Emily
so so you see here is my HTML and we got
the list so that's at least you well you
see there's at least and I want a
command to remove the list so for
example I want to for example I press a
key and let me show you again so you see
now look and look at the commands on the
pink window okay so I press a key that
causes the command HTML remove HTML tags
so you can see that all these the list
tags are gone now if we show in browser
it becomes one line because there's no
markup so I'm going to write a command
to remove the list but hold on a second
didn't you just call command that
already does that
yes but there are subtleties you see
this command this command I call saw
HTML remove HTML tags will remove every
tag
so for example let's say let's let's
call the command okay let's say that
okay you see now I have a code tag
inside the least okay show in browser
you see now it becomes read modify
excite age that's a Emacs command cuz I
knew page to include a fix on date
actually not date title anyway so you
see there is a tag here there is the
code tag now if I call the command like
before cuz I HTML remove action around
tag now that tag is also good I don't
want that I want just to remove the HTML
why is that well because for example I
so here is a list right so show here's
the list I want to change the list -
let's say paragraph or something or some
other type so first of all I want to I
want to remove all these list tags oops
wait you see remove those this this
these tags
let's see you see that that cumbersome
you know sorry I got a phone call
[Music]
yeah
I got the phone quite I need to pick
pick that up so I want to remove the
list
let me do it and let me do this first
okay remove the list I want to come and
to just to remove the list ul and Li tax
so let's go ahead and do it okay so the
reason I want to remove it so so is for
example I want to change this to a
paragraph so each one is a paragraph
showing browser you see oh maybe I want
to change the middle one to type you
know showing browse or something like
that so all I want is just remove the DS
tags not not any you see I want to keep
this and sometimes there's links links
to Wikipedia or links to other so I want
to keep them I only want to remove the
DS tags so that is why I want to write a
command that just remove the distich
otherwise manually do it manually is
kind of tedious you know do it manually
is kind of tedious you know and you can
use Find and Replace but again still
it's tedious so okay so
so let's write a command it's let's do
that okay so let me just start Emacs
this then okay so magnify the fun okay
saw HTML remove least okay dark string
version today's date and dark string
remove you l-o-l li these tags okay
let's say remove HTML okay so
okay so what we do let's say a region
okay let's try this simple let's do the
simplest way possible just to get the
code going am i doing all right okay so
let's do it
so I want to first of all you have a
region let's assume you know the person
selected the region so let P 1 and P 2
position 1 position 2 P set Q P 1 region
beginning that's that's right and set
position to region end now we got a
beginning and end now so let's narrow to
region okay now a to region okay P 1 P 2
so we narrow the buffer to the two just
parts we are interested so we can delete
things and do things without worrying
about a changing order or the outside of
it so narrow to region and narrow risk
to restriction save restriction yeah
whenever you can our two region you have
to coerce a restriction because so that
when your command is finished the buffer
will be whatever or in general narrow to
region it was otherwise you don't want
you know when user caused your command
and your command cause narrow to region
and what when the command is done it's
still Naruto region you want to return
to the state so you you want to rabbit
with a saved restriction
and by the way oh these are in my Emacs
least tutorial okay so you go to ogle
Emacs website just search it you'll find
it eMac Lisp and and there is my
tutorial by my tutorial if my if you
like my stuff ok let me show you
you see save narrow to region so it's
right here so it I tell you why we need
to do that and so on okay let's go back
to the code so save restriction arrow to
read region and and now we want to find
to find and replace why because we want
to remove these let me just type type
these things okay
we want to remove ul which is an ordered
list and we want to remove Oh air which
is ordered list and also we want to
remove our I which is the list item okay
we want to remove all those things okay
and and how do you do finding replacing
in Magnus you do first of all go to go
through buffer mean mean gold go to go
to cha but for me what's the command but
for you you want to go to the minimal
position of the buffer namely the
beginning of a buffer now there is a
tricky issue here because the beginning
of normally in a buffer in a Emax buffer
the beginning the first character is
always position one always and but the
maximum the end of the buffer may be
depends on how you know what you have in
the perfect but when you have an arrow
to region when you have narrow to region
the beginning is still 1 but the end may
be something else it's different from
the hope of it but okay so let me go to
cha what's the command that tells you
the but you can actually I can just say
one okay let's just say well go to cha
that's the beginning of about what and
okay then
while a while loop such forward okay
such forward what you want to search you
want to search for word that
okay optional bound
no no arrow no area must be true income
we don't care so no ever true found Neal
okay those are the optional argument so
once you find a URL what you do you
what's the command would replace a
stream it's been a few months I haven't
cope encoding eMac B's so remove the we
want to remove replace match okay that's
it
replace match that that that is it
that's the command we want so whenever
you do such forward Emacs keeps certain
internal data you can such as the
matched stream and then you can cause
certain commands that will work on those
internal data such as replace match
replace match this command what we do is
that it will replace the you know
whatever you searched stream so new text
is going to be empty okay
optional fixed case we don't care a
literal yeah we don't care
stream stream okay those are you know
you can read you can code this scribe
function and read the inline doc if you
want to know the detail okay describe
function
so anyway replace match replaced by
empty and that's it okay that's
basically all it is that's all what we
want to do that's going to work okay now
we're just going to copy that and a few
more times and do on the several other
okay so you are and oh L and the o al
closing tag then Li is a list item then
closing tag for Li okay that is
essentially it let's format our code to
be nice and that's I think that's all we
need to do let's double check one last
time and we'll be done with this command
okay I think I think it's good save it
eval buffer now let's go to HTML page
close reopen magnify okay so here we
have a list now we want we are going to
call the command that should remove the
list and but keep the links or whatever
let's let's create a link let's go to
let's do this just say Google comm htdp
google.com okay so there we have a link
let's say let's put this link here
showing browser you see this link is a
google.com
now once we call the command that will
remove the list but but the link and
this is this code will stay so okay
what's our command name let's I forgot
ok excited hear me I'll remove list okay
did we evaluate it eval buffer okay go
back okay we're gonna try it select it
meta X saw HTML remove list go whoo-hoo
it's done
you see showing in browser it's correct
you see there is no more list tag but
however you know the the other tags H
name pack stays so that is actually what
I wanted to do that's all for this
command successful but we want to make
it nice because every you know every
time we have to call this command we
have to select you know the region first
that's annoying
you know you want why don't we create a
command that automatically find out you
know the the between empty lines so you
see typically that's what people want to
do it you see there's an empty line and
there's a empty line empty lines so you
want to make this command automatically
work on a text block
similar to the concept of the paragraph
so user doesn't have to go here start
mark and oh and and go go here and you
know before going in the command so
let's do that
so let's add so all we have to do is
change the position 1 and position 2
beginning region beginning you giant we
want to automatic automatic we find it
so how do we do that
well we can do it by let me show you how
okay so for example it's it's so for
example set p1 okay and what we're gonna
do to p1 okay what we're going to do is
save excursion let me show you this okay
such backward okay we want to search
backward by two empty lines
okay so empty line Emacs is that okay we
want to search backward and okay and
remove those we don't need okay then
then search for word such forward Oh
forward cha okay move to character to
the right to positions so why is that
because you see when you search empty
you when you search to empty lines for
example if we do that right now
couette oops wait so we can call this
command oh the actually its backslash
not forward slash backslash means a new
life backslash n by the way in Emacs
buffer every line empty line is
represented by the backslash n which is
ASCII line feed which is the ASCII line
feed character so actually I need to
answer my phone okay so sorry about that
guys I'll be back in two minutes
comments guys comment okay I'll be back
in two minutes
hello I'm back wait is it going
why is it not showing me yet I'm
wondering what is going okay yeah this
is a delay okay I'm back
so so such so we want to search backward
so we can actually evaluate this command
let me show you okay call the command
evals last sex you see the cursor got
moved to two over here you see why
because we are our cruiser was here and
he was trying to search backward two
empty lines so so we found it so you
know it ends up there so but what
actually what we actually want is the
kusa position to be here you see to be
here so that that's why we want to do
for were character too so the end
position will be will be here so now we
say point point returns the position of
the kusa so
so you can see that's formatted so the
city that's how you said q1 I mean p1
position one okay in a similar way to
set the end position you just say P to
such forward okay
such forward that's right and that and
we don't care about options such forward
and it's the same thing then you want to
backward chart to actually it instead of
back over chart to let's such backward
okay
that's right then we don't want that so
why is that you see let's let me show
you why why we do this such forward in
such backward you see when you if we
call such forward we do it you see the
kusa ends up here now we need to return
to here you see we need to return to
here so so that's why we do such
backward let me show you okay okay so
like here like right now like Russa is
here I'm going to call this such
backward command by calling eval as the
expression and you will see that the
cursor will be will be back here so for
example let me call it evil ass
expression you see that's it so why do
you do such backward why not why not say
backward cha why not say back hoe cha to
basically the same thing but not exactly
because sometimes actually sometimes you
want actually the proper way it gets a
little bit complex why is that because
when you want to find a text block block
let me turn on whitespace okay sure
white space smart now you can see my
white spaces you see sometimes there is
a tab let me show you you see sometimes
you know in programming code is common
to have tab or o or some other
indentations but however you want to
consider this whole thing here too
the empty lines because they are empty
so that is why if you have situation
like that then our our code for finding
the text block will be incorrect you
know because it's not just it's not just
two empty lines that's the you know
that's the simplest simplest scenario
but sometimes you have tabs in space you
know things like that but for our
purposes let's just go on with this for
now okay turn off whitespace mod eval
buffer okay let's see and we don't need
these lines anymore
okay and eval buffer again yeah that
should be that should walk let's go back
to our code
you see here's our code showing browser
back to Emacs showing browser showing
browser you see we got a list back to
Emacs now we're gonna call the command
we we thought without having to select
okay we just put the cursor somewhere
inside the block
couette exciting HTML remove list enter
whoops wrong your own type argument
symbol P forward char - okay some
something went wrong when we went on the
forward cha why is that such backward
empty space empty space for Chan - I
don't understand ivar buffer
let's just call these hearings seem
simple P forward cha - so it's expecting
a symbol but actually it got forward cha
- I know why okay so
okay wait I cannot figure out I don't
know why so so so we are going to do
some this eMac this debugging the first
thing you want to do is turn on these
arrows by calling this command okay I
don't I don't remember the command name
but I must say I have no soul memory for
the command key so I just press this key
and you can see on a right window is a
stuggle debug on arrow so once you call
that command it toggles it on and off so
when it's on when there's a list arrow
it will actually pop up the food detail
arrow so so let's try it
so you've a buffer go back to a HTML
file and and and let's go back to here
yes because we've been working on this
page so now call the command search tml
remove list do it okay here is the debug
on arrow
message okay wait so it says okay what
enter the beginning evaluation function
wait that's not it and it's let's try it
again
couette XHTML remove list drone type of
argument there it is
oh okay I know what's going on CD a CD
error okay I made a CD arrow so why is
that because you see when you call set
p1 then you have three three code here
what emag does is that the result of
this will become p1 what actually what
we want is this okay let me show you
what actually what we want we want to
wrap it with a program P okay let me
show you so so this is what we want you
see so once you have a program P that
means return that means to exactly the
same thing do you know do whatever the
disco then but return the last line of
the code so that's what we want so okay
so we just add that okay
eval buffer go back to our list code go
through it call the command HTML remove
list do it
yay success
okay how long have I been talking hello
Freddie
how long have I been talking let's play
half an hour so should we continue
talking about keyboards or some more
Emacs stuff let me show you okay so
anyway I got this code fantastic let me
show let me show you one more thing okay
okay we got this code cut it and put put
is put this in the Lima in in this in
this HTML page but before we do that let
me show you in browser so right now it
looks like that and now I paste in the
code show in browser so now you can see
the code here and you can copy it later
on you can see this is Microsoft
Hawkshaw page just search it on my iMac
solid re info later on your be there
once I upload it so anyway you see the
list code now I'm going to press one
button and you'll be seen hax colored
now now go back to browser reload is the
syntax coloring this is fantastic and
this is this is all inks are HTML mod
it's it's on github so we've done this
task and you know that's what we want oh
oh one more thing to to finish this
remember we talked about these two empty
lines that's the simplest space but
sometimes you have tabs in between we
want to deal with those situations as
well so we need so the code will
actually be a little bit more
complicated but let me show you the code
okay okay so hold on a second let me
show you again so you can see the actual
code there it is there is the actual
code okay let me copy it and they may
explain it okay yeah no don't walk let
me explain it okay so now showing
browser now I need to move this code to
a to an independent file so I have a
command do it so we are looking at the
dist code again so I can edit it here
and now we're gonna show the new code
okay the new code here I mean let me
explain what's what's going on
so you see if first of all you have the
regular expression search for word
instead of just two empty lines now it
becomes more complex you see empty line
I mean end of line character I mean
that's it technically that that is a
form feed ASCII character but it
commonly known as end of line characters
or line return you know ASCII is a bit
complicated because M is historical
because you actually you have line
return you have a return character you
have a form feed character then you have
a line feed character so it's you know I
I can show you aski actually that's
another topic let me just see let me
just go with the least code here so you
see so you need to search for a new line
character then then you need to search
one zero or more space or tab then
followed by another line you know empty
line character so that's how you search
then you want to
[Music]
then you are okay after you search let
me show you okay
if region if region active PE
okay that's so if region is active okay
let me do this okay let me show you
so if region is active what we want is
just you know if regions active then
let's just use region user has selected
the region
now if region otherwise if region is not
active then we do when then we do this
part okay
so skip char forward then skip jump
forward then search backward search
forward ok then set P one point okay
then
and this is actually not the code we
want but but let's let's move on
such forwards then be such backward okay
okay then set P to position to point
okay I think that's it so so comment out
our in general simpler simpler case so
first of all if there is a region and
also we want to say the excursion okay
save excursion what that means is that
you see here over here we are moving
closer about because we are doing
skipped a forward and such for that
moves cruiser in general in your you
know
so when user calls your command it moves
the cruiser usually you don't want that
because you don't want an expected
cruiser movement for the user so so what
you do is you call this safe excursion
so and put the code inside it let me
show you okay like that so that means
whatever you do here once it's done Emax
the savings cushion will return the
cruiser to wherever it was okay so so
that's a that's that's what you should
do so if there's a region if user
actually manually selected then we use
that otherwise otherwise we skip cha
forward
then we search in such forward then set
set point why let's just run it it's
just give our buffer let's just try it
because those nitty-gritty details takes
a lot of thinking to actually carefully
go through ok let's go back to HTML code
showing browser and let's go work on
this paragraph okay so call the command
remove this it works now let's show show
the whitespace let me show you the
intricacies ok so now we have several
things like that let's put it here you
see now we have several spaces there we
are we always still walk call a command
do it yes it does
yes fantastic but with our code the you
know the before to simple lines code
that won't work so now if we let's say
if user actually selected some part of
it we always still work let's do it yes
it does you see this is very useful
inconvenient so if user have a selection
that means you know user just you know
for example this part is not removed and
also you know that you know user just
want to remove the list tags of a
specific region so anyway our command is
done I think actually that's it for
today and we've been talking for
so if I mean yeah that's that's it for
today for Emacs so thank you guys for
watching great to have you guys here
Emily Freddie every ok many of you I
know join this code okay so joining this
code a lot interesting people's in
different opinions and we have Emacs
stuff we have a chat room about
keyboards we have math although not many
people talk about math and we are
programming there you have tons of
people talking about programming and
technology a I you know also technology
people people people to talk about so
join this code and buy my Emacs tutorial
ok if you like my stuff let me let me
let me put a code here okay
so the code remove that and copy it and
remove the empty spaces put it here make
it colorful show in browser that's it
for today and let me show you one more
thing before I go now I need to sync to
my server so what I usually do is I go
to Asia oh wait hold on a second let me
show the command ok
I go to ECL then I have to type our sink
us I think then then I think the server
name the password and 100 bunch of
options like that options I don't even
remember so what I usually do I have a
brief you know I talked about a brief
many times you can just search for
Exodia brief in acts so I just tap type
a sync and I press space the full 100
characters command-line we will show but
so I've been using that for several
years now that's not good enough
why because after a while I have a few
hundred or briefs now some of these are
briefs I used commands you know I use
often but some of them I may not have
used for
a month or two I forgot what's a brief
name once you if you forgot what's a
bereavement a brief name you have to go
to your a brief file you know and for
example here is my Aubry file let me
magnify so I have LST for live stream
wpm t forward four minutes I don't
remember that
and he lisp t4e magnus you knows so i
have i have few hundred of reefs
especially command you know unix command
you know you forgot after you have have
not used them for a while you forgot the
name so i want a brief system that will
actually pop up a menu let me select and
let me select which your brief i want
you know i can use you know you know
like it's like i do so i just type a few
characters it will show me all the brief
containing those characters so what i do
so this so I wrote that command that
command is called this one wait
wait
yeah so so here is a command the command
name is saw interactive a brief ok once
once you call the command it will pop up
a list of your whatever you want to put
there let me show you okay so I have a
key bounded to it so I call it you see
there's a pop up under so you have a
sink one you have SSH you have vmm inbox
vmm up image one Mac screenshot and so
on you know those are usually Unix
commands your long Unix commands so let
me try it again so magnify so do it I
think one that's the one I want the
first one then you see this long command
then I just hit enter then you ask me
for a password okay so what
I forgot so but I have a a brief okay I
forgot the password as I have a brief so
it sinks to the server it takes a 10
seconds
why is it taking so long
la cacica so many of you guys came here
before I forgot you know what it's been
a while so I forgot what way this is
taking unusually long
maybe it's because I'm doing livestream
okay thank finally it's done you see so
it uploaded so you if you if if now you
go to let me show you the URL okay you
go to let me show you okay magnify you
go to this URL you will see this code
let me let me show you okay so I can
call here I want to go to Chrome okay
open Chrome open link in chrome do it
this is taking longer than expected
maybe because I'm doing so there so
there is a code so let me let me
actually paste it so you guys can see
what was the other thing Oh oh yeah so
so here is a thing okay now you see I
showed you this interactive abri but now
I have a even more improved system show
you okay so before remember I have to
press a few keys let me do it again okay
press three keys it costs and active a
brief then then I can select you know
one of the brief let's say image scale
so that's you see that's a command to
convert images to scare scare that's
part of the image mad magic so let me
show it again press three key you have
client active abri then you select a
brief let's say the first one I think
you know then then you you press ENTER
then you type password okay and and I
have a brief or password three keys or
four keys
but now I have a even better command a
better system now I just press one
single key the entire thing is automated
let me show you okay so you see now here
is back back to my you see this page you
are familiar with now I'm just going to
press one single key actually I can show
you I can I show you
let me show you here okay
you see my keyboard so again
yeah I cannot do a video without showing
my keyboard I have keyboard reviews this
is Canisius advantage - okay Kinesis
advantage to a fantastic this is my main
drive then this is the ultimate hacking
keyboard and right now I'm using it it
is a programmable keypad this is the
most powerful programmable keypad okay
and now I'm going to show you this one
finger key up operation I need to be one
finger key operation okay so you can see
my screen so and you can see my key okay
so I just press this one single key do
it
I look at my email screen there it is
synced to my server once a single key so
I before he was like one two three four
five six seven eight nine keys nine
keystrokes wow yeah so now it's just
single key okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching stay safe
and learn Emacs bye guys