good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Kasa talk show today is 2020
December 22nd three more days to
Christmas and Good morning George from
Australia and today we're going to do
emac list coding so it's going to be
nothing but emac Le coding okay and let
me check one more time if I'm alive and
well video check audio check we are good
to go so let's begin okay now if you
have a questions comments okay comments
okay uh if you want if you have a
questions post it and pay me okay
there's a a dollar sign
pay okay so uh I'm going I'm you know we
have several items so this is today's
talk show we have several items of emac
list coding and we are going to um do at
least three of them three or four it'll
be one hour okay so if you have a
preference which one to begin or which
one you you want to see Post in the
comments okay uh morning Jacob uh what
happened to your eye nothing I mentioned
before I have cross eye since I was
young I think so I have cross eye not so
severe but sometimes I cover one eye
that that makes me see
better uh okay so I'm going to just
start coding okay post post one of the
items okay post comments and uh stuff
and pay
me so modify Exile HTML rename source
file path
so comma becomes SL low line okay so we
can so here's a bunch of uh emac this
tasks and also uh some emac workflow
demo uh for each of the emac list task
I'm going to demonstrate it I'm going to
show you what it's about why it's useful
and then I'm going to uh code it because
I need to do some modification so
um okay so let me let let's begin with
the first one okay so that one isar HTML
rename source file path so let me show
you what that is
about okay so uh for example I'm going
to do a screenshot okay so I press one
key um then let's say I highlight this
section okay now that's a screenshot now
I can go back to emac now on the pink
window on the right you can see all my
emac command command CES okay if you
don't know what I'm doing just look up
the command and you'll find the source
code so I just did a screenshot okay so
then I'm going to call this
command by this key this command is a s
move image file so it ask me for
directory I say the current directory uh
no file name okay let's do it again
screenshot uh let's see wait let's
screenshot here
screenshot let's say I want screenshot
this part okay
now back to
emac now I call the command now watch
the pink window okay Some Mo image file
it's asking me for a directory to put
the screenshot too so I say that
directory that's a current directory and
it ask me for a file name so okay I just
use the default file name enter so you
can see it added this section okay let's
magnify okay so you can see it add added
this section and it also uh optimize the
PNG image and it also removed any
metadata uh you can see if you go to the
messages buffer you can
see uh it removed metadata and it also
optimized the PNG file so if I show in
browser you can see there it is that's
the screenshot I just did okay so that
command is
uh where is
it
okay where did it go so oh yeah it went
up here so move image fire okay now
anyway that that command is useful by
itself uh because when you do a
screenshot depending on if you are on
Mac or Windows or or Linux it saves to
different places like uh maybe sometimes
in desktop in Linux it saves in your
home directory I think depending on
which screenshot tool you use so anyway
you when you if you are a blogger you
want to move that image to your blog so
with this command it's just one key
press you know one key press it will
search all the directories with a
screenshot name certain screenshot name
and move it to a directory and create
the HTML uh Tex for it so for example we
have the figure tag which is for uh HTML
figure and we have the figure caption
tag
which is for uh annotation for example
you can see
now now let me show you this command
which is what I'm going to do often
times when you have a image in HTML file
or if you have uh for example if you
have a CSS file or whatever file a link
to a file a local file you want to uh
for example for example let's go to the
screenshot okay for example here is a
screenshot okay this is a file path I
can press enter to open it I can press a
key to go to the uh go to the DI
directory you see this is the file
screenshot now that name is not good
because I uh for usually I want some
descriptive name so I want to change
your name so normally the way you do it
is you open the file you go to the DI
directory then you press a key to start
rename file so let's say uh I let's say
I rename it one two three okay
let's say that okay let's hide uh wait
wait okay anyway this is a new name okay
once done press contrl c contrl c so I
got a new name one two 3 at the
end and uh let's magnify okay uh well
okay so let's now wait
open let's hide the description now now
we can magnify so you see I just renamed
the one two three now close this now
back in the HTML file you see the file
name no longer match so if you show in
browser it's you know it it shows an
error uh so I have to rename the link
here as well one two three you see I
have to rename it now go back to the
browser show it now it shows so often
times you want to rename a file and uh
the process is a little bit tedious even
with emac so I have a command that let
me rename like right on this HTML file
so I can rename it and it will
automatically REM rename the file on the
disk so let me show you so okay so I
want to rename this file let's I just
press a key and the command name is HTML
rename source file path now you can see
in the pink window okay now it asks me
what's what name I want to type I want
use I want you see so here is a mini
buffer at the bottom so let's say random
okay let's just say random enter you see
it changed it changed the link it also
uh I can press enter to open it and go
to diet hide detail
magnify uh oops uh you can see it also
rename the file on disk so or you know
you you can do it directly in HTML let
me let's let's try it again okay so this
is file rename it
uh something okay now renamed enter open
it go to diet hide other things magnify
you can see the file name and press a
key to show it in
finder there it is that's the uh mag
finder okay close
it back to emac close it close it so
that's a name I
rename uh this command allot lets you
rename things in HTML directly any any
link to local
file okay uh but there's one more thing
I want to do so what's the thing today
we I want to modify it so I want to
modify this command so comma becomes
Slow line okay so
yeah uh let me show you okay so comma
okay
so okay so let's do it open it go to
diet Let's uh let's rename it again
using diet hold on a second Let's uh
High
details uh show the pink window and uh
and start start the retired um Target
read only so now I can okay let's do it
again so now I can rename the file
directly let's just say
x s okay 1 two
3 uh let's add a comma so so here's a
new name
x uh let's just let's just put s okay s
comma one 12 3 okay contrl c contrl c to
uh to save it okay now open the file you
see it's renamed close
it copy the file path by the way this is
a command very useful s copy file path
there are other ways but anyway so copy
the file path go close that now we are
back in the HTML file now this file is
no longer uh correct because I press
enter it says file doesn't exist now I I
press the
key I mean I paste it here you can see
here is a new New
Path okay uh what do I want to
do I want to uh so comma becomes Slow
line
modify
anyway uh so let's make it a image file
okay and now delete this we don't need
showing browser same thing now the
problem
is there's a comma uh what is my problem
you see I wanted to automatically change
the comma to underscore to a low line
because typically in file name comma is
not good I'm not even sure it's uh valid
URL
um but what's the uh situation I
forgot let's see the
comments okay so no not much comments
six 15 people watching say hi
okay so I want
to
um rename source file path so comma
becom Slow line I I forgot what actually
how do I want to do
this basically what I
wanted you know when when I do my work
on my website I write down things I need
to change and for some of them that
might makes a good idea to do a video uh
in talk show I write it down so but now
I forgot when do I want this to change
but the idea is basically uh sometimes
you got a file with a comma
there I don't want to manually you know
change the comma to underscore like like
right now you see now I just change it
to comma to underscore I don't want to
do it manually I want it some kind of of
automated
way um but however when does that apply
I forgot
actually okay I think and I think I know
what what's going on so I think it it is
actually another command I want this to
be done
automatically yes it is the yeah let me
show you okay hold on a second so anyway
this file we don't need anymore press a
key to delete it you can see um this uh
this command is delete file okay so the
file no longer exist remove that showing
browser okay
so what I want to modify is that I want
to modify a
name uh okay
so let's go to desktop can we go to
desktop desktop so uh I don't even have
the
desktop okay let's go to finder and
let's go to desktop
okay there is no file there okay let's
do a screenshot press a button let's say
uh that oops uh actually that that's not
the right screenshot because that copy I
want to save to file so so let's do it
again press a button let's say I want
this screenshot okay done now go back to
the
desktop there it
is so that's the new screenshot we just
did now I want to rename this file so it
contains a comma okay uh hold on a
second
so so I'm going to rename this
file so it contains a comma okay there
it is now back
to
emx now let's call the command again
that moves the screenshot to my blog
location so
do it move image file okay the current
directory okay so it ask me a new name
you can see in the mini buffer it asks
me for a new name okay now let's say I
don't want to change so
enter it's done now yeah here it is you
can see it automatically
renamed uh replace any space by a low
line okay that's that's great but
however
it still got a comma there you see it
still got a comma there I wanted to
automatically change the comma to low
line as well so let's start to modify
the code okay so this code is
called okay let
say this code uh this code is this one
okay
so Kasa move image file actually so
actually so put it there show in browser
you can see this is the correct code
that I want to
modify okay so we are going to modify
this command Okay so let's go to the
source
code okay there it is tab go to it there
it is magnify
magnify uh examp move image file now
let's uh narrow to region okay so we
only see this code nothing else let's
magnify okay some move image file now
remember what we need to do is we we
want this command to automatically
change any comma to underline okay now
there is already code there's already
code that changes space to
underline so all we have to do is just
search for underline there it is you see
this line of code we uh replace rejects
in string so it replace Space by uh
underscore now all we have to do is
[Music]
to we we want to replace coma by uh you
know do it again so so let me do it this
way okay now you can see copy it paste
it again now
comma okay now cut this part put it
here that's that's it that's all you
want to do predy the whole
code okay uh shrink a little bit then go
to the top modify the version name okay
the version uh date
so December 22nd so that's a new version
so now we got we are going to evaluate
this code so let's just do that eval def
okay now now let's try it
again now we are back to our
HTML first of all let's open this
deleted deleted showing browser now
let's do a screenshot
again
screenshot let's say screenshot this
part okay now go to
finder there it is now that's our
Command now how how do I make this
larger oh yeah you can okay so now we
want to change the file name and add a
comma okay let's say comma comma comma
or comma okay a bunch of
commas okay so that's a new file name
now that's in desktop now let's try our
Command again so let's try our Command
again show in the pink
window space space m there it is it ask
me a directory okay now it ask me a new
name I'm too lazy I don't want to type a
new name so enter there it is now you
can see it added this section and the
file name you see the comma will become
underscore so
fantastic mission accomplished showing
browser there it is that's our new
command so mission accomplished so okay
so that's that's that one for that one
okay open it delete it clean up uh
delete
it okay so this one is done uh some move
image file okay now now this one where
do you can where you can where where can
you get the code let me show you okay so
uh we want to go to the SCE code again
uh
wait okay
copy describe function go to the source
code uh and widen so we can see all
other things on this in this file and go
to diet so and hide details and magnify
so you can see this is my emx in it so
all all these are my emx init uh this
files okay select those backup delete
them yes okay now go to
eell
magnify get
status
okay uh actually let's try magic okay
hold on a second close it call Magic
status okay so you can see two file name
changed one is a breeve I made a lot
change to a breeve and then here is what
we just did okay we going to uh stage
stage
commit uh what cc CC for commit now type
A commit
message much ad do in live stream okay
done now I need to push it to my to my
uh GitHub so p
p there it is it's done so now you can
you just go to my emex in it on GitHub s
you'll find it that code the new
code okay close that that's that is done
one task done that is this one so next
one which
okay so which you like to see
next uh that's in the emac in the my
YouTube uh live stream description
okay let's see what you guys are saying
nobody says anything cam tank says if
you want an idea of something to talk
about I know very little about how to
debug when Elis throws errors no I don't
need ideas to talk
about I mentioned that many times I mean
that's one of the the
frequent frequently Asked question but I
suppose you asked you you want actually
you want to ask the question that's a so
the question is how do you debug emac
lisp okay I I am a oldfashioned
programmer I debug emac list or python
or Goan or or JavaScript the the way I
debug is just add print statements okay
that's all I do I don't I've never used
any debugger you know because I'm not a
lowlevel programmer like C or
C++ so it's not really necessary I I
always always just
use
uh print messages uh let me show you
okay let me show you quickly we we got a
lot other things to do uh let me show
you
quickly so let's go back to the source
code again let's
see okay so here is our command again uh
image file uh let's say we don't know
what's going on so in in the code in the
relevant places you just you all you
have to do is you just
um put
messages oh my
God something is
wrong this okay then you put then you
put whatever uh things here for example
file list okay then you just run it then
you go to the message messages buffer
press a key you go to the here is the
message buffer then you just you know
that's how I debug so that's that is the
most fundamental way there's another
thing I do in emac this is that you turn
on this command okay let me show you
delete that
okay uh wait what what is
the no not that
um no okay I forgot what's the key
now there it is so you want to call this
command Okay
magnify tarle debug on error okay tarle
debug on error so so I just press a key
to turn it on now it's on now when I run
a this command any emx commands when
there's error it will pop up uh you know
all the details on on you know where it
is wrong so this is what I use very
often uh so you want to look into that
okay toggle debug on
Arrow okay that's how I uh debug emac
list code and that's sufficient for me
now now some other people you know they
have other ways but I I've never uh try
it there's uh anyway you you can you
know there's uh Sasha I believe or you
know there are blogs about it just
search for emac L
debug I think there's one called Ed buug
or something I never used it okay so
that's one thing now I want to do
another thing
modify uh modify this command s atom
update entry date to color changeed part
okay so let me show you that one
this one modify the color basically I
have a command that changed some text in
the buffer once it's done I want the
change part to be highlighted okay so
first of all let's go to emac uh block
let me show you what that command
is Okay so here is my emac block let's
go back to my talk show page here is the
talk show page okay now copy the file
path go back to the emac block
magnify so we go to here add a new
section which is which is here and paste
paste my talk show and make a link okay
then add a paragraph then show in
browser you can see that I just
added
this thing okay now I want to add it to
my atom blog you know so atom uh
uh web feed so you know there's RSS web
feed I'm using the atom format okay so I
want to add the what I did you know
today's blog to the web feed so how what
I do I go back to the
buffer and press the key and that
command is add a new entry so basically
it just added automatically added this
part
to to the you know to the to the ISS
file so let me show you the file okay go
go to the diet so here is the file okay
so hide hide whatever the details so
here's a file you see here is my emx
block and and this uh XML is the atom
web
feed so I just added it okay so um
uh which is all good okay actually we
don't want to add this because I'm just
doing this for testing
purposes uh okay delete delete so so
there it is so that's the atom file but
but what do I want to do there is
another command Okay so let's
say let's say this one so open show in
uh emac uh so
so I have this file that's a tutorial on
file encoding in emac this is very
useful if you uh work with languages
other than English or Emoji uh because
or math symbols because you need unic
code so uh this tutorial is about how
you know all the decoding encoding
issues uh in emx
okay it's uh written beginning in
2009 and let's see if it if this is in
my atom already
uh back to
emx uh okay problem scratch buffer okay
so the last entry is the problem of
scratch
buffer which is this entry
so the next one uh emac magic magic mod
problem uh magic mod is a great mod but
it's got some problems now I'm still
working on this
page okay
so so the next one is emac file encoding
FAQ so let me do something okay close
that so the magic mod so here is the
magic mod problem section okay I wanted
to add a to-do okay work in progress
okay go back to the browser refresh you
can see it says work in progress now
whenever I have a to-do tag there that
means it's not in my atom feed yet okay
and this one emx file
encoding which is not in my atom feed
neither so this one so I want to add to
the atom feed so let's do
it then okay again the F the command is
s atom new entry you can see in the Ping
window okay then I'm just rep re
reposting this okay so no to-do close it
save it no Todo okay back to the browser
refresh okay so now it's in my atom feed
okay uh now I need to of course I need
to sync to the server then you can see
it so I just press the key uh then it
syns to my server my web
server a lot to do 1,000 things to
do and you don't have time and you are
getting
old so building file list it takes a
while whenever I'm doing a live stream
what is not done
[Music]
yet
what it is done you see it updated you
can
see it updated my emac block my atom web
feed file uh and my talk show page close
it okay so what's my Point okay let's I
haven't got to it yet so um oh yeah so
so now here's the thing okay so I just
added this to
um right emac file encoding fq I just
added this entry to the item file but
let's say I want I made some change like
sometimes I you know
I you know I find some other errors and
I made some changes so I say instead of
re repost I say something
okay
uh instead of saying repost let's say I
say
uh updated okay you know like whatever
sometimes I want to make other comments
or sometimes you know it's not just link
sometimes I'm writing a Blog you know I
made changes to the blog so now we go
back to the atom file
we go back to the atom
file you can see in the atom file it's
you know it's not updated so I can
update it
here
let's say I made some update now when
you update the atom file you also need
to update this updated um field okay so
I have a command for that m x atom
update entry
date okay so
enter wait did it change now notice yeah
yes it it did you see so this is uh
December 2nd uh 22nd 15:00 40 minutes 57
okay now I call S atom update entry date
so you see it change it changed but what
I want to do now so that's a command but
I want I want it to highlight the
changed part okay so let's do that close
close go to the source code uh here is
the source code open it so here is the
command uh narrow to region so you can
see nothing but this command okay now
all I want to do is just uh just
add add the changed part
okay I mean highlight make it colored so
I forgot what's the Highlight so go to
the emac go to S emac list
tutorial so you want to highlight
something in a emac command what you do
is you go to EAC list right major
mod and you go to um
color commment no you go to wait
yeah Define phase color comment uh
keyword comp completion create key map a
brief text properties overlay
highlighting okay now actually I gave a
uh talk show about this topic so we are
not going to do again we are just going
to copy and paste code so the copy and
uh uh code is actually just this
okay
cut okay delete that so the code this is
the code we want overlay begin end okay
beginning end is position one position
two phas and both we don't want to Bo we
don't want both we want highlight okay
now we need to text properties
uh we want to find out a default phase
in
emac okay list faces display okay let's
show let's show
it list faces display so here you can
see emac lists or it's building faces
okay one of them is named
highlight there it is this one you see
you see this one uh you see this one
okay highlight that's the word I want so
close that so instead of both say
highlight there okay pedify the whole
thing and change the version date let's
add today's date
okay now the will check one last time is
this
correct uh Delete region P1
P2 okay we delete it first then we make
it
highlight uh no
wait highlight it first wait
uh okay I know what's going on
insert so after we
insert
then search backward okay search
backward
for
that bound no found no error uh okay so
search backward then we need position
P3 P3
P4
then set position P3 okay now search
forward search forward for this
okay
then send
P4 Point okay now now we make
overlay P3 P4 okay clean up the code
eval the buffer expand the
region uh widen the narrow to region
okay evaluate this section of code
shrink the window back to my uh back to
my
uh my
emac block log
then then open the uh open the atom file
okay so you can
see now I make so you can see here's the
entry okay here is the entry emac file
encoding FAQ so now let's make some
change uh let's just say repost okay now
I made some change now I want to update
this updated date tag okay now we're
going to call that command
again and it should highlight the
changed part okay so the command is CL
atom update entry date do it yay you see
there it is now there's a slide Arrow
you see the it included
the yeah it included the the the tag it
shouldn't okay but uh we can fix that
easily so okay so let's fix that uh it's
actually easy to
fix uh all we have to do
is you see this line we want to
say
minus uh Point minus one okay
so in instead of
point it will be actually not minus one
plus one
okay yeah one
plus okay delete that line and same
thing for here here will be one minus
okay minus point one okay evaluate
that's
it that's it for that so we complete did
uh close it close it we don't need to
taste uh test it let's go back to the
talk show open it so we've done two of
the items now let's see how long have I
been
talking we can do two more I
believe so we've been talking for 40 40
minutes we can do actually two more
uh what's your favorite key mapping on
the kesis keyboard one you cannot live
leave
without my kesis
keyboard uh yeah okay
so let me show you
okay so you can see here is my kesis
keyboard and uh the and the you see and
that's the
ultimate hacking keyboard okay kesis
keyboard so what's my favorite key
binding that's
uh that's a easy
question my favorite key binding would
be the map the caps lock
to to home because I'm using sofly keys
and the home key is used to switch to
the command mod okay let's see let's go
to Sly Keys website okay so show in
browser magnify magnify Sly keys and
this is a friend and this is his uh
kesis keyboard and you go down you go
down there is there it is uh
the uh command layout so you can switch
to quy you can switch to vorak or
JavaScript I wrote you can switch to
comac and it will not only change the
key binding in the layout diagram but it
will also change all the commands you
can see here for example look at look at
this uh line
okay so if I say quy it's i j KL for the
cruiser movement if I say vorac it's
chtn for the cruiser movement
so anyway my uh okay so I wanted to show
you there it is my
uh optimal layouts for Batman keyboards
for cly keys so if you are using Kinesis
there it is my layout Kinesis again you
can
change
C
vorak
comac comac
DH Workman okay that's the back ground
of this question now so what so I'm
using clis keyboard so what's my
favorite key binding well if I have to
name one what the one most important is
this home
key uh in fact on kesis this return key
I mean this this key uh on the on the
home row on the right hand the rightmost
key is actually also uh switching to
command mod mod because my left hand
Pinky otherwise I use this pinky too
much so now I also use this
pinky of course it's you can also set it
to one of the thumb keys but
anyway so that answers that question now
I think I want to do one more emac L
then
uh cam so uh sit Addy I want to update
upgrade the firmware to add the feature
of mapping key to do something on a key
press and something else on press and
hold yeah well you can
um yeah you can do that uh wondering if
it's very useful or gets in the
way uh that depends on so what's the
question exactly I want to upgrade the
firmware to you you definitely should up
upgrade the firmware the kesis uh
keyboard okay you yeah it doesn't hurt
it you should uh Ming key to do
something on a key press and something
else on press and hold yeah so one of
the thing I did recently on on the kis
keyboard is to okay let's go
to Let's digress to
keyboards so keyboard block ergonomic
keyboards you go down and you go down
you will see my kity keyboard okay now
one of the map one of the thing I did
recent I've been using this keyboard for
by now four years yeah four years since
2016 so by
now uh three and a half a year but one
thing I discovered in last year is that
you half a year ago is that I I made the
right hand keys to to become embedded
number pad whenever I press this key the
left thumb you know the end
key so and I have tutorials of course I
have tutorials about how to do that
let's see
um size comparison video review on the
flag keymap and marro
fantastic driverless programmable key is
yes design advantages where I
explain and uh let's see mechanical key
switch yes Mac Linux support yes how
long does it take to get used to about a
month for if you are new to this uh
Batman keywords default layout okay then
kesis keyboard key map Mark how two so
this
page this page I explained how you know
how how do you map keys but anyway so if
you just scroll down there's
um make the number row Do symbols and uh
shift embedded number pad there it is
basically this is what I did okay so now
I hold down the one of the Thum button
on the left hand then my right hand
fingers become
numbers uh that is much more uh
convenient than pressing the number keys
on top even though you don't have you
don't need
modifier so let's go back to emac Let's
I want to go back to emac hi I have a
few questions but they are off topic
just okay post your questions
okay uh post your questions
okay uh let's do one more emag list I
want to do one more uh finish emac
list now I'm just going to code silently
I'm just I I want to finish this quickly
so emac this modify title case Regional
line title case Regional line okay so
just like before but I'm just going to
uh do this quickly so
that so you are looking at my workflow
okay
uh so I want to add color okay so how do
I add colors let stream
pairs oh okay so
yeah searching for what search for word
uh replace
match so it is this block of code I need
to add
things this block okay so let's
see so while search for Words some thing
in a least do them one at a time so when
it's found replace
match okay and you also want you want
get the position of the match
okay position of the match which is
uh match string
okay that is that's how you get the
position of the match
no not match string match data
okay that is
the okay look up the
documentation match data okay integers
reuse repeat okay return the list
describing what is the last search
matched element 2 N is match beginning
and element 2 n + one is match end
okay element 2 N is the match
beginning return a list describing what
is the last search matched
uh such
matched let's say
zero okay let's see what it
returns okay void variable you see this
is about the D bugging someone asked
before when you turn it on the debugger
on this is what it
shows word variable reuse okay we don't
care about that do it
again uh 0 one match beginning or match
end ah what the so I I need to
get so what I'm doing is that it did a
search whenever did it did a
search it will has have data of the
beginning position of the match and end
position of the match I want to get
those
positions okay so actually we don't need
this so let's try to do okay there it is
there it is so that is the
position uh
uh okay so let's do a let I guess
that match
plus
uh match data
okay for
okay show my
last uh show my copy
history because I need that overlay
thing
here paste it
here so overlay
put position one two is going to be
a
ref okay let's do it this way
okay so position one position two so
plus one plus
two I think that's it
okay evaluate
this
command
okay change the version
name
okay back to uh back to the
HTML let's
see something in water okay now let's
call the command
what is the
key yeah title case Regional line so
okay
wait there it is but it's incorrect you
see we just called the
command and the command did you know the
first one is original the second one is
changed you see the command capitalized
the current line by the sentence case I
mean not title case so some words is not
cap you know it basically capitalize
each the be the first letter of each
word except some adjectives
adverbs you know uh pronouns things like
that uh but what I what it should
highlight is actually the change part
not the uh unchanged
part so there is some error in my code
let's go back to the
code so the match data is
actually what's going on with the match
data
[Music]
oh
okay match data so uh match data when
the first one 2 N so this is two and
this is uh 2 n +
one yeah okay two three okay so that's
let's try that
again save it run it run a code
then
uh uh let's try it
here find day
on the Phil philosophy of emac
okay so call it you wrong type
argument
it did change uh but however
wait what the title case Regional
line it did change but the highlight is
incorrect okay may uh I don't know what
I'm doing so maybe that's it for
today uh what other questions emac
related do you know of p
po stro star
his emac videos are very informative he
is also in into Western Philosophy from
what I've seen do I know that guy know
uh that name does not ring a bell but
also I you know I've been using emac for
20 years now and uh over you know 21
years old and and I'm getting old so I
don't I no longer watch other you know
emx videos like I
I don't have much uh time left I'm doing
something else so I don't want I don't
watch this days much of other emac stuff
or even new
stuff do you have a recommendation on a
math book to learn history of math yes I
have quite a few great question also a
recommendation for learning algebra from
zero with
proofs uh I Google but don't know which
review Shield to trust okay I can tell
you but exactly okay are you still here
so exactly what is
your question okay so if you want to
learn history of emac I can
recommend uh a few good
books now but your second question a
recommendation for learning algebra from
zero with proofs
uh what do you mean exactly by that you
mean so you mean you never had abstract
algebra before right is that so answer
the question you never had a abstract
algebra before and you wanted to begin
to learn abstract algebra modern algebra
is that right and you prefer a book with
proofs now if that's your question
I don't have a good recommendation you
you know for uh uh introduction to
algebra uh and also about learning
proofs there is
no such a thing okay there is no such a
there there exist books that teaches you
how to do math proofs okay and but
however such a subject you know don't
you know you don't need those books if
you want to do math and if you want to
learn about you know proofs proofs is
part of real math basically all
mathematicians all they do is proofs
nothing else okay mathematicians or you
know real you know uh math it's all
about proofs so you don't need to like
study how to do proofs okay it just come
with it it's
like okay uh yeah trust me so you just
all you want to do is just study math
okay uh okay so uh history of math books
I I can show you a few okay let's stop
emac today so let let me just talk about
math okay
uh math blog so you go to plan curves
then you go to uh just search for visual
dictionary of special plan F curves this
is a project I did in
1995 uh and also was my most popular
website like 30 20 25 years ago uh it's
you know one of the most famous website
on the web
because back then so you go to math you
go to my math page uh then you go to
[Music]
plan curve books okay now these are
books about plan curves
however they there are several excellent
one of the best math books on math
history okay let me show you uh one of
these is Morris client's mathematical
thought from Asian to modern times it's
three volumes
okay this book that's there are three
volumes of it okay so I highly recommend
it I still have the
book you know I uh I've been doing Ma
you know it's my this you know in 1990s
I read most of this you know because I
was a big uh math fanatic I still am
but math is alien a you know alienated
me
okay that so that's a great book okay
moris K so get this book three volumes
now this one Howard EES is also a
classic okay Howard EES okay well
it go it went to Wikipedia or they
here Howard EES now H Howard EES already
dead okay I think he's dead a while back
uh but however you know this you know
when you have a textbook usually they
create more and more editions long times
after the author dead so these editions
they don't change much they create new
editions because they want to sell so
that you know when you do homework and
you know in a university you know if you
you can so so that they prevent you from
using last year's old book you know they
want you to buy a new one because it's a
new edition but actually they there's
nothing to change you know they just you
know it's a artificial it's a commercial
tactics so this Howard EES you know he's
a you know he's a great math uh
historian and uh the by the the time I
WR I read it it's already you know sixth
edition like in 19 in
1992 but today I there's more editions
you know and there's interesting thing I
noticed you know like last year I was
browsing Amazon you know you know
sometimes I recheck the things that
written you know I so I recheck what's
going on with these books are they still
you know popular or what not so some
sometimes I recheck and I I went to this
book on Amazon and I I noticed somewhere
okay uh in the introduction or somewhere
it says it says we cover we we we cover
female you know women mathematicians and
we you know we H they how female
mathematicians they are something
something blah blah blah basically you
know it's kissing social justice
Warriors
ass you know as time change you know but
the content doesn't change you know the
content is the same the you know
history of math it doesn't all of a
sudden because we are into you know
women now over a sudden oh there's 10
more women mathematicians it's nothing
like that but however you know I noticed
in introduction it says you know we
cover uh women something like that it's
like purely marketing they just
added that you know for nothing okay
anyway so this book is a good one uh you
know if you can just find the old
Edition like usually you can find in Old
bookstore $5 or $3 okay you don't have
to spend you know the current edition
you know
$322 these
scums so where is it yeah you rent it
for $1
but the you can you believe that
now this book is
$300 this this scumbags this
administrators you know this you know
this uh you know this
scums back in you know back in 1992 this
is still expensive the textbook is like
$80 you know now it's $400 you know
$390 amazing you don't need it okay go
to the used book store you know get get
a like you know early editions for $5
you don't need a new edition at all
there's nothing they can possibly change
the only change they can possibly make
to this kind of books you know math
history book is to make it worse you
know make it more
okay so this is also a book a
good book okay actually this is a big
topic and there's quite a lot you know
and this also this one mathematics and
its history okay now this one I haven't
read actually I don't have this book I
haven't read but I know this highly
recommended uh you know mathematics and
its history so anyway the moris clan CL
is a classic three volumes the Howard
Eaves is also classic uh and there are
quite a few I also
read uh car booer okay uh do I have at
Le it here I think I think
so
uh now the book I just mentioned they
are not specific to plan curves okay
they are like the general history of
math c a r l oh there it is I don't have
uh for some reason I don't have a
picture so caroo
caroo okay so history a history of
mathematics this is also a good one so
there are you know there are quite a few
math books depending on how you know if
you are really really into math of
course you read them
all but if you are you know just
beginning you you know you just pick one
of the books uh you know and uh read
them okay that's that's it that's it for
today yeah so if you want to study
abstract algebra I don't have I don't
have any particular recommendation for
abstract algebra but however you just go
to
my uh you know today actually you don't
really need
you don't need a printed book because
every essentially every information is
on Wikipedia so if you are really uh
self motivated you know you don't need
someone to like equip you every day you
you need to study math you need to study
math you know if you are not like that
that's what most people are who go to
universities you know they they parents
s them to but they have no idea what
they're doing but but if you have
intrinsic uh motivation you know to
study math you don't really need a math
textbook because there are a lot tons of
them free
online okay I have I have collected a
few uh linear algebra uh few math
textbooks abstract algebra okay I don't
have I don't have a free one but anyway
I I don't have recommendation for that
topic okay so that's it for today thank
you guys for watching and you go buy my
stuff okay go buy my Emax tutorial go
buy my JavaScript in depth
tutorial that's it for today thank you
guys for
watching
bye uh there's a question upcase
initials region does this title case no
because in English Okay let me explain
this one okay this is this is about
English uh conventions you know grammar
EDS idioms and writing
okay uh wait you know in in in you know
if you notice uh on second so wait what
the yeah anyway my command is
up so anyway so so if this is a
title on the philosophy of emac there
there are several uh conventions to cap
case them okay one of them usually
followed by um you know depending on who
who is the publisher which newspaper
okay they have different convention
different styles okay one of them is
that you just capitalize the first
word uh you know the first letter of the
first word of the sentence just like a
sentence the same way you capitalized it
like a sentence okay so it's on the
philosophy of emac okay that's one way
now another way is you just capitalize
um every first letter of the word okay
so on the philosophy of emx you know
this is kind of uh you know programers
we love this because this is systematic
you you know and simple regular you just
capitalize every word you know every
letter first letter of every word now
but however the American tradition is
that some some of the um adverbs and uh
adjectives like of and or uh a you know
V you don't you don't capitalize those
so is is so this should
be on the philosophy of emx something
like that
anyway just look up Wikipedia you'll
find uh you'll find detail information
about title case okay they they're going
to tell you about all about it title
case rules you know this is this is when
we venture in into the
Garian uh
land you have AP style book you have
Chicago Manual of style you have
actually you have quite a few they don't
you
know uh yeah
anyway so you can see my command you can
see the the way I do the command is like
you you just capitalize every
word then you lower case some of the you
know the words that should not be
capitalized okay that's it thank you
guys bye