good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
where i give you a gander
to the underground of the hacker coat
of the elite program programmers nowhere
nowhere else you will see that you know
you go to youtube
there are lots of tutorials on emacs on
javascript on this and that
you will you will not get the
information uh
you get here so who are you here who is
watching
say hi type in the chat and we're gonna
talk
and today's topic is going to be random
talk about
javascript and emac these
very advanced topic advanced computer
science okay
javascript and emac bs okay so let's see
i have
tons of things to do let's go to start
talk show page
magnify the magnification is becoming a
ritual
of my talk so today's talk is javascript
and javascript
in javascript and emac list
and functional programming okay so the
background image of course i need to
sell my keyboards
so i let me show you the background
image and let me tell you about
which programming programmable keypad is
the best one okay
now you are looking at the background
image the best
the most uh the best okay so uh in my
life yes i
am alive and moving and animation and
talking and audio
so the best programmable keyboard keypad
is uh i would recommend this one okay
this this
is from china cheap
60 or something so you buy this and you
have something like
50 keys let's see one two three four
five
six seven eight eight times one two
three four five six
eight times six uh
i was a 48 48 keys
so this why do i say it's in general
okay there are so many
different uh programming uh programmable
keypads
but in general you want this one because
for general purpose programming keypad
this is the best
the on the flaw of this one is that you
have to have a windows
uh you know you have a you have to have
a windows machine
in order to program the keys because the
software to
program the keys comes in windows only
so you have to
so you do that once one time then you
can plug this in
in any uh computer on the mac or on
linux or at work
at home you know you carry this keyboard
anywhere just plug it in
and all your keys your macro keys your
shortcuts your switching tabs your copy
paste
will all be available without spending
hours
to reconfigure on each operating system
so i recommend this one okay i have this
one in fact
i have two of them somewhere i don't use
it anymore because
because i have upgraded you know let me
tell you okay so i have upgraded to
um to the more expensive version
yes okay so now i i need to i need to
show you my keywords again
now again this is kinesis advantage uh
keyboard that's my main keyboard
and the one you see here that is the
ultimate hacking keyboard
and i'm using this one as my
programmable keypad as you can see
i press the key to switch tabs okay now
this is the programmable keypads okay so
wait so you can see
yeah so i press the key so you see exact
show page
javascript test equality of objects
and what is this javascript operators i
believe
javascript operators full of loop new
feature in javascript
for each length property very
interesting you know javascript length
property so anyway
so you are looking at my um
uh you know ultimate hacking keyboard
okay that is my
that's what i use as a programmable
keypad for now and that's 250 dollars
so if you really need something like 70
programmable
keys then you use that okay so hold on a
second let me go back to
where i was and
tell you about uh these
these okay and so when you so so when
you buy this you know it's
uh it's bunch of keys and there's a
smaller version
cheaper or you can buy two of them
then it will become a ergonomic keyboard
so this is fantastic okay
now okay so so that's programmable
keypad that's a general purpose one i
recommend
but there are some others for example
this one this one's got a display uh you
know you can
you have a display on each key so it's
more expensive 150 or something
then then you have the ultimate hacking
keyboard this is what i
use right now so these are programmable
keypads
this you know this might be overkill for
a programmable keypad because this is a
this is actually one of the best
ergonomic keyboard one of the best okay
there are quite a there are a few but
the advantage of this one is it's the
the
it's got the most powerful
programmability and the most
easy to use um software
for example let me show you okay i
showed you this many times
the ultimate hacking keyboard you go to
my website and you can see a review of
it
with video
but today we are going to talk about
emacs list
and javascript lots of things you know
tons of things i'm going to tell you so
if you have a questions about those
topics just type it okay so here is you
are
looking at ultimate hacking keyboards uh
you know the programmable software so i
can change any key i want easily i'm not
going to show it today
so that's ultimate hacking keyboard then
you know then you have quite a few
others for example this butter stick
this is great if you are into
do-it-yourself
uh things you buy this you can assemble
it yourself or you can buy it
pre-assembled but one flaw with this one
is that
it's got a uniform array of keys so that
means
when the keys you want to press is in
the middle you
can you have to have visual contact you
cannot just touch it
and feel touch and feel you require
visual contact
so one tip about keyboard design is that
you do not want uniform key array okay
like that like that you don't you know
for a few keys this is kind of okay
because only got you know 20 40 30 keys
30 keys is okay but
if you have lots of keys you you rather
want
kind of wheels and knobs i talked about
this the other day
so so this page is a bunch of
programmable keypads just search for
saudi programmable keypads you'll find
it
okay that is about that okay now let's
go to
now let's talk about the real topic
javascript okay
so you guys into javascript good morning
alan good morning hello beautiful people
hello beautiful people
kodo and hello matt
okay so so let's go back to talk about
the
the what i'm gonna do with my stuff okay
let's uh
i have a bunch of lots of things to talk
about
and let's start sas start
command log mod so on this window you
can see all my emacs commands
such as moving cursor and you can also
see
all the keys i press on this pink window
so what are we going to do so go to
startup show page and create a new
buffer
and let's go to uh
notes topic notes there is something
emacs this i want to do showing browser
so let's see
okay so run current file
okay all right uh everything is good
cause i'll run current file let's do
that okay considering current file
okay so there's a lot to do okay so let
me show you what's going on okay so cut
that
show the pink window and go back to talk
show
cut this close this yes close it don't
save and open the talk show page
and open it here and magnify
magnify we need magnification and paste
it here
so you can see the command show current
click start run current file show in
browser
magnify and so
let me put this up here so you can see
you know i can watch my my own live show
so this is recursion of watching my live
show within your live show
so we let's comment that out so this
that's the youtube part
press the key to comment out showing
browser so it's good
so now you can see this run run current
file okay
which is this one this one okay show the
pink window
now i press the key so it becomes code
and go back to browser refresh you can
see now it's red
okay now i'm going to modify that
command first of all let me show what
that command does
okay so create a javascript code uh
wait uh yeah wait what
uh okay show the pink window close that
create a javascript template so you can
see that
and put it into a buffer magnify
so console.log three first four okay
run it you can see the answer here is
seven
okay so you can run it you so you can
run javascript
for example let's do something more
complex uh
uh array okay so let's say array uh
constant array okay
now three four five okay we got array
yay okay and now array we want to add
let's say add one to each one of them so
array
dot four each yes
expanded and the arrow function so
for each x you want to return
x plus one okay so that is what we're
gonna do
and instead of for each actually let's
say array map okay
uh let's see array map
yeah so run it so you can see the result
here
so four five six that's correct three
four five becomes four five six
so you can run javascript now let's cut
that paste it here
pretty if i show in browser so we have
our javascript code here
there and you can also do emac these
okay so let's uh create a template
so e max least three plus four
okay magnify and show the pink window
and run it
symbols function definition is is void
of course how idiotic i
have been because in emac this you need
this
parenthesis notation so that's no good
this is a this way so run it
where's the answer run it
but janet
where is the answer it's not wait uh
it should normally it would pop up
oh yeah so yeah you run it this way okay
so run it
eva last six
okay but um if you want to run it
you know if you want to uh run suck
you see you we are talking about saturn
current file that's the command we are
trying to demo
so let's try to demo that so message so
message
uh let's print the result of three plus
four so
run current file uh
not message okay so okay so let's do
print
okay so not point print okay now we are
talking sauron current file
uh it doesn't it it doesn't pop up the
result
instead you have to go to the message
buffer yourself so we just
did so there it is seven okay so let's
try it again
run it so you can see at the bottom
seven
you know so let's do the same thing with
javascript like a list
okay so print a list of
uh you know array in emac this okay
let's do array
uh array image is called vector
the complexity of programming languages
so vector
3 4 5 so now we have a vector
now print it you can see here's a result
now xlr and current file now we want to
add one to each one of them okay so
so let's say uh let
vect let's say ar
equals to uh
let's say ar equals to three four five
and let's say i want to print
and give a lambda okay let's uh
yeah stupid e magnus okay so lambda
lambda is a function for each x returns
uh x plus one x plus one
so
so let's say a result okay so
so we need to set
result and
run lambda okay then print result
now emac this although emac this is a
functional programming language but
you cannot easily
type you know like the way you do
in javascript for example we did in
javascript uh
let's see where is the javascript code
uh okay javascript code is here so you
can you can see
the way we did javascript is that we
created a array
then we just array dot map so
then apply a function you know inline
function
like lambda but in magnets you
you you cannot easily apply your lambda
without first of first
uh well actually you can okay uh
yeah okay that's okay so actually you
can so let's do it
so map car okay uh actually not that
map car okay
map car takes a function so the function
will be that
and the sequence will be ar so that's
what we're gonna do
so then we're gonna just print that
result so cut that
and print it here so yeah so we did the
same thing with javascript now let's run
the code okay
uh now show the message buffer so you
should see the result
at the bottom so show the pink window
and now run
run current buffer run it there it is
the result
three four five six that's correct
correctness
is our concern now paste the code here
prettify it make it from syntax screen
so there it is
javascript and emaclis so what do i have
to do so this command is
versatile this casa run current file
command
is versatile it can run lots of things
for example it can run
let me show you okay describe key then
press the key focus our run current file
so
then you can see the documentation of
this function
then you can read it here or let's jump
just jump to the source code okay
open it so here is the source code
consulting current file
so you can see this source code it can
run
emac this php perl python ruby
javascript typescript golan
bash or camera visual basic and so on
and uh what i want to do with jesus
you know this is not what i want to do i
want to do some javascript and stuff
comments questions let's see where where
we
are uh go back to
no comments uh okay
what are we doing so i don't know what
are we doing so
uh end stream no let's go back to so
what i want to do is actually
i want to modify this function so that
so that you see the way this function
runs
is that it looks at what is the file
extension
then it tries to call the corresponding
program
so for example if you have dot php
then you want to run the command line
lan
command line program php
so if your extension is start pl then
you want to call perl
if it's py then it's python and so on
and but the the program name can also be
a
file path for example for example if you
are running python 3
instead of python you know depending on
your
your setup on your operating system on
windows for example you might have
you know in the drive you know something
something python.exe
so it depends on your operating system
so this
for example and also for example if you
are running javascript you know
js for most people you are probably
running it with not
js but of course you can also run it
with deno
and also you can run it with a bunch of
other
javascript frameworks uh you know
javascript runtime system so
so this this file extension and the
program to call is
depends you know it's it's it should be
user configurable
so in theory i mean it's it's probably
best to move it out
so that's what i'm thinking i'm doing
that's what i want to do so let's show
the
uh the website for this function so you
can see
here is the website for this function
you can go there and grab the code
it's also inside uh stuff like keys
so now we have this function let's see
uh sauron current file because i run
current go file oh okay
okay so we got so we i want to
[Music]
uh so there is a question you know i
want to move this
configure you know this file extension
and the program name the mapping
to a variable now there is a
design issue involved here
the the question is why should i move it
out
the reason for moving it out so that it
becomes somewhat
i mean the purpose is for so it becomes
configurable
for example if you download and run this
program but however on your system
you know for example if you run
javascript using nod
then of course this doesn't work so you
have to change
so you can just change the variable you
know the you know program
you know some you know create a variable
so if
if this command use a variable then you
can do that
but however another way to modify this
code is simply copy the entire code
to your init file emacs in a file like
you don't you know why do you need a
variable just copy the whole thing
it's not too long it's only you know 50
lines of code
just copy the whole thing into your init
file
then when you want to modify it just
modify the code itself
so that way is in some sense simpler
you know so there's a design decision
should you
or should you not create a separate
variable
for this function to use what is the
advantage what is the disadvantage
i mean i know you know for most people
for most programmers they will think oh
yeah it's
actually better to create a variable but
not necessarily i don't
i don't think so because you can just
copy the whole thing it doesn't you know
doesn't
it doesn't matter that much i mean the
problem with copying the whole
uh function is that if i upgraded the
function
then of course then you don't have the
upgrade
if you download my newer version you
have to kind of
change it over again
that is supposedly the problem
with copying the entire function so that
is why you want to move it
out you know create a new variable just
to configure
uh this command but however there is a
disadvantage
advantage for that because if you move
this out
into a variable then it creates
complexities
complexities is the pain of programming
okay
you you can you could almost say that
every problem
in our programming industry is a result
of complexity
you know when you run program oh it
works on my machine but it doesn't work
on your machine
or there's this bug in that bug or
chrome google crash
or [ __ ] chrome google you know crash
then you have to search then there's the
bug database the [ __ ] complex bug
database
you know you then you have to assign who
is responsible what's the problem who
created you know
the [ __ ] complexity [ __ ]
so the problem of creating a variable
to use for this function so that user
can configure that variable
uh you know the problem with that
is that it creates a complexity now if
you do that this function now will
depends on a variable
what if you don't have a you know for
some reason you
deleted your unifier or something then
this function
no longer runs you know before it's in
the independent unit by itself
you know it's like uh you know they
programmers say black box you know
whatever
you know it's an independent unit by
itself
if it exists it works but now if you
you create a new variable now it's it's
something else like
the function exists but it may not work
because you don't have a variable
so that is the problem so after all this
talk
uh maybe i shouldn't change it actually
yeah
okay so because i was working on my
website so
you know and i wanted to change
you know this came up a few times i
wanted to create
you know separate this out
but it doesn't you know now you know so
whenever you have a problem it's
beneficial if you talk it through
or talking to yourself or talk you know
create an audience like you guys
and think about it and do a monologue
monologue
and then you realize that you
analyze the problem then you realize
what you know you you understand all the
logical
issues the corners and the special cases
and then you know
then you have a clear understanding
of the problem then you can decide what
is the best option
you know there's another advantage of
creating a variable to configure for
for the configuration of this uh command
that advantage is for
familiarity okay because for vast
majority of programmers when they see
when they see a variable i mean they are
used to the concept
you have a config config file you know
that's
that's that's the creation of the most
[ __ ] up in the programming industry
100 config files you know you you
are you familiar with bash config files
these
z shell config files you know every
program has 100
[ __ ] config files complex then you
have to read the documentation
for the config class that's a problem
but there's a you know the the advantage
is that once if i create a you know
separate variable for this
function so user can config
it then people are used to it you know
it's natural like use they are used to
it they don't think you know people
don't think programmers don't think
so they are used to that so they see the
config file they just
you know just they tries to make it
work and then
in turn that creates
popularity for your program you know
then i become famous
then most people will say oh i love
sovereign file current file
because if i don't do that if i do not
separate it into a config file then
the common idiotic programmers they will
complain
they will you know some of them nice
people they'll say oh
i love your sovereign current file but
you know maybe you should
separate you know this uh this
this program you know extension
and program name map into a separate
config
so that they can configure it
yeah but but that creates complexity you
know they haven't thought of
okay so there are some of the issues
about this
now let me mention another another issue
okay i you know
config file is no good okay so config
file in a sense they create dependency
now have you you have you must have
heard the term the phrase
dependency hell you know a common phrase
in programming industry
dependency hell so now if i create a
separate config
you know variable that you know you have
a dependency before you don't have that
uh okay so but suppose i create
a um suppose i do create a
separate variable then there is another
programming uh decision to make another
question
that is if i create another you know a
variable
where this function depends on start run
current file
you know the variable will be named
something like cell run
file uh file extension
program name table you know file
extension and program name
map something like that so if i create
that table
there's another question you know one
way is that i can make this command
implicitly
uh depend on that variable that is that
variable will be a
global variable so in the code somewhere
i'll just refer you know reference
to that variable so this is a implicit
dependence and this is in fact most
programs work how
how vast majority of programs work in
bash
in ruby in what whatever [ __ ] whatever
tools you use
you know config tools whatever you know
automation tools they
they all have a config file apache you
know
new you know whatever it's web server
you know mpx or whatever
almost every tool they have a configure
whenever they have a config file
the dependency is implicit you know they
are just
assumed or glo or the worst is
environment variables that's the worst
[ __ ] in
created by the unix [ __ ] the unix
[ __ ] with their unix philosophy
environment
environment variables they are just
global variables okay
they are global implicit global
variables
so one way for this to work is you you
rely on the variable you know the config
file or variable as
implicitly you know assuming it's a
global variable
or environment variable but the other
way
which is rare you know this which you
which is uh rare is that
you have explicit dependence
on that variable name that is in other
words
your function will take an argument and
that with that argument
is the map okay is this is this uh
you know file extension and program name
map so your function will actually
explicitly take that variable
this way it's theoretically better okay
it's better because
because now the dependence dependency
is explicit and from another
perspective now you have a function you
have a pure function because it does not
depends on the magical
global hidden [ __ ] environment
unix philosophy [ __ ] variable you
know it doesn't
implicit depend on those so if it fails
you'll say oh no argument given
then you know you know it's explicit you
know
and from functional programming point of
view you know haskell people they love
it so you know
you have explicit dependence so
if i'm going to create a separate
variable to do that
so i have a explicit you know i could
make it explicit uh dependence
okay uh i i think for now i'm not going
to do it okay i'm just going to have
this
unit you know this is a
soft style okay so if you want to use
this function just use it
you know just copy the whole thing put
in your init file okay don't worry about
upgrade you know upgrade you know do it
manually
so after a year or two you know if you
find i have a new version you can you
can upgrade you don't have to
i mean this is like a trivial function
okay
you can just you know like open source
this is
part of the advantage of advantage
of open source you you grab it put in
your
init file if it changed you know i mean
you don't you don't have to
so you it's your own now you know you if
you need to some change
just just just modify it it's simpler
okay
so i think actually that's what i'm
going to do i'm not going to change this
uh for now okay so
okay that's one big topic finished i was
going to
talk about then we have several other
topics okay we have javascript and we
have um
javascript okay let's maybe let's go to
javascript but
let's see who is here who is watching
and who is
and what you guys have to say
alfonso says alfonso rafare says how are
you doing i'm good
hello how are you justine justin scarfi
hello mathematician hello great
mathematician
justin scofie how are you doing how are
you doing
so and pandemic says hikes are greetings
from peru
pandemic okay what the name
greetings okay what's uh
okay so how long have i been talking
let's let's go to the next topic
you know today i was so busy working on
my website you know so many so much
things to do
so let me show you some of the things on
my uh website okay
uh so i've been talking for 34 minutes
okay so good
good so far so good yes
so run current fire okay go get it go
get it
it's fantastic it can run pro java ruby
python and so on
go land too uh okay let's
let's close that let's let's
close that close that and what is this
page
star talk show okay
okay now let's go to close messages
uh let's go back close this page amazon
search
programmable keypads okay that's my
keyboard blog close it close it close it
close it let's go to my javascript
blog so i have been working on my
javascript
a lot in the past two months
javascript the most
the the worst language on earth
uh style guide did he operate this this
you know
there's so many to talk about
let's see what i want to talk about okay
equality javascript equality okay
javascript equality
is the worst crap possible
and javascript you don't have a object
you know if you have two objects in
javascript you cannot
compare if they are the same object
[Laughter]
javascript this that that's one of the
biggest
flaw with javascript you know if you
have two objects
look at the code okay if you have two
objects in javascript
you you compare them it's false and
you know why because well the technical
the technicality
the technical excuse is that well
each object re returns a reference to
the object
so when you create two objects even
though they have
identical keys and values they are still
different
because when you use the triple equal
sign
for comparison they are comparing their
value which is the reference to the
object
what what does reference mean i mean
okay that means the
address the address of the object that's
the
the most idiotic fact concept
from the most idiotic programmer [ __ ]
[ __ ] it
that that's that's c c plus plus
this haskell java pearl
ruby python all these programmers are
idiotic facts
including java why because they are not
mathematic
they are not math languages math
languages doesn't do that
but in this industrial languages you
have this concept of reference
and the worst is c and c plus plus
the worst the most extreme
you know you then you know you have c
and c plus plus then you have pointers
then you have reference arithmetics you
know this
idiot c c is the mother
of everything wrong in programming
languages
so and then then you have c syntax that
is just
it's you know c and unix c and unix the
unix phosphate c and unix
they put strap each other they are like
that you know they are like
virus you know they virus and they
spread and spread
so today almost every industrial
language have the c
syntax the worst [ __ ] possible
the worst you know if you look at
computer languages
you know imagine you are alien from
outer space you are from mars
and you are a mathematician for mars
okay imagine suppose
suppose you are just in scotia okay
a mathematician from us and you
you look at all the possible syntax of a
programming language okay
uh then then you know
c and c c sin x is actually the worst
okay
but that's what we get you know see
because they they are viruses they
spread and spread so today
basically every industrial language uses
c like syntax so that includes
c c plus plus c sharp
java d the programming language d
and javascript and perl
and ruby and even python even python
they inherited much of c syntax
the worst possible [ __ ] [ __ ]
and uh so back back to the javascript
object you know the reference you know
so in javascript you cannot it is
impossible okay get it
it's impossible
to compare the equality of
objects objects is the most important
thing
entity in javascript but it's impossible
to
compare the equality of object in
javascript
of course you can do that by writing a
program you know you can write the
entire program you know they
and that's what i did so i wrote a
program
to compare the equality of javascript
objects or array
because array is actually an object in
javascript technically speaking
so i wrote this program of course if you
are using any one of those
frameworks for example this idiotic you
know these popular frameworks you know
know
what's the name what's the name of some
of them you know frameworks usually they
provide
uh usually they provide this function
you know the function i wrote myself
but i i can tell you my implementation
is one of the best okay you can trust me
on that
uh so so you have this function size
object equal
that compares that tells you so exactly
what it does it do it
returns true if the two objects
uh are equal so what does equal mean
equal means
uh they deep compare innumberable
properties of object so that means if
each object's
their innumerable properties their key
and values
of all innumerable own properties are
the same
then it's equal including you know if if
the nested items are objects themselves
then you just dive into it and compare
them
compare their innumerable uh
objects key and values so you know
javascript is a very complex language
it's one of
the [ __ ] up in comp in programming
history
you for for each object you have the
concept uh properties then you have the
concept of
type of the key the the property key can
be either a string
or a symbol then you have the concept of
property attributes for example some of
the attributes one of the most
important attribute is whether it's
innumerable
another attribute is for example whether
it's
configurable and it's very complex okay
very complex
let me show you okay some some of the
complexities
the property attributes
okay so reaper you know one of our
members of our
uh discord reaper asked about
why is javascript worse than php
yeah i can tell you why because the
explanation
will take a day to explain and i'm
starting to explain some of the reasons
why
so before so so you you know what is the
properties right so so now you know
about
property attributes okay let me show you
property attributes uh property property
property property attributes there it is
so you have the value you have the
writable okay writable
innumerable and configurable so when you
deal with properties you have to be
concerned about these attributes
and not just that and because you know
when you have a property
first of all one okay let me explain
one of the [ __ ] up of javascript that is
javascript properties okay there are so
many so many but let me categorize okay
i'm just going to explain one narrow
aspect of the javascript complexity [ __ ]
up
okay so javascript has a
entity called object that is one
giant [ __ ] up okay there are so many
reasons
but we are not going to into them right
now okay just
just take for granted each object has
properties okay
now properties is also one giant
spectacular fuck-up of javascript
javascript properties
why first reason is that when you have a
property you know of an object the
property
key can be two things a string
or symbol symbol is new since 2015 okay
which is a very very complex tool
so javascript symbol is also a [ __ ] up
javascript symbol properties this you
know simple
symbol type for the
keys of a property is a [ __ ] up the
reason it's created in 2015
is because it's trying to fix some other
[ __ ] up in javascript
well it's created because it's trying to
avoid key collisions okay
so that's why you have symbol poverty
you know you know if javascript object
property is well designed you shouldn't
have key collisions in the first place
but
because it's uh one great giant [ __ ] up
so you have key collision problem and
also because the inheritance
you know so that's why you have the
symbol property
create created symbol property which is
fairly complex because
symbol the symbol type
value you cannot actually see it it's
it's like a magical it you know it's
almost like a random number
so anyway a property has the property
has
key value you know a property is a
key and value pair and the key
can be either a string or
a symbol type okay value type
so that's a [ __ ] up and the symbol type
is also a [ __ ] up
why because in the because if a well
designed language for example in java
in in almost every any language python
perl
ruby the key usually can be any type
you know it needs not just to be string
but javascript is one [ __ ] up one [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ] the
[ __ ] that's why the key is a string and
it also
it it so that's a [ __ ] up
but not just that but because when you
when you try to access
properties you know it's not obvious
it's string because it's it it tries to
automatically
convert whatever your key into a string
behind the scenes
so that's a so so this all these
complexities
creates misunderstanding so let me show
you array uh property access okay
property key property key is you know um
so this page so let me let me explain
okay property access
oh my god we we can never finish even
even if we narrow
down to the just trying to explain the
[ __ ] ups of the javascript properties
itself on this very topic it will take a
whole day
because because then you have the dot
the property dot notation versus the
bracket notation
they differ in quite you know quite a
few details
for example you are familiar with the
dot notation right but
then you have also the bracket notation
why the
[ __ ] do you have two notations and what
the [ __ ] is their difference
you have to read this page i
i gamble you know you don't know the
details of the difference okay
what you so why why why why is there
such a difference why do
you have two ways to access properties
because it's
one [ __ ] up [ __ ] okay but in short
in short the dot notation is convenient
however it's not powerful because for if
your property key contains for example a
space
a space in your property key then this
dot notation doesn't work
then you require then it's necessary to
use the bracket notation
so you know so so many [ __ ] ups you know
but that's javascript okay
so then then then let me explain
so let me go back to so another so we
were saying
um property access okay
access properties right you are familiar
with this
you know normally you say something
something dot something
you know okay so you know
object access you know you don't you
don't put the double quote or a single
quote
to make it a string because javascript
script will automatically convert
convert that key
to a string because because
property key must be a string or symbol
so you
just do that behind the scenes so that's
another [ __ ] up because then
then you don't know because everything
is implicit you you might think oh you
know
something something but it's not so
that's not all yet so let me get to the
point okay so
property keys the keys can be
a string type or a symbol
type that's a [ __ ] [ __ ] and symbol
type is a backup
uh and uh then okay so so then then
a property what's the property property
is a key value pair right
then each property has
you know these attributes uh we talked
about before
so uh property attributes okay let me
show you
so property attributes okay so sp
so that's a complexity you you know is a
property can be writable
can be innumerable or can be confu
configurable
you know each one can be true or false
but that's not all
then you have the getter and setter
properties [ __ ] up the one [ __ ] up
[ __ ] javascript scatter and setters you
know what they are because
technically speaking okay so let me let
me
try to do a summary from the top again
so object has properties object by
definition is property is a collection
of key value pairs
those are called properties that's not
all because
object has more than that object has
special things for example
for example a function a regular
expression property
date object regular expression object
date object array object they have they
are not just key value pairs they have
something else
[Laughter]
but technically a proper object in
javascript
script is key value pairs okay let's
ignore other special things so
a property i mean object is key value
pairs
key value pairs and key the value of a
key can be of two things
a string type or symbol type the value
of a property can be any type any value
type okay
now a property also have attributes
we talked about but before that a
property there are two type of
properties okay
now remember the property is key value
pairs and the key the value for the key
can be a string or symbol type
that's not all that's that's not all but
now there are two
there's a new thing a property there are
two
type of properties one is called
data property okay which is which is the
normal property we are familiar with
there's another type of properties
called
accessor property also known as
get getter and setup properties
okay so that so we are we are focusing
on the complexity of the
javascript property [ __ ] up you know
very complex
that's what i'm trying to cover so so a
property there are two type of
properties
data property and accessor properties
and of the two types they have different
attributes
actually you know so we talked about
attribute before you know writable
configurable um um
and and you know and and and what's the
other
value writable configurable and uh let's
see where
uh here okay yeah innumerable yeah the
most important
number okay okay so there are two type
of properties
one is the data so called data property
which is
what we understand the normal property
then there is also
getter and set of properties also known
as accessor properties
what so what is excessive properties
they are kind of they are actually like
methods okay
but they prepared they are like methods
like functions but they pretend to be
properties
that is if you you know try to access a
property like
you know something object dot property
name equals to something
it actually calls the function behind
the scenes
so that's very complex so you have two
type of properties scatters
i mean the data property and versus the
excessive properties and they their
attributes are different
so you have two type of properties then
you have property attributes
that's not all okay we haven't done yet
so the complexity of properties
is not not done yet now we talked about
property attributes so what's a big deal
well let me show you okay let me talk
let me show you
the accessor you know property
attributes
uh so you can easily understand
what's the complexity by looking at
least properties
so for example if you have a object you
want to know all the keys
or all the values you have this this
very [ __ ] complex complexities
so first of all you have to ask yourself
do you
do you want just the in just the
innumerable ones
or do you want it to include
properties whose key are symbol type
symbol type
or do you want to uh do you only want
just the
you know the string key and not include
the symbol key type
so so you have so depending on what you
want so you
have the uh combinatorial
blog explosion of the possibilities
you know the in number of only or
include symbol keys
or whether it's just a string keys so
you have
combinatorial explosion so depending on
exactly what you want
you have to use different methods so you
have object dot keys
you have object dot values you have
object dot
entries then you have object dot get
owned property names
then you have object dot get on property
symbols
then you got then you have this you know
this
maverick out of the blue blue you know
inconsists
inconsistent reflect get on keys
[ __ ] that came from ecmascript
2015 and notice the name ecmascript
what the [ __ ] ecmascript
so i hope i covered one aspect of the
complexities the [ __ ] up of javascript
uh and this aspect is narrowed down to
the javascript properties okay
i hope that i hope i have not been
repetitors
and you know javascript
javascript that's javascript let's
javascript we are looking at okay so
let's look at the comments and maybe we
should shut down
uh okay so maybe we should uh let's see
how many how
how long have i been talking been
talking for 55 minutes
uh and yeah so let's read the comments
uh what you guys are saying
a phone cell says c is cool no
this is not cool pandemic says
how to customize emacs for view
documentation
on html css in javascript
or what is the package i need how to
customize emacs
for view documentation what do you mean
what are you talking about
pandemic okay are you still here uh tell
me what you are talking about
what do you mean customize emacs for
view documentation what
what documentation on each i mean your
question is very ambiguous the way you
expressed it what do you mean view
documentation
on html you mean documentation that's
written in html
or do you mean what like what
so i don't know what you're talking
about okay ask again if you are still
here
so juhani says javascript is cancer yes
it is
however it's a cancer we cannot avoid
it's here to stay it's going to be
it's going to stay with us for good and
deep you know deep you know deeply you
know it's because
now it's in outer space already it's
used by
space x to send you know it's using
you know controlling space x consoles
you know it's with us
in fact javascript will likely outlive
i'll leave c probably
that's how big it is so what's up people
just came to say hi okay so uh
king s uh stronger than ever okay
so arie ran hey good morning aary hey
harry i haven't seen you for a while on
discord
feel free to come back to do your link
dump
okay so everyone says hey
how to know if something is member of an
object or not
yeah so i guess i hope that i just
explained that yeah
so yeah uh and ariane says yeah
uh and observe and be okay
so yeah so no chemotherapy for
javascript yeah javascript is very
complex
you know that's the condition of our
industry and
c and c plus plus is no better okay
now of course you have c and c plus plus
fans
c and c plus plus is the worst [ __ ]
c and c plus plus
no better and perl is not better okay so
uh python is a bit better python okay so
what what is better
python golan julia
java even java you know i don't like
java but java
you know i don't like java because it's
op and it's like you know it's has
it's not my style it's not my philosophy
the java language has has a philosophy
and has a model of the runtime it's not
my you know i don't like it
at all i don't i hate java java is op
it's not functional programming you have
to do something sim
simple if you want to do something
simple it requires
3000 lines you know to code in java
i don't like it but however java
objectively speaking
all things considered you know with
respect to
human human animals creation of computer
languages you know the entirety
we we we look at the from the
olympus mount olympus look at the java
look at everything human creation what
humans are doing human animals are doing
with computer languages
then java is we could say
it's reasonably good okay it's not as
it's not as what's written as c c plus
plus [ __ ]
[ __ ] c plus plus [ __ ] the c plus words
coders
and [ __ ] the c c coders and [ __ ] unix
any one of you are proponents of linux
or unix you
you are a fuckettes you you are kind of
technically speaking
cc plus first okay and they they
they are crap they are they're the worst
[ __ ] possible in javascript
and perl okay and bash
including bash but java
is is it's not a [ __ ] java is
reasonable okay java is not a
hack all the others are hack they are
hackerman hacks
see let me repeat this is important c
there are these are criminals c c plus
first
javascript pearl
uh bash and unix
shells basically anything unix anything
come from unix
including linux including apache
including any unix tools that requires
config files and dot files [ __ ] unix
[ __ ] unix is the the the boss
of the criminal gang in in terms of
human animals programming industry
what we humans do with respect to
the quality you know the goodness of it
but java is okay java i mean i don't
like it but java is like reasonable
okay that's that is my opinion
we are programmers and we are talking
about opinion that's what we have
opinions as opposed to mathematicians
that's that's a big that's a giant
difference between programmers and
mathematicians
in programming industry that that is us
everyone is you could almost say
everyone is idiot
everyone is petty you know they are
gonna gonna tell you
oh my language is the best oh my editor
oh e-max versus vi
the [ __ ] petty [ __ ] everyone has
their own opinions
how you should format your code oh this
you know you should
uh space versus tab you know indentation
my style is better than yourself [ __ ]
programmers [ __ ]
this is programmers is in sharp contrast
to mathematicians because in mathematics
there's no nonsense allowed
if you have nonsense get out and you
know this is
actually easy to see of course there are
still crack pots but they it's it's not
easy for them to grow
you know if you are a crackpot like the
pearl
you know like the larry wall who created
paul or the
guido guido von rossum who created
python you know or the martin fowler the
worst crackpot
in my opinion okay in my personal
opinion this is not objectively
objectivity talking in case they see my
ass okay
you you cannot sue me because this is my
opinion this is free speech in america
okay so the pearl guy you know idiot
the larry wu the martin fowler who
created
created uml you know the and bunch of
other crap
uh and uh you know they they they are
kind of like crackpots
you know they create theories they tell
you what to do
they for example they spread you know
all the other unix philosophy crap
they create codes uh you know they you
have lots of codes
so and they can easily create a massive
audience in followers
you know they have you have per perlers
you know you have the
republic of pearl you know you have the
onions you know the
you know onion the the nation of onions
or whatever the
apocalypse whatever the pearl creates it
you know the
bunch of things and you have pythonic
you know you have the python priests and
and so on then you have the elite
phonetics
you have the e-max
commune you know they're talking about
buffers you know the scratch buffer
the you know the nested parenthesis the
the macros you know a bunch of crap
anyway so
it's easy you know in the programming
community it's very it's almost
trivial it's easy to create a code that
has no
no solid scientific basis such as
the patterns the programming patterns
[ __ ]
the agiles [ __ ] you know these
uh codes so but in contrast
in math it's not easy to do so
yeah you have crackpots in math too now
and then you know but they don't they
don't they cannot grow they don't grow
they don't get followers as much
they do have followers but you know
there are some crackpots
they they will tell you they created the
new theory
for mathematics you know they they found
a solution
where mathematicians are unable to solve
for a thousand years you know there are
there are people like that and some of
them
have followers you know they have some
followers but their fellows are not
mathematicians
that's the difference between the
programmer programming code and
mathematicians
code you know if you you could have a
code but you don't have much followers
and your followers are not
mathematicians they don't know what to
do
they don't know what is math they their
their followers are programmers like you
guys
okay i think that's it for today so
let's see uh what other things
we need to shut down because i talked
non-stop for one hour
rambling this uh
hello professor kasa hello i've been pro
called professor
a couple of times in my life you know
although technically speaking i'm no
professor
hacker news the source of everlasting
opinions on tab versus space
exactly not very popular now but
back in 2010 exactly and i have an
article on that of course
i can talk about that topic that very
topic for one hour
uh in fact well yesterday so yesterday
we did a topic or two
two days ago we did a topic about
uh code formatting uh so
uh you should watch it okay i recommend
if you like
my show you know you you like the
general
smell of my show you know you watch a
few times a few of my shows you like it
i recommend the one i did like two days
ago
you know the one before this one that
one is talking about
uh code formatting you know issues
obvious space okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching and if you
like my stuff
of course just pay me okay you know
where to look you know yeah
you you just you have to pay me so we
can grow the casa coat
so pandemic has a question so i mean
like
company quick help package but for html
css
javascript so company so
pandemic has a question
about seo don't i don't i still quite
don't understand your question about
something
something formatting html css javascript
in emacs so company quick help i don't
know what that
is i haven't used that package uh
so what do you mean format yeah so sorry
so what do i think of rust you know
that's another very popular question
okay i'm tired of answering that
question you know that's type th
that's the type of question the elite
hacker types love to ask
which is my audience which is exactly my
audience it's
it is them you know it is you guys
who watch my show and who often
ask that question what do you think of
just i don't like rust okay i
it's good okay i'm not going to wow
well i do what do i think of res rust
well rust is a low level language okay
it's it's
modern so in general
modern ones are better than 10 years old
once or 20 years or once
so rust is i think it's definitely
better than
c or c plus plus technically speaking
okay so that's my opinion rust is better
scientifically better for sure for
absolute certainty
rust is a better language than c [ __ ]
or the c plus plus [ __ ] absolutely
for no reason other than it's created
after 20 years
you know because technology you know
always improve you know complex you have
complex
situations environments you know so
if you have a language that's like 10 or
20 years difference
the later one is almost always better
okay that is my opinion what do i think
of rust
it's better than c or c plus plus for
sure
but however rust is not my cup of tea
okay i don't like rust you know i don't
like rust because it's not my
philosophy i what i like i like
functional programming i like high level
programming
i like mathematical programming language
programming languages that is designed
for mathematicians
where the model of the programming
language is modeled on mathematics
not the [ __ ] cpu the hardware the
memory
let's do memory let's do okay let's
let's create references to memory [ __ ]
that's what rust is about that's what
rust do
you know the cpu the gpu the memory the
ram
you know the cash level one cash [ __ ]
[ __ ] rust
so that it so you want to know my
opinion about rust that is my opinion
about rust
okay technically i like i think it's
better than c or c plus plus
i don't like it personally because i'm a
high level guy
i you know i can talk about this for one
hour about the low level languages in
higher level languages
i know i like high level mathematica
it's the best language possible
mathematica sim symbolic pattern
matching
you know technically in theoretical
computer science
it's called um it's called
um what's the name i
i haven't you know i so i have 1 000 uh
articles on that okay let's just let me
show you my articles
programming languages you know uh you
you guys don't know it because
because you guys are industry industrial
programs
programmers but you can if you want to
i have written uh everything on my web
page lots of things okay
and most of the things i actually talked
about because i have
6 000 articles
uh yeah 6 000 articles written in the
past
20 years 20 now 20 uh 23 years
written in past 23 years on languages
so so the for example
my most favorite you know if
without qualifications if you ask me
what is
my favorite programming language without
any qualification
that would be mathematica or also known
as wolfram language
because that language which is
symbolic it does oh
rewrite system that's the word i'm
trying to say so in theoretical computer
science
look up okay look up wikipedia there's a
term
this is called rewrite system
you know you might you know you might
think of you know you might be familiar
with terms like tuning machine or lambda
calculus
or tuning complete or you know things
like that or
or uh howard currying isomorphism
you know from haskell people so another
term
in that in this kind of theoretical
computer
science one of the term is called
rewrite
system you can look up that is
the model of how
mathematica is doing the computation
rewrite system okay that's
that's what i like so why do i like it
without qualification
i need a qualification because
because mathematica even i like it but
it's not a industrial programming
language because
it will not be suitable for example if
you use mathematica
to write a operating system that would
be cd
okay it would be very stupid to use
mathematica my favorite language
to write operating system to write
drivers for your keyboard
you know that's very silly if you want
right
operating system rust okay just rust
would be
the solution
uh so yeah again i don't like russ but i
like
golan okay gold line is also low level
but i like golan
very much and i have reasons you just
type
why i like golan uh type my name sorry
well i like
why i like golan you'll find yes that's
it okay
so pay me okay donate money to my
account patreon
or you can buy my emacs tutorial or
javascript in depth tutorial
buy it pay me and thank you very much
for watching my show that's it for today
are there lots of job opportunities for
using
functional programming languages
basically no if you compare
two other languages so if you
if you are into functional programming
and if you are looking for a job
you must be very very very good
okay so this guy uh
shinkai are you japanese okay so
he's asking if there are jobs for
functional programming languages such as
haskap
there are you know people are studying
for example facebook is
using ascot so but you must be very good
so if you are really into haskell or
functional programming
so do you know just focus on ascot okay
if you
you know if you really like haskell
focus you know study
you and not just you must actually
create projects
not just studying theoretical aspects of
functional programming don't listen to
what the fast ascal heads telling you
okay
if you are into ascot don't listen to
what you know the online
haskell forum all these [ __ ] they
are telling you
you know what to do don't listen to them
instead
if you are really into a scout and want
to be good at it
write a application in haskell okay
write write it so and you and try to
make
1 000 users of your haskell program
that do that okay write a practical
application
not not something toy no some new
concept
no clean you know pure functional
programming clean
beautiful [ __ ] that's what high school
people like to do
instead i recommend if you want a job in
functional programming
write something that people will use
you know disassociate with the haskell
[ __ ] they're talking about
monads every day this cut you know cut
you know draw a line they stay outside
you stay here
you called your own high school trying
to write a facebook
in haska okay i recommend that or
something else
trying to write the application that
have not you know trying to
have you know something practical so you
have lots of users
write that in haska or camel or some
other
functional programming language choice
of your choice
such as julia or camel
f-sharp for microsoft or you can do
ascot okay try to do that
after two years of that you will get a
job
you will get job at facebook and and big
money okay
big even bigger money than the c plus
stress c
coders but you have you gotta be good
okay dedicated you know
put put effort you know put three four
hours for two years you
you have it
bye bye bye guys