welcome to our talk show today is June
26 2009 teen today we are going to do
live coding of JavaScript or Emacs Lisp
or goal and so which one to do you know
let me know type in the comments which
one to do so let me get ready pop this
out we're gonna do live coding today
live coding one of JavaScript or Emacs
Lisp :
type here to let me know which okay so
before there are nobody nobody is here
yet
so before we start let us this is sparks
music I talked about it yesterday this
is fantastic the most cold and austere
music there is mathematical perfection
that's what they say the common you know
common comment about that so let's do
either : JavaScript or Emacs Lisp we're
gonna do like coding of that but
meanwhile you know where I wait for
people to come on let me just talk about
some random things programming related
basically so first of all saw start let
me show you this okay since we are in
Emacs so we're gonna do saw
start command log mod so that you see
all the command I call on the left
window here okay
now this code is typescript typescript
is a statically typed JavaScript wrapper
that's basically what it is it is
greatly useful when you have lots of
code when you have you know thousands of
lines of code you know typed language
versus dynamic and typed languages I
usually you know when I was younger you
know like ten years ago
oh you know the from 1990s I always
preferred dynamic languages you know
without type because I thought that that
that is more natural no more human for
example in math you don't say
when you say x equals to 2 you don't say
oh X is a type number you know but
actually there's more detail to that but
anyway so I thought dynamic you know not
typed languages it's more natural you
shouldn't need to declare variables with
a type that is actually a byproduct of
computer engineering hey guys so we
gonna you know do one of JavaScript or
email is or Golan so you know type
please type in your comments let me know
which one you would like to see because
that's what I announced but you know
since you know I'm waiting for people to
come and I'm just going to I was talking
about random things typed verses and
typed language you know so here is
typescript now so I was saying when I
was younger I prefer dynamic you know
without types because I think that that
I thought that was that is more natural
as an example you know in math you don't
have to declare types to define to
define variables or you know
functions but there's more detail to
that actually anyway so it's more
natural because and I thought the thing
is that I thought typed languages are
for example C and C++ these are the
worst everything that's wrong with
computer science with with the
programming industry start began with
see ya then simples president then Java
then C Xiao you know Emperor so so why
is it a natural white why is typed a
natural that that's a byproduct of
computer engineering which is like you
know C programming language C or C++
like you like when you have to do you
know variable you have to declare a
variable is like short you know int long
you know double float well what the [ __ ]
is that float yeah and and also with the
you know the jargon they choose they've
chosen to use you know it's in int int
is integer right but then then you have
float type which is you know it's very
interesting if you study the etymology
you know float double you know why would
they name float and double like in math
there's no such thing there's there are
real numbers
but there are integers you know which is
you know 0 1 2 3 and negative 1 2 3 so
on and there are real numbers real
numbers are like a elastic band you know
there's you know you have an elastic
rubber band there's infinite number of
them so and real numbers are usually
represented when you you know write it
out it's represented by decimal notation
like you know 3 point 1 2 3 4 you know
so in math there is no such thing as
double so but why do we have the name
turbo and fro well the reason first of
all you have floated the reason the sea
you know programming from a programming
languages have that is because because
you have to
percent numbers in a memory and you know
in CPU and and those are just
electronics on and off so in other words
it's binary system and you cannot
represent yeah actually so this is
actually a deep problem you see the the
problem is that you want to represent
the real number you know how do you do
that well on paper we can you know say
we can use a fraction we can use a
decimal number or you we can actually
use let's say you know we can write
square root of two that that is the real
number you see this is math real number
but but if you want to represent on a
computer you don't really write square
root of two you know square root of the
tooth and he's saying that's a number
you have to compute it and the many real
numbers so we so that is the question
actually you see this actually this is
this is a very interesting question
because the question is how do you
represent be your numbers you know we we
are taking this into a philosophical
context I mean in general like how how
you know how do you represent the real
numbers on paper by mathematicians or by
common people how do they what do they
need you know are they are real numbers
they don't need or you know then as well
you know with respect respect to
programmers how do you represent real
numbers let's say how do you represent
real numbers on abacus so so the
question immediately becomes then we
have to ask what kind of real numbers
you need to represent because you know
your numbers there are lots of anyway I
digress
a lot so anyway the so you know the C
and programming languages they they have
you know the float well the reason is
floaty is because they they want to they
they are not actually real numbers you
see the float you see they are just
a number a decimal number you know they
actually fractions you know technically
mathematically they are actually
fraction they can they can they are
beyond numbers because they are numbers
represented by fractions in fact so so
so the numbers you know um in computer
languages such as C they only represent
they don't have all the real numbers
it's impossible to write any real number
you can only have basically fractions
and you basically any fraction the the
subset of real numbers that can
represent it by a fraction you take that
fraction then you convert it to you know
binary numbers then you store that you
know into the CPU or memory you know why
in one island of Iona love and so on so
so the so they named it float well the
the reason they named it float in C is
that you know it's it's represented by
you have you know they are trying to
represent the binary you know a sequence
of binary digits with a point in between
somewhere so the float is actually like
indicates where that you know point is
at so it's I think that's why it's
called float you know you know in the
beginning it's represented by two bytes
like eight sixteen bits or something
like that then you have double double
means you know double precision so
that's why they have you know in C you
have types float then you have double
then you have long I think long is for
integers right I don't remember anyway
used small bits bits so anyway so I so I
Tigris you know II finish in the topic
so I was talking about you know
programming languages typed verses and
typed so I think those typed I thought
when I was younger the type top natural
because especially
with C so you have this you know int
double float then you have you know so
they are like a byproduct of programming
they are like by byproduct of computer
engineering you know this was what I say
you know when you do engineering you
have a lot of pipe a lot of byproducts
you know like things you don't want you
don't really want but it is there
because of the you know many constraints
where engine engineering for example
when you build when you build a car you
know you have the shift manual shift
right you know this you know today most
cars are automatic you know you don't
have to shift the gears but you know
before you have manual shifting that is
kind of a byproduct of engineering you
see because you know in a very beginning
you cannot you know automatic shift is
now is more complicated in involves lots
of you know Universal gears it's more
complicated you cannot you know it was
not invented so in the beginning you
only have you don't have shift at all
then you started to have manual shift so
that's kind of like the the concept of
shift is kind of like a byproduct of
engineering because of limitations we
have lots of byproduct of engineering
for example it caused tires you know you
have to pump air every you know every
once in a while you have to pump air but
that's like when you when you drive a
car why do I want to pump the air you
know you don't want to but you have to
because because we don't have because
the you know we say that the air less
tire you know now today they have tech
new technology where a tire with are
without errors so you never have to pump
it so that is theoretically better but
but I'm not sure what's a current status
but anyway so you have to pump air into
the tire that's a byproduct of
engineering because engineering is not
just is not God
you know you just say you know make a
car and you have a car in every way
perfection
so byproduct of engineering so I thought
you know the types in programming
languages the you know see like the
language see you know int float you have
to declare types before you use a
variable that is you know just the
byproduct of computer engineering nobody
you know you don't need it so this is
what I thought when I was you know in
you know almost in the past 20 years but
in the past five years I started to like
well not really like but I appreciate
I'm not sure which one I would like
prefer but I appreciate those typed
languages but not see here but by typed
I mean like typed like you know like :
Haskell okay now these are more here I
started to think that typed languages
are not you know the the way they use
types in Haskell and Golan they have
what you call automatic typing type
inference but anyway you know the way
you see it you the way you see it is
that it's not unnatural because because
the type static types used in has cow
and : they are a especially in Haskell
they are of a entirely different nature
than the types in C you know simplest
for C Java those kind of languages in
Haskell the type they are not exactly
byproduct of engineering but rather they
are part of the part of the tool useful
tool that is you are computing with
types you know before you are computing
with numbers you know in C well you know
and any numbers or strings and you want
you need to specify type because
otherwise it's not efficient you know
that's byproduct of engineering
but in Haskell type is part of the tool
you know you are not computing with
numbers or strings you are computing
part you know a significant part of your
computing the the reason you use Haskell
you know the language is is is such that
you are creating a program you know
algorithm a system based on types so you
have so how do you say you know let's
say for example let's say we have a
bunch of baskets baskets you you put
fruit fruits in you know bananas apples
you know you put them in now you have
similar basket now suppose I say you
know yes suppose you have basket at a
home and this specific basket can only
allow bananas if you have a pose you
need to use another basket you know so
every time you put a fruit in a basket
you have to you know if you put it in a
robot basket you just pop it out you
know is it the wrong this is only for
pnina's you know so suppose you have
these baskets they they only allow
certain fruits to be put in now that's a
pain that's paying in yes right but
however now you know let's you know
swap to the other side of the coin and
look at this thing from a different
perspective now suppose you have this
basket just like before they are typed
however whenever you put a basket you
know a fruit let's say banana into the
basket
it automatically you know praise the
banana you know whatever you put in
Apple pay no cherry into the right
basket that only contains spanis so in
this way you see this basket becomes
useful because they automatically sort
out you have your fruits you know you
can just dump all your fruits but in a
banana you know Apple oranges you know
Oh dump them into one place it
automatically so them out into different
basket
now that is useful now you see so this
is two different ideas so this is how I
saw you know how the types becomes
useful very useful in Hesco languages
okay so we got three people watching
yeah you know so what we're gonna do
today we're gonna talk we're gonna code
let's see we are supposed to be code in
JavaScript or go lenore-- my beast so nu
anyone got opinions you know so what
should we do what should we be coding so
we talked about types type two languages
versus and type two languages you know
how a perspective is different you know
but still I mean you see C is still no
good CSE first-person Java this kind of
language is neo type Leo type is still
you know byproduct of computer
engineering but has cow it's a different
story but anyway so let's go back so I
was you know I'm gonna just gonna talk
with random things since nobody is
saying hey hey good morning shown
JavaScript but I'll be watching anything
I like your basket na analogy thank you
so yeah okay so let's actually let's do
Java scripts because I was waiting for
people because that's what we're
supposed to do you know and you know
since you find it useful so let's do
that
so let's shown so good good morning or
good evening
so let's go troops okay so blog okay
let's go to my web blog I wrote these
more things oh by the way Shawn I did
JavaScript code yesterday
video did you watch it the entire
session like one hour is coding
JavaScript coding Tom you know right
writing a let's see programming blog
it's go to woody blog okay so so yeah
yes yesterday I think was yesterday or
the day before I did a four I'm gonna
show you I'm gonna show you now so
actually just go to the blog programming
blog yeah so and great so we're gonna do
another one actually so let's go to sod
you know go I go to my website sorry dot
info and let's go look at web dev blog
also yesterday we did this one Radio
gradient generator can you guys see it
yes you can okay so let's move this here
so wait wait Radio gradients CSS
generator so you can click random random
and you can get a code here it shows the
code here you see random rambin random
hold rainbow a change number of colors
three four seven and change the position
where they may come from you know bottom
left and you can also change it to a
lisp and you can copy the code here so
we did this we wrote this from the
ground up without any you know jQuery or
framework or whatever it's pretty it's
pretty cool so you have all these
different radio gradient let's get some
let's see for let's show some pretty
anyway so yeah so we did this this
yesterday and actually test typescript
so I was using so that code is actually
here oh no this is another one I never
mind
so anyway we did the gradient and
actually our ago I woke up four hour ago
and I wrote up this I was trying to do
this live but you know I just wrote up
quickly let's see how long have I been
talking so I think we're gonna do
another one so maybe you'll take 20
minutes so I did this you know just an
hour ago so this is this is the
box-shadow
so let's see offset offset blur and you
know and then we can change the color
and change the background color the
background color let's speed that okay
let's be darker okay so now change the
shadow color shadow let's say red so
anyway so we did this but it's still not
complete we need let's refresh what we
need is a random color box so you know
we need a button that says generate the
random color and we need another well I
was thinking we need we we want another
part that says you know just generate
the whole thing random completely right
different different offset let's see if
we can play and strain it's super blur
and also this user interface is not so
good you see you have this offset X&Y
and then you
these offset why you see offset X you
know why is horizontal whines vertical
but it's not natural to use because you
rather want some kind of like people
like people can just just point to a
direction yeah a direction than a
distance that's more natural you know
like the X Y offset they are like a
vectors you know like a mathematical
idea of vectors the first two numbers
here you can see you see the first two
numbers here so they are like a vector
so they have a length in the direction
you know like which which way the shadow
goes to yeah so so we're gonna a week so
we I'm thinking we're gonna modify you
know add the random button and oh the
other thing we I want I need to do I
want to do is go to you see this is my
visual CSS tutorial what I want to do is
I want to make a you know a dynamic
interactive app for each and every one
of them so you know people can easily
see how they walk you know but backs the
here's a then then there's a text shadow
you see take shadowy I don't have a
interactive thing it would be nice to
have so what do you think Shawn should
we start over
let's do this text shadow or should we
modify the back the box shadowed and add
a random color button yeah let me know
you know you pick is you pick is whether
I feel you know better
how do run how - let's try random okay
yeah so let's do that let's see how many
people so let's add a random button a
button okay so so service first of all
let's go through the my local website
okay so let's open the file so this is
the file that's showing Firefox in
Firefox I have JavaScript off so you
don't see you know this is not not
working so we need to go to the chrome
so let's go to chrome close that new tab
paste enter so here's the chrome and we
can let's see so yeah so that so this is
the source code this is the source file
for that you can see okay let me show so
this section this section is the the
application application the you know the
interactive thing so we have color
picker input here so what we gonna do
actually so we need to let's just add a
random boxes that instead of you know
explaining like you know the whole thing
so okay we need a new user interface
widget that says random button okay so
let's do that we need a button element
and over here yes
so button
and type equals two you have to say type
equals two button random color okay
showing browser there it is
random color let's move it up here right
sure there that's good and wait wait
wherever you see this flash that means
let's change the color here FFF
okay so hold on a second let me change
that so what I'm doing is that well
whenever i refresh this page you see
there's a flash of the background it was
gray then it becomes white
the reason it's like that because I have
the CSS here it was the gray you know
silver then when the JavaScript loads
you know the default is white so that's
why you see the fash that's no good so
let's just change this to white now
refresh you don't see that color flash
that's good so now let's go back to code
here we added a random button here here
and now we need to add an ID so let's do
an ID then okay so copy that paste here
random color button let's say button
random color okay so that's our ID good
then let's go to then let's go to open
the file so this is this javascript file
this is actually typescript I'm using
typescript now typescript is just a
superset of JavaScript so you see
basically the whole thing is JavaScript
the only difference is that you see this
thing here the HTML input element that
is that it that is from you can kind of
ignore it
you know typescript is a statically
typed language and it's very useful you
know like like I said before it's very
useful because it when your program is
large it helps in you know avoiding
errors coding errors so anyway so we
have we just added a button for random
color right now there's no action so
first of all we
to get the get the button you know
element it's this smaller than okay so
so let's say button random color okay so
get an get element by ID then we get
that element we you assign it to button
and button random color then so we got
the element at the then we need to add a
event meaning that you know when when
people press the button something some
function is called so let's let's add
the event here so button button random
color add event listener and we call the
function update now the function update
is defined here so the function update
basically it gets all the parameters
from user you know all those colors you
know XY this offset and blue values get
all those values then converted to a CSS
syntax so you have this result string
this is a CSS syntax then you just you
know added to the style box shadow you
know added here and also you know create
a stream box shadow string and and add
it to the content so that's how we got
you know the text here the CSS syntax so
so that is how update is done now
remember now we have a random color what
we want to do is
so we got a button so and we also got a
event so when user cricket your core
function update now what we are this
button do of course it changes the color
first of all when we when user cricket
it should also change the the color here
let me show you what you mean so random
color let's see so we go back to the
code function update then we we say
constant random color okay equals to oh
yeah then we need to generate you know
we need to generate the random color
string luckily we have I have done that
before so how do you random hex yeah so
we have done that before by just you can
go to CSS linear gradient same thing
with the radio rate Radio gradient
random direction so here there's a you
know random color button so we can just
open this file and get a code from there
so such for JavaScript such such such
such such yeah so here is the CSS linear
gradient code and so we have this code
here it's magnified okay we have this
random int it generates a random integer
from min to max then we have a random
color string that's what we want this
function let's copy it it's kiddoes
close it close it now we are back in a
box shadow code here and that's inserted
so we got new these two new functions
random int and random color stream so
how they work you know random in just
give you a random int so so the way this
work is that first of all we create a
function that that generates two
hexadecimals let me let me get this so
that it's easier to see
okay so
so here here is the code it's easier to
see now so this random colored string
first of all you define our inner
function that generates two two
characters by calling the two string
sixteen then you know if it returns a
single digit you just padded
you know padded a you know zero in front
because you need two extra decimals so
this function returns two hex digits
then you just return the string you know
code three times you know with a pound
sign in front so that you know signify
color so that's how you get a random
random RGB color string okay so now we
have that function now we can we can
assign the value to the random color we
just call this function right so random
color will get a random color string
so how do we then what then
so the random color actually should be
the value of shadow color because
remember how let's go back to the CSS
box shadow you see the color will be
used for the shadow so we have a issue
here so when people click on the random
the shadow color should be you know it
should be set to the shadow color value
but now the problem is how do we so we
so when we click you have to actually
find out when keyboard clicked on it
wait hold on a second
so anyway for now let let's do this it's
common this a weight so we have two
things here copy it comment them out and
let's actually just put this there you
know so every time the shadow color is
just random okay now we compile the
typescript okay it says cannot be
declare broad scope variable random
color stream okay we must have declared
it twice oh we have oh yeah oh oh I
already I already have the code there so
we don't you know we have the code twice
so yeah so we so that's what we do so we
remove that okay compile it again
correct no error so reload the page so
you see every time I reload it's gonna
give us who's reopened every time we
reload it's gonna give us a new color
but that's you know so but what we want
is when user click on that okay so
here's what we need to do so we need to
declare a global variable shadow color
okay let's declare a global variable
shadow color okay and it's not a
constant it's a
so we declare a global variable shadow
color then for the random color button
let's go back go down to the event so
when random button button random color
is clicked it should call a function
that update the color not render the
whole thing it just said color okay
it will call the function set color and
we are going to define the set color
here constant arrow function set color
okay it will not take no arguments and
it will return it will return a hex
color stream so we're gonna call random
RGB color stream here and AOB yeah so
that's it
so actually we need to do it like that
so the set color wait wait this is wrong
so actually we need a blog
so color equals to that so we got a
color we got a random color here's a
stream but you also need to change the
shadow color input box here you know
it's a nice touch because when you click
random color the you know the it shows
random color here but it would be nice
if the input also changes because
otherwise it's inconsistent right like
right now you have one pink and one
orange so we we need to update the
shadow color that's easy okay so the
shadow color item we can see on top it's
the color picker element so color picker
element value equals to CL
let's say you're on color okay there so
we get a random color and we assign it
to the input color picker and a weight
actually what we should do is we should
assign it a sign to shadow color let's
do it like that yeah so we get a random
color we assign it to shadow color you
know the global variable value then we
also assign it to the color picker input
then in the update part we don't need
the shadow color anymore because it's
already defined here but also when you
okay let's try to compile the code
okay so compile the code is say
successful no error and now let's see
what happens
refresh okay apparently there's an error
so let's open console log refresh okay
no arrow here those are you know those
errors are from Google you know ads so
anyway so we don't have a any error here
however it's not showing so there is
something wrong oh yeah when you'll be
fresh you see that's a problem when you
refresh the shadow color is not set
you know because nobody you know update
it's not setting update code it's only
set by this function f set color but
however nobody has called F set color so
we need to call it so we just call it
here you know we we call the set color
then we call the update so now we
compile the typescript code and back to
the browser refresh yay yes yeah default
default state to begin with so we it
looks like we got it working so we click
let's try no we click random color and
nothing happens
oh yeah because in a random color when
it's clicked remember we set it to call
the set color function but we did not
update the whole thing so we also need
to update the whole thing so let's say
so when random color is clicked we need
a function that will call set color then
call f update
yep so let's compile the code no error
that's good let's refresh the browser
now let's try it quick gah
what's wrong wait so button random color
set color and update so what is wrong
okay the manual setting color also is
not working
crickey event oh yeah you are right
thank you yeah quick great hey wait okay
that's the right direction but this
looks like there's still something we
did I did wrong here wait
quick what's going on click set color
and update did we Oh compile type script
update by the way Shawn are you are you
are you are you using any framework like
do you use any framework like or any
JavaScript libraries you you use often
so what's going on with the set color so
set color then update set color show
color
no just JavaScript okay just learning
yeah you know I never got into using the
frameworks but right now I'm kind of
trying to you know I'm kind of learning
the react Jes you know I actually
studied react.js for a few days for a
week you know a few months ago and I
think it's it's very good you know but
you know I'm mostly still prefer you
know raw JavaScript you know you know
like for several reasons for many two
reasons one is that you know I like I
really like the fundamental technology I
don't like the you know the wrappers
created by some cooperation because they
they can change anytime you know they
come and go actually react seems you
know to be the big one that you know one
of the top three major ones react UJS
angular you know these are the three
kind of the major ones but you know a
few years ago there are lots of other
others see you know they like they are
turn up turns of others they come and go
and you twine is like you know they they
are different they are they are fused to
Kate right yeah because in there this
you know especially in Java you know
JavaScript is very different from other
languages I mean the JavaScript industry
because in other languages you know you
see you know I don't know C or C++ but I
you know in Perl in Python Ruby :
you can use libraries the libraries
looks the same as you know you don't
have to learn you know like extra but in
JavaScript when you use a framework it's
like they introduced in it's like you
are learning a entire different syntax
and also entire different semantics the
model you know like the you know the MVC
you know whatever you know that crap M
easy you know you like every every
framework Jelani entire different thing
it's nice not good you know yeah so
anyway so let's get let's try to get
this to work then so what's going on so
let's print you know when something is
wrong and you don't know what you know
the easiest way to debug is oh it's just
print print the value let's say show
color show the shadow color now refresh
okay it's printed okay now but if I
click random oh it's working I guess I
didn't press refresh before maybe
alright but this part is not working
okay yeah so when user manually search
select a color it's not working we still
need to do that
so when user manually search select the
color okay I guess you what we have to
do is just like before
okay originally we need a value let's
see color picker color picker value okay
so here we initialize it to a value but
when use okay let's write another
function that's that's user update color
so let's change one of the function
random okay F set color random then we
have another function so f set color
random here okay so we so we use a click
random number we have you know code we
call this function but when user click
the color picker when user click the
color picker we need to call set color
let's say set color user okay well
actually we need a run we need the whole
line
then stood like that it goes let's do
like that so like that so when color
picker is clicked we have the event
click oh yeah oh yeah click we have the
event click then it will call said user
color then update okay that seems good
said said color user okay so let's go to
the function here we modify the function
here the function will be just get that
okay
then color picker value we don't need
that part right so shadow color equals
true yeah that let that looks right so
let's give our evaluate it compile
success okay let's see let's see if it's
success refresh looks good
random color looks good let's let's pick
make it big
let's make the default blur bigger
because these
let's make the default click and it's
it's you blow and spread so blur value
equals to let's say 20 okay
refresh random color random color and
color picker wait let's refresh refresh
color picker know what's going on
open the JavaScript compile it
so color picker
so when colour picker is called when
colour picker is clicked it sets a color
value to the shadow colour global
variable and the shadow color global
variable
the color picker III you know it's kind
of new it's not there you know in the
year 2000 I don't know I don't know
Wayne was it added but it's kind of new
so but I think the problem is our code
it's probably not the problem is our
code you know the color picker you just
say type equals new color
I discovered that but anyway the that
seems to be robust you know you know
because it's part of the browser
I cannot imagine they have a book the
problem seems to be wait
something happened here the problem I
think it's our code where he walked okay
there is something wrong here
only when you create oh yeah
so when you sew it here's what happens
and say red okay
wait and say refresh
it looks like you have to do it one time
first then it updates to the last color
value when you click off the picker it
updates yes I mean
it updates there is something wrong it's
not updating the thing here you see it's
only updating the user input box but
that's you know that's from browser that
behavior is from browser he should you
know also update here so let's print set
user color console.log shadow color
compare it and refresh refresh random
color random color random color is
working but when you click shadow picker
so let's trace its let's find out what's
going on quick shadow picker click
shadow picker
this is weird click shadow pika green
then close it
oh I think maybe here we need to say
instead of a click and we need to say
input oh yeah for color picker you need
input that's right I'm pretty sure
that's a problem
so compile the code back to browser
refresh random color random color works
now color picker yay so we can like
smoothly track and have color change
that seems you know so it's working so
yeah I think that's great so that's you
know great we got it okay I think that's
that's it for today let's say console
logs we moved the console log compile
the code so compare the code so you see
so here is the jar here is the the
typescript code and let me show you the
compiled code have you used typescript
if before so compare code you know
typescript you know so here is the
JavaScript code the typescript generated
basically it it tries to basically
maintain your you're formatting your
indentation everything well actually it
indents for you but but it maintains you
know even the line numbers typically you
often well not not actually no but it
tries to though it doesn't you know
reformat all your code so anyway so here
is the job the generated code 660 lines
of code
so I think that's it you know this I
think this code is actually you know the
final form there's not you know I don't
there's no I mean usually we can
refactor like you know touch up see if
there's anything we can clean up or
things like that but in this case I
think it's pretty good yeah yeah
typescript you know typescript is it's
very useful for you know for when you
have large amount of code like you know
over a thousand lines then then it
really helps by specifying the type yeah
let me show some of the complex
typescript code I have here for example
here you can see you see for example you
can see this line of code it's act it's
adding two vectors you know it takes two
arguments two vectors like like the
first argument is you know array of two
numbers the second argument is also
another array of two numbers then it
just add them together like this a 1 +
p1 + a2 + b2 array of two numbers you
know so in normal JavaScript you would
you would say like that let me show you
in normal JavaScript you would not have
that it would be much simpler you see
you just have these you just have these
but in typescript you know so you you
started to add types so this you know
this first vector array is you know a
way of number and number same thing with
the second argument and the return
result is also array of two numbers so
you started to add all these types it
can be you know it can be actually
tedious and also the color becomes
sometimes unreadable
for example when you have lots of the
let's see you know yeah it for example
here you know when you when you use the
let's see let me show you the
destructuring argument in JavaScript
ciao javascript functions functions this
argument destructuring
like for example like default argument
or when you have you know it gets
complex anyway that that's that's that's
the type script you have to add those
but it really helps it yeah I wanted to
say there's another great advantage is
that when you like JavaScript these days
is there's no there's new version every
year but the browsers typically do not
support it you know until one or two
years later so if you want to use the
latest word feature of JavaScript you
can use typescript it will just compile
you know you can use the new features
it will compared to you know the
previous version of JavaScript you can
specify you know which target version of
JavaScript to output anyway okay so yes
so thank you for watching thank you guys
for watching so that's it so have a good
evenin show bye