hello good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of sound talk show today
we are going to do emac disp coding a
very dense session of emac disp coding
uh if you are here say hi hello crystals
if you are watching offline feel free to
skip around because I talk randomish
ramble a lot so very dense emac list
coding okay so we are going to write
command to do find and replace for all
files single
directory you know all fire single
directory and then the extra feature
that you will not find anywhere is that
you can undo it so if I did find replace
to all these files and uh then I
realized it's a mistake I can call a
command undo then it will like undo all
the find and replace so that's what
we're going to write we going to write
it from scratch now this is actually for
my uh package but I'm going to do it
from scratch so this is kind of a emac
disp tutorial you'll learn how to uh
walk a directory uh you know do find
replace on all
files and how we going to do the undo
feature so by the way so if you are
looking at the if you C here for the
girl this is generated by AI gr on x.com
gr uh and uh about two weeks ago we
talked about AI generating images very
interesting how girls uh I'm not that
girl so this is just going to be uh dry
emac dis coding okay programming so
let's let's begin okay so so we want to
yeah so so so here's a problem write the
command to do fin replace for all files
in a directory so let's begin writing it
so uh by the way I'm using soft like
keys and the pink window shows all my
command CES and uh uh and the key stroke
on the left as side type I'm using a ver
keyboard okay so and I'm using flly keys
emac this Moda HTML mod so you search it
you'll find it you pay me you get those
you can buy it uh for as a donation
thank you so um s find replace okay
let's just say uh let's just say uh
that's a file name okay I mean that's a
function name okay
uh s find replace
uh okay I'm using fantastic glove 0 the
new glove 0 keyboard uh my last video
talks about
that okay so so so we're going to write
this command so this is a function name
okay so find and replace and uh find and
replace okay so you need a find
string uh okay so let's say say that
find string and replace string okay so
let's Capal you know my convention to
Capal the Capal case the parameter names
okay so find Space replace string and uh
string and you need the directory uh
root okay so let's just say that rout
and you need a file name extension
okay file name extension Okay so kind so
that's the parameters uh so find string
replace string okay let's let's let's
find string replace string root
directory and file name extension okay
that's what you need uh and yeah okay so
documentation find replace all files in
order okay and so that's one command
we're going to write okay so this one
command then we're going to write a undo
find replace undo okay okay undo
last um and this will
be this will
be undo last core
of this function okay
so okay created today's State uh version
today's date uh that's my convention
always give a date
you know like 20 years ago 30 years ago
you don't have this luxury because that
just you know documentation stram just
takes more memory and stuff but today
you do so you can
like uh okay so let's that's right so so
the algorithm is open a file questions
and comments uh hello hello mister okay
open
um uh okay so the a
ithm for each file uh let first of all
get a list of files in root then for
each open it open it and do find replace
do find and
replace okay and make a backup okay so
this is essential you want to make a
backup of the original
the therefore so you can undo it because
otherwise I mean there are other ways
but it's more compers otherwise you have
to record what is your find string
replace string and reverse find find
replace you know that's more tedious so
make a backup is the uh more simpler
much more simpler so okay so that's
algorithm so am I going am I doing okay
uh video check audio check you guys like
it
11 viewers okay fantastic so so open a
file now
usually in emac when you open a file you
you call find file for example uh let's
say talk show okay copy the file path
close it and put the file path here you
see and then evaluate this line do it
you see it opens the file but this this
is how you uh meta X find file this is
how you normally open a file but you
don't want to do that in a uh in in in
emac dis code because when you do that
it opens the file it turns on the major
mod it does a syntax coloring and it
costs like tens of hundred other uh tens
of other things like basically hooks or
events because every time you open a
file you have to syntax color that takes
a lot of time so when you want to
process thousands of files you don't
want to call the f file Okay so emac
disp so you know you can check uh go to
uh search for Casa emac disp tutorial
you'll find all my tutorials and uh the
EDM to to open lots of files uh for each
file in a directory is I can uh it's
it's here I list it here so uh file and
directory so buffer read file that's
what you want so this is this is kind of
the EDM how you open open a file in
thisp quickly okay I mean sometimes you
want to do that because you want
sometimes you want to call the find file
so you can let the user see you know
which file is opened like emac is great
in this way when you do text processing
you can actually see the process in real
time it opens a file it changes close it
open another uh you know things like
that but for Speed reasons you don't
want that okay so in in our example in
our case we don't want on that okay so
this is how you uh this is this is the
EDM for opening a file fast okay so file
path so well uh so this is opening a
file open a file okay but before we open
file we need to get the list of uh
directories so how you do that so you go
here emac list uh tutorial uh worker
directory so file and directory file
path functions work directory so there
okay so you want do you want it
recursively yes I do now all these
options you know you can you should you
know eventually when you write a program
you should have options do you want it
to be recursive and and prompt for file
name extension and so on but but we're
going to just uh quickly hard code
it so file directory files that's not
recursive so that's not what you want
okay so what you want is go go down you
want directory files recursively okay so
that's a function you want to call
directory file recursively okay so
that's a function and directory is going
to be root
okay um and regular
expression uh regular expression for is
for filtering files
yeah and okay so final name extension
let's say re reject normally you don't
want
to I mean let's just say that okay so
root directory then file name extension
uh rejects so that filters for example
only HTML files uh usually you want that
because otherwise you have image files
you have you know uh image files PDF
files all sort of video files so you go
through the through directory and filter
by that regular expression and then uh
include directories no okay so include
directories Neil these are optional you
don't need it optional parameters
predicate predicate is a filter uh
function ped cut is a filter on which
subdirectory to dive into okay um yeah
you you you know you basically P you
want to you want to skip G directories
and yeah you want to skip uh G.G so the
predicate is a fi on which subdirectory
to dive into re rejects is a is applied
first before the prut sees
it okay
so so it needs a function um yeah
TS okay the the function
is okay so it's Pass the full path of a
directory so you need to give a function
so we can actually write it here so
predicate is a Lambda
okay
uh so that's the full path
then you basically if okay so string
match if string
match literal dot then so it start with
a DOT ignore directory okay so if begin
with a dot yeah that should do it so
string match begin with a DOT match with
that path then
then that means
um ignore it okay the pred is a fon
which sub to D to okay
uh okay we'll test it out okay so so
basically it looks like that so far and
this emx um so
comments uh okay
so so we got we need the list list of
files okay so you get a variable uh file
list okay so set the variable file list
to be this directory thing we are trying
to get
okay so this directory files recursively
will return a Leist of files of file
path full path okay root the file name
regular expression then uh let's check
again root the file name expression then
include root the uh regular
expression then okay then what is this
include
directories okay no we don't we don't
want directory in the result okay so
Neil then the next one is the predicate
so if it's true filter it
out I believe so the predicate filter
which subject to dive into okay no if
it's
true you know you want you want it if
it's NE ignore
it wait uh I you know it's a bit
ambiguous so t
if it's t ignore sub directories that
can be read function if returns true
dive into that directory okay so if it's
true then you want it so so this will be
not okay so if it if the string matches
beginning with a
DOT then return
Neo return
Force okay yeah so I suppose that's that
then follow s link links we we don't
care uh no okay so Neo we can ignore
okay so we got a file list here and
before we do
anything we can so far just test it okay
test our code so you know that's our
code already uh so this this when the
font size is large you got this window
width problem and
let's see if we can yeah we I want to
make it so that it's easier to see okay
so okay so that's it that's our function
so far you know when if you call it it's
just going to print the list of
directories so let's try to call
it and uh okay so let's call it and what
is the um what what what is the argument
okay so argument
that so find string okay so let's say
find string uh find string is a string
replace string so find string let's say
uh find Su okay replace sum just for now
rout okay we want a rout so we going to
test this so we need a we need a
directory to test okay so that's easy we
going to uh what happened
and did I just delete it yeah okay I
kind of deleted the file okay so let's
make a
backup uh I deleted by
mistake yeah okay so let's just make a
let's just go where is
it okay so
make a backup okay so put it back
showing browser so here's our code so
far now let's create a directory of full
of files uh for testing purposes so we
can go to emac block let's use emac
manual because emac list manual there
are 1,000 pages so let's just make a
copy of this uh in fact let's
uh
T can can you uh tie
it yeah what what is the key for
tar
uh okay describe describe mod to see the
documentation search for tar uh search
for T not there search for wait I don't
have a
tar okay uh Powershell okay so we need
to go
faster Powershell so GCM tar I I have
tar installed uh so wa uh so this
matching lines T not found least
matching lines gz not found what
wait what uh
uh um okay forget about that so let's
just uh do this this is my command to
zip the directory okay so now it's
zipping the directory we want to zip it
so that every time we can unzip it and
make a new Fresh copy why do we want to
do that because um because every time we
do a fine replace we might to do it
again
so now go to talk show go to the
directory this file we want
uh uh okay so make a new directory x x
zip okay X
test uh file exist what make a new
directory X test okay let's XX text test
okay put it there so
now okay that's uh emac
this uh manual okay now unzip
it yeah unzip not installed what
uh yeah okay so Powers Shell expand
archive okay poell has uh building uh
unzip expand archive and Elis
there do
it okay so back to emac refresh there it
is so you got you know this is a bunch
of emac this manual open it showing
browser so you can see so uh delete it
close close okay so now we want to uh
copy the file path copy close close
close close close close close close Okay
we back here and and uh what is this uh
emac block close close close yeah so
backup open the file again so we want to
call the function here and the the root
is going to be this
um this directory that's right we're
going to do find replace there and let's
open it let's uh let's see what we want
to find replace let's say the the word
Abri
okay copy it close so we want to find
the word abbr replace it by uh XX y okay
for the testing purposes okay so we got
the
root
uh what's going
on uh the key the keyboard has a
slightly different layout than I was
using so anyway so find string replace
string root okay find string replace
string root then file name regular
expression okay so that will be okay you
need to be a reject so that's going to
be uh what is
the you know this Keys
uh okay so you want
back slashback
slash.
HTML and dollar sign okay so that means
the all HTML files so are we ready to
test it now I think I'm ready so now
evaluate this this code okay now let's
call
it oh we uh so right now it will just
list the files okay so let's do it run
it okay okay seems good show show the
message buffer so this is we got a bunch
of files copy it new buffer make it one
line per line that looks good so we got
the Lista file so so so far this code
Works a list files
next next
step open each file okay uh we don't
want to use that uh we want to um Okay
so we got a list of files now open uh
each file so you're going to do a loop
so in for each so that is map C map C is
a loop without side effects I mean with
you know without returning it Returns
the sequence itself it takes a function
and the list Returns the list unchanged
the function usually do something you
know opening a file and do something so
map C is like JavaScript for each okay
so the sequence is going to be uh file
list okay then the function is uh X is a
uh path file path okay so what you want
to do you want to open it
okay so you create a temper and insert
the file content to it so uh so then the
file path so let's just
say uh x file path okay
then you got the file content in here
okay then you want to do find replace
find
replace okay so uh then how you do that
while okay while loop
uh so while search for word uh you want
to search for the find string okay so
what is the find string
am I doing good good hello sir okay so
we are busy coding so find string uh
what is the find you know the keys got
the
keys okay so go to the top yeah find
string
there so search for the F string bound
we don't care uh bound we don't care Neo
no error true okay count we don't care
so when it's found you do the you call
the replace match okay so the replace
match is going to be the new text isace
string uh fix case literal okay so you
know those should be user options so you
know you need to more code for the user
interface but for now let's hard code
it and
so uh let's say fixed case
true literal
true
uh then we don't care about that okay so
right now it's using plan find and
replace not regular expression but if
you want regular expression just replace
the search forward by reearch forward
okay okay so we so let's you know so we
let's clean up the code so this for each
for each file in file list which is a
full file path you create a temp buffer
you insert file contents then you go to
the top so go to
CH uh point mean go to the top of the
buffer then you do a while loop search
for word search for that string if it's
found it will return true so while is
true so when it's found you replace
match okay then then
um yeah so that does the you know we
find we find and replace all uh
occurrences so that's
done then you need to okay
so so right now this is SE temp first so
you actually need to save this into the
file so before we do that we need to
make a backup
uh
okay so before we do that we need to
make a backup
so okay once you okay so once you
um okay with 10 buffers so now let's do
a
backup and the you know backup the
orinal file so how do you do backup copy
file
CF yeah CF file will
be x file path okay new name will
be uh this is going to be tedious so new
name we need the some uh temporary name
uh usually date stamp will work well so
you got the full dat stamp date and the
time date and time and with microseconds
so that kind of guarantees you have a
unique file name so you know this you
know this these are the operations by
this
command uh okay so we need to create a
backup name okay so let's Okay so let's
do let's do a a light a little let
block
uh okay so let's say backup name okay so
what is the backup name set backup name
so you want the date you know date time
stamp uh
date uh you now I forgot what's a
function for date let's go back to
um let's go back to uh emac list
tutorial so what is the function for
date so that you search for date not
here so go back to emac this Basics
search for date there it is Sprint date
time so you want oh yeah format time
string that's what you want so you want
the format that's
um oral daytime uh no so you want uh you
want a format such that it's human
readable yet easy to pass okay
so so ISO
a601 uh but you don't want the colon
colon is not a allowed character in file
names
okay uh I thought I just updated this
page
for where is it pass
daytime so daytime
string format okay this is taking longer
than I
expected uh because we haven't get to
the undo backup
yet so for Unix time we don't want that
because that's unreadable
insert daytime I thought I had a I had I
just recently updated the page what's
going
on um okay let's go to emac
blog maybe I have duplicate articles so
video tutorial
packages fun things blog
I recently I am pretty sure I recently
updated the page so
that so that it actually has a example
of the Unix I mean of
a and maybe that's wfam language that's
did I get confused godamn
no oh that's that was power shell power
shell too many languages okay okay go
back to you see I want the daytime
that's all uh that's like um like that
okay like this one basically all digits
with underscore and Dash Okay anyway so
e let's go back to emac print daytime
that's easy enough so let's just copy
that so close that so
datetime so you want to that okay say
dat time so you want the format um this
is getting complex because we are trying
to add
the at the local I mean the the date
Zone
that's why you got all these so uh
format date
time year month date then I don't want
that t just
underscore then time okay time I don't
want that so let me just show you okay
so if you run
that you got that okay so that's not
what you want you don't want the
semicolon okay so look up describe
function for daytime let's
see uh
seconds oh God this is taking longer
then minute second so what what we got
here so we got uh so that
then year month date then we want hours
minute second and microc okay hour
minute second microc second okay so
let's describe typ
function okay HMS basically
okay so
mini hour mini second and we want micr
second what
micro Okay so
and is nanc n that's too complex forget
about that okay let's just stick up to
seconds okay so this eval so that's a
that's a format okay we're going to
stick with
that and in fact let's remove the dash
okay let's
just you know so try it that's good so
we got that daytime
format Okay so
sample up don't don't care so clean up
the code this is the backup file
name okay so we got the backup file
name then uh what then we do backup okay
then copy file so here's a backup so the
new file name will be
file path
concact uh uh actually back file uh we
can do the concact here
so okay so file
path then you concact with that then you
need uh then you need
a t to day so to signify it's a backup
file that's emac convention okay so
let's try it again so you got that
that's correct so file name plus
that okay this is getting tedious we
don't want B backup back back up n back
up time stream okay let's just
say okay that's backup time stream then
the file name is going to be
concact back string uh backup time stamp
okay so that's the file name clean
it clean it okay then okay if it already
exist
yes we don't care we can just override
because this kind of guarantee is unique
so but actually we want to do
add
aine replace make sure it's unique
unique
xfp so file path uh copy
file from path two path then then
something overr right yes keep time uh
ignore okay so ignore the
rest okay so that's the backup part
let's
see so actually we need uh we need kind
of V variable that tells that whether if
a string is found because if it's not
found you you don't want to over write
it when it's not found just ignore the
whole thing you don't have to do backup
and so on so actually so we need to do
that yeah okay
so and where we going to add that so you
need a temp temporary
um yeah so actually you need you need
some kind of temporary so let's say
let's just say
that okay so X is a temp uh
found P so that means if it's found so
while
okay well that is true set that to um
true
okay okay so now back
up if x
found true let's just say when okay okay
when that is true then you do the
backup okay beautiful it's getting
good so when something is found you do
the
backup and then you do the and then you
also have to do save the file okay so
now save file
okay so you first of all you back up
then
backup and save let's put them together
there okay so first of all you
backup then you
save so how do you save save is Right
region okay
um you can look up it's I mean uh double
check emac this tutorial
daytime uh this belongs to EAC this so
go to emac this
and uh emac this then you want to write
file so read file and write
file yeah right region is the one you
want to that's how you save file
basically you never you don't want to
use Save buffer okay that because that's
mostly for interactive use because
otherwise because if you call that it
does a lot of hooks
like you know like like you know you
don't want that so right region is how
you save file so right region then right
file uh right both accountant do not
okay so right region yeah so in it is
you you call right region point mean
Point Max and file
name so file name will be X
path then append no visit no lock name
no okay no we don't care okay this is
how you say
okay so let's
see okay let's look at uh overall so get
this files so find replace get these
files get this files
then okay then open each file we don't
want that okay open each file map C so
function Lambda and map to the file list
okay and uh okay the
function will create a temp buer insert
the file contents to find replace go to
the beginning of
buffer while search found the string to
replace and set the F to be true okay
then so this this is for each uh each
file right so this is map C for each
file
then
then okay then
um let's see this is a while loop okay
then when when it's
found then you do
backup okay so first of all create the
backup time stamp uh backup time
stamp okay so this is a backup time
stamp
then then you uh then you copy the file
right that's how you
uh yeah do backup then you then you okay
so once the backup is
done then you save the file okay right
region
righted region point mean Point Max F
path okay I think that's it so this
actually this is done this is this will
actually do the find and replace and do
a backup so we can try to test it so so
eval last six and now if we call this
it's going to work let's try it okay so
open this file the testing directory
open it so you can see you got the word
a bre there okay close it this directory
got 1,000 files okay close it so if we
now call this function it will do the F
replace let's do it okay please let it
work Evol you see fantastic it says Road
Road Road ro road you know so now it's
going fantastic it's going through 1,000
files done okay so you see Road Road
Road that means so changes happen there
so not many files changed you know so
close that revisit directory so 1,00
files now go to the top you see those
are backup so you you see we got
fantastic okay now let's open the file
and
check open it yeah fantastic the Bri
world is gun so it's working one shot
coding why because I've been coding this
like for over 20 years fine replace you
know I coded this a thousand times in in
Python in go land in Pearl Pearl is the
first in year 2000 uh if you search for
S find replace you'll find all that
Pearl python goand Powershell the code
is on the
web and also emac this okay so this is
like the thing I do first when I learn a
new new language fine replace okay so
there is a that's a package and this is
how you um so there's a go
land this is a go land version and go
down you'll see you'll see python
version PE version emac version you know
and wolam language version okay so
anyway this is working
so yeah we we we know for sure it's
working correctly
so now it made a backup so now we what
we have to do we have is we have to
write this
undo the last fine replace this is what
I need to do because all the above I
already have a s package you
know uh you know for example yeah let me
pedal my stuff if you like my stuff pay
me okay so for example let me show you
so open this file let's say I want to
replace all the word expansion okay so
just call you know cine replace you can
see that command name on the Ping window
cine replace text it's for my package so
find the word expansion replace by tdt
okay do it which directory this
directory and file name extension yes uh
WR changes to file yes you see now it's
done now it generates a report so you
can actually navigate all the
occurrences or and all the files for
example list all the files that changed
so you
got uh you got you know how many
files 40 files changed you know close
that so you can jump to any of the
occurrence so you see I already have the
command and this command is
called
uh okay this command is called Place
replace
find. so here's a source
code 800 lines of code and you can go
here open in browser that's the homepage
so if you like this you can pay me and
get it it's open
source so you got regular expression
versions you got PL text
versions then you got the find count if
you just want to count you can also
specif ify how long you know the context
do you want to show the context before
the occurrence or after the
occurrence how you know the length you
want to show and things like that so uh
very powerful because you know after 10
years of using emac way I find this uh
more
convenient why do I do you know I do
find replace all the times like on few
hundred or few thousand files
every other day for the past 20 years
why because my my website is static
website so everything is static PL text
files so when you want to change your
header for example s go mod you know if
you want to change a head header or
footer for example
2025 you need to do find replace you
know there's no like template you know
the header files you know I don't do
that so anyway that that's uh that's
what you do when you use static websites
I mean static you know and all anyway
that's digression um so anyway that's
why I do fine replace all the time you
know hundreds of files or thousands
every almost every day in the past 20
years and the most convenient is you
know so I created this package okay if
you like it go to the website homepage
and you know buy it okay
uh not that but uh where is it this
one so I already have this written but
the feature I don't have is I want to
like call and do and and revert all the
files of the last find replace so that
is that is why what we are I'm trying to
uh show today but it's it's already on
hour is it
yeah uh but we can do this quickly and
takes uh takes 20 minutes
okay so let me take a break answer the
questions
fantastic do you use emac l to generate
your RS feed yeah of course uh okay let
me quickly digress for five minutes for
example uh this is my emac blog this ISS
feed you click it I I'm using atom feed
atom protocol which is ISS feed uh and
which is a XML file so the protocol is a
basically XML file so how do you
generate that um so show in browser
again emac block so you can go to uh RS
you see that this is a file block. XML
so open it this is XML it's showing in
HTML mod because then I can validate it
you know it's all powerful so for
example the author I can delete the
whole Au the
block go to the end of a tag go to the
beginning of tag or uh for example the
last entry is this one you know byx
tutorial so I can delete the whole you
know so that this is HTML mod you can
also buy it just search it you'll find
it so yeah so your question how do I
create this uh yeah so for example let's
say uh new
section something new okay you see
showing browser there it is September
12th something new now I need to RSS it
okay so press a few buttons there it is
it opens the file and add the whole
entry there then save it close it go to
Powershell then just R sync then you'll
upload to my website so you can see all
the command names on the pink
window uh
uhaa HTML atom new entry so you know
that's um that's how I do it okay so now
I don't need it so I just delete the
block showing browser that's it that
okay so that's about our ISS the other
question um
I can get along with the Leist syntax
well it gets some you know it takes some
getting used to okay uh you know this's
pros and
cons you know the the cons is that then
you got this all these nested you know
brackets some people don't like it I
actually like it very much you know so
it's a matter of uh acquired
taste okay so the disadvantage is that
you just have to keep you know t type in
uh wait undo undo you have to you
know type in this parents okay the
advantage is that you have the
syntax captures syntactical unit unit of
the programming language so the the
syntax captures the semantic unit of the
programming language for example this
entire map C okay so I can select it you
know if if I want to delete it all I
have to do just press a key so that's
one semantic
unit of the code okay important because
you you work you know you don't work
with words or each character right you
in programming you have semantic unit so
if you want to remove a feature or
remove a function or remove a module you
know so you can do that with one one
single key press for example this Lambda
okay you can highlight add
it press a key the whole Lambda is good
now in C Java go land you don't have
that well at at best you have this this
curly uh braces block but if you delete
you know this doesn't work in emac
because for example let's go here okay
let's go to uh JavaScript mod okay s
JavaScript so for example uh you can can
have that and you can have console log
let's say console log 33 Okay save the
file XX something. JS okay run it you
got 3 three and this this C braces in
see JavaScript they function as a
semantic block okay so once you have
that you can just like remove the whole
okay but not but not always for example
the problem with C for example if you
have if statements if three console log
true okay you print
true then you say else uh else okay
console log Force okay let's say so you
can run that you can run the whole thing
you know so there's a result but you see
you don't have the semantic unit this
this this whole if statements is a
semantic unit but there's no syntactical
correspondence to it so but you know you
can you can easily remove
the the the you know the curly Braes
block but not the whole so gets more
complex when you have a function names
for example you want to remove this
whole function call okay you can do it
in one shot because it's not captured by
syntax you can remove the parameters
that's it you know then you have to okay
so that's a that's kind of the uh PR and
cons of the this syntax you know it
takes uh uh get some used to I like it
actually okay so we need to do this undo
so actually there's uh I think more
question yes you can it's just not an
edit feature no you are wrong Mo okay
I'm not going to argue today
because because then we're going to you
know get in this you know but moo you
are incorrect
uh Tre yeah get out of here moo you
don't know okay so hey hey Don Hopkin
now Don Hopkin Guys Don Hopkin oh
Jesus now Don Hopkin is a great coder
he's a classic old school coder from
1980s so Don Hopkins he wrote X11 uh he
implemented you know lots of things in
you know X11 back in 1980s
and he's most famous for you know he he
Implement implemented the game Sim City
in X11 right I think and he also um uh
he's he Don Hopkins is also a
Mathematica user okay uh and uh so and
one of the most famous thing he has
done is uh you know he you know he's
also well known for having written the X
11 the x windows disaster you
know Don Hopkins 1994 how to make a 50
Ms workstation run like a 4.7 mahz IBM
PC now if you guys are Zoomers you have
no idea what this this is is you know 50
MPS that's a powerful workstation uh
from some Microsystems I think back in
you know 80s so anyway this is you know
one chapter of the Unix ha hater Unix
haters uh handbook you know written by
scientist you know by by se you know all
the author three authors they are great
uh operating system
experts but Don hop Hopkin
is you know he's he doesn't like Trump
so politics you know I'm not going to
talk about politics today um okay
so so so let's let's go back okay let's
go back to the um I want to uh code this
okay so yeah so let's code this okay let
me take two minutes and then let's code
this undo the F
replace uh moo says TRC is great yeah
it's great okay yeah yeah I mean I I was
you know I'm going to learn it I was
going to do a deep dive deep dive
because I think I also agree Trea is is
very uh fantastic but I just haven't got
to it yet because I got other things to
do I got do you know I gotta
do uh proof theories you know
mathematics differential geometry so a
lot to
learn uh Joshi says hi I've been
watching few of your past live streams
and I'm observer in the Discord chats
may I ask you a weird question what is
your take on AI girlfriends that's not
good AI girlfriend you know girlfriend
you get the real life
girl you know I mean what what you going
to do with your AI girlfriend you know
your girlfriend the the the fundamental
goal is to have children that's how men
and women get together you have children
that's that's that's why you desire
girlfriend because it's build in because
if you don't like girlfriends you die
out and AI girlfriend they don't get
your children unless one day we have a a
you know a warm Farm you know you you
can grow a
warm then you
know so you know if you are a loner you
know you can get a girlfriend okay you
know meet the girl and meanwhile all the
girls they they also want want to uh
meet
you because they too want to have
children generally speaking okay let's
let's write this until last okay so for
this to work the first thing we need to
do is to get the time
stamp
unique file name
okay so that's we have this that's why
we made this file name kind of unique
okay so we need to get this this time
stamps so we that so that's how we know
what file we can revert okay so you know
once you get
that okay
so then get get a list of search File
names
okay and the root okay so you got the
rotter then you got the time stamp then
you get a list of search File names for
each
just
replace you know replace the original
with it okay or actually rename okay
that's what that's that's what you have
to do so in order to know but first of
all you need to know the time stamp okay
so so when we call this function find
replace we need to record the time stamp
somewhere now there's many ways to do it
but for now let's just say uh let's just
create a variable okay Define VAR uh
let's say Define a new variable and the
variable replace
last time stamp okay so every time you
call this function you will record the
this uh kinds
um
uh
last uh let's say last record because
you need several information you need
the time stamp and you need the root
directory and you know Tech you also
need the file name extension but it's uh
hardcoded for now okay
so uh okay so what do you want to do so
um let's just say a vector okay uh let's
just say a
list is first element is string
of
full path of root
okay then the second
element is a string of time stamp
okay so we record this information okay
so in the beginning it's just NE okay
but every time you do it you need to set
it okay so so let's copy that so now go
here the time stamp so once we set the
time stamp
we set that
uh yeah okay so we uh you know we we
should place this code like above but
for now let's push
on
uh so so list and the
root okay I think that's it so you set
that root
and backup time stamp that's
right uh
yeah it would be nice to chat but I I
mean that's I mean for today you know
why am I coding the emac this dance emac
this today because today I
thought because today I was using this
beautiful attractive emac girl so when
people you know people will just click
it and you know so I want to do a better
like better um s talk show
so so anyway
so
um yeah we can you know for politics I'm
thinking I've been wanting to do this
for a while we can you know create a
Twitter live stream but I haven't got to
that
yet so anyway so so we we record this
fine replace last record okay so okay so
this
rout yeah set it and the backup time
stamp
yes okay then then when we do the backup
okay so this this is important okay so
now when we do this
undo so all we all we have to do is the
root okay X root so you need a root and
you need time
stamp okay so that's the thing you need
so let's set them
so uh
n okay so the nth is zero so because
this list is zero Bas based okay which
is not good
but okay I think that's
it so you got time stamp by by the way
another better way to do this this this
days since about five years ago or 10 is
set Q um sequence you know sequence set
Q so you can do it this way okay so let
me show
you
there okay but let's not let's not do
that today okay so you you you got the
root directory you then then then you
just for
each okay so then you just map see
okay that's algorithm then map C that's
for each then the sequence is
um so that's a root directory you want
to map this function too and for each
file path you
um rename okay rename file
okay
so rename it back yeah so file
X rename it by removing the temp stamp
okay so oh God how do you remove the
temp
stamp so more code but that's so that's
good because it's not too hot okay so
let's go to
the um let's move
this code to the bottom this is our test
code okay open this so for
example copy file path so we got the
example of
um you know example of
uh of a file with the time stamp so you
want
to oh
God okay let's use a regular expression
okay uh Lambda
X let a local
variable
then new name okay so you need to create
a new name the new name will
[Music]
be so this is a new name but what is a
new name the new name is
[Music]
um okay we got another thing wrong
um okay when we when we created this
time stamp this you know we need to
something we need to fix when we created
this time stamp you see this is space on
current time you don't want it to be
inside the loop you want it to be
outside because you want all files to
have the same time stamp basically the
time you call this function not when the
function visit the file so so you want
to move this up okay so let's move this
variable up to the top okay there okay
so search it so you want to move it up
um
let's see is it is that there there yeah
okay
so uh let's let's make it kind of
shorter
okay so that's your you know you make it
one shot there then let's see
then open each file when found do
backup yeah so you can paste that there
you don't need to
let you see this is advantage of this
syntax you can just
manipulate so backup
set the record okay set the record here
now now this again make it one
line copy file then back up yeah so we
got that that's correct okay so now we
undo we got the time stamp then we
um get the record then um so
then then
then new name so we need to know the new
name okay so the new name will
be uh you kind of want to do a regular
expression so how do you do
uh so okay so this is taking longer than
expected let's go to emac
let's go to emac l emac l Basics you
want string functions you want to the
string functions that remove you know
the beginning to the end of that TI uh
character so variables conditions Loop
functions so where is string string
functions there so you want to find the
index um join string split string
convert string to number buffer text uh
stream to buffer match stream by uh
rejects okay so you can use stream match
so you want to have sub
string okay then string match
H there okay so string
match you want to
match a t uh
what a a TIA character okay and the
string is
from X okay start we don't care so you
want to get the substring of x
from zero to
that
okay so let's do let's show here let's
um there okay new name is equals to
Let's test that
okay
uh so if we test
this you know let's try it run
it V variable X God okay so let's put is
here fantastic you see beautiful one
shot coding it
works okay so
um yeah so this works so this is a new
name let's say original name
uh okay so now you just rename so rename
x to the original name okay if already
exist
yes yes T okay so I think that's it
fantastic beautiful we have fin I think
we have finished this
um this s find repl P undo last let's
double check so when we call this
function you know first get the root
directory name root directory is
recorded in this variable and the time
stamp name now let's double check if
they are recorded
correctly uh so this
documentation uh let's make it better
full path of the okay so the second El
and
uh the second element is something like
that
okay so this is documentation
so so check so here is how you set it
rud and backup time time uh Time map
time stream
okay then you yeah okay so now so you
got that then you map the function to
the
rout
uh oh you need to well rout is um you
got you first of all you need to get a
list of files you know rout is a single
file path so that won't work so you need
to get the list of files so
so copy that code
uh so you got to get the list of files
so let's copy that so make a local
variable file list
then then from the rout the file name
regular
expression uh so this this is going to
be the time
stamp okay so it's going to get tedious
yeah so you so this
this so you want to turn this into a
regular expression
so reject quote okay I believe there's a
function reject quote okay
so so if that contains that then that's
how you want to that's a regular
expression
okay
then don't go into subdirectories and
Skip you know let's skip skip the file
name beginning with a
DOT uh and actually Let's ignore
that okay let's keep
it okay so so you get the file list then
then uh then the root should be
um
here wait so file
list yeah so file where is the root
here okay so root the then uh that then
Lambda okay so I think that's
it you get the list files of all the
backup files okay then for
each file in file list you call a
function Lambda
then you create you recreate the
original name then you just rename
it okay so rename file
yeah so now let's evolve the whole
buffer okay so now we have written two
functions okay so one function
is uh this one function is the F replace
and do last the other function
is is that okay so go to the bottom
evolve the buffer make a backup uncommon
it okay now let's check what's the value
of this variable so describe variable is
NE that's correct
now now if we run this it's going to be
something you know you know so let's see
what else you want to replace let's say
uh emac this let's say replace the word
manual okay close so replace the word
manual by
xmm okay now let's run it run please
make it work
fantastic fantastic now open the file
open the directory open the file there
it is we made it and go to the directory
so we can
see this is the last you know the 10
step okay
now you see there's some mistake there
you know I don't know what you know we
did a mistake there here I
think oh yeah that's from SAR find okay
so never mind so anyway this is the time
stem close
set close set now describe variable on
this do it there it is the value is that
and that fantastic okay
now now let's call this undo function
okay if we do it it should work let's
hope so it'll revert
everything EV our last
expression looks like it worked let's
open the directory again open
it refresh open the file there it is we
got the manual back fantastic that's it
for today success
chick Ching thank you Crystal thank
you so fantastic that's it for today
thank you guys for watching let me wrap
up okay so you guys need to donate okay
uh you know you can buy my emac
tutorial it's you know you got instant
access of about like
800 uh you know 900 1,000 pages of emac
and emac list tutorial okay if you guys
like my stuff just search for S emac
list so let's see what the other
questions we close down in 3 minutes
have you tried don't emx about two years
ago I I like tried to install it live uh
but that was not a good video because
you know one hour I spent one hour
without preparation but do Max I mean I
suppose it's good but I mean so D the
most the thing about Doom emx is that
it's a emac drro and uh the main feature
is that you use Vim V key binding so
everything is set up you like you don't
have to config you know how emac works
and all that you just download it it
works out of the box but the main
feature is that it uses Vim key binding
so if you are already familiar with Vim
you can use it but still you have to
learn a little bit about emac because
it's not exactly Vim so anyway so Vim is
the main feature
a model you know keybinding and the
other thing is that it's um typically
it's for Linux people okay for you nerds
out there because if you are a Windows
user you you know then you you don't
know what is vim so that will take you a
month to actually or two month to
actually learn and even if you know a
little bit
Vim the do emac is like very technical
like you expect people people to be like
Linux users
usually uh otherwise you want you know
otherwise you you know you you you might
spend a lot of time to look into
so yeah so Crystal has seen it what do
you URL keep. HTML what do you
mean what do you mean you are okay
uh CH BR I know you for more than four
years and still don't know what you are
doing I talk about technical stuff ner
stuff programming programming language
design Ai and stuff okay thanks to um
you know thanks to
uh you know thanks to
uh uh what where did he go
uh Don Hopkins thanks to Don Hopkins uh
um for
visiting um politics you know politics
is very sensitive you know you can if we
talk about politics you can't be friends
anymore that's very risky thing bye guys