Hello guys, welcome to another episode
of S Talk Show.
I haven't done a live stream for a long
time, for like a month and a half.
Uh been depressed early this year
because of AI um and other going on and
the war. Yeah. So AI and the war so got
me depressed in the first three month of
this year but now I'm better also
uh my website is back so I fixed my
website so if you can just go to
kasali.info
you can search it um you know search
search.info
okay so let's see.info
info,
you'll see my website and uh so now it's
updating again. So you can see my 10
like 10 blog blogs, keyboard blog, Emacs
blog, Google main blog, it's now
updating. So thanks to uh Reaper, Steve,
and uh another guy who helped helped me
out uh figure out the ring because I had
a problem with a sync.
uh you know if you guys don't know what
uh sync is like uh sync is
uh syntating
again so let's talk about cascading
stylesheet okay fascinating cascading
stylesheet today it it's becoming like
you need a PhD to know about the
cascading stylesheet okay Like most
programmers they would think it as
boring like you know because it's for
you know designers like usually women in
the past uh 20 you know in the past 15
years
but cascading stylesheet is actually
quite interesting technically because uh
the heart of cascading styles sheet okay
I'm rambling all over but I got some
topics um so here is my talk Kan talk
show you are watching talk show if you
are here say hi. Okay. Oh I forgot to
pop up the um the the
chat. So participants pop out chat.
If you are here say hi. Okay. So, am I
uh make sure my live stream is going?
Let's see.
Yes, I think so.
Okay. So, anyway, so so let's see
today's talk show and go to uh talk show
today. So, the last one is March 27th.
So, it's been okay. It's been two months
I have not done a live stream but anyway
let's go today. Okay. So today we're
going to talk about cascade cascading
stylesheet. It's getting very complex.
Okay.
And uh you know so it's quite amazing.
So it's very interesting technically
because of the the heart of cascading
stylesheet is the selectors. Okay.
The the heart of cascading stylesheet.
If you just go to my website kasadi.info
info. You can see I have a tutorial of
it. Visual CSS, cascading stylesheet.
Okay. So, it allows you to do styles for
your website, you know, uh commercial,
uh Amazon, YouTube, and so on. So, one
of the most interesting thing is
the heart of cascading stylesheet is the
selectors. Okay, selectors. So, what it
basically what it do is select a
tutorial. What they do is that you you
have this syntax and it will match HTML
uh HTML elements tax okay structure. So
HTML is a tree structure. So this C
cascading sty sheet s uh CSS selector
syntax they allows you to pick a branch
of the tree. So in other words it's a
pattern matching system for tree data
structure. Okay. So that is that makes
it very interesting. So um so you have a
pattern that select you know basically
match patterns of a tree
uh in a special way because of the uh
HTML. Each tree node you have the
attributes like class ID and other like
class ID uh and and and uh href and
source and so on. So so for HTML
uh syntax it's a tree structure but each
node you got attributes like information
for each node then you have children so
it's a tree structure. Okay. So then it
then CSS allows you know the basically
the they call it selector is basically a
pattern matching uh syntax like regular
expression but it allows you to select
the tree structure of HTML. So for
example you if you say P that matches
the any tree node whose tag name is P.
Okay. So if you say for example BBB that
matches any node of a tree whose
information attribute embedded
information there's a class equals to
the value of that class information is
PVB this string okay so that we'll
select all those nodes in a tree in HTML
okay so that's that so these are the
pattern matching of uh CSS okay so it
gets very complex so if you don't know
if If you are webdev, you know some, you
know, at least you know somewhat. So, so
all these selectors
I've been very busy working on CSS in
the past two weeks. Okay. So, you can
see you you have selectors. You got type
selectors which match the tag name. By
the way, the name type selector is
idiotic.
Okay, this this is another topic. You
know, the type selector that's what they
call it. Okay, that's in the spec. they
say type selector what but actually this
pattern what it actually does is to
match the tag name of HTML so it's a
it's match tag name so it's it would be
better if you say element name selector
okay but they call a type selector which
is very bad and confusing why because
because in HTML
each element or tag like um like for
example example this HTML this this for
example this head that's a tag okay so
when you when you write it you say this
head this is the beginning opening tag
and this head is ending tag and the
whole thing
we call it element okay so again
confusing jarens you know they should
just you know use one uh name so anyway
in syntax you say this is the beginning
tag so for example let's go to the for
example Example this H2. So this is uh
talk show, right? So go back this H2
miscellaneous index. That's this part.
So you can see you got H2. That's a
opening tag. It's called opening tag.
And the /h2 is called closing tag. And
together it's called an element. when it
when the browser read the the page and
become a tree you know each each of
these is called element or in terms of
tree you can call it a node in a tree or
branch point okay so this is element
okay so now for in HTML for each element
you got types okay so for example you
can uh go check out my uh my webdev
tutorial on kasadi.info info. Okay, just
go to casadi kasadi.info
and uh you know you got HTML tutorial,
you got
cascading stylesheet tutorial, you got
JavaScript tutorial, JavaScript in depth
and then you got a dome which is uh
teaching you how to
script the website using JavaScript
dome. Okay.
So what I'm saying so in DOM so HTML you
got tags you know you you create
elements you know uh but you don't call
them but but um but there are different
types of elements okay so if you for
example you go here so they call you
know technique you know this is getting
technical detail they call it node node
type and element okay so a node is
basically a a a branch point of a tree
okay a node
Then but you got something like whites
space note because in in HTML
you know you see you see this is H2 tag
and here you got a list okay so for
example showing browser so you got H2
that's the miscellaneous index then here
is a list right but you can see there is
a empty line in between them now that
empty line that you know this Um
this these actually two new line
characters those are actually also a nod
of a tree okay that's just empty so the
the node of this so those are also a
node you see do you see what I mean so
that's why in HTML they they call it uh
that's why so this this is called whpace
nodes okay so in in fact you can
actually use JavaScript to uh to get
that empty node. So it's very confus so
so anyway. So it's um it's a bit
complex. Okay. So you got whites space
node and you see this doc type at the
beginning
that is also a node and also you see a
comment. Do we have a comment? Yes, we
do have comment. Okay. You see those
HTML comment?
You see a common also also forms a node
of a tree of the HTML
document hierarchy. Okay. So in other
words, you got different types of nodes.
So you know this is you got a normal
element. Here's a link. Uh for example,
let's see
what. So let me delete that. So you got
a link, you got the list item, you got
uh uh you got this item, then you got
then you got the
an order list. Then you can select to
the parent and more and you know another
order list and then you got the header
H1. Then you got the main.
You see the this is a closing tag for
the name for the main
uh wait. So any anyway so so let's jump
to Yeah. So let's jump. Yeah. And here
is the opening tag of the main element.
Okay.
But the the thing is that you have
different types of the uh nodes. You
have empty node, you have comment node,
uh you have no more element node. So
that is why in HTML
uh
document object model you have different
types of note node type. Okay. Now you
you can use JavaScript to query the note
type. It basically it's a number. Okay.
So value of one, type one is element
node, type two is attribute node. So uh
actually attribute they are they are
part of the information of a node but
they are actually by themsel or note
exactly I forgot exactly the detail but
anyway then you got text node which is
like the inner text of a paragraph
or header and you got CD data that's
more complicated thing. So then then you
got entity no. So you see you got no
type
but then in CSS
uh in CSS let's go back to CSS. Okay.
Cascading stylesheet you
um
yeah so we are talking about selectors
which is a pattern to match a tree HTML
tree syntax the document object model
you see so then you got selector
tutorials so one of the pattern is
called type selector
I was talking about why it's a extremely
confusing name because HTML elements
elements they have different types. You
are not selecting by type. You are
selecting by tag name. Okay. Or the or
in other words the name of the element.
So this type selector is a idiotic
jargon. Okay. Some people call element
selector which is also no good because
by definition all all selector patterns
you know you got class selector. Okay.
You might if you do webdev you might be
familiar. You got class selector, you
got um you got class selector, you got
uh ID selector, right? All selectors
they select elements elements. So if you
call this type selector which is
selecting the type by type by type name.
If you call element selector that
doesn't make sense because all selectors
are selecting elements. Do you see do
you guys see what I mean? So for example
you you can uh let's go to Mozilla
reference you know you'll see the jargon
mentioned by you know the they'll say uh
type selector you see that's official
jargon for this selector pattern okay uh
okay uh Mozilla does it also mention
element selector but sometimes people
say element selector okay
so it's it's a bad jargon okay
anyway so I digressed. Actually, I
digressed. So, we haven't even begin to
get into the main topic. I want to talk
about
uh the complexity of P of CSS. You need
a PhD today. Okay, we haven't started to
talk about that yet. And and several
other things I want to talk about. Okay,
let's talk about it.
Okay, uh comments. No, I I don't think
anyone is watching. uh you know because
the these days I I think that there is a
uh AI
internet ho
okay like in this year beginning of this
year 2026 not before not a year before
not 2025 but exactly the beginning of
this year AI had a milestone
uh so AI is becoming incredible and also
you know also the war is going on in uh
in in in Middle East so and so this
I think there's something quite
significant okay historically speaking
so anyway let's get get back to CSS okay
so let's let me just talk about the
things I want to talk about and be done
okay now we talked for 20 minutes okay
let me quickly finish okay we talked
talked about selectors. Okay, so
selectors is the why are we talking
about selectors? Because selectors is
the heart of cascading stylesheet sheet.
Okay, even though it's like the
stylesheet is making things pretty,
right? You want uh you want characters
to have what kind of color shadow uh box
shadow random color you can adjust. You
see this is a JavaScript app I wrote.
You can check it out. You see you can um
the box shadow it will generate the code
for you. You see and go back. So you got
animation, you got image roll over, you
got 2D transform.
Uh then you got of course then you got
uh round corners, you got um you got and
also you got color. Let me show you some
of the updates I I did uh worked on. Um
in the past two weeks I updated uh the
the interactive code generator. You see
this this generates the radio gradient
uh kind of random one. So you can select
how many colors you want and uh then you
can select each color. Then you can uh
choose a uh position where they radiate
from. You know se several uh options you
can choose all possibilities. Then it
generates code. You see at the bottom
you see switch back to rainbow colors.
Switch random colors. Okay. Random top
left, top right. Okay. Now random. Okay.
So you see the code is generated here.
You can just copy that and paste it, you
know. So this is one of the things I
wrote. Um then you got color names. Uh
RGB HSL. So this gen random this
generate HSL color hue saturation
lightness okay
uh and fantastic okay go back to color
then you got linear gradient okay that's
another gradient thing
so
cascading style sheet you know it it's
the purpose is to style your page um you
know so you can choose choose a font.
You can choose like uh overline,
underline, line through all kind of
these things, you know, seems like
trivial but actually so so first of all
the heart of it is a selectors because
in order to determine which HTML element
you want to color you need to select it
via a pattern. So the selector is very
interesting and that's uh so as as a uh
from the perspective of of computer
languages it's very interesting because
it's a pattern that matches a tree.
Okay. Then we talked about the you know
a bunch of selectors. So selectors there
are many type. Okay. So I I so check out
my tutorial. Okay. Just search for.info.
So, so I give you a basically complete
uh documentation and as a tutorial most
easy to read but most importantly from a
logician's point of view. So the things
are the very logical and concise so you
can understand all about selectors.
Okay. So there are different types. So
first of all we talked about the type
selector which is actually just a tag
name. Okay. So then you got the
universal selector which is uh select
every every element. Okay. Why is that
useful? Because you're going to see we
because we going to start to modify. So
we can also select by type I mean by
class. Okay. The class attribute of
HTML. Okay. So you can couple that with
uh
universal selector own. Anyway, so
if you do webdev, you know, you already
know this. Okay, so you can you you have
uh class selectors. Then you have um
then you have ID selectors. These are
these are the most common.
Then you have attribute selectors. This
is a bit uh less common, but it allow
it's very general. It allows you to
select any attribute. So what is
attribute? For example in HTML for
example you can see this is a HTML
element
you know you got the beginning tag A the
tag name is A you know A stand for
anchor which is a idiotic name it should
be just named link okay but back then
because I believe it due to the
grandparent the parent of HTML which is
the SGML
which stand for um
S general markup. S stand for um
I forgot what does S stand for. So let's
ask AI. So because AI is becoming
amazing. So let's uh I've been asking AI
like an hour a day almost like every
day.
So let me think about what does uh SGML
you we got people here finally I'm
watching in fact it's very interesting
thank you uh it's very interesting thank
you so and hi Mr. Hi. Uh, hi. Uh,
Clipper.
So, let's see what does SG what what
does the S stand for in SGML? I forgot
general markup language. Okay, so that's
GML. What? But what was the S. Now HTML
that H stand for hypertext. Hypertext
means a link. Okay, you know sounds
silly today but you see when you have a
link for example this this you know for
example um you know you see these are
links back then 30 years ago they are
called hypertext
hypertext
means means that text you can click you
know you can it's active like you can go
to it hypertext okay today we just call
it link right but back then I because I
remember back in 1991 when I begin to
you know know about this um it's called
hypertext in cyerspace you know today
what's cyerspace is just internet okay
but but back then you don't have
internet so it's called cyberspace it's
like a you know space where hacker goes
to so anyway you got cyerspace so this
is around uh early 1990s or or the
entire 1990s okay you got cyerspace
basically means internet or the
worldwide web www. Okay, cyerspace and
link is called hypertext and then you
got um
um so anyway it's the jargon are silly
because you know then you got the anchor
you see this edge this this a tag that a
stand for anchor
you know today we you know it's simpler
if you just call it the link okay but it
was it called anchor why does it called
anchor actually I'm not sure
So let's ask AI. Okay.
In HTML, when you have the anchor tag A,
why is it named anchored?
>> The name comes from the old days of the
web when the A tag was mainly used to
mark a specific spot on a page that you
could jump to. That spot was called an
anchor, like dropping an anchor at a
place in the water so you can come back
to it. So the tag was named for that
anchoring function even though we mostly
use it for links. No W.
Okay, that's AI. Quite interesting. So
So it's saying well because it's like an
anchor. Well,
like anchor of a ship, but I don't
really see the analogy. So let's ask
again.
in SGML.
What does the S stand for?
>> Standard SGML stands for standard
generalized markup language.
>> Ah, that's right. Standard generalized
markup language. So, HTML is a kind of a
derivative of SGML. Okay. Anyway, that's
history. Okay. So what I'm saying is
that you got the anchor tag okay this a
so when you have a anchor tag and inside
it you you got this uh this this
information that's called attribute okay
so why are we talking about that yeah we
we we were talking about type selectors
yeah so we are talking about attribute
so I'm talking about what are attributes
so you do you see you see so you got
anchor tag and this hre hf which is a
URL
the address to go to. Okay, so that's a
like embedded information in this in
this node. And then you got data
accessed that's called custom attribute.
Custom data attribute. You can actually
have any you want. Okay. So you got data
accessed date. Then you got target
that's a standard attribute. So this the
so and so these things inside an element
those are called attributes. Okay. So
then the CSS you know this you got
attribute selectors allows you to select
attribute allows you to match elements
that has particular attribute name and
value. Okay. So you can check the value
match the value. If the value matches
then you select that element in a tree
or node in a tree. Okay. Then you can
also select just the beginning of
attribute value or end of attribute
value or you can match substring of
attribute value. Okay. So you got these
variations. All these are using uh used
to uh match attributes. Okay. So which
is very general.
By the way the class selector is just a
subset of the attribute selector you
know because it's used so often. And so
we have a special syntax for the class
class selector but you don't need it
actually because you can just use
attribute selector like um like here you
can just say attribute you know like
something class equals true then a value
okay that will select certain class okay
so so uh okay so we are digressing I
mean we are not digressing but we are
too slow because there are so many to
talk about so anyways so you got Pass
selector, ID selector, attribute
selector, descendant selector and child
selector that those are getting
interesting. Okay, these are called
combinators.
Very interesting and complex. Why?
Because combinators when you hear when I
hear that I thought it you know maybe
has it to do with a theoretical computer
science called combinators and
combinatoric
logic.
Okay, like you know you know the hacken
news y combinator.
Why are they called combinator? Because
that word combinator means the
combinator in in a branch of logic which
is uh more advanced than lambda calculus
which is created to answer the question
whether if something cannot be answer by
computation. Okay, like the limit of
mathematics or the limit the limit of
logical systems is are there anything
that cannot be logically derived things
like that okay that's a range of lambda
calculus entering machine and
combinators combinators is the first
actually for several tens of years
before okay combinator combinators very
interesting uh you should go check out
Steve
uh Stefan Wuam article on combinator and
also on lambda calculus. Okay. Uh well
uh so came from XML uh before XML. Yes.
X SGML is very old. S Oh you are you Mo?
Hey Mo. SGML is from I think 1970s. or
even 60s.
Wait, let's ask AI.
When was SGML created?
1974. That's when Charles Goldb designed
the SGML syntax. It took another dozen
years to become the official ISO
standard in 1986.
Okay. It began in 1974
and uh then became stand ISO ISO
standard in 1986. Yeah. Long ago. So
are you still using glove 80? Uh well
right not right now but it's uh you know
because I only have one desk you know
but if I have two desk I would put it to
use. So, so right now I'm using uh just
this uh keyboard.
Uh
so anyway, we are digress digressing so
much. Jesus, every time I start to do a
live stream, either I don't begin it if
I begin it, it's going to be one or two
hours. So, how long have I been going?
6:38 40 minutes already. Okay, almost 40
minutes. Okay, we got we got ways to go.
Okay. So we got we are talking about
selectors. Okay. So um so why are we
talking about SGML? Yeah. Well because
we are talking about anchor tag. You
know the history. Why is it called
anchor? Why don't you just call it link
and so on. So anyway you got several
selectors. Then you got the combinators
right? We are talking about combinators
you know. So why combinator? So yeah. So
let let me let me show you guys. Okay.
So, let's uh hold on a second. This I
don't want this too long.
So, hold on a second. But I want
Okay. So, now we got some space. Um
Okay. So, you guys, I want to tell you
guys to check out Stefan Wolfam's
article. So, let me just quickly show
you. Okay. That's the best like one of
the best thing
uh I've read and and and one of the
Stefan Wu my one of my favorite um of
his article. Okay.
So uh
so let's just search for it.
Lambda calculus and combinators. Okay.
So check out you know uh wait the lology
of lambda you know check it out. That's
about lambda calculus. But my favorite
article is this combinators. Okay,
combinators uh centennial view by
Stephan Wu. This is written in 2024, two
years ago. Okay, this is great. This is
all together there are three articles.
Okay, it'll take you it's very long. You
know each one of his blog he published a
little book. So you you know if you want
to read the entire thing it'll take you
several hours. Okay, but go read it.
Okay, so this is about uh theoretical
computer science and the white
combinator of the hacker news that
combinator is this. Okay, now so when
you are doing CSS you learned you know
they call it combinator. So you can
check out you know Mozilla's
documentation you know like then then
you started to think like what why are
they call it combinators? Does it I mean
are they talking about the lambda
calculus combinators? It turns out no
because I asked AI. AI is so helpful.
The CSS people they thought because they
are combining syntax so they thought
it's you know combining the selectors
that's why they call it combinator but
it has nothing to do with the
theoretical computer science of
combinators or lambda calculus. Okay,
they they just they just this these
people just created the world
combinators, you know, because it's like
combining.
So, you know, let me let me tell you
guys this detail like because you you
talk to the typical average web dev at
Google or whatever they never know, they
never thought of, okay, they don't know
a thing.
So, you got this combinator selectors.
Okay, but first of all, why is it called
combinator? That's a very interesting
question and we learned well just
because they it's combining selectors
it's not has nothing to do with the
lambda calculus or combinatoric logic.
Okay. Then the second thing is that the
combinators can you why can't you uh
like
like do you guys know what I'm talking
about? Like you first of all you need to
know about this uh you need to
understand this these combinators like
so for example when you have this syntax
that means you you want to select any
element s_ub_2
that has a ancestor of s1. So this is
called descendant selector. Descendant
selector. Okay. So any of these any of
these four descendant selector, child
selector, adjacent sibling selector and
subsequent sibling selector. These four
each one of them is called a combinator.
Okay. All of them. So all of them
together when you have a selector that
contains any one of them it's called
complex selector. Okay. This is when CSS
getting complex. Okay. very complex. So,
so first of all, you need to know what
exactly what it does. Okay. So, let me
show you my my CSS file. So, so for
example, this select a class bubble
uh which I use for example um
let's see if I can show you a place I
used it. Uh complain why I hate the
exceptions. No, let's not show it. I
don't know where. Okay. But anyway, so
let's go to uh what what uh so we want
to dis uh we want to look at descendant
selectors. Okay. So let's see
um
do I have any descendant selectors?
So you see but we got this. This is
child selector. This is one of the
combinator. Okay. This is uh next
sibling selector. This means UI plus UI
means when you have a UI tag name UI and
immediately it has a older brother right
right before it. So they are next to
each other. You have UI attack UI and
followed immediately by another UI. Then
this applies you want the margin top of
the second one. Okay. The so these
combinators they are read from right to
left. Okay. This is important critical
these combinators this plus sign this
greater than sign they are read from the
right to left. So when they match it is
these the right hand the selector that
match. Okay. So this means when you have
a UI
and it has a older brother right before
it then it match the second one. Okay.
Then you make the margin top 2.5 root
uh font side uh length. Okay. So you see
this is a example this plus you know
this is the example of the um
of the of the uh so let's go uh of the
next sibling selectors uh which is uh
this adjacent sibling. Okay. So you can
see so you see that's a example you see
okay that's an example in real life okay
now I have other so this is a this is a
descendant selector this means whenever
you see a DD DD is a definition list
okay so for example
this is actually your definition list if
I show you the source code you'll see
okay am I boring okay nobody is comment
okay so you got this child So if you got
a ul that's a direct child of dd then do
this style. Okay so so these are
combinator com they call it combinators.
Okay then um okay so here you see figure
caption li. So that means when you have
a figure caption
space li this is a descendant selectors
that means whenever you have a li and
then it's grandparent or grandparent or
whatever grandparent the you know the
ancestor is figure caption then you
apply this style. Okay. So that's a
descendant selector.
Uh this is a direct child selector
greater than sign. Okay. Then we we
showed also next sibling. So um
yeah. So anyway so so these are the
these are the combinators. Okay.
Descendant selector space child selector
a greater than sign adjacent sibling a
plus sign and the tilda is subsequent
sibling. Okay. So you got these four
things. They are called combinators. So
first of all why are they called
combinators? Well, turns out nothing to
do with the lambda calculus combinator.
The then secondly, you see you got
another question. Why can't you combine
them? You see like normally when you
have in mathematics, you know, for
example, in mathematics, let's say um
you see let's say uh 3 + 4 3 + 4
times
two.
Okay, that's in Python. Okay, let's do
this. Okay, you can you can have you can
use paren. Okay, so if you if you run
that
uh let's say uh 1 + 2 2 + 1. Okay, let's
make it uh simple. 2 + 1. Uh
okay, then you could print here. Okay,
let's run it. That's six. Let's run it.
That's four. So you use paren to group
their presidents like priority. So you 2
+ 1 first that's three. 3 * 2 is six.
Okay. Now in this case you group them
the 1 + 1 * 2. So that's three. Then 3 +
2 is
uh wait 1 * 2 is two. 2 + 2 is four.
Okay. So they you see you use paren
parenthesis to group them
but in CSS you cannot do that even
though you got these operators but but
you cannot do that. So why do you know
why? So you you you know you you should
ask um have you ever thought about
um so if you are here say hi. Okay. So
uh so why so so let's go uh uh work work
on give an example okay so let's go to
this page this page is a complex
selector combinator okay so let's go to
um combinator can be chained
yes okay so but and what's their
presidentidence okay their president is
this space is the highest priority then
child combinator the greater sign then
adjacent sibling the plus sign then
subsequent sibling the till day okay and
you cannot use parentheses to group them
so by uh what do I mean by that for
example sometimes you might want to
group them so let's say CSS
uh wait delete that uh and uh
okay so this uh actually so so there so
you got the CSS says let's say color
okay color red okay so you got a CSS but
but what does it mean exactly you got
the greater than sign you got the space
you got the plus sign which one has
priority okay so let's go to our
reference it turns out it means space
has the highest priority okay space so
it's like um hold on a second let me do
this uh multiple copy okay so so what
does this
It means like this. Okay. So, space is a
highest priority. Then plus versus
greater than which one is tighter. Let's
see. Plus, greater than is tighter than
plus. So here actually means like that.
Okay. So that's what it means. Okay. So,
but why can't I say, you know, you know,
I like it. I want the Li. What I really
want is to have LI plus P first, you
know, has priority. Meaning that meaning
that you see remember this is the next
sibling. So that means I want the P
right after a by the way that is
actually illegal syntax but but you know
we can change this to AI or something.
uh or or in fact we can change all these
two uh uh two um
two uh class. So let me do that. Okay.
So change all type to a. Do it. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Okay. Now change
all ul to do uh tob.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Okay.
Now change oi to C. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Okay. So because
what
then change all P to um
dot ABCD
do it do it do it do it do it you see
each one of these dot is a class so this
way you don't depend on the tag name but
anyway so so you can see why can't I
have you know if I wanted you know
Right? Why you know I want the sibling C
means a class of C followed by class of
D then
then such that it has a ancestor of B
depending on how these two is grouped so
why can't you use parenthesis you cannot
why is that well it's because
AI can you help me why is that so AI
help me so
I asked AI AI you know syntax design why
I cannot use parenthesis to group CSA
selector for presidents. Okay so I asked
AI then I say is basically well
it was designed that way so that the
syntax the president pre presidents is
fixed. So it's not like typical
operators where they have presidents but
in the case of CSS their presidents is
fixed and you cannot use parent to group
them. So why why because that way it's
simpler simpler to pass and uh see how
CSS selector actually work okay so you
read from right to left okay that's
critical and uh so why is design choice
simplicity and performance right to left
matching okay and parenthesis are
reserved
okay they are used in fun functional
notation but well that's not a good
reason anyway remember that AI is not
perfect. So some of the answer AI gave
is not like perfect but but but but it
does give tells me the reason originally
simplicity. Okay. So anyway and his and
uh let's see historical reasons.
So anyway so so you got this situation
you see you cannot use paren and you
have to memorize this order. So you
almost never see people like mix this
like kind of rare. Okay. And so you so
you cannot use par. But what if you
really need to group them? You can. So
they created a new syntax. Okay. So like
the AI mentioned uh where you have the
ease selector. Okay. So that's why I'm
saying you know AI uh I'm saying that
CSS today is like requiring a PhD to
understand. Okay. So you can group them
by um getting complex. Okay. So you got
this uh
you got this pseudo class function
selectors. Okay. This this not is where
has fairly complex. So this is is like
select a list but it allows you to group
them almost syn. So this this is
actually function like a parenthesis.
Okay.
Uh in order to explain that it will take
10 minutes. Okay. Uh so I can't so yeah
it's already we are already almost an
hour and I haven't really
begin to talk about what I want to talk
about because we are right now stuck on
the
we are right now talking about just the
the combinators okay so anyway so so
what I'm saying here is that the
combinators select let's go back to
selectors so so we are talking about the
combinators. Okay. So, wait.
Yeah. Combinators. Uh
so
you know these selectors these four um
so they are very complex and we are
talking about their precedence. Um oh
yeah so we didn't finish uh write that.
So let's um
Okay. So yeah. So delete that. Delete
that. Okay. Put it back. syntax correct
act to browser refresh. So you see
so this is how I write tutorial. So what
does this mean? This actually means like
that if we allow parenthesis but because
CSS does not allow so this won't
actually work but but you see that it
actually behaves like that.
So so you got the syntax prescence
issue. Okay. So then so after the um
combinators which is called which are
called complex selectors. Okay then you
got um okay we gota we gota um
we got to skip and talk about something
else because um
I just switched to Windows 11 from Unix.
Why do why do you do that? Are you the
guy on Twitter? I remember there's a guy
on Twitter but um I mean if you are
already on Linux I don't think it's good
idea to switch back to Windows. Windows
is is quite nasty. Okay, Windows is got
deep state control quite nasty. Uh Linux
is not much better but better but of
course user interface and other things
Linux really sucks but anyway that's
another thing.
So anyway, so let's just let's just keep
on talking about the CSS what I want to
say and and call it a day. Okay, so it's
already an hour. So we we got the
combinators. Then you got the selector
list. This is very good. This is
basically allow you to have several
selectors. Okay. Okay. Now I want to get
to
uh kind of uh get to my point about the
complexity and okay so anyway you got
quite a few selectors okay quite a lot
more so you need to study them in detail
okay so now let me talk about
let me talk about the um selector types
okay you got the simple selectors what
are they just either selecting t by tag
names or selecting every any tag regard
regardless of name or you are selecting
a class name or ID name or attribute
name or attribute value or you got this
bunch of pseudo selectors which is like
a link visited hoover active focus they
are kind of like state of an element
okay that's why they are called pseudo
class not exactly class because it's not
the class attribute value but they are
kind of like the state but so you kind
of call them class so they are called
pseudo class vectors you see that's
another complexity
then you got pseudo element which is
which is kind of like element but not
exactly such as first letter first line
or before uh HTML element and and and
more okay so so all these are simple
selectors. Okay,
all all of these then you can combine
them. Let's say you want a uh you want
to select a tag name plus a class value
or uh you know ID or attribute combine
them. Those are called compound
selectors. Okay.
Then
you have complex selectors which we
talked about like relationship between
two elements child or descendant or
adjacent sibling or subsequent sibling.
Okay, these are called combinators. And
if a selector has used any one of them,
it's called complex selectors. Okay,
this this this these jarens are kind of
important. You know, simple selectors,
compound selectors, complex se
selectors, it sounds complex, but you
actually need to understand them because
because when you use selectors,
especially when you combine them, you
need to know when you can have one or
the or the other. Okay. Anyway, then the
lastly lastly you have selected list.
Okay. So that's about selectors.
selectors is the most is the heart of
CSS. Okay, CSS we think of it as a
styling language, you know, just style.
So it's boring color, size, you know,
font, margin, you know, layout, you
know, but actually at heart you have
selectors which is a
pattern syntactic pattern to match tree
structure
and then we have seen their complexity.
Okay. Now this is interesting because in
Hascar in functional programming
languages Hascar or camel F you also
have patterns
and in Wufam language Mathematica you
also have patterns which is a term
rewriting system you have patterns that
matches you have patterns that matches
symbolic trees. Okay. But but either
this these patterns in F or camel or wam
language they are very different from
CSS selectors. So CSS selectors is kind
of a different um view. So it would be
interesting to think of all these
selectors they are used to match tree
in a coherent way. For example, why? For
example, Wuam language is also um
is filled with pattern matching uh
nested syntax of tree. So why are they
different? So it would be very
interesting to uh to think about them in
that way. Can you unify them? And also
as far as I know
F and Okamo their pattern matching is
not very powerful. They they don't match
uh complicated nested
syntax. They don't match trees uh in in
arbitrary ways. Okay, because it can get
very computational intensive.
Okay, so we talked about selectors. Um
we have not um so today so we talked
about complex selectors okay so
uh math block close but today's talk
show I wanted to talk about by the way
so this amazing AI generated
pictures okay so we uh we I wanted to
talk about there are so many other
things okay uh I discovered but I think
that that's it for now Okay, that's so
this video is just about CSS selectors
and CSS complexity you know so so
selectors is one part of the complexity
there's quite a lot more okay so we we
spend one hour just to talk about
selectors only actually I also gave a
tutorial so you know but so but but then
you got anchor scope you got this anchor
new things okay you got add sign
position at rule. Okay, you got Okay,
that's about anchor. Then you got the
insert thing. Then you got this this
these are just a a few of the example.
Then you got the okay color CIE lab
color. Okay, lab color extremely complex
device CM YK color. Color is a science
by itself. Like if you want to
understand color, you you spend four
years to get a PhD just for color. Okay,
just for color because color
it's um you know physically it's
electromagnetic waves of certain
wavelength. Then it involves human
perception
and involves psychology the human eye
retina you know your nerves what color
you can see some color you can see but
cats cannot see or dogs cannot see but
birds can or cannot see and see better
than you. So you different animals
because of their of our eyes. of biology
color.
Uh then you got TV, you know, TV can
display things or your monitor, right?
But actually they got problems, you
know, because they cannot represent
certain color and and and then then
painting all your painting the artist
you have another way subtractive way to
represent color like color mixing. You
mix red paint with uh let's say blue
paint. What do you get versus red light
versus blue light? What do you get?
You get different things. Okay. So you
you the color is very complex science
and also your camera and so on. So um so
now you know they are in CS CSS you got
this you got this different color
models. You you see this this is a
certificate of CSS PhD. This is a OK lab
color model. Okay. Like what the is
it? So that's just color. Then you got
word break uh fairly very complex. You
got new aspect ratio thing. You got
support thing. You got layers scope
thing. That's about cascade and
specificity.
That's another
that's specificity is about the priority
of selectors which is related very much
related to what we were talking about
today but it's another topic like which
selectors apply first okay the
specificity
very complex and I do have a tutorial so
you can read about specificity here
specificity is a subsystem of the CSS
cascade system. Okay. So first of all in
order to judge which CSS rule is takes
priority
it accord it is done by the cascading
rule this page okay cascade rule then
when you have a tie
then it's about specificity okay which
is another fairly complicated thing to
understand okay so we so
uh but we don't we not going to talk
about Then okay so then uh so yeah the
CSS you don't know you need a PhD okay
then you got then you got um you got
quite a lot of things okay so rebecca
purple by the way CSS got a new color uh
it's called Rebecca purple because one
of the uh contributor one one of the big
contributor to CSS his daughter died of
cancer so they so people made it you
know uh named the color after his
daughter
Rebecca above which I don't think is a
good thing because it contaminates the
thing people don't understand you know
when you have jarens like a peg jogg
but
you know so that that's kind of a thing
interesting
Oh yeah, then you got of course uh flex
layout and uh flexbox which I wrote a
tutorial recently. Uh then there's a
grid layout. Uh then uh anyway
I think that's it for today. Uh let's
see.
CSS selector is fastest way to find
element in automation in automation
testing.
Uh what do you mean?
Okay, I think that's it for today. Um
yeah, today we talked about the
complexity of CSS.
Okay, and we mostly talked about
selectors. Okay.
And uh is there anything else? Yeah, we
we talked about cascade. Uh well, we
didn't. There's a new thing cascade
layer and scope add rule. Okay, those
are new things which I don't have a
tutorial yet. I'm writing one with AI
help.
Then you got uh presidents of
combinator. Yeah, we talked about that.
Okay, that's it.
Bye guys.
Comments like my video. Okay, so how
many people are watching? Three. Sunday
night.
Bye guys.