Hello, good morning, good evening.
Welcome to another episode of Kasan Talk
Show. We are going to talk about
programming language design on stream.
So, am I live? Check. Video check. Audio
check. Yes, good to go. Uh, programming
language design. So the topic is the
programming language C sprint f or print
f crime and best new syntax for string
called rock rock string. Okay, that's a
string syntax I just designed. So if you
are watching this offline, play at 1.5
speed minimum. If you are watching here
live, say hi. Okay, love to see your
comments. So this is uh kind of
technical uh for those programmers
you know if you have like you know one
year experience of programming and uh so
I'm going to talk about the problem of
C's printf and uh many of the issues on
uh string syntax design and uh at the
end I'm going to show you a new uh
string syntax that solves all the
problems. I think at least okay that is
one of my best work I think I just came
up uh you know yesterday but based on
from based from my 20 years experience
from you know coding and uh learning the
many different programming languages
lisp
uh list PHP pearl python javascript you
know their design and the problems I
found and and bash and shell so let's
let's begin Okay, so let me just go
through my uh notes. Niha, GPS, Niha.
Uh so C and Unix, you know, I'm a big
hater, giant hater of C. Okay, I think
that C and Unix caused pervasive harm in
programming languages and computing
industry. Okay, that's my claim. Now C
print F, I'm going to explain what that
is. Okay, is the quintessence of its
hack nature. Okay, I hate C very much.
If you are interested, you can look at
one of my article I've written why I
hate C the language written in um 2012
why I hate C. So you know there are many
reasons I gave and what and one of the
reason you know so if I can capture the
essence of why why YC is the worst hack
possible like no design no brain worst
hack possible I would say it is you can
you can see it from from the C print F
syntax okay
so let me quickly so actually I can show
you so I don't have C I don't know
actually I don't call C but the C sprint
f function has been borrowed to so many
languages because C is like a virus. So
it's in Python, it's in EMAC list, it's
in uh Python emacs list, it's in Goland.
Actually I don't have you know I should
link to Goland. So you know you can see
Python PowerShell. It's also you know
went to PowerShell. It's in in pearl.
Okay I didn't prepare. So it's in Python
pearl I I should have a link powershell
emac this you can see there and uh and
more okay so um actually I don't have an
article for per pearl print f okay but I
can I can quickly let me just quickly
show you what print f means okay so
python uh let's start a python code okay
so print okay let's say uh x equals to 3
uh
some random number. Okay. Uh 3.256.
Okay. So, uh
and let's say
the price is X. Okay. So, and then you
you put a percentage sign then X. Okay.
Actually, you put percentage sign there
and F. Okay. Now run the code.
Wait, is it running? Uh, not yet. Wait,
what? What?
Okay, so you can see the output. But but
why is that? I can't run this. Uh,
okay. But anyway, here's output.
Oh wait, this is uh incorrect. We are
running in closure mod for some reason.
Okay, Python. Okay, so
so wait, this is incorrect.
Cut it. Okay, now run it. Okay, here. So
here's output. So you see you want to
basically you got a number and you you
this is kind of function as a um string
template and that percent f means means
that's a argument and it came from this
x which is defined here and that f means
it's a floating number. So and uh so
this is output. Now let's say if you
want to uh show just two decimal places
at the end because you know this is not
good. You don't want you know 0.25600 0.
So what you do is like I believe two.
Okay. So let's run this again. So there
is the result. So you see so this this
this
thing this kind of the you know
percentage sign dot something something
f or uh let's let's show another
example. Okay. So let's show another
example. Let's say a hexadimal. Let's
say hexadimal. Um let's say
hex equals to um 17. Okay. So you want
to print x let's say y. Okay. Not x. Uh
okay. So you say y. You want to convert
that number to a hexadimal. So what you
do here is you have to put x. Okay. Now
run it.
Okay. Okay. The price. Okay. So, wait.
So, let's change this hexadimal
of
y
um of of y. So, this is how you do it.
Okay. So, you have to put a d there. D
stand for decimal. So, this you know is
this. Okay. So, you just do y I believe.
So, let's try it. Okay. Wrong. So you
need a comma here.
Okay. Run it. Uh
wait
code. Uh type not enough argument for
format. Why is it not enough argument?
You got Y and Y. Um
okay.
Perhaps you forgot a comma. Wait, I just
add a comma there. So
not enough argument. Why is that? I
don't know. But
you know this is a python issue but
anyway so so this is what basically this
is what cintf do. Okay. So now let's go
back now let's let's talk about the
problem. So C and Unix is causes
pervasive harm in my opinion.
Yeah. So you GPS you are talking about
the new Python syntax. Okay. That's kind
of a bit different. What I'm doing is
the classic, you know, I I want to
demonstrate the C sprint f. Okay. And
that is borrowed in Python's this
percent thing. Okay. So, so because C
sprint f is so lousy, such a hack that
every language creates a new syntax. So
Python in the case of Python it creates
it over the you know 10 or 20 years it
it has three different syntax for uh
formatting strings. So you can look at
here. So so first of all we demonstrated
the you know print f I mean the print
with a percentage sign. Oh you need okay
I I've just found out what is wrong. So
you need a paren here
you need so the percentage percentage
sign goes here and paren okay now let's
dd the error okay now run this okay so
it says hexad decimal of 17 is 11 okay
that's how you do it now this put it
back syntax color show in browser
today's talk show at bottom so that's
what we code it okay so c print f is so
lousy like every language they they kind
of so in the case of Python they have
three they have actually four different
um like three
um syntax for to do what the C print F
does okay so the earliest the original
is this print f I mean print okay with a
percentage sign then they later on they
created the format format so you like so
this is similar to uh C sprint F the S
stand for string. So S print F that's a
that's a that's a name of the C's
function. So in the Python case they
changed it. So they don't use you know
they longer no longer use you know they
don't have like S sprint F something
something they so they created a entire
new kind of uh syntax they call it
format method. Okay. But and instead of
using percentage sign they use the they
use the curly braces to stand for uh
placeholder for the argument. Okay. Then
later on like five years ago they
created a new another new you know uh
function or syntax s you know basically
doing exactly what the C's print f does.
Okay that is the that's called f string.
So you just um so here are some examples
you know.
So why is Python create you know have
this all these diverse ways to do it?
Basically they do the same thing. Okay
that is because the C scum the C you
know the so extremely lousy uh print f.
So you know in the beginning like 30
years ago Python just borrowed it
because C is very popular you know. So
pearl borrowed it python borrowed it le
borrowed it and so many others. Okay.
And so they borrowed it. Then event, you
know, after 10 years they found out, you
know, it really sucks. So that's why um
really sucks. So they created a new
thing, you know, oh, we need the dot
format method. That's because that's
more clear, you know. Then then after 10
more years, they they they found that oh
that's actually not, you know, optimal.
So we need to create the fing. So that's
a story. So, so, so,
so the Python having these three
different formatting string uh ways in
my opinion is significantly partly due
to the C print F hack. Okay, so that's a
Python case. Now, in in in other case,
similar situation. For example, in
PowerShell, in PowerShell, they also
have like
very similar to the C uh print f with
the uh with you know this little code.
Let me show you. Okay. So, for example,
here. So, okay. So, let me show you.
Okay. So, let's just run it. Okay. So,
here. So, let's save this as as xx
uh ps1. That's a file name extension for
powershell. So, now it's this is
powershell. So you want to format this
this big number and you want to add you
know show this two decimal places with
grouping comma that's what you do. So
let's run it. Okay. So
uh let's do it here. Okay. New. So run
it.
Okay. So you can see now what what if
you want to convert to hexadimal. Okay.
So let's try it. Okay. So let's delete
that. Uh let's try hexadimal. So
hexadimal 17 just like before and here I
believe it's x. Okay. So you write 11.
Okay. So you say uh the number the
decimal
number number.
So you put a D here for decimal
in hexadimal
is that. Okay. So let's do it. There you
go. So the decimal number 17 in
hexodimal is one one. Okay. So let's uh
put it back. Wait. So copy it. Delete
it. Let's make a new example here.
PowerShell. Okay. Paste the code. Syntax
showing browser. Today's talk show. go
to the bottom. So that is a PowerShell
example. So you can see PowerShell also
kind of borrowed from the C print F. You
know they didn't borrow the percentage
sign but act but but they use the this
this cryptic code D for decimal X for
hexodimal. Okay. So
so C and Unix
creates pervasive harm for like 30 years
in programming languages. Now C print F
is the quintessence of the hack nature
of C. Okay, that's my clear. Now why is
print F a problem? I mean what's what's
the problem? You just you know of course
you have to learn a programming
language. So that's so you have to learn
this uh cryptic code. Well
so bit so the problem is that the C
print effectively creates a mini
language that is cryptic,
incomprehensible
and hard to use and not extensible.
Okay. Uh so it's cryptic you know
percentage f percentage x percentage d
that's cryptic incomprehensible and and
uh if you want to uh you know have two
decimals you have to use you know like
um like 2f that means two decimal
places. So it's very bad and like every
time you need to do something you you
read the documentation. For example,
let's let's look at the uh documentation
for Python's print f. Okay.
Uh open Python doc. Okay. So here is a
feature documentation of Python. And uh
let's let's search for um uh
print. Okay. So let's see if we can find
the documentation for print for that
percentage thing.
Okay. print converts print statement to
print f function. Okay, so there it is.
Uh print print system output something
something class class class property. Uh
and uh where does it show the percentage
sign
you know? So we want to find that the
the
uh code
Python doc is really sucks. Okay. So I
don't know where do you find uh format.
Let's search for format.
Okay, let's let's look at format because
it's kind of similar. So, here's a
documentation for Python format and
where does it show the the bunch of
percentage sign code.
Uh so, format specification mini
language. You see why you know they they
literally called it a mini language. So,
there they are. So you can see in the
format. So let's go to the Python uh
example. Uh yeah. So you see this
placeholder
is a mini language because you can if
you put percent.2 that two there f that
means um it shows two decimal places.
Okay. Now you can also have um you can
also have like let's say three.
Okay. So let let me try that. Okay. So
one, two, three. Let's see what this
returns. I don't know because like
because they are cryptic. So 3.2F that
means print three decimal. Okay. So what
what if you say five? Does it
you know it does nothing. Okay. It gets
interesting. So but but if you say
uh zero
let's see what it does. Okay. It does
nothing. So, what I want is padding. Um,
I don't know. You know, you can pad zero
in front of it, but I'm not sure how to
do it. You and also you can control how
many total number of uh integer digits
uh digits in the integer part. So, let's
say let's say nine. What does this do?
There it is. Okay. So you can see now it
adds
spaces in front of the number. Okay. So
9.2F means total of nine uh nine uh
slots and uh two
uh two of them in the decimal places.
Okay. But how do you pad? Let's say how
do you pad? I want to pad with zero.
Okay. So this is not correct. I don't
know. So that's what I that's why I say
it's cryptic. So you look at the
documentation and you can also control
whether you want uh to add the uh
positive sign or negative sign or uh
grouping operations. Yeah, the group you
know this group separators like every
three digits you add a comma and then
type you see you got B for bite C for
character I believe D for decimal number
E for exponential notation for number
and okay there are two version capital E
and lowerase E uh I I forgot the
difference so you can check there so
it's cryptic then F for float and
capital F I don't know what is capital
F. So each programming language they
borrow borrowed from C and then and they
got this kind of little mini language
thing to format the number. Yeah.
Typically for formatting numbers and
they differ slightly. Okay. Because they
try to improve it. So that's why I say
that the C print F is one of the extreme
hack and very very bad. Okay. Like brain
listing. Okay. So you can see here the
Python documentation, you know, they got
several 10 p 20 pages to just to explain
this this formatting issue.
Okay.
So and that's also true for lisp for for
example let me show you a list uh uh
version. Okay. So actually we can we can
actually demonstrate this version. So we
demonstrate python syntax color and we
demonstrate powershell. Then let's
demonstrate uh emacisp. Okay. So, print
uh format there it is list use format.
So, uh let's say hexadimal. So,
so um this uh decimal number
uh let's say let's create a local
variable. Okay. So, x = to 3. Okay. So,
wait x = to 17. So decimal number
that in hexad decimal
is percent x. Okay. Then you put the
argument. Where do you put the argument?
Uh here. Okay. So uh x and x. Okay. So
now we can run this code.
Uh
there it is. Decimal number 17 in
hexodimal is 11. Okay. Emac list. So put
it back. Show in browser. Show in
browser. And you can see here's a list
example. So this C print F went also
went to lisp.
Okay. So that I demonstrated the
complexities. Okay. Cryptic,
incomprehensible and hard to use and not
extensible because you see every
language when they try to explain when
they try to extend it, they basically
create incompatible syntax. Okay?
there's no way around it. So this lisp
way you know they are you know mini code
and python is not compatible and not
compatible with the C neither okay and
and powershell not compatible with
powershell neither neither okay so each
one becomes a mini language you know so
very bad okay now next point the reason
why print f is hard to use explain okay
I I did because it combines okay here's
a key because it combines
several distinct operations into one and
uses a cryptic ad hoc syntax for them.
Okay, so uh short article. So actually I
have written this out uh so I just
written this uh article new article uh
recent like a few weeks uh last week
computer language the hack of cintf
format string the origin format code
percent f percent x in programming
language where it came from it came from
C okay not from this not from uh forran
some people will say it's forran we had
an argument in Saudi code but actually
it came from C. Okay. Basically, you
know, C borrowed it from B and you know
a little bit but basically the the the
the way we see it today basically from
C. Okay. Then the C programming language
print format damage. Okay. It it create
a damage in computing industry in all
the programming languages. uh effective
effectively a mini language and um uh
why other programming language borrow it
from C because C is popular you know
because people because by habit you know
most people already know C you know back
then 30 years ago so when they create a
new language oh I already know you know
let's just do the C you know it's easy
no-brainer you know you just copy it
copy the you know the design of C so
that's why it went to uh C++ It went to
Java. It went to Python. It went to
Pearl. It went to PHP because PHP came
from Pearl. Borrow you know PHP was was
basically Pearl script and went to Ruby.
Went to Go language went to Emac this.
So what about Goland? We can see it.
Okay. So let me show you Golan.
Golan is a great language. My you know
my favorite lowle language. So you can
uh Goland you go to print f. So there
there you see it. Okay,
Golan is basically a family of the C
kind of. Okay, but Golan is a very good
language. It it it fixed you know
majority or the problem of C. Okay, but
however it you know it also borrow the C
print F. Okay, so you can see Golan
should should I demo the code? Okay. So,
let's um Okay. Let's do so copy it and
go line tutorial close and uh let's
let's create a new section. Go paste the
code there. Copy the URL and paste the
URL here somewhere. Python Python
PowerShell Emac Lisp uh and Golan. Okay.
Link it. And now let's go to our Golan
code here. Pop it out and let's demo run
it.
So two variables X and Y. X is a string
John and Y is 36. So print name is print
name is John age is 36. That's how you
do it. Okay. So if you want to let's say
you let's say I want to convert decimal
to hexadimal. So let's say x is um x is
a number. Okay. So 17. Let's try again.
So uh decimal
uh let's use v v is new in golan. Okay
the percent v that's you know golan
created its own. So uh decimal v in
hexadimal
is then you say uh x okay then you don't
need the new line. Okay. So that that um
that back slash N that stand for new
line character. That's another hack from
C. Okay. Actually this in this case I'm
not sure it's exactly from C. This this
thing we'll talk about later. Okay. It's
another major harm damage to computing
industry that back slashn called it's
called escape sequence. Okay. So it just
stand for new line in in embedded in
this printf format. Okay. So now decimal
x uh hex a decimal let's let's not use v
let's use d okay so is uh so y okay so
uh x uh x okay remove that now run the
code
there it is copy and and uh uh copy that
and paste it to your output okay format
the code fantastic okay so this
demonstrate that this printf thing is
also in golan
Okay.
Now, so let's go back to so we talked
about the reason why print f is hard to
use. Okay. Because it combines several
distinct operations into one and use a
cryptic adhar syntax for them. Okay. So
I showed the article. So so what are the
distinct operations of print f? So let
so so the article is here. So let's take
it apart. Okay. Let's dive into detail.
Why? What exactly in technical detail?
Why is the print f very bad? Okay. So
what the first thing is that it compi
combines several things very distinct
operation you want to do. So what what
are the things you want to do? One one
of them is a string template system. So
when you have a string sometimes you
want to embed variables inside it. So
that's a string template system. That's
one thing it does. The other thing is it
does number two string conversion
uh you know so number two string
conversion so it basically print f does
it okay why do you want to convert
number two to string because when you
print a report whatever programming
language that's also that's often
necessary right you want to you know
print a report and another thing okay
template system number string two string
conversion and it also does format
formatting number. Okay. So why do you
need format for for example number of
digits number of decimal places
important for f in finance because you
want to print you know uh 3.25
you don't want to print 3.25769 25 769
you know you want number of places and
sometimes in in another another report
you want to uh put zero in front like
padding uh for example if you want to uh
print ID
identifier numbers you know if there's a
zero in front usually you want to
include that you know like you want to
print let's say credit card number you
know there's like 12 digits you know the
if there's zero in front you you want to
print zero
Okay. So formatting number that's that's
one task which is very different from a
string template system very different
from number to string. Okay. Then you
also what it also does is convert
decimal number to binary or hexadimal.
Okay. Why do you want to do that?
Because uh in digital computers which is
what we use today since like 50 years
ago digital computers you know the
circuits they happen to be binary number
because the electronics on and off uh
most easily reflected in binary numbers.
So in other words binary number is most
suitable
uh for for uh mirroring uh digital uh
electronics. So that's why we use binary
numbers. By the way, there's also
tonary, but that because but the but it
turns out it is not too uh it turns out
binary is actually better. So anyway, it
it so happens we use binary numbers. So
when you say and and why do you need hex
hexadimal? Because hexadimal number why
do we need them? Because they they
happen hexodimal is a a very condensed
form to represent binary numbers. That
is why we have we use hexadimal numbers
a lot. For example, in unic code uh for
example in unic code each character
has a character ID which is a integer.
Okay. Each unic code character may be
emoji may be you know this uh using
French may be mathematical symbols
summation or dagger or hard or copyright
symbol or trademark symbol. Each
character has a character ID. Okay,
which is a integer. And the standard way
to represent represent that integer is
by by this. Let me show you. Okay, so
let me let me let's go to emoji.
Uh okay. So does it show here? There it
is. Can you see? So the you see that u U
+ 1 F0
that is you know U plus is a kind of
stand for unic code and then what
follows the plus that's the hexadimal
so that is a hexadimal representation of
the integer that is the ID for this
character okay so in unic code every
character has has ID and the standard
notation to to show that ID is to show
them as hexod hexodimal because it's
short and compact. Okay, so it's used in
unic code. So let's go back here. Uh so
this page explains unic code character
set encoding UTF8 code point. Okay, so
you should read that offline. Okay, so
let me post the link to my talk show.
Uh so let's uh post the link to the talk
show. So here. Okay.
So, so we are talking about so let's go
back to uh the C uh
the the hack of C printer formatting
string. Okay. So it it it does all these
things
template system string template system
number to string format number convert
decimal to binary or hexadimal. Okay. So
it does these basically four things
combine them to one print f and uh
and so that's very bad and also it
creates a mini language you know the the
cryptic codes okay so what uh but there
are but meanwhile there are also related
things it does not do because when you
convert a number to hexadimal typically
you also want to convert it back a
hexodimal to back to number so string to
number The print f doesn't do obviously
and convert binary to hex or hexadimal
to number the print f also does not do
but they are kind of very related. So on
the other hand, so what is the better
way to do to to to code you know to
design the print f you should have a
separate function uh function to for
string template which in many of today's
programming language they have that for
example Python
Python's fing is a string template okay
you can use it without the percent code
you know whatever it's it's simply a
string template system okay that's
available in Python in in PowerShell in
um you know as a separate thing like not
exactly tied to printf okay so you
should have a string template then you
should have a convert number to string
function by itself then you should have
a convert number to hexadimal or binary
by itself then you should have a format
format number uh function by itself okay
that's that is how it should
So and here is you know example in
different uh programming languages and
and also another thing interesting to
note is JavaScript. So JavaScript for
example they have a template string
which is created like 10 years ago. So
in this template string it's a string
template system but nothing to do with
uh print f you know percent sign formats
you know stuff and nothing to do with
converting a number to decimal to to a
decimal number to hexadimal okay nothing
so it's a template string system by
itself which is great JavaScript
JavaScript hap so happened JavaScript is
kind of odd in that it is one of the
early language age from 1995 that did
not borrow anything of the C's print f.
Okay. So you can convert string to
number you know using this method.
nothing to do with the C print F percent
and you can uh convert decimal and
binary number to uh and convert
hexodimal and also convert to string a
ded a dedicated function convert to
string uh and uh and pass integer which
is the inverse of converting a hexadimal
back to a number. Okay, hexadimal or
binary back to a number which also
implies string to number. Okay. So, so
JavaScript. Okay. So, that is this
article. Okay. So, the hack of C print
format string. So, now let's go to the
next point. Uh so, so here's a question.
You know C was designed 40 years ago
actually. Act actually 50 years ago.
Okay. So, this actually I think it's 50.
It's from 1970. Okay. 1970 to today is
50 50 years ago. Okay. So uh
okay so C is designed 50 years ago why
blame C because obviously it's all
technology right but you know would are
you you know just blame C for the s you
know you you it's not fair
so my opinion so why do I blame C I
think C deserve the blame because you
see many many technology after decades
they become old then you can
You know the design is bad you know like
design is difficult you know but once
somebody designs something and you as a
look looking into that design you might
say oh you got this flow you got that
that flow but you are not the original
designer because it's easy to criticize
once something is designed but it's not
easy when you are actually designed okay
so you can always look back retro in
retrospect saying it's bad this way or
that way Okay. So I don't blame
bad design but however I blame C because
C creates a code. C and Unix they create
a code such that even today they instill
a notion to programmers that C is the
best design. Even today like today even
today you you you you can constantly see
that many of the C fanatics they will
say you know C is the best language you
know it's kind of a code because they
you also often associate it with like
the concept of C is a real man's
programming language because it's
cryptic because it's hard to it's very
hard therefore it's the best you also
see that because why because it's a kind
of a code C and Unix
you know so that's why I blame C you
know not because
the design is bad because C and Unix
they they they
are affiliated with this kind of the
code phenomen phenomenon okay so that's
why I think it you know they create
pervasive damage in programming
languages and the computing industry
like today I'm talking about the you
know the problem of C print f but if you
show this my talk show to other people a
lot we'll say no you are wrong you know
they they don't read the details they
don't you know they they don't know
anything they'll just say you are wrong
okay that's a problem of C okay so I I
think I explained that so what is the
proper fix uh which the proper fix is to
create
separate functions for each of the
things that print f
do Okay.
So now I kind of covered so that's
that's the most the things I want to
cover. Now now there are two other
things I want to talk about uh but I may
skip them one of them. So one of the
thing is the let's see one one of the
thing I might skip is the wam language
okay wam language design wam language uh
I don't have a link here which is
entirely different. So it doesn't you
know have the percent something uh not
based on print f. So but
that's a bit involved because both wof
language they have a you know like
typically in all these programming
languages when you convert to when you
want to let's say
um
control the display let's say the you
want to print a decimal number with two
decimal places
inevitably they always converted to
string because there's no no other way.
You must convert a number
with many dis you know a number to a
string first then you decide how many
decimal places after the period right it
became a string there's no other way but
wam language doesn't do that wam
language um actually have a form that
that
uh actually in order to explain that I
need to start to show you the code okay
so actually so wuam language separate
you know it doesn't convert a number to
string it. You can tell woof language to
show all strings in this expression with
three decimal places or you can show all
numbers in binary
binary uh notation. You can also tell
you tell it to show all numbers in
hexadimal notation but does not actually
convert the number to a string at all.
So let me let me quickly demonstrate
that. Okay, because that um um
wra language. Okay, so let's pop it out.
So let's say three uh let's say
hexadimal. Okay, so let's type the same
thing.
Decimal number 17 in hexa decimal is uh
is 17. Okay, so let's say x equals to
17. This is wam language. And how how do
you what do you do that? So what what
you do is um uh I don't remember. So um
so let's look up my wam documentation.
So the wufam tutorial, search for it,
you'll find it and you can download it
for free. Just search for kasaw wufam
language tutorial and it's on.info.
Okay, so http no s. Okay, then you go to
uh so recently I was working on it. So
you go you go to the string section. Uh
so you you go to wufam language for
programmers. Then there's uh
okay there's download there's basics
common string. So print uh and string
okay go to string then you go then you
go to the string template format. Okay
so this function string template is does
just one thing. It's a string template
system just like JavaScript.
It doesn't combine you know the
converting a number to hexadimal or
formatting string it doesn't command
okay just template so we need to use
string temp template okay so so let me
copy that and go to s talk show uh so
let me paste the link here
uh so so wam okay so now let's go to
precode
uh so let's go to yeah so this string
template. Okay. So that's what you want.
Yeah. So I remember. So you uh paste the
string there and 17 will be uh
grave grave accent. Okay. So two grave
accent. That's the argument. Okay. So
that's a template string. Then you pass
the argument x.
Okay. So
run that.
Okay, starting wam language. The first
time it's a bit slow.
There it is. Okay. So,
okay. So, it prints 17. That's the x.
So, let's suppress the output. So,
decimal number 17 and in x decimal is
17. Wait. Uh. Oh. Oh. Okay. So, wait.
So, this remember this is only string
template. It doesn't do the uh
conversion. So when you want to convert
you you do it here. Okay. So um so
decimal so this is you want to convert a
decimal to hexadimal. Okay. So how do
you do that? Uh so let's let's put this
here. Okay. Two string
uh two string and uh two string x and uh
and uh uh
uh I don't remember. So let's go down.
So convert to string. Convert binary
heximal.
Convert to binary hexodimal or base 64
integer string. Okay. That is what I
want. Uh
integer string. Okay. X. And so delete
that. So integer string X. And you want
it in hexadimal. So that's 16. Okay. So
delete that. Run the code.
Uh,
why is it so slow?
Invalid syntax. Okay, we got it wrong.
So, what is the integer string? Uh,
integer string base. Integer string
number base. So integer string number
base. So why is it wrong? Okay. So you
got uh
Oh yeah. So okay. So it needs to be I
think it needs to be one line.
Yes. It needs to be one line. Okay. So
hold on a second.
Uh let's put it one line. Run it.
There it is. Decimal number 17 in
hexadimal is 11. Okay, that's how you do
it. Now this is
this is uh this is an example but but
what I want to show is another example.
Let's start wan language. Uh so I was
talking about you can make it show all
numbers in binary form, binary notation
or hexodimal notation. How do you do
that?
In order to do that, you have to do it
in uh the wolf notebook. Okay, so let's
uh start it. Evaluate three to start the
kernel and magnify 150. Okay, so so but
this is one example syntax color showing
browser and go down. So here is a woofer
language example. And now I want to show
you how do you um turn all numbers to um
to show them in binary notation or
hexodimal. So let's so let's um
so let's do another example but for that
you cannot do it in
in the wuam script which is what I'm
using. So let's give us some examples.
So uh 1 517 okay three numbers now let's
say uh let's say 0157 okay so you want
to show it in binary form so base form
base form this expression
and in what base let's say two okay so
delete that okay so copy that
paste it show Right? You see
now this this part the first argument
can be any expression can be integral
can be a can be whatever long list can
be a matrix can be whatever okay so
here's you know but it shows them in
decimal um I mean in binary notation so
if you want hexadimal
all you do all you have to do is say 16
you see and let's say if you want you
know in base 36. Okay, you can actually
do it in base 36. Okay. Uh, shift enter.
You see H, you know, 17 in base 36 is H.
Okay. So, here's an example. Okay. So,
now let's um
Okay, let's make a copy of that so I can
um I mean, let's make a screenshot.
Okay. So,
so what the so wam language separates
the display of the number from the
number itself. It never changes actually
even you know if you have a variable it
doesn't change it. It doesn't turn it
into a string. So in order to have this
kind of feature you need a renderer. So
that's why you can do this in the wuam
notebook. You cannot do this here. So if
I do this here, it just return itself.
You know because this is a text based.
You see it just return itself. So if but
you can you can you can turn this to
string though. So let's see two string.
Okay. Two string then that. Okay. Let's
see what it does.
You see it it returns this thing. Okay.
So uh delete let's okay so it returns
that okay so
so you can see this is a asified
version of the two-dimensional display
with subscript if you want the actual
subscript and type setting you have to
have kind of a front end or like a
browser you know like you have source
code
let first of all let's put it back okay
let's put it back syntax show in
browser. So we are looking at the HTML
source code but when you render it it
shows differently so that's so the
browser is functioning as a kind of the
rendering engine. So similarly if you
want to do this kind of notation you
know type set you need um you need uh
the you know the renderer the the front
end the notebook. Okay. So if you really
want this kind of formatting
uh feature, you need a renderer. Okay.
So that that's a demo of wraim language.
Okay. I think that's it for today. But
one more thing the so I came up with a
new design of string.
So how many people are watching? So
let's go to YouTube.
Um that's it. Uh 10 more minutes and and
that's it for today. So let's go to
YouTube
six people. Okay, say hi. So one more
thing this is um I you know this is a
great work I believe I did uh that is a
programming language design a new
programming language string syntax
design and I decided to call it rock
screen uh rock string rock string. Okay.
So what why do you need a new string
syntax? Because in this syntax it fixed
several problems
of the string syntax in all other
programming languages in Python, in
JavaScript, in Goland. So what what are
the problem? What first of all no escape
sequence
escape sequence creates a major problem.
Okay, so uh why? Because let me show
you. Okay. So, let's search for um uh
truth pick. Okay. So, if you code long
enough, you you are probably familiar
with this toothpick syndrome. You know,
back slash slash especially when you
have regular expression. That's
extremely painful especially in EMAC. So
you you know you can see here you got
seven seven backslash and here you got
you know 10 backslash to escape escape
and here you got like 20 backs slash
this the longest record. So 17 here you
got the 17 backslash
incomprehensible especially when you
have regular expression. Okay that's
extremely painful.
What is the cause of this? Why do you
need back? You know what why what caused
this to happen? That's because escape.
So what is the hard the heart of the
problem? Let me copy the link. Okay. So
uh copy the link. So let me paste the
link here so you can see uh all the
things we talked about. Um
okay the heart of the problem is that is
that when you have a string you have
some kind of escape mechanism inside the
string. So the string is not literal. So
you know like if you want a new line you
say back slashn. If you want a tab you
want you say back slasht. So let's show
some example. Do I have an example? Yes.
So for example uh string escape sequence
in Python. So you got this little code
back slash little code for ask bell for
backspace for form feed for line feed
for carriage return for horizontal tab
and so on and for unic code. Why do you
need it? You kind of need it because
because for example line feed the new
line character is invisible. uh and and
some of the unical characters such as
you have a non-breaking space or
non-breaking new line or uh right to
left marker you know for languages such
as Arabic you have right to left
beginning right to left writing so you
have this invisible characters or tab
you want to present them but if you put
it literally in the string it's like
invisible you know so you can't see it
so that's so in those situations you
want you want to code them like give a
little code to represent them. So that's
why
that's a purpose. I mean that's that's
kind of that's why you need to have this
escape sequences.
But however this came from C. Okay.
However C is very bad design badly
designed. They they put these things
inside the string. So when you have a
string you it's not literal. You have
this but in other words you have to
decode them. So that is why you start to
have this backslash toothpick syndrome
issue. Okay.
Uh so that's so so whenever a string has
a backslash it has a special meaning. It
creates tremendous complexity especially
in regular expression. Okay.
So so this is very bad. You don't want
you don't want this back. You don't want
this uh escape sequence. This is in in
Python, in JavaScript, in basically in
all all languages. Okay, you don't want
this.
But however, you do want to to have the
solution to represent invisible
characters. Okay, so so that's why u
this new string design rock string
solved the problem. Okay, so let's go
back. So you uh so I have a new syntax
for this rock string. So no no no escape
se sequence
syntax designed so that you do not need
escape se sequence. Okay. But and has
ways to embed nonprintable characters or
any unic code such as new line tab, no
break space or right to left mark. Okay,
you can embed them and can embed
expressions. So you don't need typical
print f. In other words, it also
functions as a string template system.
Why? You know, first of all, why do you
need string template system? Well,
because you want to embed variables so
that a string you don't have you don't
you don't want all the variables at the
end you know you want to like embed them
so you can actually read them you know I
have x cats you know that x is a
variable you don't want I have something
cats and then argument argument argument
so that's unreadable so string tempe
system so this rock string syntax does
that and simple grammar uh only one
single syntax no use of different
delimiters or triple quote. So for
example in Python in different languages
they have like variety of uh string
syntax. For example, in Python, you have
a, you know, you have single double
quote, you have,
you know, the apostro apostrophe quote,
then you have triple double quote, then
you have triple apostro apostrophe
quote. Very complex. Then then you need
then then you need um
then you need then you have in Python
you have these prefixes U for unic code
F for format string R for raw string B
for bytes you know and similarly in
Pearl for example you have single quote
versus double quote in PowerShell you
have similar okay single quote versus uh
double quote so let's show PowerShell so
in PowerShell you have single quote
like that then you also have double
quote. Okay, but in in my syntax in this
rock string syntax you only have one.
Okay, so here here's how here's how it
works. Okay, so the basic string syntax
is just double quote. Okay, something
then you can have a like a prefix uh any
uh character okay uh up to 10 random
character. So this is a syntax for
string and that's it. That's the only
syntax you have. So so this random
prefix you can for example here's
another example of a string
uh here the random string must be the
same in the beginning and end. Okay. So
when two strings are separated by white
space they are joined. So string aa
string bbb is the same as a a bb. Okay.
Then what if you want to include a
quotation mark so what you do is just
you know very simple you start with ss
you know so that doesn't happen inside
the string so basically it's like
literal okay there's nothing special he
said quote something quote end quote
okay nothing there's no in other words
every string you create it's literal
okay there's nothing special you never
add something inside it there's nothing
special in in your string Okay, so this
is how you saw you know double quote
mark thing
and what if you want to embed some
variable so you have a function you know
character that's uh C you know stand for
character so the N is the character ID
so tab is C9 line feed is C10 and the
non-breaking space is C 160 okay that's
a unic code character ID for them so a
typical JavaScript a back slash and B
that would be like this. Okay, very
simple.
So CN can take multiple argument to
represent multiple characters that's
like extra addition. So that so you know
that's a minor detail. So we can design
C. Now if you find the C you know the
character ID incomprehensible because
it's a character ID you can also create
it such that C the argument can be a
string for example string new line or
string then breaking space or string tab
you know to represent new line or tab so
it's readable okay but so it's a minor
detail so what what if you want to embed
expression very simple so just like that
okay you know x= equals to four I have
xc cats two string join okay so this can
serve as a template string you don't
even have to have a special function
okay so that's my new string syntax so I
cannot implement it you know it would be
nice if I have an example I can run it
but that means I have to create a new
programming language so uh and right now
I I I don't know enough to do it you
So I cannot do it. So but that's my
idea. Uh I and I call this uh new syntax
rock string.
This is from my like 20 years of coding
and study about all these programming
language string problems. Okay. So
there's a article I wrote uh programming
language design string syntax uh written
back in 2010 uh when kind of popular
when to hack a news. So you know one of
the problem is the backslash toothpick
syndrome and another problem is that you
know for example you have regular
expression right so suppose you want to
find you have a python you know let's
say you code python you have 10
thousands of code 10 thousands of files
and you you want to find a particular
regular expression you used in your
python code and that becomes basically
impossible
Because when you want to quote a regular
expression backslash, you need to add
more backslash. So it be basically
becomes hell. So it becomes impossible
to find a regular expression in your
source code using regular expression.
That's another kind of effect with the
escape sequence sequence. That's the
result harmful consequence of the escape
sequence. Okay.
Another problem besides toothpick
syndrome is like when you want to pass a
string
to shell you know then the back backcape
becomes a hell. Okay. So so anyway so I
hope this uh uh you know the
uh rock string syntax solve all these
problems. Okay that's it for today.
Thank you guys for watching. So uh KBTXX
says what what are the random characters
on both sides of the strings supposed to
show that is just that's that is idea
borrowed from here do dark okay you
probably
young to know so here do dark began with
with pearl okay so do I have a pearl no
so let's uh let's add pearl tutorial so
you go to pearl my pearl tutorial or
search for it. You will find it per
tutorial on kasadi.info.
Uh go to string and uh go to here
string. So here do is a syntax beginning
with pearl that allows you to quote
arbitrary long text. Let's say 10
million words. You know you want to grab
you you you know you have literature of
he Shakespeare or programming language
or whatever. you know 10 billion
characters. You want to make it into a
string. So normally when you use double
quote or Python triple quote it may not
work because the string the text itself
may contain triple quotes. So it will
it up. So Pearl has this thing
called um he do. Okay. So that allows
you to quote arbitrarily long uh text.
What you do is you use two less than
equal sign then a sequence of random
characters. Okay, like this BB whatever
random sequence then at the end of the
string you have that occurrence of that
random sequence again. So this random
sequence of characters serves as a
delimiter. So when you have a random
sequence it's almost imp you know one
one in a gab billion you know
possibility you know for it to occur in
a string. So this is a robust way this
is a bulletproof way to ensure whatever
text you know this syntax can allow any
arbitrary text.
Okay, as far as we you know practicality
is concerned you know unless you have
like infinite you know text. So this
this began with pearl like about 30
years ago in 1990. Okay.
So then it came also it came to uh PHP
because PHP is kind of a derivative from
pearl uh and the syntax uh varies
slightly. So let me post link here.
Okay. So um toothpick syndrome
and u pearl let's say PHP and so PHP
tutorial my P my PHP tutorial is not
very good okay but anyway so you can see
the PHP version of here do they differ
slightly from pearl okay so let's um
copy the link here and that's it for
today so and then we have uh powershell
Okay, so PowerShell also kind of
borrowed the here doc. Okay, they call
it here string. Okay, so PowerShell
instead of using random sequence of
characters, they use the add sign in
front but with the caveat that this this
delimiter must happen in a new line at
the end. Okay, so this is a PowerShell.
They kind of borrowed from the here dot
concept but does not involve random
sequence of characters. So can this
actually work? So in in the PowerShell
uh way the PowerShell syntax syntax the
problem is that let's let's post the
link here. Okay. So, okay. So, the
PowerShell issue is that you must be
sure that your text must not contain
apostrophe at as a line by itself. Okay,
that's the only thing you must watch
out. So, the text cannot contain
apostrophe at
that is a problem when that's a problem
when you embed PowerShell source code as
text. Okay, so powershell actually do
have a problem. This this back slashes
escape problem often occurs when you are
embedding the language by itself.
So for example, you want to pass regular
expression by a regular expression like
you want to search for a regular
expression by a regular expression. It's
a problem. uh backlash when you you know
the escape syndrome when you want to
escape another escape that's why you got
the toothpick syndrome so similarly when
you when your powershell code is
actually processing powershell source
code then this becomes a problem because
this text body
you know we are likely very likely to
contain a you know apostrophe at okay so
but as long as you don't you
you know you know you know you you are
the text is not powershell s code source
code this is not likely to happen okay
so that's a powershell solution they
don't they don't allow the arbitrary um
random sequence of characters okay
so that's it so so my uh my rock string
design
you are required to have arbitrary
strings you know as delimiters and it
must match at the
And they do not need to be aligned by
themselves. Okay. So, okay. So, that's
it.
Bye guys. Bye guys. Thank you for
watching. So, if you like my stuff,
okay, support me. Okay. Um, you know, go
to my website.info.
http no s. Okay. Uh, and go down. You
can see my PayPal link, PayPal, Patreon,
me, Amazon gift card, me, PayPal coffee,
$10, $10, $20, buy me a dinner, dinner,
if you work at a job, you know, pay me
$100, you know. Thank you guys. So,
that's it. We We shut down in one
minute. So, it's been uh 70 minutes
talk. Okay. Fantastic.
Bye, guys.
uh spread my videos, okay? Share it on
Twitter or your blog or tell your friend
to watch it, okay? Because Google, you
know, they don't they don't, you know,
they don't promote live stream. uh and
also because
you know I don't talk in a way like
pleasing you know like for the mass
audience like when you when when you
search for Google Python tutorial
uh you you know like YouTube you know
you you search for Python tutorial then
all you see is this like meme
you know for example
you know you got Python in two hours you
know like smiley face you know friendly
you know and this what the whatever
generation genius why does it show up
here I'm searching for Python tutorial
but people but that's the way marketing
you know that's way you know smiley talk
hi everyone uh this my you know my name
is Kali today I'm going to introduce you
Python you can learn it in one hour uh I
have been programming professional for
30 years and uh if you like this please
support me sponsor you know you you and
then you have to do promotion then some
of the promotion are nasty because they
are paid uh and uh you know so you you
see these kind of things and often most
most of the time they are not good
tutorials they are and you see you know
then you got Python in 100 seconds this
is popular two 2.99 million views you
know you got you you got post you know
put a
Guo vonome, you know, and then you got
post, you got to have this, you know,
thumbnail of hacking, you know, 0 one
01. That's crap.
I don't I don't do this. Okay. So, so
consequently, you know, my video is not
very popular. Okay. Thank you. Bye guys.