I know guys so I think I'm starting
streaming but I'm not sure I'm using the
OBS software to stream YouTube so this
is my first time streaming yesterday I
tried to a stream using YouTube but on
YouTube I can only stream I cannot
stream oh looks like it's streaming
actually so on YouTube I cannot do great
okay now can I see people's chat like
Chad okay Chad should be here new hold
for ensuring appropriate message yeah no
no okay
don't put anything inappropriate
okay don't type random so I hope to
see chat here yeah so guys join me and
join me and okay I'm actually stream he
that's great what is this
what okay that's a max wait
so I'm planning to do a few things to do
download the test streaming test
streaming video oh yeah I did a video I
need to download that so let's do that
here now or not I don't know
one guy watching hey some say something
so in this so this is what I'm not
decided so this is my streaming i'm
testing streaming and but also I plan to
do a few things I have a few things on
my mind so I want to do for example
download so this is about Emax download
do mod line so do my do mark line now
supports self like keys
that's my self like he's so that's great
so I'm gonna maybe do that in real time
and also to do a video on writing a
Emacs command to remove recent recent
history so I'm gonna do that yeah so I'm
gonna do that either streaming live or I
make a video recording so but right now
actually right now I'm testing streaming
so when people watching hey say
something are you following me
for Emacs oh are you random Joe you know
one thing I'm not sure he said on when I
start streaming who goes you know who
comes into the Chan channel to watch I
mean he said my followers so is it just
somehow YouTube alerts you know to the
public and any random people can join so
okay in order to do this I guess you
know I have to actually start to tell
people I'm streaming so on Twitter and
Master Dan
treats so that's my master then and this
is my tweeter and this also Ocoee max
pretty so let's do that so actually so
my plan is actually I wait for a few
people to come up then I'm going to do a
live some kind of live demo of doing
Emacs stuff then you know that will be
fun so you know people can ask me
questions so they can say no don't do
that
you know I want to see this instead I
mean you get interactions so you know
that's that that tends to be more fun
fun fun for me and fun for you so here
I'm going to go to Twitter so I have
like three three Twitter account three
or four three I think so I have Emacs so
this is oh password
password
I hope that's good I hope that's good
that's what is the you know it's so this
this is a software I'm using let's see
how many people watching one people okay
one key was so this is a software I'm
using this is OBS OBS you can see the
name so OBS is a open podcasting
software and you know it's for streaming
and it's also for recording videos you
can stream and record videos and it's so
someone told me about this software it's
great it's available for Mac Windows and
Linux so I'm using it on a Mac and it's
actually pretty easy to use you have to
go through a tutorial though because I
mean if this is your first time using
the software if it's your first time
using streaming and you get you might
get confused but it's actually quite
simple you choose what sauce you want
yeah you know just go to youtube and do
a OBS search for OBS tutorial and you're
you're you're know I mean you know I'm
not going to do a tutorial about
hobbies' because that's not my thing so
and this streaming this is also going to
be recorded and so yeah so it's gonna be
permanent on YouTube of course unless I
delete it so let's just get started
actually let me ask a few people to you
know Emacs people to join so then let me
tell people doing a live stream now come
join me
and walking out great so
so thinking of doing a live stream now
come to show you me not Joey joining me
talk about Emacs this is my it was
streaming using OBS software and since
our ingreso conserve some chat
okay so let's push that let's see how
many people watching one person now is
that are you are you let me guess who
are you are you the mail guy so it looks
like there's a lag let's see how long
does it do delay okay it seems to be
delaying for like five or ten seconds
that's that's quite long actually
so notifications with a book so yeah I'm
named just post not such stupid
okay let's first it and post it here now
and also go to master done and post it
there like I'm doing massive spam
manually you know I have a tech missus
my technique my system massive span yet
manually yet efficient okay let's turn
Mikey dog so Kira let's go to yeah you
know now I've done this so many times
it's like muscle memory helper fog open
that file Evo Evo Evo and you CD you see
my Emacs command log
what does I mean that means every every
command I call in Emacs including moving
who's you your show including typing
like some typing here you can see on the
other window your show you know selected
DVD you see select line ends on TV back
watch ah you know all these I'm using
soft like keys which is the most
efficient key binding possible for Emacs
and actually I found out the other day
yesterday I found out last week someone
copied it to the J to the what's the
company name is a big editor company and
they make great products wait how can I
possibly forgot Python so they make
editors they make specialized editors
for intelligent Ellijay okay that's one
of the
that's one of their editor I think but
basically yeah IntelliJ IDEA that's the
company name so they make a lot editor's
so someone made a clone of stuff like
he's for IntelliJ editors you know like
they make several editors and from what
I heard it's pretty good quality I mean
it's one year you know how do you well
it's hard to judge editor quality today
well I well not not this not not
necessarily that it's just that I don't
know you know I haven't explored but
there are so many editors now like
there's c4
for example intelligent ed EJ idea they
make several editors let's let's see
Tours cookies and IP address yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah shut up you know I you
know whenever I see these kind of things
I want to I don't want to say ok or not
I don't I don't I don't want to give you
any any information so what I do is I
selected inspect ok inspect DVD DVD DVD
DVD wait I cannot that'd be deleted ok
select that TV okay now it's good so
they make several editors you know
pycharm yeah the one full Python you
know specialized for Python is called
pycharm and let's check let's check my
vide YouTube well I'm talking I'm
checking like say hi you know whoever is
watching you know I got we got two
people watching come on say hi so we got
intelligence IntelliJ editors pycharm is
for Python resharper is for what a
visual studio ok extension for darnay
developers
phpstorm inside that's for PHP web stone
is for Java
you know when web dev so they make
several editors but I believe this okay
you'll be mine they specialize in
diversify you know this they have one
for goal and now goal and and you know
they make one is instead of one editor
they they cut it apart and they
specialize but actually I believe
there's one that's like everything maybe
that's this one yeah no I think yeah I
don't know for sure well I know for sure
before they had one editor that's you
know combined you can you can code in
any language but now they diversified so
the I mean these days there's also Adam
because Adam from github
Adam editor and there's vs code which is
using the same technology Adam is using
that space song it's basically it's
written in JavaScript it's based on
Chrome you know based you know these
days the JavaScript landscape has
advanced to such a degree that have
advanced to such a degree that you know
one problem with this setup is that I
cannot see myself I wanna I wanna see
myself so there it is my so okay I have
auto click now turn it off now shrink it
put it on outside no that's good now
turn back auto click okay so so they
have yeah so JavaScript have developed
to such degree the JavaScript landscape
develop to such a degree that they you
know it's like you write Windows app or
Mac app or no more app you know desktop
have you know using javascript and they
have a engine you know underlying system
what's the name Adam I I don't
remember what's the name so Adam editor
let's look
so Adam editor let's see Adam I oh that
is it
you know these days you know these guys
you know hackers they like to use this
hacked URL like dot IO it's so cool
thought I oh you know him well in fact I
always some some it's some country you
know it's hack you know I don't like
hacks of any type I don't like this this
is incorrect this is like incorrectness
Adam to dot dot dot hi all my ass so so
you could have like Adam dot editor Adam
calm or Adam dog you know dot net.com
dog is the classic so by the way the
first website the first you are however
the first website do you know which one
it is you would be interested if you are
using Emacs it is I have to remember the
name the first website it's the Saudi
keyboard
he will God you know say something okay
to here watching so sorry keyboard so so
keep physique he bought keyboard history
sale keyboard this is a granddaddy of
all keyboards kind of well at least it's
a granddaddy you know on the keyboard
you have control key code key
you have meta key you have this command
key you know weird weird
where did they came from they came from
this keyboard or all of them
you know except shift shift is there
from typewriters
what about control key control key came
from now did control key came from this
one oh is it before this one I don't
remember so let's look at big you see
meta here and this is control meta shift
okay I don't remember if control key
came from this keyboard or it was there
before it must be there before data
point 1969 yeah I don't remember if
control key but but anyway the command
key the old key the Windows key they
kind of all evolved they well they this
is the first keyboard that introduced
this these funky modifiers so I was
saying so what what is the first URL
website I'm going to tell you that is
actually that came from the list
keyboard one of the list machine company
symbolics
yes symbolics calm that's that is the
very first URL website is a symbolic or
symbolic symbolics
I think with s so let's try
yeah yeah the words first and oldest
register.com domain name on the Internet
but now I think it's Internet Museum you
know the domain name you got sold out
you know companies come and go oh 2007
copyright by Symbolics calm so it they
still on the site I suppose I mean if
you trust what is they see you so I
suppose they still own the site it just
said this you know the the Symbolics the
business has long been good I think the
company is still there but they you know
they
so anyway Symbolics cymatics is a
company that makes least Lisp machines
that's back in 1970s late 1970s and they
you know there's they created small
symbolic keyboards and from which we
have Emacs meta key and all that okay so
let's you know we're not talking about
keyboard let's go back to Adam editor so
Adam editor is using you know they are
using automated teletype you know what
what the is teletype I never know what
exactly is still type I'm like I'm you
know I am I'm like out of touch so
anyway so let's go through Wikipedia
Wikipedia is the source of everything in
story Adam Adam text editors so here
you'll be easy to find chronium okay
you'll be easy to find what engine they
are using so good control yeah and the
reason Adam is based on electron that is
the word so electron is a software that
basically it's well essentially you know
I haven't studied it but essentially
it's like Google Chrome browser it's a
Google Chrome
browser you know including the entire
JavaScript engine so Google Chrome
browser but but with code so that you
trick the interface you remove the no
more tabs you remove the URL field so it
basically becomes a framework for GUI
that's basically essentially what you
know what is going on so and you use
JavaScript to and to control it and CSS
so your Ektron so let's see yeah Krong
formerly known as atom shell so so
anyway so atoms electrons so and
Microsoft also created editor code I
believe it's called vs code okay visual
studio code which is a derivative a kind
of derivative from visual studio the
editor the IDE you know but however
Visual Studio code is you know using the
new you know the JavaScript fad 3 people
watching hey info info Matic where you
from so okay so today I'm going to you
know I was rambling about editors you
know there's so many editors here
patents and JB
oh yeah Iowa I was saying you know
someone created takes off like he's a
chrome for for the you know for the
jetbrains editor I'm flattered you know
I wish I can get money out of it but
well it's open source you know stuff
like ease is let's go through my website
stuff like his web site so stuff like
he's is a key binding mod minor mod 4
Emacs
so with stuff like he's it's very
efficient efficient you don't have to
press meta
and you don't have to press ctrl X and
you know so I have a page here you can
see and it also has a video tutorial you
know it's just such focus off like keys
and so anyway so they're there so
Morocco Wow amazing
well I know so I know where is Morocco
but I didn't expect so how do you think
may I ask you how did you find how did
you find out about this livestream is it
because you were following me on on
YouTube or is because YouTube just
popped up something about a new stream
so let me know I think there's a
10-second delay in streaming so anyway
I'm today I was going to you know I'm
doing a test but do you guys so yeah
whoever is watching let me ask you guys
what do you like to see and do you like
to see so I can do an install of doom
mod flying you know just just for fun
you know there's no big deal about
installing stuff I mean I'm sure
everyone knows so but you know just for
fun I can do that or I can do a video of
coding Emacs Lisp a simple function to
remove the history of recent recent up
so actually yeah so um you know if you
guys let me know yeah because I'm you
know whenever you know I'm not familiar
with video so whenever I do a video I'm
worried about how long should it be you
know you know usually typically you know
you people supposedly you know ten
minutes is good ten minutes 15 minutes
if it's too long people don't want watch
it but but what is the purpose I mean
what is your goal you know basically
people score we're making a video is
that they want to maximize viewers you
know so they want to so with that goal
in mind you know how many minutes should
a video last you know so I always wonder
about that you know usually it's like 15
minutes but you know but for some people
you know it depends on people's video
and what type of video and style you
know some people have longer videos like
an hour so anyway so I so it looks like
so this so I'm doing a test streaming
for the first time using this software
OBS it's a great software by the way and
so looks like it's it's successful you
know it's working so I don't know what
to do now you know from I can you know I
can stop now oh I can you know there's
five people watching I can you know so
let me you know let me let me know what
you guys like to do so we can continue
you know for a while following since the
last year migrating from them to Emacs
oh that's great thank you for you know
thank you for for following me and yeah
you know I never know you know I have
you know people you know people from
Morocco yeah so I mean we are in a Emacs
community tell great
okay so do you want to do you have
anything you like me to show I can you
know I'm I'm an easygoing person okay
you know so if you do you have any
questions so you can you know let me
know like Oh something writing you know
some question about Emacs so you want to
watch me doing something I can do it
so let me yeah so I you know I'm
watching so let me just actually I want
to do what I want to do myself is to you
know yeah let me know what you want to
see but meanwhile I'm going to I'm just
going to install the doom mod the doom
our line so what's my line my line is
the line at the bottom you know I'm
using a default marlyne it which looks
you know kind of ugly so let's try the
doom our line so I'm going to hear these
packages MMX lists packages search for
doom there it is okay enter switch panel
tap install install it
yes all right
it's installed now okay it's installed
now close window
azita I mean story I'm installing it
because you know it's supporting stuff
like this now so yeah so okay let's turn
it on then MX dome mod lie
oh there it is interesting okay this is
great let's see it's so hold on a second
let me show ya show that screen so what
what is is it's got a Chinese character
but first of all let's see yeah
you see Wow okay so it's supports stuff
like this you see the first character
there it's C C means I mean command mod
so I for example I press key you and oh
you you you you you you you oh and what
they do is move backward word Oh forward
word you see but now if so that's why it
shows see here you know that you see the
green C in the beginning now if I switch
to I press I press the key and switch to
command insert mod it shows I okay I'm a
little bit disappointed about this
because that's no different from what I
had before
you know without doing my line my mod
also shows that you know I and you I
mean I and C so you know it's not really
pretty it's just it adds the angle
brackets for example let's turn it off
let's see tomorrow yeah you see you see
that see you see means command line okay
so you see hold on
say okay save instead not commandant
incident command mod u CC and I switches
between C and I so let's back to dome on
fly so dome on line what does it
okay it shows you the path and it
doesn't do much it added the github you
know thing you know I'm on branch master
that's kids so it added that now this is
the HTML mod this is size tml mod funny
feed it doesn't do much like okay yeah
okay I'm somewhat disappointed line
numbers at the site no it's not from a
minor mod that that is from the command
well yeah it is a minor mod it's but
it's building from Emacs that's from
this command let me show you you see
that command global display line numbers
mod you see I can turn it on I can turn
it off you can see from this panel you
can see the you see that's the command
global display line number mod turn it
on turn it off and remember this one is
different from there was an old one
called
display Linum mod that's no good okay
anyway so global display by line number
smart that's from Emacs I believe is
from Emacs 26 you know possibly 25 but
it's new it's it's written in C so you
want to use that
Dian Dian big picture I'm sorry did I
pronounce your name wrong
the young OD young oh yeah so that's
great yeah gobo display I was so happy
to have that because before no not Linda
Martino Lena Maude is the old one
Lena Maude is written in Lisp in Emacs
Lisp and it was the you know the old
implementation and it has a lot problems
for example if you open a file with you
know say two thousand lines it's
extremely slow yeah like it was Emacs we
are stuck for like you know ten seconds
something like that so Lena mod is bad
you know it's deprecated you want to use
the the new one the global this rail
line number mod thanks so any anything
else let's see I'm going to do okay I'm
going to so I did the streaming test
yesterday so I want to download that
video so let's try it so this is the
YouTube I'm going to show you okay I'm
going to tired let's let's show the so
this is my tired directory let's go
through so I'm going to create a
directory named it AI hinter and go into
a directory split the split window go
into e shell and the YouTube download
abbreviation now this is a command
YouTube
- DL you can download it from the web
it's open source and this command will
download any YouTube video so basically
you just well yeah then you can just
give a
YouTube URL here or just 11 digit ID so
I'm gonna do that so that will download
the video I did yesterday I don't have a
copy on my machine because I was
streaming it yeah so it's downloading
yeah so this YouTube download II yeah is
a great command I recommend it
you know you can let's see let's search
for YouTube
- DL YouTube - DL yeah so there's a
Wikipedia page you can read about oh you
can just go to the home webpage so it's
open source and you know you can
download any YouTube video you know how
they remove that Wikipedia page for some
reason but anyway so you know don'ts
don't steal other people's video you
know just just don't do that but but how
many other occasions you know some
videos they are you know you need a copy
because and they and you know for many
reasons you need a copy so you can do
that so electron you know I was planning
to look into electron because I was you
know code in JavaScript but you know
it's a big project let's see what else
so okay so looks like you know so again
you have if you have a questions you
want to see me do something just say it
download entire playlists yeah that
that's great so let's see what else to
do so I'm going to go back to my Emacs
blood blog to do installed doom I
already did that to do video on writing
Emacs command so okay I'm going to write
an e max command about recent of you
know if you don't want know what is
recent you know it's funny name recent F
you know it it basically shows your
recently opened fire
so for example you know I I'm not sure I
want to call the command because it's
going to show my history you know like
the history of files I opened and some
of them you know is not very good for
public so let me do this
[Music]
it's okay let's describe variables wait
describe web variables recent
okay so that's the
describe function okay so yeah that's
you know so so this this is a variable
let me show you so copy cut new new
buffer so that is a variable and the
value of that variable is the least so
what I want to do is just to Emax mod
sorry max mod so what I want to do is
set Q set it to Neil so that will clean
up my recent of this list so let me
evaluate that and that's done and so let
me show you my so let's save it okay
save a random name close reopen there it
is so you see I call the command I call
the command recent of open files and it
will list all the files I opened
recently and in our case is just one
file because I just I just cleared the
history so you know you clear his you
could you clear the history by running
this eMac this code you know it just set
the list to Neil
so I'm going to write a function so that
it's you know I'm gonna call it you know
frequently it's convenient so let's put
here so let's called a command South
Korea
recent of history okay so that's a
command I want
that's it so that's the command I want
evaluate it okay cut daveed the file say
go to my Emacs directory let's go to a
brief my my Emacs in it directory then
open because I am axe miscellaneous so
this file is my miscellaneous commands
so let's put it here paste and there it
is so next time I start a max you load
the command but now I already have the
command
so let's you know let's do the recent of
now you can you see I call I call recent
of open files and it shows three files
because that's the three files i just
opened recently so you know sometimes
some way and why i want to do a video
you know review something on video and i
want to show people how to use recent of
but I don't want you know it I don't
want all these files show because
sometimes you have secret files you know
you you know private files you don't
want people to see so that's why that's
why we write this you know command so we
can just call it you know MMX sorry a
recent of history you know do that then
when you call open recent to open files
you'll say there's no reason for us to
open you know it's just cleared you
basically start over so that's great so
that's that close that ok so I think
that's it that's it I'm gonna you know I
think I'm going to close unless you guys
have other questions ok so I use the
Emacs so in is
hah start learning okay
quite a few started learning rust but I
see you going the Golan route can we
hear your opinion on rust
oh yeah dressed I don't like rust myself
okay why the reason is is because rust
is a low level language because you have
to manage memory I don't like you know
the idea of you know dealing with you
know I want to increase a microsecond
you know I want to make it
what microsecond faster so I want to I
want total control of the memory you
know we're going you know I'm not that
type you know I prefer high-level
functional you know mathematical you
know kind of approach you know like
proof proof systems you know that
automation you know compiler you know
smart compilers good language that that
so you can comply you can compile
automatically by mathematical theories
you know to the optimal you know
possible so I don't like I don't like
the worst memory you know I don't like
the idea of low-level languages however
you know of course this you know good
use is you know real-time systems you
need that I don't think mathematical
theories can you know can actually do
the optimal you know because there are
so many situations so anyway so that's
that's the reason that's the reason I
don't we rust is not my thing you know I
know a lot of people like it
you know you know so so that's why so is
why I went with coline and go like : is
like so simple I mean it's really simple
and you know it's like a mono language I
mean in fact if you compare : - Ruby -
Python to Java - closure - - even eMac
this all too common lisp or too
you know to all these languages : is
actually simpler I mean in in the sense
it's easier to learn it's got less
things yet it's very strict and robust
and and used massively in industry
because you know it's from Google so
that's why I like you know it turns out
I actually like Golan a lot and so
that's my take you know last verse this
is good
john john carmack
cedrus is cool and i can't think of
anyone else opinion on sea to sea
derivate languages who is probably more
trustworthy yeah if you I think you know
at a low level languages C or C++ or if
you count Java I mean if you want really
real time you know in full control I
think rust is is is the right choice I
mean easier an alternative to rust I'm
not sure there is I mean of course
there's Scotland but colon has automatic
memory management management by that
itself many people just don't want it
people wants to you know game
programmers for example I never had any
experience kimper but game programmers
like you know John Carmack you know he
his probably they want that so is there
a way to make Emacs store a session well
depends on what do you mean by your
session okay so if you want to record
all the other open files all the files
you have opened right now like again do
you know I puffer
I prefer that's all the files I have
open and if I quit Emacs let's say I
quit
let's be sure I don't want to create
because he is still downloading my video
because I create it's gonna cut that out
you know because I didn't start with a
you know
the emphasis and so anyway I don't want
to quit
so yeah depending on what do you mean by
session you can oh
by default almost it records all your
open open files oh and your cruiser
positions you can you for each file
you'll remember the cursor position and
you can also remember the search text
like for example Emacs hi such it's such
github you know next next you know so
yeah remember your search history and so
many of these are turned on by default
but some are not you have to turn it on
yourself so if you mean what do you mean
by session if that's what you mean you
can yeah let me show you where so this
is not this is my Emacs tutorial so you
need set up so maybe you have already
seen this you know so maybe you know but
okay so where is it so so there's one
called desktop mod you know the name is
silly it's just called desktop mod now
that mod wheel my numbers okay let's
just go here it's such for disk okay how
to restore open fire so so this is you
know desktop save mod is on by default
these days and there is also save cursor
position
East open fires default window sighs
yeah and Emacs will also remember your
default window sighs like right now I
have three windows or Emacs frame open
and if I quit Emacs and restart Emacs
will open the three frames again I think
that's also part of this desktop mod and
but you can also remember Crusoe
position
let me show just let's see okay so I'm
showing all the minor mods I have hung
so let's go back here
so okay so what is the command what is a
mod that remembers the kusa position
that's that's what I want to know right
now so this this is how to read let's do
that okay so
and saying a new high numbers
it's strange it's not here okay let's go
through my Emacs you need file he makes
a brief open settings so this this file
sorry max settings this is all the
settings that that does not need extra
package you know so all these are good
for default Emacs so let's search for
clues
okay wait blink
cruiser mod who's this
okay so the so Emacs will remember the
kusa position for each file but but what
what is the minor mod that does that how
is it part of desktop mod I don't
remember but I think I'm talking too
much like protracted that's no good
I said way too it makes session so yeah
you know including a bunch of related
files in the state of oh that's your
question including a bunch of related
files in the state of an interpreter I
use Emacs for Python related work with
shhh Jedi and being able to reload my
work session the next day as if never go
see max I don't think you can - you can
restore to that degree but but I don't
know much I haven't used you know Jedi
version so I think you have to ask the
people who does Jedi or the Pete the
Python guys who you know who use Emacs
for that but and but maybe there's a
package doing that but if you want to is
restore the state of an interpreter I
don't in general I would say no yeah
because it will will require some work
so to find the answer I think you have
to ask ask those those guys who wrote
the package Jedi related people because
to restore an interpreter state here we
hard because you have to it's not just
email is you have to like it's part of
it it's part of the Python I think you
have to do something with Python
do you work in some company a our job no
wow I'm a freelancer yeah so I'm
basically a freelancer because that's
not I'm suing you said you make yeah
well I don't I don't know if I should
talk about my sob stories you know I
don't so I don't work right now
basically I just live from I live from
Google ads and you know in donations you
know so but why don't I get a job you
know that's it's a good question you
know because I don't know my life is a
mess so if I you know I if I go to a job
interview you know they I don't I don't
communicate
I guess normally you know like right now
I talks very smooth I'm at ease with
myself but whenever you know if I talk
to strange strangers or interviewers I
don't communicate well I don't talk well
and well usually when you my if I go
interview you know they think they they
will think you know we got a high school
kid like who we just graduated who just
graduated high school and the kid thinks
he knows so much like but he cannot talk
anything substantial he cannot
demonstrate anything of substance yeah
then they start to ask me stupid
questions like likes of a person like
introductory programming like can you do
you know how to reverse the string you
know not like that but something you
know similar so you know so I haven't
really yeah that's a problem you know
it's a problem something I have to do
you know I don't know what the what's
the answer so
constructive proof with algorithmic into
interpretation oh yeah
so yeah I'm into that so right now my
goal you know like you know I'm kind of
getting old but not too old
you know I'm 50 years old so my iPhone I
see you know in next you know a few
years a few things I want to learn and
one of them is proof proof theories you
know that's involved a lot of things you
know proof theories it's you know it's
part of luck logic and homotopy type
theory you know yeah there's lots of
things I don't really understand them so
I hope to you know have some good
understanding about proof theories and
also they are also several proof systems
like coq Lydia let's look at proof
theory you know proof theory involves
like multiple branches branches of math
I mean proof theory itself is not
actually your term I mean there's well
you know so structure proof theory
reverse mathematics you know that's okay
automatic automated theorem proving yeah
so sequent calculi that's important
that's you know that's important and you
know the hurry Howard correspondence you
know that's the thing Haskell people
like to say a lot you know something
vamping Oh hurry coward conquers mothers
you know but I heard but I'm not so sure
you know the idea the the the the vision
is that with this theory
you know hurry Couric Howard
correspondence
basically means that every every
mathematical proof okay can be turned
into a computer program and vice versa
now don't don't quote me on that because
I'm not expert on these you know I but I
have interesting logic so that's so far
I think what it is every every math
proof have a computer have a can be
turned into a computer algorithm
something like that okay so I mean the
computer computer the algorithm
you know mathematic mathematics is is
like how to I mean math math is what is
you know it describes what something is
exactly but algorithm is how to you can
you know you know you use algorithm to
do things but but it's hard to describe
exactly what happens what what it is so
they say you know there's a contrast you
know it's a deep problem you know people
always wanted to kind of merge them I
want to understand them together like if
you can just change them one to the
other then things becomes much simpler
for example you know for example we
write programs right given any even a
short program it's extremely hard to
describe exactly what it does I mean in
a mathematical way anyway that
yeah that's not why you know it's I have
to you know it's hard to talk about you
know I have to I get into but meekness
constructive proof I've studied a little
bit of proof theory and found it through
early tractable and enjoyable painful
yeah that's great so I I'm I'm you know
I'm trying to get onto that road so once
you study and so I have to like study
these you know her curly Howard
correspondence
you know the thing about programming is
that some people you know I believe
there's a very well let's just show it
it's Rice University racket let's go to
it so I'm you know I so I'm just going
to talk randomly five people watching
okay I think we canal hints so anyway so
there's a great guy one of the greatest
computer scientists who is a language
researcher what's his name
so I'm trying to find his name you know
he wrote a little schema the little
whisper do you know you might have know
so I think his name is Matthew oh okay
the easiest way is actually go to Amazon
the little schemer
that's one of his book there it is oh
then yeah Daniel P Friedman and Matthew
fell instant fairy instant fill Anson
okay I cannot pronounce I cannot
pronounce people's names but anyway
these two guys are great
computer science scientists and they're
they specialize a lot on programming
languages programming language design so
and they they have written a lot books
so you can like for example you can look
at these guys
the little schemer the season schemer
the little Amy our realm of racket he's
pretty old now
I think he's 70 something you know how
to design programs but anyway so I never
this this book a little Java a few
patterns this one I actually tried to
read in around 2000 I don't like it at
all and I don't understand it and I
think I tried to read some of the others
I didn't I didn't like them because they
they they are returning a style of they
are retreating in a style of telling a
story but I like a writing style where
it's just pure math like definition
examples you know theorem and maybe
application you know definition in in
the most concise logical words or
formula possible I actually like that
style you know because I'm I'm I'm a
logical kind of oriented I like that
style I do not like books that talks in
English style of a story like you know
one day you know once a fast time anyway
so a lot book talks in a style of a
story and
times they tell you a joke and you know
and then you know I don't like that and
some of those books are very bad many of
them just indicate you know like when
you write a book first of all do you
actually know enough stuff to actually
write it do you actually understand it
so well that I mean first of all if you
understand a subject so well like let's
say a programming language let's say
scheme you know let's say Python okay
that's Python is more people know Python
so if you know Python so well then you
can then you you might you know choose a
style to express it to teach it you know
you can try the storytelling style
whereas everything is informal and you
can be chatty I mean we're talking about
writing a book okay about doing a video
is another thing it's but we're talking
about writing a book so it can be chatty
and you can be you know you can tell a
story or let me tell you a story or
there's a guy named function and what
this guy do is that he eats arguments
you know you know there's something that
you know it's a you nice tile maybe you
can you can be library elaborate but you
actually you understand Python so where
are the details of every function or
whatever you know objects in Python what
it does mean its relation to other
things in Python then you can you know
maybe you can put express it in your
style but storytelling maybe it's funny
or you know not necessarily in a sense
you know I was talking about you know
you know but anyway you can do that or
you can on the other hand on the for
example on the other extreme you can
write it so that it's it's symbolic
logic like there's no ink it's almost
like there's no English words it's like
it's just symbolic logic so what I'm
saying is that first of all you you the
quality of you write a book the most of
it actually depends on how much actually
really
then the other thing is is how well you
can express what you know into writing
okay that's the other thing then another
thing is that you know doesn't matter
what level you have you know how much
you understand the language or how how
how good is your ability to to write it
you know how good are you as a writer
so the other thing is the style you know
then you can you could you know try the
symbolic logic style you can try the you
know the talkative
you know storytelling style but you know
so there are there are these things you
know so so what I'm saying so so that's
one thing the other thing is that I
would say majority of books they are in
a story typed story kind of style
storytelling style informal and kind of
sloppy
why because because well part of the
reason is is that the symbolic logic
style is actually much harder because if
you want to write something like you
know a python tutorial you see in the
kind of the condensed you know little a
you know little irrelevant sentences
like there's almost no sentence that's
not irrelevant if you want to write in
that style
that means you actually have to know a
lot about Python really well like you if
it implies that to be able to write in a
cell you have to know a lot Python
meanwhile if you write the storytelling
style you know almost any bloggers can
do it you know anyone can do it you
could Python for a year you can start to
write oh you just you know do this for a
function and you do that and this output
you know it's easy so so there's our
Styles so so what I want to say the
other thing is that you see I like the
symbolic logic style and that really
gets very deep you know if you actually
really you know if you know Python very
well I mean suppose
you you want to write a book and you
want to read it our symbolic logic that
is a tremendous task and in fact that
task is the major research of that we
were talking about hurry
you know Curie Howard isomorphism you
know correspondence you know because you
are trying to turn something into logic
logic what they call it axiom or you
know fear foundation you know you are
trying to you know yeah so that's the
math you know that's that's what I like
about that's what I want to you know
that that involves is part of the proof
theory and the foundation of math and
all that so that's what what I'm
interested anyway I
oh yeah the HTTP I'm kind of older
generation the H deep the that book you
mentioned that let's go to Amazon yeah
how to design programs an introduction
that I'm kind of old too old for that
well I mean when that book came out I
remember a lot of programmers is saying
you know the book I remembered you know
when I was you know studying programming
you know like starting to study
programming is the you know sick you
know computer and interpretation of
programming the structure and
interpretation of let's see I actually I
just wrote a blog the wizard book the
structure and interpretation of computer
programs you know some some people made
this so that here's a Japanese version
and some people made these funny icons
so I read this book in 1998 I read so
there are five chapters I read the first
three chapters and I liked it I enjoyed
it very much but by the time this how to
design programs you know I heard from
you know functional programmers you know
people say oh you know read this you
know this is so great but I don't have
time to read it and by that by that time
you know I think he's around mm you know
mm something so but I did look into that
book you know many few years ago maybe
10 years ago I mean but you know like
once you pass you are you have to I you
know I don't I don't have much to say
about the book guy so I you know it's I
suppose it's a good book you know I need
to learn other things now you know I
need to learn
for example how to design programs an
introduction to programming and
computing on that topic you know if I
have time I want to learn the logic you
know the foundation you know like this
kind of things there's also you know the
sequent calculus the Hubert calculus the
and gödel's theorem you know go they are
second incompleteness theorem I want to
understand that you know you know
probability logic reverse math okay
formal proof yeah I like you know I want
to I want to form formal languages and
the formal proof that's the part I
really want to get into now what does
the formal proof means formal proof
means prove to prove something using a
formal language now what is a formal
language this topic I'm fascinated and
you know I I I know something well I'm
fascinated by this topic so what what is
the formal language is actually very
simple you know in programming languages
we have strings right you know just ABCD
or whatever strings so formal language
is to actually just strings it just
strings and you manipulate you you you
create rules - you know maybe replace
some string with others or change
position or whatever you manipulate the
strings that's basically that's what
formal language is and so what about it
you know what why do you want to you
know what's so great about it
what does it have anything to do with
proofs well so so the way the words okay
okay it's the way it has it's actually a
very significant that's this is like
formal language is the foundation of
many the deepest questions in computer
lying language that's one aspect of it
okay so but okay so but how does it work
I mean why for example
for example let's say the famous
programming problem the Haute ho teen
problem okay actually I'm not fit to
actually talk about that because I don't
but let me go on just you know
considered as a opinion you know the
voting problem so you want to know you
know given a program if it's possible to
tell if the program will stop or not
that's the famous holding problem and it
has been proven that it is impossible
basically it's a imparting you know it's
impossible to solve that problem
algorithmically
that is you cannot write a program it is
mathematically impossible to write a
program to tell if another given program
will stop when you know when you run it
it will like just stop it is impossible
you can prove it now there are I don't
know how they are it's proven but but
one of the ways that where the formal
language comes in so formal language is
like you just manipulate strings so
instead of when you you want to frame
the question into the screen string so
so the question becomes is it possible
given certain rules that replace string
you know string string replacement rules
such that beginning with this string you
end up with that string you know
basically that that's that's the essence
okay that's the essence I feel like so
pressured talking about this because
suddenly I'm like anyway yeah so that's
why I'm not very good at talking to you
know when you know any anyway so I think
I'm gonna stop so yeah yeah well I kind
of you know this video I kind of random
remember hey well so so after all this
is a live stream so any any questions I
mean
that's why we are here I mean I guess
I'm doing fine
okay so thanks for watching and so I'm
going I was testing so this livestream
I was test testing with this software
OBS it's a great software and it works
it seems to work so it's great thank you
guys for coming by and for the chat I'll
see you next time
oh you know so go to my beat YouTube you
know follow me and you know let me know
what you want to see so because I want
to do videos regularly because well
because I enjoy it you know I've I have
like opinions I want to talk about I
mean even just for myself like I feel
like you know I'm kind of like observer
kind of guy so I feel like I want to
make a recording of myself it's like a
log like captain's log you know start
date so even for myself I want to see it
so maybe a few years I can look back and
see oh that's you know oh you were you
are wrong to think that way you know
back then oh you know oh you can see you
know what have you learned you know so
so thanks guys
and you know yes subscribe and comment
and let me know what you like to see bye
okay so go back here stop streaming here