good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Santa's
show today's 2019 November December 2nd
oh it's December now Monday 4 o'clock
4:30 San Francisco time in the afternoon
and today's topic is matrix and matrix
multiplication with vectors explanation
of vectors I'm going to explain that to
you guys programmers and we are also
going to code them in JavaScript matrix
and vector functions so I'm going to
explain to you what matrix are how they
work things like that and good morning
zoom way out
good morning to Florida thanks for
coming by and good morning young bond
and bought and Nybo so shall we begin
I'm thinking maybe one hour today or
less you know I'm trying to shrink the
talk shows time so this is today so
let's begin then let's begin and if you
have any comments questions posted ok
posting a chat chat that would be great
be fantastic okay this is Orton
impromptu without preparation you know I
like that way I like it that way because
that way is more natural and also I get
to practice my oration skills so matrix
multiplication we got we got a beginning
we got a begin somewhere we got good
start to get into on track so are there
more preparations to do yes
let's pop out this thing and let's move
this window here and let's see you
Korean I don't understand
good morning Alan
safe and Rob this is the you know this
is safe and Rob you know this is
something like this is 20 years old you
are looking at 20 years old more than
that clothing why shrink you know
because I'm talking too long usually
rambling on and on for 90 minutes so
okay we need to begin matrix tutorials I
mean talking about matrix so let's begin
by lid okay so this of course sir
command start command log so on the left
window you can see all my Emacs commands
for you to grab it's on my website if
you find the command name you can search
it and these on my website so and we are
going to go to JavaScript
okay so let's we are going to code this
in JavaScript okay start a new window
let's see TS okay on a second
will be the truck Sartre yes
search for index yes open in browser and
go here these are my temporary kind of
temporary nodes in place okay so
JavaScript okay so I need to open my my
types typescript stuff the technology of
typescript fantastic technology of
typescript let's see where is it that
and go here and the typescript library
there it is okay
now I need to do this very useful lesson
from sorry thank you
good morning Dan Morris I forgot where
you from Eggman and Justin Jones and
justin hays Jones has given a lecture on
Haskell I saw it on Twitter so Justin is
a has Kokoda
just seen Justin post the link if you
can you know so people interesting has
cow can go there and and watch and okay
so let's get into the track of matrix
matrix multiplication and vectors
vectors and matrix the fantastic subject
of okay on our second there is something
I need to do matrix linear algebra this
is the rearm of linear algebra guys and
linear algebra and we are this is a
practical part of linear algebra you
know that the subject might the subject
matter is called linear algebra but
actually if you are a mathematician you
studied linear algebra it has it's
nothing to do with matrices okay the
math I mean if you are a mathematician
you study linear algebra is a branch of
algebra okay when you if you are a
mathematician you study linear algebra
it's nothing about programmers notion of
vectors oh oh graphics 3d graphics
idiots
the programmers okay vast majority of
the talking there are hacker news on you
know on how can your song already do
this Odie's for grammars idiots
that's so we if you are a mathematician
mathematician you studied linear algebra
it's nothing about vectors it's I mean
it's nothing about vector multiplication
of matrices or determines well that's
part of it you know but but it's they
are actually studying the abstract
structure of linear space okay that's
what linear algebra is
a certain abstract structure of linear
space okay but but computer graphics
matrices vectors they are kind of
practical aspect of linear algebra in
fact the most used aspect of linear
algebra you need that to do computer
graphics so example for example we did
talk show about rotating polyhedra you
know we rotate a platonic solids I I
could say he'd run and so on rotating a
cube and you you need to find the
coordinates when you rotate something in
space there are new coordinates for them
so you need to find it you find it by
using a matrix rotation matrix so code
basically it's just a function okay you
use that to compute new coordinates and
where does that matrix came from well
it's from linear algebra okay now first
of all so let me start to explain the
matrix okay what is the matrix a matrix
is a so a matrix is just a function okay
let's write it down and so we have a
proper index table of contents but
before we do that we need to so there's
so much to do so we need to go to saw
Emacs settings and we need to magnify
the font so all the people can see so
here is a code such for menlo on a mag
make it 15 okay and evaluate the code
now I got everything bigger so for those
of you say now who cannot see such as
myself now you can see okay now the
phone is better so so what what is the
matrix okay let's write it down matrix
is just a function okay again I'm doing
this for programmers okay basic
introduction if you forgot your high
school algebra or whatever college you
can now understand so properly among
programmers
when they say oh you need a matrix
something-something now you understand
you can tell them no that's not true
because this or that okay so matrix is
just a function you you know you know
what a function is you have input and
you have output so matrix is a function
it's a particular function and matrix is
a linear function is a linear function
okay now what does linear mean so it's
linear basically it's a way of function
satisfies certain properties we call it
linear so what is a linear function
okay let's explain that explain what is
the linear function okay let's do X
plane what is a linear function okay now
we don't need okay so what what is the
linear function oops what's going on
okay what is the linear function a
linear function is a function that
satisfies this property property t y
okay are all all properties okay okay
what is a linear function let's show in
browser this is today's talk show what
is a linear function so what so let's
actually let's move this here and put a
break and now showing browser now
actually that pig parts
video this is today's video we don't
want to that we don't want that okay
there it is so let's magnify one finger
operation you see efficiency matrix is
just a function remember that okay next
time you as a programmer now I'm
assuming you guys don't know this yet
right so you know I'm talking to these
kind of audience I mean if you are a
mathematician then this is the wrong guy
you are watching okay there are a lot
you know more focused you go there you
know you you study you know you go there
but here is just
talk show which will be useful
you know so so a matrix is just a
function remember it's just just a
function your function that takes some
input
you know argument Danny about outputs so
that's it now a matrix now but why is it
called matrix I will we'll get into it
that later okay so if it's just a
function y what do you call it matrix
okay so if matrix is just a function why
is it called matrix okay we'll get into
that now a matrix is just a function now
a matrix is a linear function now a
linear function is a function that
satisfies certain properties okay we are
going to explain now the next question
if a matrix is just a function why is it
called matrix because you know when you
see a matrix you guys have you guys seen
your matrix so the matrix let's go to
Wikipedia for answer Wikipedia is got
lots of anthers answers you know I go
there and I'm just going to read off
whoops don't want this this is the
matrix the matrix the programmers are
familiar with you know the the the
jargon matrix has become so many other
things you know so that's the matrix
movie repeal repeal guys rip you so here
you are seeing matrix you are seeing
matrices so basically it's a array of
numbers you know a grid of numbers row
and column of numbers that's what you
call a matrix so there are many ways you
know so anyway it's just a function okay
but the notation when you write it out
it looks like you know a grid you know
that that that is why that is the
etymology that is you know you as you
are looking at matrices here for example
here is a three by two matrix
that's a dimension you call that the
dimension of the matrix okay three by
two matrix now this is a matrix for
example this is one by three matrix or
you can call it a vector this one is
also a matrix this is 3 by 1 matrix or
you call it a vector okay you know I'm
not going to explain why anyway so here
is a square matrix 3 by 3 matrix so that
those are matrixes so why do you call
them matrices if they are just a
function well well because different
aspects of looking at things you know do
you call them matrix because they
because they looks like a matrix of
numbers so that you know that's easy to
recognize well anyway the the meaning of
a matrix is a linear function okay it's
a linear function now what is a linear
function a linear function is a function
that satisfies the following property ok
ok let's begin to talk about that so
what what property it and and also ok so
so a linear function is a function that
satisfies these properties and also when
a function is a linear function you know
when when any function that satisfy
these properties you couette the linear
function so it's also a theory that any
linear function can also be represented
by a matrix ok so that is why matrix is
kind of synonymous with linear function
ok now so what is a linear function now
linear function is a function such that
that's ready down so if we have a
function f ok then we say F X plus okay
FY y ok so this is very familiar to you
guys right FX plus FY now if the result
of that equals true if the result of
that equals to
that that's why I'm with the condition
you must satisfy okay that's one of the
condition if you want to call it linear
if you know whether it's a linear
function or not
so f FX plus FY equals to F then the
argument put together you know addition
so that's one of the condition the other
condition is let's see if I can write it
out so x times f x equals 2 equals true
okay so f times FX equals to s times X
okay you see that so that means if you
have a function FX applied to X you come
out a number then you multiply that by a
certain number s okay so my odd number
now this result is equal to always equal
to you just you just multiply the s and
the argument together first then you
apply the function okay so these two if
any function that's showing browser if
any function that satisfies these two
equations then that function is a linear
function
okay now let's check out check out check
up look up Wikipedia just in case in
case I'm wrong I don't remember so but
anyways but before we do that there's
one more thing why is it called linear
okay okay so so okay hold on a second so
a function if a function satisfies these
two equations then you say it's a it's
called linear function
now that's one thing okay that's math
now but being quiz Stickley now we have
venturing into the realm of languages
linguistics so but why what do you call
linear I mean what what what makes it
like
linear linear means are lying okay
linear English means a lie so why do you
call this such function when they
satisfy these two equations what do you
call it linear like a lie
well it's it is because when your
function is linear and if you look at
the function from a geometric point of
view what it does is that it basically
transform the point in a in a manner of
a line okay that that's kind of a I have
two shows maybe I have to show some
pictures so why is it collinear because
when a function is linear then from a
geometric point of view the function
transforms the space in a manner of a
line okay so so for example rotation
scale scale up or scale down such as
room okay so for example in browser we
zoom in we zoom in now we zoom out now
that's a linear function guys that's a
linear function you are looking at
zooming zoom out why is a linear
function because you look at the screen
as a plane like you know geometry XY
like a plane then you can see the other
you know text on on on the pages you
know points in the paint then when you
zoom in basically everything just scales
you know right right you scale up and
the function to have such a results such
as scaling up or scaling down that's
that is a linear function guys you know
it is it will satisfy these two
properties that's that is why so why is
it linear because because when you look
at such function from a geometric point
of view you know think of plane or 3d
space or or four dimensional space five
dimensional
in Salaam these functions their behavior
is kind of just like like a lie well how
do you explain like like well there's a
lot I can explain like scaling scaling
is an example zoom in zoom out also for
rotation use an example let's write it
down okay
so they transformed the space in a
manner of life such as scaling also
NOAA's zooming out okay
and the rotation and shear okay
that's three examples rotation shear and
flip okay now if you do photoshop or if
you do image manipulation you you are
probably familiar with it shall shall we
show example why not okay so let's go to
keyboard the fascinating keyboard page
and let's go to let's look at this
monstrosity okay this this monstrosity
so let's open that and here is the image
a big one now obey it copy it
hold on let me show the Emacs command
okay open it away and close that so we
have this image we make a backup go to
tired and we can see this is a backup
copy and we're gonna rename it for
simplicity let's just rename it X X okay
done
now go to the xx page okay it's too big
let's scare it down 50% okay yes sharpen
okay now we have the image okay now
we're gonna open this in we go to
Photoshop then we're gonna rotate
it and scare it all those are linear
functions okay so we are basically
operating in the two dimensional space
you know two dimensional plane
space so I mean why are we doing this
because we are trying to explain why is
it linear what do you mean linear okay
so for example you can see your line
here you see your line guys there lie
lie lie you know so a linear function
when you have a lie then you apply a
linear function to it for every point on
the line for example if you have a line
you know to begin with then you apply a
linear function the output line will
always become lines they don't change
you know it's not like after the
function the line becomes a circle or
something else that's another function
okay that's not linear function anymore
meaning that they don't they they will
not satisfy these two properties but
before we go on actually let's go check
check the definition just in case I got
it you know I mislead all the young
people we have a lot of comments thank
you guys for comment so I'm gonna get to
them okay so we let's look at linear
function okay linear function wikipedia
the savior of infom information so
linear function there it is linear
function so let's say what it says in
mathematics the term linear function
refers to two distinct but related
notions oh really
let's see in calculus in related areas a
linear function is a function whose
graph is a straight line
this is idiocy this well you know it
well you could say that is true but
that's not that's that's kind of okay it
says in calculus and related areas a
linear function is a function whose
graph is a straight line such as such as
x equals to two Y ok well y equals to 2
X y equals to you know some X yeah
that's a linear function you go at that
but that's not what mathematicians
really
work with I mean that's this kind of
introduction
you know the introduction to math to
students it's not that's not okay if you
are a math that's that's to base that's
that's just for children okay the linear
function we are talking about is this
one mathematician use okay so it says in
linear algebra mathematical analysis and
functional analysis analysis a linear
function is a linear map okay stupid
Wikipedia map just mean a function okay
so a linear function is a linear
function yeah so in this case and in
case of a possible ambiguity the named
affine function is often used to the
concept above okay so anyway a linear
function they didn't explain the
property yet and they say the notion of
linear function for calculus that's
called a funny function anyway that's
getting complicated anyway our linear
function is linear map okay let's go
there now in math the word map usually
just mean a function okay they are kind
of synonymous like if you take a
geometric point of view you call it map
instead of function but it's a same
thing okay so there here we are looking
at linear map here they will tell you
the definition which is the property we
talked about so it says in math a linear
map also called linear mapping linear
transformation or in some context linear
function is a mapping v2w between two
modules two complicated words between
two modules okay that preserves in the
sense defined below the operations of
addition and scalar multiplication okay
that's one way to say it now module you
know module is a is a specific algebraic
structure but anyway they are they are
kind of getting too complicated for us
so let's let me just go to jump to the
definitions okay there it is definition
first consequences okay so you know we
are reading Wikipedia and they are using
mathematicians language you know the
mathematicians talking a particular way
and I will be the guide for you to
decipher their jargons okay but
basically they are just saying what we
just covered before linear linear map or
linear function is a function that
satisfies these two equations okay now
let's read what they say let V and W be
vector spaces over the field K a
function f v 2w is said to be a linear
map if for any two vectors u V in V and
any scalar C in K the following two
conditions are satisfied ok f u plus V
equals to F u + FV okay and F C u equals
to C times f u ok that that's just what
we said here now if you don't know math
you know if you are a programmer if you
haven't studied abstract algebra or
analysis before you might be wondering
so so why is Wikipedia
you know why does such a simple thing
but why does mathematicians mission
field and then scalars and vectors and
spaces vector spaces well it's kind of
get complicated but anyway for us just
remember ok the let's see let's see fine
we if I we need to
yeah it did you know it's in they
they're chuggins to are required kind of
because over here the definition I give
here is a bit ambiguous because what are
x and y and what is s they are kind of
different
okay they well so so so so to explain
that well to explain that gets a bit
complex but anyway you so you and we
because you see our definitions here it
looks pretty good you know if you know
but the question is what is x and y and
what is s you see the S here is actually
not the same thing as x and y there
because in other words s is from a
different space you know it's starting
to get complicated but basically but
basically the x and y here are vectors
which basically means a bunch of numbers
ok as considered as one thing a vector a
vector is just a sequence of finite
finite sequence of numbers in our case
ok and the SS here is a number ok s here
is not a vector so that is important
actually so we need to add that so ok so
let's go back to before we do the before
we do this thing let's actually need we
need to modify our explanation I mean
our definition a little bit and let's
not get parked out so we need to say
where x and y are vectors and s is a
number ok let's just say number usually
you say scatter
it's but let's just say numbers now it's
also note vector is just a finite
sequence of numbers for example 3d
vector okay usually we write numbers
okay the number then another number then
another number
okay this number too big let's shrink
them a little bit let's say five okay so
let's say okay so show so we need to add
a little quad a little a little
clarification because what do you mean
by X Y and s because s remember again
remember s is not XY it's not it's not
the same thing so x and y they are
vectors a sequence of numbers and the S
here is not a vector okay so so we need
this qualification and that's not enough
neither because what does it mean X plus
y how do you add two vectors together
and what does it mean ex you know x I
mean s multiplied by X you know a number
x vector what does it mean you know for
numbers like one two three four we can
we understand what plus and
multiplication means you know five times
three is fifteen that's multiplication 5
plus 3 is 8
that's addition we understand but now we
are dealing with first four vectors we
have to kind of define it and we here we
are dealing with multiple create
multiplication of a number and a vector
so we actually also need to define it
that's why that is the reason when you
read this mathematicians definition they
started to mention you know vector
spaces and fields and scatter and
scatter see in K you know things like
that but now you kind of you understand
what it means okay basically just
specifies
you know vectors is a sequence of things
and how multiplication you know addition
between vectors are defined anyway we
get in too long here so that is a linear
function okay that is a linear function
and so in outer context you know let's
not get bogged down with you know the
complexities in our context any of the X
Y here they are just vectors you know
like a point is you know let's say a
plane XY plane okay so you got a point
in XY plane so that point is specified
by two numbers x and y right the x
coordinate and the y coordinate so those
are vectors okay very easy to understand
now if you are talking about
three-dimensional space then you have
another vector that's Z okay so a number
a point in space is specified by three
numbers X Y Z those are vectors okay and
scalar so so vector addition you just
add the components I hope you guys
already know that and scatter x vector
just means you you multiply the number
to each of the components okay I hope
you guys yeah you guys know that right
right
so him I'm starting to do monologue so I
need to check up am I still alive and
doing well
ten people watching and I'm still alive
oh my god it's all 34 minutes we don't
have time so anyway so let's meet maybe
I should read the comments so I want to
learn Mathematica where should I start I
am reading Wolfram language first
introduction to programmers that's a
great book
yaagh read that I have that book he sent
sent it to me face keeps example of
something that is not linear okay yeah
that's great question and why you know
it isn't yeah you
okay so hold on second let me
demonstrate I need to close my window
it's getting dark Johanna
so this book is a basic introduction to
the Wolfram language written by Stephen
Wolfram the guy the man okay you can see
he's got a photo of himself in the back
he sent me a copy this is new this is
this came out like three or four years
ago okay so if you want to learn
Mathematica yeah that book is a good
book I would recommend that book yes
read that one first you know go to
Amazon buy it I don't have a link
ready so okay what do I need to support
saw talk show okay so support you guys
PayPal me and stuff okay so Wolfram
language there it is so let's go to an
elementary introduction to two from
language this guy this guy is his
pompous he's known as a pompous guy so
he anyway so the tyro is a elementary
introduction it is actually true you
know this is this book you know because
Mathematica is huge this book is an
elementary introduction so let's grab
the link and what's going on
I need to get the link
why is the link not showing now we're
going to cover we're gonna get back to
matrix okay now that pretty soon now
let's see what are the other things here
Mathematica new book hands-on start
anyway so anyway so let's copy that
second edition oh it's already a second
edition no interesting so let's let's
get get Amazon dink there you go so okay
the photos of you in Amazon USA you go
buy it okay now now that sensor okay so
let's explain why is it collinear so we
explained the definition of linear we
explained what is a matrix you know it's
a linear function we explained why is it
called matrix because it looks like
matrix you know that's - the etymology
of english i suppose originally matrix
just means a grid
I don't I don't you know we have to
actually look up etymology of matrix
okay so actually let's do
okay etymology of matrix let's see what
they say so late 14th century matrix
matrices uterus swamp okay that is the
arrangement uterus swamp women things
and directly from latin matrix and
pregnant animal oh wow that's why the
movie matrix that is why the movies
named matrix oh wow i didn't know this
or engine of the word matrix okay so
that is that means uterus swamp matrix
okay the many configurative and
technical census are from the notion of
that which encloses or give or ancient
to something okay so birth basically so
the general sense of face or medium
where something is developed is recorded
by 1550s meaning mode in which something
is cast or shaped
oh okay then he says the mathematical
sense of a rectangular array of
quantities is because it is considered
as a set of components into which
quantities can be set mmm okay that's
that's very interesting though so this
is a great fruit of today's talk show we
learned the etymology of matrix so it
actually means the whomp so the math
sense of a matrix actually came from
that some kind of you know it creates
numbers or something Oh mattress okay
Spanish okay so okay that's that's
fantastic good great great thing to
learn I have learned today so okay so
matrix so now let's show some and and
the matrix is a linear function okay so
let's show some examples why is it been
you
okay so for that let's go to camp so
we have shown the zoom in zoom out
you know that's we already show that
that's show rotation okay now okay let
me show okay now remember I said before
you see this image to this face you see
lines here line line line those are
lines remember a linear function why is
it collinear because lines becomes minus
itself line ever become something else
nine remain lies that's linear by the
way affine transformation now we are
talking about matrices which is linear
transformation there is another function
called affine transformation or affine
geometry okay affine function is a kind
of a superset of linear function so in
affine transformation lie also becomes
lies but it's got something else by
anyway we've let's focus on linear
function here so you can see we can
rotate this thing now obviously when you
do a rotation you see lying remain lies
so that's why you know so these are kind
of a linear function that's why we
called linear but also besides this okay
hold on a second besides rotation
besides scaling zoom in zoom out there
is also another transformation called
shear
okay this one so I'm going to do it and
you can watch watch the picture okay
watch the picture what what happens
it's too slow too and I'm trying to
increase them in real time but it's kind
of - so Scioscia let's say 30 okay let's
try to do 30
are they computing let's say 300 okay
let's just do it well there you go
so can you see that it kind of just
shaped the thing you know but however
now remember lying remain lies you begin
with nicely it's osteo lines so these
are examples of linear transformation or
you call it a linear function okay now
let's show you something that is not
linear okay that's very easy okay so
what what is something that's not linear
so we're gonna show you you know when
you deal with from a geometric point of
view it's easy to see what is what is
linear and what is not it's very easy to
this to see okay for example I'm gonna
show you some pictures these pictures
you see now all of this they are
transformations meaning they begin with
a grid okay so for example this this
this this the top row and also this one
you can see this this and this but not
and also this one okay and also this one
okay anyway let's focus on the top two
rows you see this they begin with a
great rectangular grid then you apply a
function so you have a point you know
you apply function a point is x and y
you apply a function then you get two
new pair of numbers the point moves
somewhere so after you apply function
they transform the grid each so you can
now visually
visually see the result of the function
now you can see so in this for example
in this one you already speaking with a
line but now the line is not
no longer lying you see this one no
longer lying there you you know the line
becomes some wavy thing so any of these
are not linear functions okay so that's
easy to understand so in plain words you
could think of them as kind of some kind
of distortion but distortion is not a
good word because because she is also a
distortion but that's still linear you
know so anyway so that's some examples
of transformations
that's not linear and also here but if
you look at this one this is actually
linear you in this picture we begin with
a it's magnify okay we begin with a
circle I mean bunch of circles polar
grid then you see this thing this
slanted thing is the that slanted thing
is the result of applying a function to
the circle so it becomes you know a
belong thing and this is actually a
linear transformation because it's
actually just sheer you know it's just
sheer it's a linear transformation Y is
a linear remember line become lines so
originally you have this line blue line
and now it becomes this line you see
that way that is why it's linear in fact
all these lines in a circle you see we
in the in our internal picture we have
all the lines radiating you know the
radius of the circle they are still
lines they they still always remain
lines that's the point that's why that's
one of the property of linear function
okay now by the way there is another
very interesting thing about linear
function you see this line become these
lines actually those this vector is
called
this vector is called the
oh god I cannot remember names now does
anyone know like remind me does anyone
know tell us you know math okay don't
know why I thought the English world
would be different no meaning okay so
Wikipedia so actually we got I'm
starting to ramble a lot and not going
anywhere I think we haven't got to
talking about implementation JavaScript
yet and I'm losing people let's see how
long have I been talking 48 minutes yeah
we're talking we are starting to ramble
too much let's get back okay
so what what is that name I mean to
think just for a second linear function
so we you have a linear function you
have characteristics characteristic
polynomial you have I had I forgot the
name oh oh actually it's right in the
page I mentioned I ain't gone better
okay so that's the word eigenvector you
see those lines the blue lines they are
actually eigenvectors now angle vectors
has a it has a special property
particular to any specific linear
function but let's not talk about that
anyway it has a geometric meaning when
you have a eigenvector any point on that
vector line remains remains on that line
anyway something like that so I'm not
you know I'm not going to look into that
now so we are back to linear functions
okay so actually that concludes the
explanation of matrices a mini well that
didn't
that concludes the concepts of linear
function and matrices now the next thing
we need to talk about is given a matrix
how do you actually compute it like how
do you so I mean now we understand what
is a linear function but how do you
actually do something with it like how
do you write it down how do you how do
you compute it let's close that close I
curse you know how do you for example we
have a function now we suppose this
function f is a linear function but how
do you define it how do you write it
down okay you can do that with matrix
but okay so that that is the next thing
we need to do we are getting wrong here
so we need to where is it so here how do
you actually define a matrix okay in
code for example in code how do you
actually define a matrix and then then
how do you actually compute matrix you
know how does like we need to see your
example others others and how do you
actually do it okay so close down on
these close down is me okay I'm kind of
weak okay so we we need to do that oh my
God look okay so next thing is how do
you actually compute it and how do you
implement in JavaScript and so let's do
that okay
let's do that but let's let me have a
drink first okay I need to I need to get
my my mind ready for it okay apple juice
so so far so good guys so far so good
so why drink
what shrink okay so what what other
questions do we have
we caught some code yes maybe this
knowledge I can define code games for
the Vic tricks what is that
pan-pan pan-pan energy drink sugar free
okay so just in search for Justine
gentle more Nats okay just in gentle
Mona's search for that if you want to
look at Haskell and Ascot Mona's yes a
gentle introduction okay so what so III
need to get back to matrices okay matrix
movie base and we repealed yes yes
indeed matrix that looks horrendous okay
what I need to somewhere H and G oh yeah
that keyboard okay so okay so let's
that's it's let's begin talking about
matrix okay so so how do you linear
function okay so we need to define a
function so how do you actually do it
so let me see an example okay so
rotation is an example we can we can try
to do that an actual example now are now
about rotation
you know let's supposing a plane now
when you deal with linear functions the
context basically basically is linear
space meaning that you have vectors okay
that's the thing you work with vectors
you know basically a sequence of numbers
that's a thing consider as a thing just
think actually just think of it as a
point so in two-dimensional space we
have points you know XY the coordinate
in 3d space we have XYZ one more extra
coordinate so each point in space
those are vectors okay now you you could
go on into 4d space 5d space you just
have one more components so this is
actually what higher dimension means
fourth dimensional space even though we
can see it but that's mathematically
what they mean four dimensional space
now you so now you understand for what
is four dimensional space
five dimensional six dimensional it just
go by this analogy from 2d to 3d
then 240 you just add one more component
to the vector that's what it means now
so so when we talk about linear function
remember the context just like Wikipedia
tried to defy it the context is vector
space meaning you you work with these
points in a particular space of
particular dimension 2 d 3 d 4 d ok and
when you sell vectors so let's say 2 D
okay let's say 2 D for now so for
example you want to do rotation now you
when you want to do rotation the problem
is given a point and let's say you want
to rotate by 10 degrees around our
engine so you have explain I mean you
have the plane you have the x axis you
have the y axis you want to rotate
things by around the or engine so by
let's say 10 degrees and you want to
know so given a point you want to know
what is a result and how do you find
that how do you know well you can do
that via trigonometry now if you have
studied trigonometry you can derive you
can find out the formula basically you
you get a formula to do that and in that
form formula is can be written in a
matrix form so what does I mean so
anyway before we get into matrix so
anyway so now remember we want a from we
we want a formula that two rotation ok
so we can do rotation by you know for
example formula for example so we have X
you have a function let's see x xn f x
and y ok equals to some function ok
let's let's go to JavaScript ok let's
begin our journey to the land of
JavaScript okay we we need you need to
defy it
ok so constant arrow function wrote
eight okay let's say we want to rotate
function so the rotate function takes
two arguments X Y and the Alpha takes
three argument so it will rotate the
point XY defined by the XY coordinate by
alpha degrees around the origin
so what is the how do you write a
formula well okay that for this I know
the answer okay so the answer is what is
sine cosine
okay cosine sine right right actually I
know the answer okay so actually did
wait hold on a second so let's write it
this way so x and Y is a vector that's a
we are using valid JavaScript syntax so
this is actually a way in JavaScript so
that's a vector and we want to rotate it
alpha degrees so the result is what you
do is okay this is what you do math dot
cosine ok math dot cosine we are in the
realm of JavaScript mastered cosine
alpha and math star sine alpha okay ha
now second let's get this into the
proper format so we return a vector that
is that looks like that
okay so we are actually returning this
vector now that's not it of course
that's not it
we need to we need to put the X Y
somewhere it's getting more complicated
are you guys good here so Syria am I am
I done for today maybe it's best to call
it a day that's it for today so when
there's a problem let's say we are done
okay so I know what to do but it's gonna
be more complicated
well actually the easiest way is just to
look at Wikipedia okay so no no actually
we can do it so rotation well you need
to find the length of X Y okay so length
so we need to define a function first
that computes the length of the vector
so the way you do that is constant arrow
function so length length of vector so
we starting starting to write
maybe so x-coordinates in array in
y-coordinates in an array yes that's
what we are doing here that's that's
this thing then write a function that
map's the property function over both
these arrays yes we gonna do that
but first of all we need a length of
vector actually you know you know
actually there's gonna be a lot of code
we so let's just cheat and look at my
things I've already written okay so yeah
we're gonna cover this anyway so here it
is okay vector length well but if I show
this code you don't underst
you know like I need to explain it so
here is here is a function that returns
the length of a vector for any
dimensional vector and this is actually
valid JavaScript code okay this one yeah
but but then you see this function
hypotenuse it's actually a it's a
function new in JavaScript 2015 and what
is actually doing is this okay let me
explain okay so so again we have a
vector X Y Z let's say free dimensional
vector let's say two dimensional for now
okay and we want to find the length you
know so the way you do it is PI X so you
return a vector okay you return a vector
of two things okay and the first part
will be X divided by square root of x
squared plus y squared now why because
this is a Pythagorean theorem okay so
you have math start squared
square root so you want to take square
root of the sum of x squared plus y
squared and the second component will be
the same okay so that is a formula so
that is how you find the length of a
vector for a two dimensional vector and
for three dimensional vector it's the
same okay let's write it okay so three t
and say okay you know this is we are
starting to do some practical stuff so
for three dimensional vector you have
one more thing Z okay wait right we you
have one more thing Z there and forth
three dimensional vector you do actually
you do the same thing here and let me
show you that's what you do okay so that
is actually what you do so let's clean
up the code here a little bit so it's
easier to read so for this is so in
three dimensional in three dimension
this is what you do there you see what
if it's 40 40 is the same okay 40 is the
same you just add more things X Y Z W
then you just first first of you here
okay and you add one more component and
this is 40 okay so this is
four-dimensional we are venturing into
the fourth dimension so anyway that's
that computes the length of vector how
do you know that well it's a Pythagorean
theorem it's pretty simple okay so now
we got the length formula now remember
all these are lengths for specific
dimension vectors but in JavaScript they
introduced this function math I parted
hypotenuse okay basically
it allows us to define a generalized
vector length for any interventional
vector so the code is that okay you can
run it in browser shall we do it why not
since we are doing a show
we should might as well learn it to
prove to prove that our code is actually
not okay now we define that
function hold on a second let's let's
shrink the name so that I don't have to
type so much okay so let's shrink the
name to F L okay
define it now let's say F L let's say
two two and cut type area what about oh
yeah because well you have to it's a
vector right you have to give a is way
there it is so actually it already give
you a number before you actually press
Enter what kind of feature is this let's
see let's try it okay let's say one
let's say one oh my god it gives you an
answer before you even type at you know
before you press ENTER this modern
JavaScript dev thing amazing now we are
let's look at this one from this one I
can tell it's correct because you know
if vector length 1 1 now 1 Y is a vector
very easy to imagine so you have X you
have Y the X unit is 1 the Y is unit is
1 so it's basically a point here ok it's
like a square so so according to the
vector formula then what we have is you
know here is 1 square plus 1 squared is
2 squared of square root of 2 is 1 point
for something so we have 1 over square
root root of 2 and 1 over square root of
2 and that gives us
what is math square root of two right
and oh I'm sorry for the hoedown second
I got my I got my formulas wrong why is
nobody mentioned in it this you see we
are computing the length of a vector a
length of a vector is a number it's not
it's not a whole bunch of numbers so you
got all this wrong okay
so length of vector is that okay so
similarly for three dimensional vector
is just that okay and for four
dimensional vector is just that okay
right so now you know so so in
JavaScript 2015 we got just one function
that does you know generalized length of
a vector so anyway and we have shown
here so vector given a vector 1 1 the
length is 1 point 4 1 which is basically
square root of 2 and we can also compute
you know another weight
what's going on so we can compute that
see if L let's compute what
that okay so that's a three-dimensional
vector 1 1 1 and the length is 1.73
which is basically this formula okay
basically the square root of 1 plus 1
plus 1 the square root of 3 okay that's
the length of vector now we are going to
try to do rotation okay so the rotation
let's go back member given a vector we
want the rotate we want so how do you
compute that I can tell you ok so the
result is first of all ok before we do
rotate we let's we need to write another
function ok we write 2 we need to write
another function called no more lies ok
we need to write a function called
normalize basically that means so if you
have a vector now vector is the length
okay now typically when you walk with
vectors you often it's very convenient
if you have a vector in the same
direction but you want the length to be
1 so you want to normalize the vector so
create another vector that's the same in
the same direction but however the
length is only 1 why because when you
have a unit vector that's called a unit
vector okay when you have that it's much
easier to work with it so the function
to shrink a given vector to length 1
vector but still pointing in the same
direction that's called normalized a
math jargon is called normalized okay
and I have code here ok so I call it
unit vector here so but mathematicians
usually co-ed normalize so you can see
so it returns a unit vector in the same
direction so here is a code ok now by
the way on the left window you see here
they are typescript but you know I'm I'm
trying to make it
into plain JavaScript there it is okay
here is a function unit vector okay so
what is this
okay here is a unit vector function
returns the unit vector of V also known
as normalize okay in fact let's look
Wikipedia what normalized normalization
means okay you can see science
mathematics no moralization of an
algebraic variety normalization of
abstract rewriting normalization
normalizing a vector there it is you
know that's the definition okay so
anyway it's very easy okay so actually
the bunch of formulas I did before
that's normalization so let's undo let's
undo them all let's get back to the
formula I had there we have it that's
the that's my formula my friend that's
now we need it back there it is so okay
so let's hold on a second let's copy
copy copy so we got the length then we
got unit vector then we got then we got
well okay so we'd here is
oops hold on a second okay so here are
so here is how you define a you get how
here is how you get a unit vector so you
normalize vector given a vector in two
dimensions you divide each component by
their length okay so now you can say
actually by the length okay so we wait
am i still makes sense okay I'm kind of
get this is getting long and I'm not I'm
not doing much so anyway so so you see
this part let's see how long second so
you see this part this is how we do it
normally but because now we already have
the length from length function so
therefore we can write it this way you
know but anyway so anyway so here is a
normalization of a vector in 2d you just
divide each component by their length so
what you get is a vector in the same
direction but the length is not one okay
now for 3d vector it's the same okay and
here is a 4d vector and in general you
can write a function such that it can
get you the unit length for any
intervention or vector that's this line
okay that is this line of code so first
of all you say now this line of code is
hard to read because I'm using nested
function so so let me try to get so let
me try to rewrite it okay so
so unit vector let's let's say normalize
vector okay now we are going to rewrite
this function first of all give a
bracket and give a constant length
equals through that okay then
this is how you would do it in a
readable way okay now okay let's compare
now these two functions this one and
this one are the same okay hold on a
second let me mean cream up my brackets
these two functions are the same now the
the one here is more readable so first
of all you compute the length of the
vector then for each component in a
vector V you just map each component by
divide you know each component by the
length okay so basically this function
is doing what all the others here are
doing okay do I make sense now this is
this video is getting long we haven't
get to the then render function yeah so
let's look at actually let's try it
actually so let's look at my talk all
the people is gone gone to dinner let's
try it okay let's try this function so
let's copy the line we can demonstrate
that this works okay we define the
function then we say normalized vector
and now we give it a vector let's say
three three three okay that returns
something hard to understand well so
let's try it again let's say three zero
zero so that's let's say three zero then
it returns one zero that makes sense
because we have a vector that's length
three now it's a vector of length one so
I think this is taking too long so let's
see how long
I'm been talking so maybe that's it
1 hour and 17 minutes yeah so it turns
out you know it actually takes a lot to
do this a lot of time to do this what
what other things
any any other comments questions oh yeah
we haven't done rotation yet so I'm
trying to we I'm trying to do rotation
so the rotation will be let's let's
finish this rotation ok so rotation of
vector in 2d space will be first of all
you get
normalize the vector okay so first of
all you normalize the vector constant
unit vector equals to normalize it then
you
[Music]
that's it should I do
well I don't know I don't know this
okay so Alan show you great normalize
get so values between zero one no well
yes that's true yes all the components
will be less or equal to one for sure
yeah basically you can think of it's a
it's a vector on a circle or in free
space it's a vector on the sphere so you
know yeah so so now okay that that's
encouragement Alan's here and so we need
to do rotate should I actually rotate a
vector actually we kind of getting now
we this is getting kind of long and and
I wonder how do we should I just either
I finish the rotation on my own or we go
to Wikipedia and look at the rotation
formula so that that will save a lot of
time to save us five minutes
oh then then we look at what else we
haven't covered you know that's probably
gonna be it for today so I was going to
explain that product and the explained
cost for that that's not gonna happen
and I was going to explain matrix
multiplication we are just beginning to
do that because first of all we explain
matrix you know we you know we are doing
live coding so we had we begin here
already
then we need to finish the rotation for
mirror then I'm going to show you why it
is a matrix then we you know you then
you started to see why the matrix is a
bunch of numbers row and columns you
know it makes sense
because once we finish the rotate
formula then then we start to talk about
matrix multiplication with vectors yeah
but we haven't begin yet so it's already
80 minutes no you don't need to
normalize but you see yeah okay so let
me let's this finished is normalized
because why so why why am i normal yes
why am i normalized because as I
mentioned why do you normalize things
why do you have this normalization
because when you work with matrix I mean
when when you work with you know
complicated things in math usually you
take them apart you componentize you
know like programming modules you make
them into you know components so you so
when you think about rotation okay for
example rotation now you have a you know
let's say in two-dimensional space so
you have a circle you big you know you
start to think about a circle so you
have let's say the simple simplest case
of rotation is rotating a vector X 0 you
know that's just x axis one unit you
know so the the radius is one y one
because what one one will multiply
anything is anything you know it doesn't
change so it's most easy to work with 1
0 the vector so you rotate it by 10
degrees actually we we can start to draw
I need to get our game to draw you know
so you do trigonometry and you'll see
you'll begin to understand actually I
should do it because that's the part of
the ship yeah but we are getting too
long though so anyway so two-dimensional
rotation the easiest case is to think of
the vector 1 0 you start to try to
rotate at 10 degrees and then you draw
you know take out your rulers and for
trackers you draw it on a paper and you
will see then then with the Pythagoras
theorem you will find out the formula
for rotating to do mean for rotating the
vector 1 0
then then you can start to generalize
you know then you can start to
generalize you can you can start to have
a vector on the x axis that's not one
okay let's say three zero you know start
with a vector on the x axis and you can
see for any vector that's scaling so so
when you work with a vector on the x
axis instead of you know you can begin
with the sofa so you so that's why we
need to find the length okay so you need
to find the length of vector so because
a vector it's just like you can think of
it as a kind of elastic if you multiply
a vector by a number let's say by three
it just expanded by three like like zoom
out or zoom in okay so if you time a
number by four it just increased the
length by four so when you have a vector
of three that's simply the vector 1 0
multiplied by 3 you see that's how you
think about that so now so now with this
idea now you know any vector in the pen
you can just reduce them to the vectors
on the circle unit vectors that's why
that's why we are doing all this
normalization that this is fundamental
you know when you do linear algebra
especially in programming you you always
almost always work with unit vectors so
you see the idea the idea is let me just
repeat it one more time any vector into
B to D okay let's begin with 2d any
vector you can see the idea of scanning
a vector a scanning a vector is just
multiply its length in the same
direction so once you know this then
then you know that any vector can be
reduced to the unit vector because any
vector in space is simply its unit
vector vector times the length of the
vector so so now you can reduce
everything to the unit vector then you
just do any
rotation or whatever with the unit
vector then you just multiply by that
number to get back to your original
vector so that is why why I am trying to
do the why I am trying to derive or
create a rotation formula I want to
first first of all get the unit vector
to think about the rotation on the
circle then Winston I simply multiply
the whole thing by unit vector yeah so
actually I know what to do so actually I
want the length okay so here so let's
yeah so now actually I'm able to do it
constant function length equals to
length of XY okay so hold on a second
let's see if is correct actually we
don't need that so in order to do this
we need to write another okay so length
so this is how it works okay actually
here's the answer here here is our
rotation formula for the for inner for
planar vector so you are given a vector
XY and you want to rotate it by alpha
degrees so first of all like we talked
about before about the idea of scaling
so you don't worry about your vector I
mean just think of just think of a
vector in unit circle so that's just
cosine sine okay so it's needs two DS
so when you have a point on a circle
that's rotated you know the unit vector
1 0 rotated by alpha degrees that's a
formula sine cosine it's simple simple
the most basic trigonometry
sine cosine that gives you so this thing
you are seeing cosine sine that's the
that's a point on the circle of radius 1
rotated by alpha degrees okay that that
gives you the vector then you multiply
that post component by the length of
your internal vector then you get the
result of your wrote your vector rotated
to you know that's how you do it so
actually we don't need to normalize here
so that that is formula so now so now
you know the rotation formula now okay
so we yeah we don't need the word we
don't need to normalize it yeah so
anyway so so here's a rotation formula
so what do we go next let's see how long
have we been talking that's it I think
that's it that's too long it's long one
hour and 30 minutes
ok so let's summarize two or three more
minutes maybe yeah yeah trick-trick nama
tree yeah once you reduce things to
things on a circle then it's just very
basic trigonometry you know because the
circle you have a circle of radius one
everything is simple then because of the
scaling idea so everything is just
reduced to a circle then we just
multiply by the length of the vector to
get back to where we so okay so we
that's it for today thank you guys for
coming and we haven't get into matrix
multiplication this is always more than
I expected it takes
a lot time to get onto but yeah we I
wanted to write functions about you know
I I have a bunch I want to write three
dimensional functions of vector
functions cross-product dot products
matrix multiplication but we haven't get
into thank you guys so so anyway anyway
so that's it for maybe next time then I
hope you guys got some ideas about
matrixes you know if you have no idea
about what they are at all my guys more
topic for future shows yep Henderson
yeah the spice must flow