Hello guys.
Hello guys. Good morning, guys. Good
afternoon. Good evening.
Video check. Audio check. Welcome to
another episode of Tsar Talk Show.
We are going to do
coding,
geometry, and Wolfram language, okay?
Let's see. To do close. Let's go to
today's talk show.
Talk show. That's there.
Tsar Talk Show index. And today's talk
show coding, Wolfram language, geometry,
tangent lines, normal lines. That's what
we are not going to do. Geometry, okay?
Tangent and coding, okay? So, we are
going to just do a lot coding. This is
my office hours. So, I do my work and
you can come here, watch me code, or ask
me questions. So, [snorts] we got a
question from William. Now, William, are
you still here?
Because
uh if you are still here, say hi. So,
I'm going to answer your question, okay?
So,
William, you here?
Uh
So, William asked a question about
Bertrand Russell. Could you say a few
words about Bertrand Russell, who is one
of your favorite author? How was How has
he influenced you?
I talked that about that in the past.
So, Bertrand Russell is one of my
favorite author. And he is also
the guy who has influenced me the most.
Okay, let me tag William. So,
What?
Oh god. You know, so this
Are you still here, William?
Anyway, so William, you know,
So, anyway, let's wait um
So if you are still here, say so. Then I
answer your question. Otherwise, I'm not
going to going to talk about it because
we I talked about that before because I
got to work on my um
my special plane curves, okay? I got to
do work. So
uh the first task to do is we got this
tangent line, okay?
This tangent line open it showing
browser. So this this code needs to be
rewritten because right now this code
requires my package. If you don't know
about Wolfram Language, watch
uh my previous talk in the past week. I
talked about Wolfram Language for in
hundreds of videos. So
and the location to download my packages
plane curve plot, okay? So you can find
it. Just search for visual dictionary of
plane special plane curves and you'll
find the packages uh plane curves. So
info about this side references uh
miscellaneous gallery what um
Uh oh [ __ ] these are old. So these are
my packages. They are on GitHub, okay?
And Wolfram Language, you can also
download for free. I talked about many
times.
But anyway, so today so this this code
is relying on my package
uh
but let's make it not do that. Let's
make it independent so that anyone can
run this code in Wolfram Language and it
will draw
um tangent, okay? Let's do that.
>> Okay, where is the Wolfram? Did it start
yet?
Okay, there.
So, Wolfram language, so
um
So, you see, so if you copy the code,
and paste it here.
Paste the code. What?
Yeah, so there it is. You paste it
twice. Select all, paste, okay. Shift
enter.
It will load my packages, plain curve
plot, and we'll plot it.
Why is it taking so long?
Am I
Shift control escape. Am I running into
some kind of
CPU issues?
Red wine. So, there it is.
Okay, so that's the code, uh but we want
to make it independent. So, that's the
first job, so people can copy and paste
and
and run it right away.
Uh in this case, so okay. So, tangent,
so you need um
tribute to okay. So, let's put it back.
Copy, paste. Sync task color all, and
now let's show in browser.
Let's make a new copy, okay. Let's work
on the new copy, okay.
So, um
So, uh
wait.
Parametric plot, okay. So, we want to do
a parametric plot
of
Okay, parametric plot,
and uh remove that. Okay, so remove
that. Okay, so
those are not what we want.
Plot range aspect ratio automatic. Okay,
that's good. That's good. That's good.
So this is the Wolfram language default
when you want to plot
this. Okay.
So let me show you.
There it is. A sign. Okay. Now you want
to Now you want to draw a tangent. So
Uh yeah.
Tangent vector. So you want to write a
function.
Tangent vector a function.
Uh
You First of all, you want a derivative.
Okay, so you want a derivative
of
um
Oh god.
So William, are you still there?
So William's got a question. If you are
still there,
say hi and
you know, ask me about the Bertrand
Russell. I'll answer it. Meanwhile, are
watching this is my office hours. I'm
just going to work on my website. If you
have questions, post it. Okay.
So let's see where where is my
description. Um
Okay, so
let's see.
I work on my website, coding
geometry
in Wolfram language.
Watch me.
You can ask questions
here.
Or just watch me, okay? So, that is the
premise.
So, let me post that there. So, there.
Okay.
Okay, so William, so let me answer
William's question. So, another
question. Hi Sai, I am a complete
beginner in math and programming, but I
want to learn linear algebra. Good
choice.
Multivariable calculus. Good choice. And
statistics for machine learning. Good
choice. How would you recommend
starting? Okay. So, let me answer the
Bertrand Russell question first. That's
um
that might take 5 or 10 minutes. In
fact, I can talk about 1 hour. So,
Bertrand Russell
Okay, so let let's um well
let's be thorough. Why not? You know,
since we are talking about because
people don't know who the who who is
Bertrand Russell.
Okay, so Bertrand Russell is one of the
greatest philosopher and mathematician.
In fact, logician. Okay, so Bertrand
Russell Wikipedia, you can read about
it. He is
He Bertrand Russell is one of my
favorite author. Let's say top three or
even top one, okay? He He is also the
person who has influenced me
kind of my life the most. Even greater
than
you know, I
I would say like the most. Almost like
you know, may you know
may be not greater than my dad, okay?
So, influenced me, my thoughts the most.
And is the person who I admired the
most. Basically, more or less.
Especially when I was younger. When you
get older, you you you you you um
like you don't have like oh, I admire
this guy that that kind of thinking
much, you know, but when you are
younger, you know, so
uh
throughout my 20s and 30s, okay?
Bertrand Russell has influenced my
thoughts the most.
I admire the most. He's a mostly he's a
logician
uh you know, well-known mathematician,
specifically logician,
um
whose greatest work is the Principia
Mathematica, which is trying to
build a logical foundation of mathe-
mathematics by pure logic, okay? Which
spurred
today's proof theory
uh you know, and type theory
you know, like foundational figure.
And he's also a philosopher, so mostly
he's well-known for he's well-known for
quite a few things. So, mathematics,
logic, and philosophy is a he's a
prominent force in philosophy, Western
Western philosophy, okay?
So, mathematician, philosophy, and he is
also
uh literature, okay?
He's a great writer. He's like a like
like
uh common educator, he's a writer, okay?
So, he write about lots of things. What
we might call blog today.
He wrote several books, you know, many
many books.
So,
so Principia Mathematica, which is very
difficult. I mean, okay, it it you know,
one of my uh top interest, but I
this this book is very hard to read,
okay? But usually so usually even if you
are in this field, proof theory, usually
you don't read this book any anymore.
So, [snorts] this is written like 200
years ago or is it or is it um 19 Okay,
100 years ago, 1910.
Anyway, so, Bertrand Russell influenced
me the most. I admire the most most my
favorite writer among the top, let's
say, three, okay.
The other one is
Li Ao. That's a Chinese guy
in Taiwan, born in China.
He who who he died about 5 years ago,
actually, by now, 10 years ago. Li Ao,
okay. In English, you spell it, okay,
let me show.
So, that's one of my other favorite
author.
Not not this not not this.
Uh
Okay, they you know, they they you know,
[ __ ] deep state, you know, it used to
it it's not this guy. Deep state made a
change so that you don't you don't find
the guy this guy, okay?
This guy.
Yeah, this guy. So,
I have no idea who is this first
Chinese operative bass baritone on that.
Okay, so, Wikipedia, so, Li Ao is a
Chinese historian. He died in 2008.
Okay.
Wow, 15 eight yeah, quite a few ago,
almost 20 years ago by now.
2008. So, he is my also my favorite
writer and thinker, okay? Influenced me
the
the most, okay? Him and Bertrand Russell
and what's the
other possibly um
Well, mostly mostly these two, I would
say. You know, I think there are other
people and and and also Stephen Wolfram,
actually. Stephen Wolfram, the guy who
creates Mathematica. He's thinking about
about computation, about math, the way
he thinks I
agree with
very much and influenced me very much.
Okay, Stephen Wolfram. The the way he
look at computation mathematics. Okay.
So anyway, Bertrand Russell. Okay, one
of my favorite and and so what is your
question? So
meanwhile, let me show you guys my
website. Okay.
Um
Well, if I go show my website, that's
going to be like controversial like
xahlee.org. Okay.
xahlee.music. Let's go to xahlee.org. So
you can go there by you know, this this
scums.
>> [laughter]
>> This you know, I don't have a website on
last.fm.
But someone
like someone must have someone created
listen to music from xahlee like the
most efficient Emacs workflow more
efficient than Vim. Open source Richard
Stallman. Why?
What what what did someone put me on
last.fm?
Oh, someone did I guess long ago. This
you know, must uh
This is not me. So
interesting. Okay, I guess someone
Or is it generated? I don't know, but
apparently
some some of my videos back in you know,
in 2021,
4 years ago, someone put it on last.fm.
I don't use this site. Okay. So anyway,
go back. So here is my music blog. So
you go there.
Uh
What?
Oh god, what's going on? So you need to
click on that.
Yeah. So xah music blog. Also, let me
mention again, I got some issues with my
web hosting provider, so I have not been
able to update my website for about a
month. So, you are looking at the last
update is January 20th. So, for about
month, I haven't been able to update my
website, okay? Anyway, so, if we you
know, we going to search um
Yeah, yeah, you can search from here
because that's limits to uh music
search. You want to search periodic
dosage. Okay.
Well, let's
I don't want to do that. So, let's just
say Bertrand Russell Xadi, just search
that. General web search, okay? So, I
have
uh posted several of his articles on my
website like 10 20 years ago, okay?
So, for example,
uh one of his article is What desires
are politically important by Bertrand
Russell, 1950, okay? So, this is
Bertrand Russell's Nobel lecture,
November 1950.
December 1950. So, by the way, he won a
Nobel Prize for literature, which is
which is kind of silly because he he the
the the greatest um contribution of
Bertrand Russell is in mathematics and
philosophy. He In philosophy, he created
the
positivism
and analytic philosophy, okay? That is
actually my philosophy, okay? Analytic
philosophy, which renders many of the
metaphysics question
useless.
Meaningless, okay? So, anyway, that's
another topic. So, Bertrand Russell, um
he won Nobel Prize for literature, very
silly because his contribution is
actually in mathematics and philosophy,
far more greater, you know? Bertrand
Russell is also a peacemaker, you know,
he he and Einstein wrote a letter to USA
president to stop nuclear
proliferation, you know, nuclear bomb
and things like that. And also he got
he got
uh
persecuted by Christians, okay,
Christians are very nasty group of
people. Today, there's more nasty
religious people like you know, in in in
in the the the same branch Abrahamic
religions, okay. It's quite quite nasty,
but but Chris Christian is was one of
the nasty.
So, he got put to jail by Christian in
USA and prevented and forbid, I think
it's in New York City or New York State.
They forbid him from
>> [laughter]
>> uh holding a teaching job, you know, a
professor or teacher, you know.
He's been put to jail for like a
a couple of years or something. But
anyway, he won Nobel literature prize.
So, so this is one of his article, What
desires are politically important by
Bertrand Russell, okay. So, that's
[snorts] one of his article and I
annotated it, okay. So, this you see
those uh this uh you see this
are my
annotations, you know, the
you know, this markup markup and this
rape of the Sabine.
It's that's a that's a classic Western
history, okay. Rape, like the the
Western white man society, they're
talking about rape all every day. Rape
rape rape they rape, you know, [ __ ]
idiots, the white people. But they
uh since since like ancient times, okay,
rape of the Sabines, you know, from
Roman
you know, kind of Roman uh era.
So, he's talking, you know, so there's
Islam. So, but Bertrand was Russell,
What desires are politically important,
okay. So, you go down, so
uh you know, my annotation um the love
of power, okay? Did you see that? The
love love of excitement. And
and um love of power, you see? Today, we
have a a a big war going on in Iran.
There's some of the reasons going on
there, okay?
Love
love the power love of excitement.
Okay, Bertrand Russell, "What desires
are politically important?" 1950, okay?
Anyway, so I have several articles of
him.
And then, okay, two more article by him.
Uh let's open that.
So, one of them has religion made useful
contributions to civilization. Okay. Has
you know, did did religion ever make
actually useful things?
Contribution.
There's one article and another article,
"Why I am not a Christian?" Okay? So,
1927.
And the other one is 1930s, okay?
Cheers. So, anyway, Bertrand Russell,
that's you know, um
you know, is my favorite author
influenced me the most. And what is what
is your question? I hope you are doing
well.
I am, thank you. Could you say a few
words about Bertrand Russell, who is one
of your favorite author? How has he
influenced you? Okay. So,
I talked about Bertrand Russell before
in my live stream because but well, but
you may not see it because
because I I almost do it live stream
every day. By now, I have 700. So, you
know, by the way, another thing
interesting is about the live stream
thing. You see,
technology has
communication technology, that's what
made live stream possible starting like
even 20 years ago, you know. First of
all, we have YouTube.
Actually, some other website, you know,
videos, like tiny videos even 30 years
ago. Then we started up live stream
like live
chat video, instant chat video. You you
can talk to grandma, your grandma, or
your grandparents, or your girlfriend in
some other place, you know. Then you
started to have lots of YouTube, and
then you have started to have kind of
live stream things. You can, you know,
people do live stream on Twitch, you
know, for example.
And more and more. So So today you got
like every
every second you got like thousands or
tens of thousands, or you would say even
millions people doing live stream. But
So but the then you got a issue that so
many videos, like
like even if you are watching me, how do
you possibly like nobody actually
possibly watch every video. So I was
asking So I have the question. I was
asking Kwok about it. Like do people
the fans of some some live streamers, do
they watch every show, or like what what
do they do?
Like many of the streamers today popular
so-called influencers, influencers, they
have like millions of followers, right?
So I asked Kwok one of the question, AI
fascinating.
Uh somewhere somewhere in my Kwok um
What? Yeah, I don't want stupid, you
know, like sometimes you click some
thing by mistake. Right now it's like
telling me what is Ksardi. Like who is
Ksardi? Kwok is going to tell me who is
me.
It happened a few times. Ksardi is a
dedicated math and coding enthusiast
who has authored specialized book on
JavaScript, Emacs Lisp, and Wolfram
Language, sharing nerdy insights through
regular in live streams and uh uh
share sharing nerdy insights through
regular live streams on geometry plane
curves and programming optimizations.
Okay, that's actually
just like my latest happening because I
noticed, you know, Grok usually whatever
summary Grok does is usually at least on
Twitter is just
like past few months.
So, in the past few months if if you
talk about something, Grok think you are
that guy, you know, it's kind of silly.
So, anyway, that's not what I want. I
wanted to tell you about
um
uh tangent geometry uh
quite a lots of interesting things going
on. Okay, so um
evolution of online communication
technologies, okay, what uh method of
normals by Descartes. That's a new
very interesting technique.
Okay, let let me focus, okay, let me get
to the point.
Yeah, one thing annoying about AI is
that they they changed they retitle your
question. For example, my question was
when fans watch streamers, do they watch
every episode? Isn't that few hours a
day?
Like even if you are a fan of someone,
you can't possibly watch every episode,
right? And usually these streamers, as
far as I know, I I I
I I checked out some of the, you know,
teenagers, you know, there's a speed guy
or, you know, there's all kind of also
girls, but like what the [ __ ] they do?
They got millions of followers, you
know, they do live stream. Usually like
few hours a day, so it's even more than
me. Like I was wondering
they got few million followers, Like,
what what the [ __ ] do they do?
Okay, for the girls, obviously
>> [laughter]
>> half [snorts] of the reason is because
they are pretty. You know, you just
watch girls. That's
That's natural, okay? Like, and girls
also watch girls.
So, you got to have charisma, you know?
You You just watch them, you know? You
like that's fundamental human nature.
You watch
beautiful people, okay?
And all successful and rich people. So,
if you if you are very rich, people will
watch you. You know, because people
follow, you know? Anyway, so
then
there's a young teen guys. Like, like
usually they also
Okay, so like
also partially because they are
handsome. They are handsome, they are
young.
Um anyway, so
so turns out people do not watch it
every every day, you know? But
um you know, so anyways
So, I was So, I was So, let's go back to
the Bertrand Russell. So, I was saying
that um
I So, I was saying that um
live stream. So, you know, I talked
about what What I was I saying? So
uh
Anyway, Bertrand Russell, right? How did
I get into that live stream [ __ ]
Medium, are you still here?
So
So, more specifically, how would you
recommend Wait, you are saying that how
has he influenced
you? So, Bertrand Russell influenced me
in thinking about mathematics, the way
he views mathematics, philosophy of
mathematics.
And Bertrand Russell also influenced me
deeply about
philosophy, okay? Because he created the
the uh
uh positivism.
Positivism, that's a branch of
philosophy. And it's actually
Bertrand Russell created analytic
philosophy, okay? So,
you see, positivism is a philosophical
school that holds that all genuine
knowledge is either true by definition
or positive, meaning a pos- teriorary
fact derived by reason and logic from
sensory experience, okay? Philosophy can
get quite esoteric, but
uh but that's not
So, let me uh see um
Let me just randomly show you what I
wanted to show you um
uh positive logicism uh
Wait, what was it uh
positive logicism, I think. Um
Uh actually
Actually, you can just go to Bertrand
Russell article, okay? So, Bertrand
Russell, you just search for
analytic
philosophy, okay? So, there it is,
Bertrand Russell analytic philosophy.
That is a branch of philosophy.
Basically, he
founded it, okay?
So, what is So, in short, analytic
philosophy is basically
taking the science approach to
philosophy. Okay? Instead of just
thinking and talking, you take more of a
scientific approach, where you can
verify things, you can try to prove
things, you can, you know, end argument
by formal logic and analysis of
language, like because language is how
we communicate. We talk about
philosophy. So, what does language mean?
What Why, you know,
things like that. So, linguistic and,
you know, is part of it. So, analytic
philosophy, which is philosophy from a
scientific approach. Okay? So, this
basically began by Bertrand Russell in,
uh,
1900s. Okay?
And one of the, uh,
and and one of the, uh,
thing is logical positivism. Okay? So,
search for logical
positivism.
Positivism. There it is. Okay? So,
logical, uh, so, so there it is.
Logical positivist.
Okay? So, there So, let's just go there.
Okay?
Logical positivism. That is the
philosophy I
follow. Okay?
Kind of even today. Even though, I mean,
like almost every philosophy, there are
also deniers. I mean, there are also
criticisms, like
Okay. So, like when you have a bunch of
philosophy, there's always criticism
saying that, "Oh, well, that doesn't
work because this or that."
There's always that.
Like in or in in every school of
philosophy. But anyway, basically
logical positivism positivism is my
philosophy.
Which is basically basically you can
just say scientific science-based
philosophy. Okay? Scientific philosophy.
So, that's what I believe. And how do I
know this? Well, because Bertrand
Russell. Okay? Because I read a lot of
Bertrand Russell. I
read quite a lot. So, almost
you know, quite quite a lot of his books
and his, uh, biography. I think, you
know, biography.
>> And in fact
logical positivism
is basically the practical philosophy
done in Western society reflected in
Western society in the past 100 years.
You got all these sciences going on.
Basically, that's because of this
logical positivism. Okay.
So, I think that I answered that your
question. William James, are you still
here? If you are
uh
say hi and uh that would I would
appreciate.
I think I answered your question about
Bertrand Russell. So, I showed you
several articles I have on Bertrand
Russell.
Basically, who he is and what he has
done in philosophy and uh
and what he has done in mathematics and
my other favorite author, the uh
historian. By the way, this Wikipedia
article is very short. It doesn't say
much and it's
So, the the important things is they are
it's not mentioned here even though it's
some somewhat long. But but this but
you know, so if you really want to know
Basically, if you want to know about
Chinese stuff, China or Taiwan, or you
know, philosophy, you basically you have
to know Chinese. Okay. You cannot rely
on English. You you
um
You can you can. I mean, English is
still pretty good, but because it's
tremendous because I even in Wikipedia
I was amazed. I mean, even if you just
read English
you can learn so much so much about very
extremely esoteric details about Chinese
Chinese culture
or and and even Chinese history, okay?
>> [snorts]
>> Even if you just read English
on Wikipedia alone.
Even suppose you don't read anything
else, just Wikipedia, the English
version on anything about Chinese
Chinese history, you know, Chinese you
know, all these for example, you can
start to follow this all these links.
Tangwai movement, I don't even know what
that is, you know, for democracy 1970s,
you know, so new party and whatever. So
you can read you you know, you can
actually literally spend years reading
about Chinese history, Chinese
philosophy, Chinese culture on Wikipedia
in English
by yourself, okay? So it's quite
amazing.
The the amount of information about
Chinese is quite large, okay? But most
Americans like the most the vast
majority of English speakers, they talk
on Twitter about China or Taiwan, they
don't know a thing. They
they don't they don't know not a thing.
They just like babble is it's just like
the typical
drama Twitter, you know, brainless like
or fortune people like the they they
brainless, you know.
So anyway, so if you but if you really
for those who really want to know what's
going on in China or you know, the
Chinese history which is huge, what one
of the most ancient civilization and
today became the most powerful
basically.
You you can start to read, okay? But
but what I'm saying is that but of
course if you read Chinese, if you
actually learn to read Chinese which is
not trivial, you know, it takes 5 years
to actually learn about reading Chinese.
Well, 3 years if you if you spend 1 hour
every day, I would say you can become
reasonable. You can get reasonable skill
in reading
actual reading Chinese
in 3 years, okay?
Provided you spend 1 hour every day.
Every day you must, you know, spend 1
hour. Then in 3 years you'll have
reasonable skill in reading Chinese,
okay? So, but once you read another
language, I mean, include Chinese or
even
including Russian or Arabic, you you you
kind of expanded your view.
You you can start to see opinions that
you never seen before.
Okay? Like when you expand your you
know, like not not in English, but most
American idiots, like the white people,
American idiots,
they they just read English, right? But
they
You you might think you might argue, you
know, well, but English is pervasive,
you know, there's always translations
you can, you know, but not really.
Because
here's the thing, you know,
the logic the logical way to explain
this is that when you um
Am I still Am I still going
Are you guys still like watching this?
Okay, William says, "Thank you." Thank
you, William.
Uh
is my answer satisfactory? Are there
like follow-up questions?
Anyway, so
uh so I was randomly uh talking about uh
languages. So,
the the logical reason is that, you
know,
like you you might, you know, you might
say logically, today translation
technology is so powerful, especially
because of AI, right? So, you might say
that any possible idea have been
expressed in English
uh already,
which is kind of true
by all the translations. And And so so
so it doesn't hurt if you only know
English. It you know, literally doesn't
matter. You don't have to know another
language because
anything possibly you know, any idea is
basically already written in English in
one way or another.
So, that's that's a common you know,
Americans you know, idiot idiotic
American English or UK Brits [ __ ]
I started to hate them despise them so
much in the past few years.
You know, you might think that.
But actually no, because because because
most most of the time you you know,
human animals we are not machines. You
know, you are not born
a machine then you're going to logically
find all possible opinions and read
about it. That's not what you do.
We are just here to just you know,
like human like kind of this petty thing
who make you know, we have to live. We
have to eat eat and we meet some friends
like a couple of friends.
Uh meanwhile there are you know, 8
billions of people
and all over the place, right?
So, what do you actually
do everyday and what we actually know
everyday is just what happens to be
around us.
You happen to be
like speaking English or white people or
whatever culture you came from. You
happen to be
No no, you know, you happen to know me.
So, that that influenced your view a
little bit. You happen to know you know,
whatever your environment. So,
so that is why when you
speak only English you
your exposure to
the kind of information and point of
view is limited. Okay, so for example,
if
you also, you know, if you know Spanish,
which is very common in USA, you know,
or if you happen to also know, let's
say,
German. Well, German is kind of, you
know, German,
French,
uh UK, they are kind of like related,
okay? But
but it also helps, okay? But if you
happen to know more different
uh languages, like Russian, or Islamic,
uh or Japanese, then you suddenly then
you will see opinions that's very that's
more different than what you are used
to, okay? That's the my point.
So, even logically, yes, every idea
basic almost is almost every, you know,
every idea that a person can practically
ever read in a lifetime is already in
English, but
it is not true that you can, you know,
if you learn
another language, you will not change
your view.
It's very likely if you know another
language, fluent in another language, it
will change your view. Like your your
opinion, your your head will be
different.
Okay, your behavior will be different
when you see things differently, then
your behavior will become different.
Your your behavior, your daily pattern,
okay? That's
So, that So, we are talking about the
language, okay? So,
anyway.
Okay, so that's that's one question. So,
the other um question is um
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> I'm a complete beginner in math and
programming, but I want to learn linear
algebra, multivariable calculus, and
statistics for machine learning. How
would you recommend starting? Okay. So,
those topics, linear algebra,
calculus, and uh statistics, they are
basics in any college education.
So, they are almost required in high
school. Uh I mean, like high Yeah, high
school beginning high school.
In USA, in any Western countries, in
China, in Japan, in any um
modern countries. So, they are required
subjects. So, I don't know who you are.
So, you 2614.
Like, I don't know who you are, how old
you are, where where like which country
you are. So, those those are topics
required in almost every country.
So, one way to learn them
is just follow through.
Just be a good student.
You know, you go to high school, you
will learn
Well, actually, so
Yeah, yeah, I mean, depending on high
school, depending on, you know, how
high, you know, how how what quality or
what what is your progress. So, linear
algebra, multi-variable calculus, and
statistics, they are usually
taught At least in USA, they are taught
in first and second years of
college.
Also known as university, okay? So, it
was known as freshman and sophomore.
They don't call it freshman anymore.
Freshman in in in English in USA means
the first year of university, but they
don't call that anymore in the past 10
years because the social justice
[ __ ] the deep state, you know,
they twisted They they they think sex is
a construct, so they don't want any
English word
for
thousands of years that contains the
word men.
So this when they say you know freshman
freshman
By the way freshman is a idiosyncrasy of
American of either American or or the
Brits, okay? Because it's a
you know like you
funny you know it's a idiom. Anyway the
social justice warriors deep state in
the past years past 10 years they forbid
this word because it this word contains
the word men.
They say no you can't you cannot be
didn't include women or it didn't
include trans later on. So they forbid
freshman they have to say fresh people.
But the problem the problem is when you
say fresh people it like doesn't make
sense it's not
you know because freshman is like kind
of idiosyncratic it has it has a
cultural background you know.
So you if you say fresh people it kind
of what do you mean fresh people right?
So they stop saying freshman they you
know they just say first year college
student something like that okay? It's
this Wikipedia so this this is a little
linguistic detail.
You see this this is you see this is you
know by the way you have to understand
especially of you white people. This is
white man's history.
By white man I mean like Brits and
German or engine kind of okay? That's I
learned the hard way that's what white
man means okay? So
so if you are that kind of you know that
that that blood blood line this is your
history okay? Freshman fresher first
year or colloquially
frosh
is a person in the first year at an
educational institution, usually a
secondary school or at the college and
university level, but also in other
forms of post-secondary educational
institutions, okay?
One bunch of mouthful. But anyway,
this is like um
this is like a idiom for you know, for
some reason.
But the funny you know,
so I find it funny and insulting and
kind of like
like twisted is that in the past 10
years, the white people, the same the
same group you you know, the white man,
they forbid.
Now, they forbid this
this terminology.
Because it contains the word men. They
say, "No, you cannot be allowed, you
know, for the [ __ ] scum."
So let's see. Did Do they mention that
here? So you see um
You see,
freshman is you know, in United States
beginner freshman is commonly
in use as a US English idiomatic
term to describe a beginner or novice,
someone who is naive,
a first effort, instance, or a student
in the first year of study. You see,
idiomatic, like what I said.
Uh but anyway, so
do they mention the did did they mention
the like the change of terminology like
forbidden?
I think they did. I think they do
somewhere. Let's see.
Let's see
um
It would be interesting if they didn't
because Wikipedia has been very much um
because this is like polit- becoming
political um issue. So, Wikipedia has
been corrupted in past in the past 10
years. They So, they change
uh I find so
they did not
This article may contain original
research blah blah blah.
Okay, so
I find it interesting social justice
warrior [ __ ] did not
change things on this page.
Okay, I don't I
It looks like they didn't mention it.
They didn't mention this is like
controversial or something. That's
interesting because I'm sure they have
done.
In the next step is to go into view
history and start to do research, you
know, spend a year an hour or two or
several hours to see
to see how did it change, who changed
it.
You know, that's typically that's what I
do.
Um anyway, that's a lot. That's going to
be a few hours.
So, anyway, so your topic you're you're
talking about linear algebra,
statistics, and calculus. They are basic
standard [snorts]
educational courses
in mandatory you know, in in this
so-called institutionalized
education.
And often is mandatory. So,
in
in Western societies and and also not
just Western societies, but in any
um so-called industrialized
societies, modern societies, you know,
well-to-do societies.
So,
so what do you mean? So, so so how old
are you? So, maybe you are younger,
maybe you are like 10 years old, 14
years old. So, you haven't begin high
school, okay? So, I'm 19 and from
Ireland. My school didn't cover much
advanced math. So, I'm starting from the
basics. Okay.
So, anyway,
linear algebra, calculus, and
statistics, they are like the most basic
and required, kind of required for any
college.
Required in the sense that it's even if
you don't major in mathematics, for
example,
my experience is from USA, okay? So, in
USA, in college, in university, like
usually 4 years,
after the first 2 years, then you start
to you you you have to pick a major,
like what you specialize in.
Do you want to be a mathematician? Do
you want to be a physicist? Do you want
to be a chemist? Do you want to be a
engineer? Do you want to be a program
programmer? Computer science? Or do you
want to be a lawyer? A writer? You know,
like you start to have a major,
so-called. That meaning that, you know,
what you specialize, okay?
But,
linear algebra, calculus, and
statistics,
they are not even part of the major.
They are like part of the general
education. So, in the first 2 years,
before you even have decided you're
going to Oh, I'm going to study math.
I'm going to be mathematician. Even
before that, they are so basic
that for any, basically any engineering
student or any kind of people who are
more interested in sciences and
engineering,
They have to take one of these, okay?
Linear algebra,
statistics,
statistics and calculus. Um you know,
usually they they will do calculus,
okay? So, these three are so basic and
fundamental that
that
that any
um
you know, people who want interested in
physics or engineering
or in chemistry, they have to take it.
Okay.
So, that's how fundamental they are.
So, if you are in Ireland in 19, you
know, maybe even you know, maybe you'll
go to college or something. You you you
know, you'll you'll you'll run into it.
But otherwise, you may not because a lot
people, you know, maybe for a lot
people, you know, they don't
they they don't like for a lot people,
not mainstream. They are not in the
mainstream. So, they don't have a
channel to go to the
this institutionalized
educational system. You know, they don't
have that channel. For example, I don't
I didn't have
that path, okay?
I never I never had I never I can I
don't even have the
uh opportunity, the path to go to high
school, okay?
So, for those of people who want to
learn it, you can you know, today
if
So, you can learn it. So, this is
important actually. So, in fact, it may
be even better
than going to college to learn about
these topics, okay? This is the
This is actually my answer to you. This
is more important.
Today, if you want to learn any linear
algebra,
you know, you No, or statistics or
calculus, okay? You can just search the
web.
The first stop you will see is
Wikipedia, of course.
Massive Wikipedia. So, you you can start
to read it. That's what I do, okay?
Like any topic as do like do you know
how to read? Of course, you do.
Start to read it.
Begin like you can like begin today.
>> [laughter]
>> After watching my video, like you can
begin today.
Like what So, part of math So, it
begins, you know, it says linear algebra
is a branch of mathematics concerning
linear equations. Oh, Jesus. What is
linear equations? Click
and read.
So, you can click and read, you know,
you just start reading about it today.
Read and read 1 hour a day. Just
fascinating.
Linear algebra is actually my favorite
math topic, too. More than calculus,
linear algebra. And so
And so,
it's one of my favorite, okay? Linear
algebra. More than calculus and more
than statistics.
Statistics is my least favorite
mathematics.
It's kind of boring, statistics. But so,
anyway, so these are the fundamental
uh required classes, okay? So, it's good
to learn. So, you can
So, they are and there are many ways.
So, the first stop is linear algebra.
You can just start to read and read on
on I mean on Wikipedia, okay? Then, of
course, there's there's 1,000 videos.
The the Khan Academy is very well known.
That that's the people who began who
kind of began the video tutorials, okay?
This Khan Academy, okay?
Uh turn JavaScript. So, you can start to
read there.
Okay.
You see and and uh what the [ __ ] accept
cookies, okay? Uh Jesus, they start to
ask for money.
I never I actually never used uh Khan
Academy because select amount
>> [laughter]
>> donate. What is So where where is the
video like
Anyway, so there's a lot of them. Okay,
so this besides Khan Academy there's a
lot a lot. So you can learn.
And YouTube of course is tremendous.
Then you can also pick Encyclopedia
Britannica. Okay, there's YouTube. Okay,
so
you can learn in all sorts of ways and
plenty and so what So my advice to you
is that you can just start to learn it.
Looks like you have the will to learn
you know you you you really want to you
are interested.
That solves a major problem.
Then you just start to read it. Okay,
just start you know watch video
or read Wikipedia or read books there's
quite a lot
professional level
free
books like uh textbooks on linear
algebra that's free.
In fact my website has it. Okay.
Sal linear algebra. Okay, so you can
find
personal info about Sal whatever you
know Sal profile contact. Okay, Sal math
linear algebra notes. Okay, so
yeah I I you know so I have lots of
notes like 20 years ago those are not
good. But you you just you know you just
go to like um
you'll find a lot free books. Okay,
there free math textbooks.
By the way this book linear algebra by
David C. Lay is the one I read and I
liked it very much in 1993.
Okay, but it's not free. Um
yeah I don't think it's free and also he
the guy died in 2018,
I learned.
Anyway, that's just my like
personal nostalgic notes, okay? But what
do you want is go to free math
textbooks. This calculus several free,
completely free. They are like open
source and this
linear algebra, okay? So that is not
free. Oh, but $10 on Amazon.
And this linear algebra by, you know,
other people free PDF and comes in PDF,
okay?
And same thing with statistics and
calculus, okay? For example, calculus,
okay? These are free books.
Uh by the way, if you're going to buy a
textbook, I don't recommend buying any
textbook, okay?
Like for example, this like
commercialized textbooks they are used
in colleges today.
Never buy them.
Because they become super extremely
corrupted.
In several ways. First of all, they
become they are now today very expe-
expensive. Like they are few hundred
dollars for one like one book. One
[ __ ] book.
Few hundred dollars. Amazing. Why?
Search my web, you'll find a blog.
You you'll find an article about why
textbooks are expensive because
tremendous deep state corruption in the
past 20 years in USA, okay?
So anyway, I don't recommend so do not
buy any textbooks. Of course, if unless
you are going to university, it's re-
required,
then you are, you know, you are in this
trap.
Then you owe a lot money to the
government, you know, student debt and
so on. Anyway,
but you are in Ireland. Okay, so anyway,
so I so I don't recommend
uh
buying any modern textbooks recent
edition, I don't recommend it, but I do
recommend that textbooks on calculus, on
algebra, on linear algebra, on
statistics, okay, all these textbooks on
chemistry, on physics from
20 years ago.
Okay? Just buy, you know, go to used
bookstore
and pick one of these, you know, classic
topics, calculus,
uh geometry,
uh physics, you know, engineering,
mechanical engineering, all these basic,
you know, fundamental engineering,
linear algebra, uh complex, even real
analysis, complex analysis, differential
geometry, those are advanced. Anyway, so
pick a book from 20 years ago.
20 or even 30 years ago, okay? Those are
good. Those are the best. They they cost
you like $2, okay? Like
like literally two $2, $3, okay?
Almost all or free, you know.
Get those books, okay? Don't get the the
the like modern, the latest edition
because they First of all, they are like
few hundred dollars. There's tremendous
corruption. You don't even know it, you
know, you don't know.
Then Then, secondly, they
they temp they contaminate contaminated
all the content by the modern social
justice [ __ ] okay? They started to say,
for example, there there are books on
history of mathematics, okay? So, do I
have Do I show you somewhere you know,
uh
Okay, they are For example, I read quite
a lot history of math books, okay?
You know, so in the past few years I I
have the occasion to check what is the
current edition, what's going on.
It turns out
the current edition, they they add lots
of like
political things. Like, for example,
they they add, for example, history of
mathematics, they add women
mathematicians. They started to have a
lot to say about all of a sudden, "Oh,
women are important in mathematics
because this or that." They added that.
And all all the trans part, okay? They
suddenly added, "Oh, by the way, sex is
not important.
It's just a thought."
They started to add that in statistics
books, I noticed. You know, they added
like, "Oh, because the court
judge in USA, you know, the
because racial issues, black people or
trans or gay sex, gay marriage,
therefore, we have this case example in
the court, and because of statistics,
this or that, therefore, it is because
that way." You know, in the statistics
books.
The current edition.
You know, these things doesn't occur
in in few editions before. They Why is
it in the current edition? Because they
want to, you know, it's it's politics.
Because
that's how people want it to be, you
know, because this
um
Anyway.
Do you guys Do you guys get what I'm
saying?
So,
so that's about textbooks. I don't
recommend any of the modern textbooks,
okay?
Uh buy them from 20 or 30 years ago from
used book store. That I can recommend.
Or
just check out the many online
free PDF versions, okay?
They are
they are um
open source
by license, okay? For example, the Moon
Calculus open source by license.
Uh you can
you know, open it. I mean let me show
you, okay? So, there a wait.
Uh why is it on GitHub?
I forgot. Why did I put on GitHub?
What?
Okay, because I think because it's huge.
Uh
Wait. So, why does it show why does it
not show? Unable to render code block.
What's going on with the GitHub?
Okay, so it's a huge PDF, okay? So,
let's see math books. Anyway, there's
quite a few.
Yeah, so they are in that they are open
source, okay? So, they are open source
books.
Um
So, because I I think it's because it's
huge PDF, so that's why
the GitHub page stopped rendering it.
No, but can you actually download it?
Uh something is going on on GitHub.
You see, this this this is a nasty thing
about all these websites.
So, let's see. So, can you actually
download it? Save pages.
Okay, so you can download.
Right.
That's right. Okay, so that's right. So
you can still download. That's good.
Okay, for example, this is a
open source calculus book. Okay.
You see there's a license there.
Gregory Hartman
uh calculus. Okay, so we you know, okay.
Okay, so I think that's it.
Um
Well, I was going to work on the math.
Turns out we didn't work on the math. We
talked about Bertrand Russell and we
talked about lots of things. Okay.
Um
So I've been talking for an hour. So
now
what do we do? So do we um
I can
Uh okay, I can continue to code this or
I can stop.
I think it's better I stop because I
talked for 1 hour about Bertrand Russell
and about
basically
education, learning mathematics
and about
textbooks.
People like male live streamers because
they are rich and act with low
inhibition.
Uh
Okay, bye guys.
Yeah, so
So, this thing this thing is about
drawing a tangent, okay?
Creating a Wolfram language code to draw
the tangent. Uh
I'll do it offline.
Bye.