welcome welcome welcome welcome welcome
welcome to another episode of saw talk
show I am your host Solly and let's
begin streaming streaming the modern
technology and let's go to Twitter crash
classic live streaming okay you have to
wait for it even though technology is so
advanced but you still have to wait for
it
and should I go to Twitter and tell
people I am live it's kind of late ok so
we are here and let me pop out this
window as usual you coming see my show
my talk show and you type questions
there and I'll talk about anything so
first of all San talk show and let's
give a date good morning break the loop
how's your morning
so let me fix the title first and yeah
so guys you know whoever you are coming
coming on you know just go to the
website this website and below the the
info box on YouTube and go there and
pick a topic just type it and I'll talk
about that topic
I had a great sleep break the loop
mine's good just finished having
breakfast breakfast is good I had a I
had Chinese shouts shouts so how do you
say that in English dumplings okay
Chinese dumplings you know you buy a bag
so if you guys in California you know
except at least you know in Super Mario
you know San Francisco Bay Area
you can go to there's a Chinese market
called Ranch 99 and you can buy these
dumplings Chinese
dumplings let's see dumplings
now let's go to okay so guys speak a
topic okay go to course our talk show
page and pick topic now this is how dumb
thing looks now they look delicious you
know back in Taiwan my my grandmom my
dad's mom used to make these
so by hand you know manually you you
make the dough dough you know floor and
water you make a dough and you row it
then then you row it into a strip like a
cylinder strip then you cut you know one
one piece out then you flatten it you
know then you got a little about this
size flat very thing though then you put
meat into it and you seal it then it
looks like that this this these are
dumplings break the loop good morning
alie
addy were you from I always like to ask
that like what country so so break the
loop says I did a little JavaScript
programming and gonna continue so why
are you learning Java so I mean so what
yeah are you learning Java for job
reasons or for something so anyway
there's something so you go to the
wrench market so in California there is
there's a market called wrench market
wrench 99 okay actually there you know
yeah so it looks like that it's a chain
store so basically they sell Chinese
food stuff so you can go there and you
can pick up like you know like a bag you
know $3 or $4 oh they are you know more
experienced 'iv ones like six or nine
dollars okay a bag of Chinese dumplings
then you you can just pull your them you
have to make them manually so let's go
back let's go to San talk show and let's
start talking about some topic some
serious topics of humanity of the human
animals so good morning good morning
Adi good morning DeYoung good morning
Kuwait oh my god Eddie is from Kuwait
you know it's funny
good morning Erin so di is from Southern
California and we are you from Erin so
you know I got my followers tends to be
around the world I mean even though I
you know I only use you know I basically
all my blocks are English but Americans
typically you know so so what I'm saying
is that disproportionally I have more
followers outside of USA in you know
Japan Germany Israel South Africa and
some other African countries I've seen
and you know and of course China - you
know China and Taiwan and Hong Kong so I
mean so it is it seems to me okay I
don't have I don't really have the
statistics seems to me that my followers
tends to be I mean this proportionally
outside of USA because you know I kind
of that's my guess okay but I kind of
guessed why because he you will say you
know I attack the American things all
the time you know before it was
conservatives you know God believing
conservatives and now it's the social
justice can and does the San Francisco
the Bay Area programmers they are like
you know they are all like nice and they
want to help the world and to to the
situation today we have the worst word
possible so they kind of shown me you
know I get annoyed about that too
because you know like you know you
it's hard to say you know it's hard to
deal with these kind of problems because
you can say you know I you know I have
many acquaintances you know and I'm you
know for example if we go to Twitter on
Emacs you know like all the Emacs staff
know me know me okay you know it's hard
to talk to them about oops wait what's
going on okay it's hard to talk to them
about things because especially today
you know especially today under the
social justice era because you can't
think you can't and you cannot say
things you know it's like you know it
becomes to such a degree anything
outside of you know programming you
cannot say it you cannot talk about it
because almost everything becomes
controversial you can you cannot and
then then the another problem is that
you cannot talk to women anymore female
you know like once you talk to them that
this is a situation where it will have a
hold on a second you know you are you
you know it's gonna be it's gonna be a
problem you know that you go are you are
you harassing me or something you know
so but if you don't talk to them then oh
my god it's another problem are you are
you you you are you know sexist because
you don't talk to women it's so bad you
know like I can tell you I can actually
cite examples like today you know like
Emacs you know my Emacs Twitter account
ago Emacs start ago Emacs Twitter okay I
mean you know so we I mean these things
are hard to talk about I mean a lot of
these people I know and some of them
follow me right I'm not saying you know
they are I mean it's just like you
cannot talk about this anything anything
out outside of technical topics I mean
also if you observe them you know also
they like they they are very it seems
like every day they are all you know all
these typically white programmers so
okay they they are you know you look at
their poll
okay I have I follow you know some of
the I have to login so let's login and
let's go Emacs go Emacs okay okay Emacs
password okay
you know so you know you look at their
treats you know some of these technical
people you can clearly see that they all
say today they have also become let's
see followings okay say password no
never save anything to the browser's
okay you could use these people okay
this guy is a keyboard fan hi Troy if
you are watching I mean okay I'm you
know it's so what so what I'm saying is
it's a hard topic to say you know it's
not like I don't like them you know it's
even mentioning that that is a problem
what do you mean you don't like them you
mean implicitly you already don't like
them no but you know so they are my
acquaintances and some of them are my
friends and you know I'm following them
but many of you and you look at their
post you know - they are like they avoid
you know easy you can tell you know they
avoid they de consciously avoid anything
they only talk about and phrasing when
you know talk they only limit themselves
to you know very technical or very
general facing topics nothing
controversial yeah I mean you know you
know so so people has become that you
know - it's it's pretty bad yeah and you
know sometimes I you know I talked some
sometimes I'll reply to some of them
because McSally twitter account you know
i tends to talk about anything so you
have a situation where they I can tell
you know they they cannot readily talk
to me because because then they are
associating with someone you know
potentially bad yeah
so so anyway so let's read the comments
and it's start talking about something
did a little bit of Java gonna continue
where you are talking in a background
Chinese dumpling is the best
good morning Ali ABI Ali is from Kuwait
yeah that's amazing
Kuwait break the loop says no in Java
for for test automation at work oh ok
test automation and also long-term I
would like to create an Android app ok
that's good you know I Android app it's
it's unfortunate to me that Google you
know choose Java for Android at all so I
find it fun to do programming challenge
problems yes
good morning Deon good morning Erin oh
did you already talk about compile
compile no I haven't talked about how
compiler this works so maybe let's talk
about that how compiler walk I'm just
you know I can I can give a introduction
that's what I that's all I can do you
know I haven't written a compiler by you
know so but you know most vast majority
99.999 programmers have not written a
compiler in fact 99.999% of programmers
who you know make a living programming
they don't even know the basic steps of
how a compiler works so maybe i talked
about that
oh yeah Deon is from London baby so
welcome Paris might be a big topic you
can talk about what you are in a mood
okay
beyonce is sorry chad is very widespread
over the maybe because you have so many
pages about unicode addiction to
politics rots the brain anyone here know
much about deep learning yeah I don't
know anything about I don't know
anything about deep learning or machine
learning I haven't learned it
yes I mean that machine anything you
know I like to but actually that's not
what I want to study you know machine
learning is fashionable today you know
we can write because Google and you know
Facebook Auto you know machine driving
you know automated driving cars and
stuff is so about AI
however you know note that it's not AI
artificial intelligence it's very that
is one branch of science that is very
you know it's a good it's a big subject
and it's very the the thing about
machine learning or artificial
intelligence or deep learning is that
it's very commercial enterprise meaning
that I mean it's also a academic very
deep academic subject but meanwhile it
has a special status of being extremely
commercial look commercially look at
lucrative or even powerful today because
you know it's said that you know whoever
creates the best a I drew of the world
basically you know we are entering AI
age you know artificial intelligence age
so it so as an academic subject by
itself it's very deep and interesting
but also it has a kind of unique status
being mean while also extremely
commercially lucrative okay however many
other academic subjects in the sciences
they are extremely deep even deeper than
artificial intelligence however they
have no commercial value basically no
immediate commercial value for example
cosmology black hole physics you know
atomic physics okay well there is
nanotechnology and and quantum computing
you know that's
rice but still I mean theoretical
physics okay that's a big thing
theoretical physics is you can study
them for 10 years there's no there's not
even a job for you okay and then there's
mathematics there's proof systems you
know huge huge you know math is like the
the the the the the so the core of all
Sciences or physical sciences or hard
sciences including programming or
computer science so in this math area
again it's like very deep deeper than
artificial intelligence okay the machine
learning whatever that but it's not
there has no immediate commercial value
and also and some of the topics do not
even have immediate applicability but
but however it cannot be said you know
it must be emphasized that these some
many of these almost all math math
subjects they are so deep at the end II
I mean it's true they don't have
immediate application but they are like
the fundamental questions like they they
are extremely important okay let's put
it that way and you know the thing about
math is that there's a saying okay
basically all math is after is applied
math it's just a matter of time
for example yeah cryptocurrency that's
another you know cryptography that's
also very deep math subjects and I don't
know much about it it ties into a number
theory and and lots of other very deep
advanced math but anyway let me give you
an example where you know it said that
oh maths pure math or whatever all math
is of right math it's just a matter of
time for example the conic sections let
me give you some
let me just talk about that for example
sorry curves okay so this is sorry a
visual dictionary hiccup excuse me
visual dictionary of playing curves this
this is a project I did in the 1990s
okay and you recognize hyperbola you
probably know you know you're studying
high school or college you know it's
like boring hyperbola okay I purpose
okay oh let's show some some animations
you know these are always interesting so
I read this this is backing I wrote this
in 1995 okay so in Mathematica so you
can see well I'm not going to explain
about them but but so anyway hyperbola
and parabola now parabola you've seen
everyday actually para is the most okay
let me explain about this parabola okay
let's go here so anyway the conic
sections okay let me explain a little
bit about conic sections then we then
I'm gonna explain so one way to define
parabola is that parabola is a curve
such that such that you draw a line any
line okay you given a plane you draw a
line and draw a point not on the line
okay so given the line at a point okay
anywhere in a plane you draw a line you
draw a point okay then parabola is such
a curve that it has equal distance
between on our second let's see if this
works
okay you see this red line here this red
line here you see they are equidistant I
mean this the distance from here to here
and here to here is the same so here's a
lie
I mean this line is a given line and
this point is a given point okay it's
just like given you know it's just a
given point then then you can see thank
parabola is is a curve such that it's a
set of all points that that is the
distance from from that point to the
given point and to the line is equal so
that's how you get parabola okay you can
see in other words another way another
way to do it is that you draw a circle
anyway
I'm not going to go into details okay
but you can see so that's parabola
that's one of the definition of parabola
but however there are so many others
okay that's that's so interesting about
math because there are so many ways that
makes them together so here's an example
of parabola you see this every day a car
you know the headlamp of a car so
parabola has the property that you know
the you shine a lot for example this one
okay you see this orange curve that's a
parabola and this red point suppose it's
a light source my my neighbors you know
they are clean does cleaning the street
so it's making noises let me close the
window
okay so I'm back
so parabola has these optical properties
so you shine a light light and they
reflect off the mirror and they shoot
out straight provided that if the point
is at the right position that point is
the same point when we you know it's
called a focus okay
so you can see here is a parabola and
here is another parabola and that's its
focus and here the green curve is also
another parabola so you know they you
know they shoot the Rays straight
now if the point is at different places
then the way the light weight will will
not be straight so that's one
application of parabola okay then
there's so many other interesting
properties okay and let me show you
okay I have lots of photos actually but
okay that that that okay and and okay so
so here's our table then the and Oh
Annie Lisp okay Elyse is one of the also
very interesting one
Elyse okay Elyse is a curve that such
that given two point the set of all
points that has the same distance to
these two given points forms a lisp that
that is the defining definition of lee
elise one of the definitions okay and
there are many other properties such
that you can generate the ellipse by
mechanical means okay mechanical meaning
like [ __ ] we also pulley so you know you
know linkages you know things like that
so here is the example of a link kind of
a linkage that generates a lisp ellipse
okay so so anyway many properties okay
and at least can also be generated by
rolling a circle now many machines you
know cause you want to converts motion
you know into a different rotational
motion into a linear motion things like
that that's applied but anyway and also
if you have a cylinder and if you cut it
through a plane that shape you know he's
actually also an ellipse ellipse meaning
that this shape you know satisfies all
these properties about the Lisp you know
such as equal such as for example there
exist two points inside this circular
shape such that any point on the Elise
is it has equal distance to to you know
these two points so so you see the so
all these parabola hi
Alysse they are all called conic
sections why they are called conic
sections because if you have a cone and
you cut it then the the intersection the
the yeah the internship is sections are
one of a list a parabola or hyperbola
okay so so all these amazing properties
now the point I want to make is that
these conic sections okay all the six
things so far I've talked about all
these properties they are known packing
the Greeks you know by the Greeks like
two thousand or two thousand three
thousand years ago why do they know it
because they that's pure math they just
study this out of pure curiosity okay
there's no application well there is
some such as you know the the mirrors
you know anyway you know mathematicians
back then studied these conic section
curves out of curiosity but you know
today we have rockets right we went to
the moon we shoot rockets to the moon it
turns out you know the gravity gravity
the Newtonian physics you know gravity
and how things move you know they are
all based on conic sections theories of
conic sections like certain you know
earth move around the Sun in a
elliptical path and essentially yeah the
Sun is the focus you know remember we
talked about at least before conic
sections let's go to you know Elise
ellipses you know this so the why in the
middle that's a focus that's a Sun and
any of the path is conic section you
know it turns out you know planets move
evolve around the Sun
you know elliptical paths so it becomes
extremely applicable you know we found
conic sections without the theories of
conic sections you do not you cannot
send people to the moon you cannot you
know fly rockets and stuff and also when
you shoot a cannon like where does the
Canon lens you know when you shoot it
you know before before we have missiles
you know we have cannons you know a big
gun you should stone up and you land on
the enemy's territory so but you need to
find out at what angle you will land
queer and that's conic sections that's
parabola you know that that that is
parabola which is one of the conic
sections the parabola with these optical
properties you know so all these you
know but the Greeks studied them like
two thousand more than two thousand
years ago and pure purely for interests
you know curiosity but there is you know
heavy applications like almost like two
thousand years later now that's one
example where pure math becomes
extremely applied math okay of topic
Queen okay and the other thing is is the
let me give you a another example you
know the cryptography okay when you want
to shop on Amazon you have to swipe
credit card you know that that relies on
cryptography which is among programmers
so the most popular topic you know or
the programmers Trevo like when you talk
about cryptography all the programmers
gets excited oh my god is you know they
want to they think it's some fantastic
topic but cryptography it's based on and
on the number theory okay number theory
okay I'm not going to get into no I'm
not okay but I'm not going to talk about
number theory but I mean I'm not going
to explain what it is but anyway number
theory
was a pure math topic people study it
purely for curiosity reasons you know
again like 2,000 years ago and today
becomes it becomes cryptography
cryptography is in essence the bulk of
cryptography cryptanalysis it's all you
know especially today's public key let's
see exactly
PGP public key cryptography and new PG
good new privacy guard okay let's look
at that
PGP tutorial let's open that and public
key cryptography for beginner open that
so I have a introduction to new PG okay
you can you can read and I have a
introduction to public key cryptography
for beginners you know I am just I don't
know the subject you know I'm just
giving you a introduction which is good
enough to programmers ok so you can read
you can start to understand what does
key means what does you know how it is
done you know you get the basic idea
then you can if you like the subject you
know you you could study it but it's you
know if you really I mean the the the
heart of the subject is is advanced math
ok to know that to understand the math
behind public key cryptography you have
have you have to have a math degree that
meaning that you have to study four
years of undergraduate math to begin
with okay that's just that just means
you are ready to actually study the
theory the number theory okay sorry math
textbooks and let me just mention
another one here are some free math
books you can read I talked about this
in my in Saudi talk show before okay
there is actually no well there's a
basic number theory but basic number
theory they don't cover cryptography we
you you you know today's cryptography is
rather it's it's beyond basic number
theory but you know if you are curious
you can read this introduction to number
theory book you know it's elementary
number theory okay now number theory
this is written by Edwin [ __ ] I you know
my we are acquaintances you know kind of
a little bit but anyway you know but
yeah so that's the introduction to
number theory okay so back to so
cryptography is a example where it's
pure math you know people are studying
number theory just for the sake of you
know extremely interesting things but
now today it has application you know in
cryptography which is which is the or
important or the most important thing
for the web essentially it becomes not
for just for the web but between
militaries you know militaries cellphone
you know you know it becomes the most
powerful thing pure math okay so where
are we talking about pure math because
we were talking about
I forgot okay let me read some questions
and then let's talk about good time 34
minutes let's let's let's talk about an
introduction to compilers you know like
introduction to how compiler works okay
that's I cannot give an introduction to
compilers actually because I don't you
know I'm not qualified okay so let me
read the check the comments oh yeah so I
know why I'm talking about pure math and
you know how how pure math becomes
applied math so we were talking about
artificial intelligence you know machine
learning and you know data mining
machine learning whatever they call it
you know neural networks you know the
fashionable things you know today every
programmer is like a machine learning
machinery [ __ ] them you know [ __ ] the
elite pop programmers you know the
hacker news every day hacker news and
read it so anyway so I was saying AI you
know the subject AI is very interesting
and deep academic topic okay but however
it has the distinction where it is also
extremely commercially lucrative
inapplicable it not just to commercial
not not just make money but to the
government military you know military
that is you know you you have AI you
control things you know because we are
entering into a aih you know machine
robotics you know the you see how you
know the robots you know the parts they
can run you think they can you know you
most of you have seen you know you know
the past and dynamics you know parts
robots and they can run like a cheetah
they can there's also parts that can fly
like a bird you know with wings like
flapping wings they are also like
microbots you know they quote on a wall
whatever they are also parts that can
swim like a fish you know
not by a propeller but you know moving
the way like a fish moves and there are
parts that you know like a spider there
are parts like all kind of like snake
they move like the way snake moves you
know by different type of locomotion
okay I mean so there are bars and they
are a I so we are entering this age so
the AI becomes extremely important but
it's let's get back to the topic okay ai
so it's fashion it's very commercial and
very active applicable immediately and
in fact it is an urgency because all the
countries need to get these need to
compete to have to prepare to make
progress in this area because it has
significant consequences you know
whoever has the most powerful AI
significant consequences
now keep your comments going okay I'll
read them and you know anything
interesting your opinions just type it
so what I'm saying about AI okay so yeah
but AI but I haven't myself haven't
really studied any machine learning I
haven't studied neural networks I
haven't studied cryptic what cryptology
other than just you know basic no
knowing what it is you know so why not
well because because also remember these
are deep academic topics but meanwhile
also have very extreme act you know
commercial value and you know
applications but however there are lots
of you know huge amount of other
academic topics in maths you know for
example math let's just focus on math
okay in math they are extremely deviant
even far more deeper than artificial
intelligence yes okay deeper you know
the the question in this math you know
they their question is is even deeper
than artificial intelligence but however
he is
thing however they do not have immediate
applicability okay one example if is the
foundation of mathematics
you know the topics in math that that
are associated with the foundation of
math or inputted in other way logic
systems proof systems ok homotopy type
theory for example okay these subjects
you know as I mentioned before they they
are equally deep then then to AI or
cryptography even deeper because they
they they answer some of the fundamental
questions about in a sense they it's
like in physics you answer some of the
fundamental questions in physics or
cosmologies like the history of the
universe okay for example black hole for
example cosmology the shape of the
universe for example you know so what
happens before the universe you know big
pan or you know not Big Bang but what
happens before you know so these are
kind of like very extremely fundamental
questions and also other questions like
you know mind and body you know how does
what does this all mean
but anyway but however if you study
these topics black hole you you don't
you don't you know you study it for 20
years in this no job for you if you are
good if you are extremely good maybe you
become a professor and that's all you
get same okay so this these are like
fundamental questions in physics physics
okay
and you know string theory the you know
the the the the the the grand theory of
the everything you know those are you
know theoretical physics okay there's no
immediate award for you okay also person
okay
but it's extremely important in a same
way okay logic some of the foundation of
math proof systems homotopy type theory
these are fundamental questions about
math in some sense more even more
important than whatever
physics okay I don't like physics [ __ ]
the physicists you know so because
everything about physics is ultimately
based on math UK so math you have these
foundation math questions you know
gödel's theorem most of you know heard
of it you know so so because they you
know they are phenomena but they don't
have immediate applicability okay for
example in a sense that you cannot
commercialize them like you cannot make
money out of it fast you know so that's
a situation so that's a situation but so
the thing is I am interested okay a is
great I'm interested you know
cryptography is great I'm also
interested but but some of the math
topics I'm interested proof systems you
know I'm far more interested in that
okay you know or you know some or some
of the you know they are tied to
theoretical computer science okay so
what can I do you know so all the young
people like say oh do you know AI do you
know machine learning I know I don't
know what you mean but I'm interesting
it the other things and they never like
they don't even like the thing about fad
in fashion in the hacker news [ __ ] is
that they you know all the young people
you learn you know that basically the
fad things you know they even they don't
even know they are not aware that there
is this foundation of math you know
logic systems they are not aware of it
what is that you know like that is a
problem you know so that is problem for
me you know because you know because it
doesn't feel right okay so anyway so
let's check the comments then maybe we
go on to the so yeah I like to know deep
learning but I don't know where no ever
I'm going to learn it because because
they are things they
you know about proof systems I want to
learn I want to really
for example this for example here is 1/3
math textbooks ok if you go down and in
this and complex analysis I also like to
know differential geometry I mean I like
to have I mean that's that's the area I
want to you know go topology I don't
really care about apology for example
the here here is some logic books you
know here is a mathematical logic you
know ok and introduction to prove theory
ok foundation of math ok how much of a
type theory ok now if you are a Haskell
if you are fat followers you know from
the hacker news [ __ ] in Haskell you know
you probably heard of this homotopy type
theory you know but you know it's it's
very interesting because if you want to
read this mathematical logic you know
it's this book for example free book it
takes you need it's a graduate level ok
all these are graduate level meaning
that you cannot begin to read it until
you have four years of undergraduate
math meaning that you are a math major
you know meaning that you already know
you already had a course in abstract
algebra you already have had a causing
differential geometry complex analysis
we are as analysis you know four years
of study math then then you can read
this book but actually it doesn't well
yeah well actually it doesn't actually
require you to know all those things you
can start to read this book but it's
pretty dry it's pretty dry though
but anyway so so that's about these and
and this homotopy type theory also you
know I tried to read it I cannot you
know I can not care
it's I'm not at the level to actually
ready you know understand the book okay
but so I want to show you another thing
okay so sorry keyboard you can see sorry
keyboard okay keyboard let's go to
battle stations
[Laughter]
nerd battle stations okay let's look at
some of the pictures okay let's see how
are we doing how am i doing
Finch good morning Finch Schumacher
no actually wait I can't answer that
question but hold on a second so here is
a collection of nerds battle stations
basically their you know their desktop
you know their computers you know their
their desk
you know either at home or at work you
can see some of these nerds
you know equipment you know computers
mouse keyboard and whatever devices
gaming gaming gig you know the gaming
community they could gig stupid gamers
and by the way similarly for programmers
in hacker community you also have like
specific jargons you know basically each
community you have these kind of jargons
so anyways these are the battle stations
of you know some of the interesting ones
i collected so this guy got a
synthesizer okay that's a controller i
you know it's called so called keyboard
controller okay but then you run through
this one look look at this one guys this
one is spectacular
okay it does not look spectacular but it
is let me show you okay there there are
some interesting ones okay and this girl
for example this one is very nerdy okay
right it looks like matrix and in many
of these for example this guy you know
these computers are expensive expensive
computer expensive microphone it's
expensive headphone that's their
headphone is like 100 or 200 dollars you
know oh and Emacs mug okay so you see
all these fancy ones fancy systems this
these speakers are like you know 200 or
400 something like that but okay now
look at now look at this one this guy
you know this guy is a very poor guy now
look look at his monitor this is what
the 2000
2005 and look at that keyboard it's
dirty and that by the way this this
photo are collected you know in 2009 to
two months ago mm knife every so look at
this guy so he's using you know this
keyboard this keyboard is like $15 $20
and it's like year 2000 this is a
Microsoft Comfort Curve keyboard okay I
had I had that before so very cheap
keyboard and you know very cheap you
know this headset you can see it's like
you know very cheap things however he's
got books here look you know I checked
this book now the one at the bottom you
know it says is homotopy type theory
okay Cromartie type theory that is this
book and I've read this book okay
I've have I have tried to read this book
and I know you cannot read this book
until you have like not just not not
even just undergraduate degree you kind
of often after the after you have a
degree in math you have to have certain
specialization in logic in in the
foundation of math okay improve systems
then actually your head yeah then okay
then then you can maybe understand you
know I understand I mean like you can
actually read the book and make sense
you know like you actually read off
something like learn something you know
Kamata p-type theory so so this guy this
poor guy is is have this book on there
and I checked the other books okay then
then the other one this one is the the
okay let me show you that one it's hard
to read
it's that book SiC the structure and
interpretation of computer programs now
now this book is actually not difficult
to read so that's that book let me put
it down and so there's a Japanese
version and there's some funny pictures
ok so that's that book and the one on
top I forgot what it is the yellow one
this white and yellow thing that's
that's a style of cover from the
publisher Springer who who are
specialized in math textbooks I forgot
what it is but I might have mentioned it
here oh yeah so the book is with a book
yeah I so I I don't know which one is
the math book but but I'm guessing some
graduate level math book
your battle station okay let's see
Dion's battle station yeah okay not bad
Python okay cool
so let's read a comment then maybe we
start to talk about compilers can we
still do that yeah I think so
talking about compilers you know ten
minutes you know just an introduction so
let's see let me check the comments then
okay Deion say is from the little bit
I've learned about deep learning it's
not a mathematical deep subject okay all
you need to understand his chain rule of
differentiation okay well those math
animations on your website are cool
thank you
interesting okay did you create those
math JavaScript graph those are not
JavaScript those are mathematical
Mathematica animations created in
Mathematica and converted to gif like
five years ago I converted to give
before it was quick time but but the
encoding used is like out of you know
it's it's deprecated deprecated so I
anyway so my plan is to actually use
JavaScript to code JavaScript to replace
everything on this website but I just
haven't done them you know cuz this yeah
and okay it's read the comments good
morning addy I think job job
this one is Gia it's called Yad Gibran
okay now speaking of geogebra
that's a
very sad story again okay geogebra was a
open source project and it is written in
Java
let's show you some interesting ones
okay asteroid comes construction I
didn't write them okay but in you let me
tell you the story
[Music]
let me show some easy ones so that
people can I mean I want to show some
brainless ones because those was always
you know I want to show something that
spectacular also brainless because the
savants more complex require you to
explain when you show something that's
you know people can easily see it then
that's good material for you know for
popular popularization you know
typically that's the situation but
anyway here says let me show you what
this does okay this this one is called
Trammell asteroid tram oh okay you see
this curve this blue one this
star-shaped four points that curve is
called as asteroid okay and what is a
tremor tremor is Macan is a mechanism
okay it's like a linkage you know like
like when you see the train you know
when you see diesel train you know steam
engine train where the wheels there's a
bar you know all right you know it
translates rotational motion to linear
motion those are called linkages
okay linkage now Tremmel is one of those
type of mechanism so what is a tremor
tremor is this red bar you see this red
bar you see how this red bar moves
that's a tremor so so how does it work
basically the this red bar so you have
two perpendicular bars okay
this red bar is a fixed length and slide
around this to perpendicular boss you
know they just slide it slide around it
so when they slide around it then they
will trace out you see they will trace
out the asteroid you can see the bar is
always always tangent to the asteroid
curve okay so that's how you can create
the asteroid curve using this Tremmel
this mechanism you know this physical
mechanism I mean people have speeded you
you know if you just search the web
asteroid tremor you can see you know
people have made you know wooden stuff
you know and it was also used you know
hundreds or years ago you know for doing
stuff you know machinery you know it's a
Industrial Revolution machinery
okay that's asteroid but however there's
another thing very interesting now if
you fix a point on this spot then you
move the bar it will trace out the curve
and that curve is Elise you see how
interesting it is because it traced out
a curve it is it is meaning that this is
a curve such that it has the property
with two special points called focus you
know we talked about it is so anyway so
you can see that this are kind of all
the properties you know of these curves
are interconnected so that's one of the
wonders of math you know you don't
really it's really hard to explain why
they are they are all interconnected in
such a wonderful way that's yeah that's
that's one of the deep wonders of math
okay so anyways so that that experience
about the curve okay now the now the
application I am using is called
geogebra ok geogebra is an application
it's open so
written in Java okay back back in 2005
or something like that and you can
download the source code but but then
JavaScript became popular you know in
Java you know Java for the web you know
it's called Java applet it was beginning
to be face out in fact Google is the
first one Google Chrome kicked out the
java application the the framework
children chat
Java apps you know in a web basically is
so you have ten thousand you know
hundred thousand Java apps on a web you
know one day it's all did good
you know by the way same thing happened
to flash remember flash you know it's
everywhere but Apple in this case Apple
decided you know they don't want fresh
so flash got face out good and Java got
got Java you know Java apps for the way
I've got kicked out by Google begin with
Google so today no basically no browser
supports it so so that's a problem for
geogebra
you know because geogebra is written in
Java and it's used on the web you know
wrapped in Java app Java applet it's
called effort okay so what they gonna do
they gonna they need to transform I mean
they need to rewrite it you know they
need to port it to JavaScript okay they
did but however you know it's you're so
open source okay this is so-called
open source but however you cannot you
cannot download the JavaScript code you
cannot in any in fact you know and they
you can you cannot find the converter
you know to to convert your files from
the Java format into the JavaScript
basically you cannot do it okay so I
created all these you know I'd like I
have like 60 of them okay you know for
doing math you
showing all these illustrations of a
visual demonstration interactive visual
demonstration of many of these curves
properties ok so I have like 60 of them
then this switch happens so I want to
you know get you know I used to algebra
because I it's open-source you know so I
can you know I can keep using it but now
they switch JavaScript and there's no
way you cannot do it but if you look
then they said you know the the geogebra
is very big now you know he's kind of
big in math community okay they have
like oak non traffic organ
you so concerned applies to open-source
ok you guys may not agree but that's my
opinion you know so they so what they do
so what they do they what what they do
is that they created a you know a
website where basically what they did is
like they went to the cloud
ok so if you want to show some you know
math you know stuff like before you have
to use their cloud hosted by their
website that's what happened let's see
no now this is actually you know this is
still my domain but it's actually not on
my web site
I forgot but it bit you know it's not
really much on my web site you you have
to like let me show you sorry you know
basically they create this cloud and
they say you know what they say is that
oh we decided we need to you know create
this JavaScript you know on a cloud so
that so that we help the community you
know math community and the educators
something something you know they always
have reasons right but basically this is
this is a phenomenon of the scums of the
open source ok because you know all the
open source and free software foundation
facts richard stallman
use
you know you want yeah how people but
but this applies to any anyone okay you
you write open-source that's great as
soon the moment your open source project
has some kind of a little bit commercial
value you can start making money
immediately it stops being open source
everyone does it you know you you might
say oh either I won't do it but you'll
happen to you especially when you don't
have a job okay with you you know so so
this happens so so so what they do is
that let's see for example let's go here
this is one of the one of my
but anyway I have to well they have a
cloud okay I'm not going to find it you
know I can't find it in within a minute
but I'm not gonna do it but basically
they create a cloud and they basically
they don't want you you know they don't
want to just like give the JavaScript
source code so you can do whatever you
know they don't want to do that because
once once they do that they don't have a
business anymore
you know that's the source of open
nature of open source but so they always
come up with ways similarly for Google
and all these open source comes Apple
and Google you know Google make your day
a browser free suppose the open source
but actually similar for Apple it's not
something you can just grab and do you
know in order for example Google Chrome
is supposed to open source right okay so
I want to create my own I can't you know
like why Cannot you the open source the
source code is there you to actually do
that you basically you have to have like
10 years experience you know dedicated
dedicated in that specific field to be
able to even barely create your own
browser okay things like that I mean the
bottom line is that they do think they
do what they can to prevent actually
prevent the ultimate goal of open source
that is for everyone just scrap and
create their own version because once
they do that then who's gonna use Google
Chrome you know every Joe can have a
browser you know just like that you know
why don't they just create an app so
that you just click and create your own
browser you know they are not going to
do that but meanwhile they always sing
the songs of open source oh we are so
great we help humanity we are open
source Google Chrome is open source this
and that that it's all a lie ok so I you
know that's my opinion
if you don't acquiesce that's fine but
you know so I think you know today you
know I talked about this topic before
you know I you know before like 20 years
ago I was a big fan of Richard Stallman
in fact
the free software foundation but not
today
I think we should well I should mention
you know many of the ideas you know
anyway yeah let's forget about that
topic so let's let's see about okay it's
the how many let's see that let me go
back to read the comments and okay so
maybe that's so maybe we're gonna talk
about the compilers next day then
tomorrow okay
Schumacher Schumacher says that I see
you click on ICU clicks to activate your
window but you suggest different methods
on your site okay well the reason he
said okay you see I'm a efficiency nerd
so I have lots of sorry why why tiling
window sucks okay here here is a
extremely popular article that's being
on reddit and a hacker news multiple
times for some reason this article
becomes extremely popular and this
article I talk about efficiency of
operating your computer you know what's
the best way moving windows switching
applications and say and so on and
basically the two things I recommend is
that you should set a key okay on your
keyboard to switch apps okay I'm not
going to go into details because I have
talked about that in previous talks and
also you can read the article but anyway
I give some recommendations and one of
them is to set a key for example f10 to
switch to browser so when I want to
switch to browser let's go back here you
know like right now I want to switch
browsers
I should just press a key okay but I'm
not
in that now I'm using the auto click
actually I'm using auto click I'm not
clicking you know you can see you know
if I show you my fingers you know I just
move the mouse I move the mouse here you
see I'm not clicking who's I opened that
by mistake what is this you see I don't
click you know and the way I used mouse
the mouse is I don't like actually hold
it you know because that strains your
hand you know I just I just nudge it you
know usually I like I put our hand like
here just pay oops yeah so basically you
know I don't hold it you know I touch it
as as little as possible so so this is
another way I recommend which is called
trail or Auto Creek you know and I have
talked about how to do it on this page
and I've also give instructions for Mac
and Linux Windows 10 removed that option
kind of anyway so why am i why am I not
using the single key to switch apps
because because now I'm using this
keyboard and the function keys are tiny
okay so it's not actually convenient I
recommend you know one in one of my
articles I have talked about the
function keys when you buy a keyboard
the function keys must be you know pick
a keyboard where you have big normal
function keys so because of this reason
you know I cannot you know use of
function keys and this keyboard does not
have that many keys therefore what can
you do so I you know don't have that
convenient method anymore you know on
the other hand you know I have this
keypad in the middle or these keypad are
they are programmed to do things for
example close window okay let me show
you here for example cross window we
open it
okay magnify magnify shrink previous tab
previous tab previous tab next tab
refresh you know it so single key
pressed operations and all the keys are
used I don't have I don't have spare
keys to make them you know switch into
Emacs you know like you have hundred
commands like I mentioned before you
have hundred commands but you only have
like let's say ten keys or you have
thousand commands you have hundred keys
let's never you didn't think you never
have enough keys so you know some
operations you don't have a kingdom so
that's that's the reason so let's go
back to let's see go back to so that's a
question from chatter Makka pakka makka
pakka makka okay something like that
Finch says let's encrypt provided this
and free SSL cert verification Finch
says the Oregon summer school series all
the way back from 2011 provides decent
videos on proof theory type theory
category theory and other interesting
topic
oh now that one I need to I want to look
into
do you have a link by the way Finch can
you post a link organs summer school
can you so if you have a link if you
post it there'll be appreciated thank
you ok you know because generally
otherwise you usually get into these
lame pages you know then you don't know
what they are they
eventually they want your money you know
whatever that looks like my what that
photo okay I think I'm so behind in in
comments I just rant on about other
things wait a second okay let me keep
reading the comments and maybe that's it
for today let's let me get a drink
energy drink okay I've been drinking
energy drink for four years for five
years and I'm now thirsty now I'm like
talking you know everyday for one hour
and more and now I'm becoming like
lectures now and becoming like lecturers
you know in academia there is a
distinction between like when you give a
talk you know in some math conference
and so on you know the artist takes
distinction of titles that differentiate
the bank basically just like military
and and and corporations yeah I mean you
know cooperation in companies you have
you know CEO you're a financial fe EO
you have you know lead programmer
whatever you know you like you have a
like title to rank people so in the same
way you know in academic in academia you
know in these universities you have
professor okay that is the busy then you
have assistant professor okay that's
important because you don't want to
confuse like if you if you get it wrong
it it can be you know insulting you know
especially when it comes to credit you
know so you have professor you have
assistant professor then you have
lecturers lecturers is like like you
know you are not a professor
your lecture is lower lower rank so
anyway I've been talking every day now
I'm getting better yet you know
expressing my ideas the way I wanted you
know what I want to say and and other
things you know a bunch of and yeah when
you talk a lot you need to drink okay
some links are coming they let's show
them okay now I'm gonna just read off
the comments few more I think okay so
so yeah that application that math
application is called geogebra you know
you can just find on web you can use it
you know but I'm very so disappointed
with them because now I don't have
control like right now I mean oh these
all the hundreds you know the 60 or so
applications I've written you know I've
created they and by the way this is jino
be even before geogebra I was using
others but it's also again you know it's
a long story it's before geogebra
there's one called geometers sketchpad
okay which which actually connects
through the history of programming you
know the the invention of mouse the you
know the smart programming languages you
know it's course geometers sketchpad
geometers sketchpad and which is from
the idea of sketch pad which is from the
idea of a very very innovative
programmer and designer in archie tech
who basically invented the mouse and who
invented kind of the internet link and
something like that what's his name I
forgot anyway anyone remember his name
he died like few years ago you know it's
like the mother of all demo yeah that
he's his famous the mother of demo he is
a very very famous it relates to the
this guy Douglas Engelbart okay yeah
anyway so you can read Wikipedia about
it and there's YouTube you can see okay
yeah Doug Douglas Engelbart yes thank
you Finch
let's see how many people are watching
now
am i okay eight minute eight people I'm
I'm kind of done let me just read
question-and-answers like read the
comments in as a few questions in that
is it for today for today April 13th
Saturday and I hope you guys have a good
Saturday enjoy your Saturday so let's
see yeah let me read the comments
okay question your thoughts on
cryptography on the web today I think we
kind of talked about that it's very
important
oh I my website is not using HTTPS
because you know usually you need to pay
to get that HTTPS cert but I heard
there's a free one
but I just haven't looked into I just
never looked into and I don't like
Google you know Google kind of pushed
idea you know they basically they want
to eliminate every website that's not
HTTPS you know you know other
programmers it's like oh yeah you know
for most security but I think this is
kind of a sinister move it's kind of a
devious you see so from now on you know
Google decided this like last year when
you have a site that's not HTTPS it will
say you know not secure scumbag Google
why is a sinister because you know to
force everyone to HTTPS you know HTTPS
is kind of more complicated you have to
get the certificate also even if you are
you is using HTTPS okay there's lots of
going on underneath it okay it's not
well it's secure but it's not it's not
like hundred percent because the the
organization's which is big
organizations they run the certificate
there's lots of dark things happening
there okay
semantics and you know this speak giant
corporations they control things so so
you know for example back to a few years
ago Google Google and Symantec they have
a huge fight because google claims
blames you know
you can search the web search the words
I just talked about you'll find the
articles google claims as semantics is
abusing certificate for example they you
know like you know like bribery for
example i mean this may not be the true
case but for example i'm a government or
something okay i'm a bad guy but i got
money
hey semantics enemy you know let me pay
you this much and can make a certificate
for me but without these you know is
requirement something like that so
semantics says oh how much and big money
oh yeah okay let's let me do it okay
don't tell me any don't tell anyone okay
okay okay yeah good let's do it then so
you know so google is claiming that
semantic is doing that abusive you know
abusing the third power
you know semantic they bought the
certificate company from you know the
guy who began the leanness linux you
know open to you know open to guy yeah
ivan sutherland that's a sketch pad
creator yes yes but the geometers
sketchpad is a bit different but from
the same idea yeah anyway let me get
back to the topic so so yeah so what i'm
saying is that the certificate is very
complex going ons
you know under these corporations and
for average people you know it's it
takes one more level of sophistication
to create two to create a HTTP website
okay so when google makes this move when
Kouga wants to remove you know kind of
they want to eliminate all websites
that's not HTTP that's on a surface
appears good you know they always take
with them you know when marketing
department you know you know say all
their ideas to programmers trying to
convince programmers but i don't think
it's I don't think it's not that
that's simple okay then I think it's not
a simple thing so for example for me I
want to I need a suit what do I do I
have to pay you know each domain it used
to be like $50.00 a year I don't know
how much it is you know so I have to pay
to do that and my website is not a
ecommerce website I don't really need a
certificate you know so but Google
making this move is forcing it's
basically forcing the millions you know
obedience websites out there to do that
so so the consequence basically the
consequence is that they force they
eliminate the bottom lines you know the
average people eliminate their their
ideas you know whatever they can say
they becomes more corporate you know the
big giant players can pray that's what I
see at least this is one aspect okay but
the stupid [ __ ] programmers by this
hacker you need you know whatever even
including open-source you know they
don't see it that way because well not
necessarily that they are wrong but it's
just that I mean this is a complex issue
but they don't see it they only see one
thing that oh security is good everyone
should you know HTTP you know that's
that's the only thing they see and they
don't they don't think they've just what
is you need programmers you know they
did they just read hacker news every day
they just read they never like sit down
and like you know just just just just
sit down and think about like you can do
it today right now you know after the
video okay the cloud hug show you see
there and this neck for the next hour
you can go to with you know you can
spend with your family you can spend
with your girlfriend or wife or husband
or whatever okay watch your movie don't
do that
spend that one hour do nothing but think
about the situation of HTTP to HTTPS
like a philosopher okay no pain no gain
so you have to sacrifice your time to
play or whatever and just sit down and
think about this one simple issue among
the millions you know
in technology in programming think about
HTTP issues should it is it good or is
it bad what is the nature you know what
it does it take you know to require this
what does the technology how actually
work no there are so many ways you can
think about just think about this then
then then yeah after you have done this
for one hour then your opinion is good
you know that's not a case for the most
[ __ ] on the on a website they tell
you whenever this C should come up they
tell you oh you should you shoot this or
that or whatever you know crap the
printer springless means
okay so what what are we okay Finch says
sparrows malaise Malev Milewski provides
good foundational material in his books
and lectures but homotopy type theory is
very advanced indeed yeah I know that
guy's a little bit you know I looked
I've looked into east of I don't think
it's for me you know he died I haven't
you know I think he's a program turned
basically I don't well it's hard to say
yeah I don't want I don't really have a
comment yeah yeah but anyway I suppose
he's a good you see he's his background
his has cow okay
wait where I have someone whose
background his house car I don't want to
touch it okay it's it's it's it's likely
no good his background is programmer and
has cow and he's like into a category
theories category in my ass okay
category theory is another very
fashionable among programmers because
why because of Haskell okay now a
category theory I can you know the only
person I can trust
through the category theory is form from
mathematicians professional
mathematicians and even better if they
don't they know nothing about
programming by the way Haskell
category theory has cow is is a little
bit different not the Ryoka category
theory in math and also by the way I'm
not you know category theory and that's
not what I want to study category theory
can be used as a foundation of math but
as I mentioned before there are other
things you know I'm far more interested
in homotopy type theory anyway I don't
want to make too big issue out of this
because I don't really have the the
necessary necessary foundation to
actually
qualified to to say you know I like this
better than that you know I mean the
category theory and you know the math
foundation you know the real thing
things like that okay I was pronounced
sick P how do you guys sick
oh the the book sick I didn't pronounce
the P I always pronounce is sick so
Finch says like someone equipped like
someone equipped in a lisp talk once you
cannot have six without ICP interesting
ads where I don't I didn't even look at
that you know Google here's another
thing evil about Google you know I'm
running Google ads of course because I'm
really I'm you know I live under poverty
I mean the like the poverty among the
poverty okay
and so I have to you know I even googled
let's base achill II almost basically
the my sole income okay and they they
started to do all sort of things you
know anyway so it's Auto Creek focus
feature peered into Meg yes actually I
have article if you just search Saudi
trail you'll find it my go is this it's
just such utter click you'll find
articles for Linux and Mac OS X ok
Hoover to switch window that's one how
to avoid Mouse hand pin that's one and
actually I have a saw talk show on that
and I have a page on the Mac let's go to
ok here's a Mac who were to switch
window okay
I'd give you the details how to
configure it because actually
configuration is important okay and yeah
some tips you can eat you can find the
Linux page here auto raise window and
the Hoover quick there are actually
different things in Linux okay so the
official link but files are for example
so this page is organ programming
languages summer school proof us
programs foundational security software
security reliable computing yeah
concurrent and distributes of and now I
don't think I'll read it because these
these are not types in logic
verification yeah this I think okay so
what I'm saying is that they are practic
practicality oriented they are not
actually teaching you the theory about
these topics yeah I wouldn't be
interested you know like they are trying
to tell you how its kind of like how to
mixed in with practicality like you know
like a career-oriented you know kind of
thing spectrum of types now let's see
why do they speakers where's the video
like is this a video course or what yeah
but anyway just looking at the topics I
don't think I mean where's the like
video and material
oh it says for some inexplicable reason
an uncompressed and Odion is gone okay
so this is released various YouTube okay
I'll check it out
trackballs now I talk about track pause
the other day but I think ultimately
Mouse is better okay dear Lydia already
left
curriculum link okay
okay lecture great I'll check it out for
sure so thank you guys for coming I'll
see you next time have a good day
hey Noah hey Noah and guys well I have a
good day I'll see you next time
and coast close