Welcome to another episode of S talk
show. If you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed. If you are here, say
hi. So, we going to code uh pearl. I'm
going to demonstrate a pearl find and
replace script of all files in a
directory. Uh, and I'm going to
demonstrate formatting pearl code. Okay.
So, let's see. Let's look at the pearl
code. So, PL. So, there it is. So,
here's a code. It can do multiple find
and replace pairs. Uh, it can do regular
expression or literal find replace. And
it can filter file by file name regular
expression of course and automatically
make backup and generate a report. So,
several several things. So, we're going
to do show that then we're going to demo
how to format pearl code. So, so for
example, if you have pro code like right
now, like if you um if if they are not
formatted correctly, I can press a key,
I mean you go to shell, you go to shell
and call a command to automatically
format it. Then we're going to write a
emac command to call that command. So in
EMAC, I can now press a key and it will
be formatted, you know, like uh like
before. Okay, that's what we're going to
do. So, first of all, we going to de
demonstrate this uh pearl find replace.
So,
so let's pick a directory so that the so
those are documentation. So, can you see
it? Yes. Comments. Okay. So,
demonstrate. So, we want to the
directory is going to be here. I made a
some temporary files. So, this is
emacisp
uh manual. Okay. So if you go to the
directory there are 1,000 files. Okay.
So open the top one show in browser. So
that what's that's what it looks like.
So we're going to find replace all files
of a text in this directory. Okay. So
close close. So so that's where you
specify. Then this is uh here is where
you specify a backup directory. it will
make the changes and all original files
change files.
If if there's if there's a change in a
file then there will be a backup and all
the backup will be created in this uh in
this
directory. Okay. So that's this uh
backup.path. Then here's a regular
expression. I can replace all HTML
files. So JavaScript files and so on and
write to file. So this is a feature I
added originally. This script is uh
written in 2020 I mean two 2000 so
that's 20 five years ago. So I just
updated today.
So right to file zero and here is the
pairs of replacement. So let's say gnu
uh let's say gnu uh let's say replace
gnu to be ttt ttt. So and then you can
say uh use regular expression yes or no
uh and file size limit. If it's beyond
that don't don't make any change.
Okay. And the rest of it is code. So
let's do it. Let's do a demo. So let's
go to this directory again. Uh let's
open a new
window so we can kind of see. So
okay. So open that. Uh well
let's make it wider.
Okay. So what we doing? So yeah. So go
back here. So we we open this file.
Let's say we want what do we uh want to
replace? So gn replace by ttt. So there
is one occurrence of
gnon.
Uh and let's say
write to file
zero. Okay. So run it.
So total file zero file changed because
you say write to file uh wait right to
file zero. Um
what why is it not doing a report? Even
if it's zero, it still should do a
report. Okay. So,
I think it's because we don't have it
capitalized. Reet. There it is. Okay.
So, you can see total files 1,86
file changed and each change is reported
here. So, that's a script. Now we if if
we look at the uh this file close it
reopen it's not changed because we said
write to file force
um let's see
find go okay not go so here because we
say write to file false now if you
change that to true now pearl doesn't
have a boolean data type so one is true
is zero is force force. Okay. Run it.
Okay. So,
so again the same report. Now go here.
You can see now it changed.
Now let's say let's change multiple
things. Let's change all EMAC to close
that. Let's say we change um
what Emac to be E. Then let's change tdt
to be hh. Okay. So we can do multiple
time uh pairs at the same time, run it.
Hello tmate. Hello SCP.
Yeah, this is ancient. Uh, so again 1,00
file changed and some of them four times
three occurrences six. So switch back
here so you can see it made those
changes. EMAC became E, Emacs became E
and uh, you know, TGD became H. So and
if you now if you go to the backup
directory, close that. Now where do we
specify the back directory? Backup
directory. So go there open it. So you
can see it copies the entire directory
structure. So you see the you see the
backup directory is that but because we
are in a directory called xx so it
copied that then eag this then then
there so here you can see is original
file. I mean it's original file because
um we did the replacement again. So, so
that's a demo of this code. Okay. So,
close it, reopen it, go to So, you can
get the code. I just update it right
here. So, if you go to talk show, close
that talk show. It's right here. Okay.
So, you can copy the code if you want.
Now, by the way, there is also um there
is a Golan version for grip and find
replace golan version and Python version
and there's also Emacs version uh or and
Emacs how to so it's you know you can
use any one of those the code is all
there okay so that's one thing now
now let's demo the formatting pearl code
okay so right Now I'm in uh this is go
program. So I can I can munch up this um
you know and I press a key they became
formatted. Let's say undo. Okay save. So
you see right now it's not formatted
well. So for example you know it's now
save it. I'll press a key. It formats
the entire code. So that command I
demonstrated a few days ago is here and
uh so that was the talk show
that was the talk show about uh talk
show
three days ago. So three or four days uh
last week let's see there talk show
episode 673
about a week ago format Python
JavaScript Goland HTML CSS in Emacs and
Wuam language auto format okay so you
can get a code so you can format it so
but now we are missing we don't have
pearl
so close that now go to pearl.pl PL so
this file so if in so in this file if if
you know right now it's not formatted
correctly so you know I make it one line
uh now save it however I can do it by
uh pearl tidy okay pearl tidy and the
file name so file name is that correct
so now watch watch this line okay do it
okay Now back here now auto auto revert.
So now you can see they are formatted
well.
So but the problem now is that so this
is demonstration of pearl format. This
pearl tid command is bundled with pearl
like usually uh otherwise you can call
cpan cpan then pearl tid to install it
but I think it's bundled in every pearl.
So that's how you uh format code. Okay.
But I want a command in Emacs. So I
press a key. It'll just do it. Okay. So
let's write that. Okay. Let's write that
command.
So far so good. So far so good. Okay. So
now we want to write a command. Now we
can just copy existing command. So So
for example, let's go to go and uh
describe key. Tab F. So here's the
source code for for Goland Goland format
buffer. Okay. So how do you select it?
Uh not that.
Okay. Copy it. Let's see. Is this what
we want? Uh
yep. Okay. Close it.
Uh
suff go. Close it. Close it. So, here's
a pearl program. Now, let's make it not
well formatted. Now, go to some talk
show today's talk show and let's write
one. Okay. Uh, wait.
Pearl code. Paste the code and pop it
out and pearl format. Okay. And uh,
wait, this is shouldn't be pearl. Should
be Emacs. So, let's
do it again. Uh,
emac this code.
Put it there.
Pop it out. Now, this is Emac this mod.
Now, this is correct. Okay. So, we want
to write this code. So, replace all go
by
pearl. Okay. Just one occurrence. Okay.
So some uh pearl format buffer. Now
let's see what is a command. This is a
command cut. So eventually we need to do
this. Okay. We need to call that command
in shell. So format current file by
calling uh by calling pro
tidy. Okay. Ber is saved first. Yes. And
do I have a URL? Not right now. Uh and
uh creation date.
Version date. Okay. So now
so when buffer is not a file report
error. Okay then if buffer is modified
save it. Okay then
create a temp variable local variable
output
out buffer. Okay create the buffer pearl
format output.
Okay that's good. Then uh save current
buffer. So this now there's a better way
to write this uh width
with 10 buffer. Okay. So with 10 buffer
output buffer then erase buffer. So let
me explain what this does. Okay. Save C.
Save current buffer just uh wait what?
Save current buffer just means
you know not not saving a file sense but
you uh so you can restore the buffer
whatever buffer you are in. Okay. So
anyway so then you set the buffer. So
you make the current buffer that's what
set buffer means. So you want to make
the current buffer to be output buffer.
Then you erase it. So basically what
this line does then then because you are
doing save current buffer then so after
this is done it'll just revert to
whatever the uh previous buffer.
So that buffer so this line basically
means you know you create a buffer
uh of this name
if it already exist then do anything if
not then create it. That's what this uh
get buffer create means. Okay. And that
returns a buffer. So that's the output
buffer.
Uh okay. Then
then you you want to erase you want to
empty that content before you run this
command. But a better way to write it uh
is just with temp buffer. So with temp
buffer means uh make make this buffer
current
then erase buffer. So okay you can uh
with 10 buffer is actually just a macro
for that. So we can look up describe
function with 10 buffer. Go to the
source code.
Uh wait
uh it's not with 10 buffer it's with
current buffer. Okay.
Yeah. So actually this should be god I
recently changed stuff like keys. So
there is so so this is equivalent to
that. So describe function with current
buffer jump to the source code.
So you can see it basically just call
save current buffer. You know this is a
markup. Okay. So anyway so so far so
good. Yes. Then call uh call process go
format. No we want to call pearl tidy.
Okay.
Pearl tidy
then new output buffer Neo then an
option will B means replace the current
file B means override the current file
okay then buffer file name means the
current buffers file path
okay so then then what is this uh so per
so now actually so now what we want to
know
Right now actually this command will
work. But what we want to know uh is
that we want to know whether pro tidy
uh
return code exit e ex exit code. We want
we want to know if it uh formatted
correctly.
Uh
so uh is there a documentation for pearl
tid? Let's see.
But anyway, regardless, you know, let's
assume it's successful.
So what what the the rest of the code
does is that if if the so this should be
with 10 buffer. Okay, with with current
buffer. So if the buffer output buffer
the
basically this checks if the output
buffer is empty. So if it's empty then
kill the output buffer then then the
current buffer is whatever is your code
then you just revert it that means
revert it to whatever is on disk because
this command just changed it but if the
output buffer is not empty then you show
it. Okay, so this command should work.
But to make it better, we should uh
check
what pearl tidy actually returns. You
know, we need to check the exit exit
status. But let's ignore it for now.
Okay, so now run the code.
Okay, run the code and uh copy the uh
the name. Now go to the pearl code.
Let's see where is the pearl code. Close
that. Uh, here's a pearl code. Okay.
Now, meta x
s pearl format buffer. Do it. Fantastic
and beautiful. Okay. Now, let's
experiment on something. Okay. So, let's
just create a file xx.pl.
Okay. Basically same file. But now we
screw up that. But let's also screw up
the syntax. So this now becomes invalid
pearl code. And now we call the format.
Let's see.
Let's see what happens if you know
whether it's going to erase my file or
not. Let's do it.
Okay. So it does not did it did it even
complain? No, it didn't even output
anything.
Interesting.
So the pearl formatter actually does
some kind of huristic format you know.
So this line you see this line of code
is invalid. Okay wait uh what this line
of code is invalid
but pearl just formatted the the best
way it can. So you know if you run this
right now it won't work because you see
you see
you got syntax errors and so on.
But if you add the comma there then
call format
do it now it's good.
Okay. So actually we just wrote so now
uh so okay. So now we just wrote our
code successful.
Uh and this part is now redundant. I
you know this uh
we kind of don't need but because
apparently pearl the pearl tidy doesn't
output anything.
Okay. So
so what should we do? Um,
yeah. So, we just we don't we just
revert the current buffer and uh don't
do anything. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. And uh cut that out. Put it back.
Syntax correct. Showing browser.
So, that is it for today. We
successfully done. Okay. Okay, I think
that's it for today.
Jean Claude Lemonu, what's up, guys?
Okay, I think I'm done.
Uh, so yeah, let it be short. If you
guys like my stuff, donate. Okay, so go
to.info.
Go to the bottom. Lots of programming
tutorials about 6,000 pages. Patreon me,
Amazon gift card me, or PayPal me. If
you work, have a job, pay me $100, one
shot. That would be appreciated. Thank
you.
Okay, so we shut down. Should uh should
we shut down? Yeah, I think we you know
done this uh we shut down in two
minutes.
comment and questions.
So, here is my uh banana juice and
coffee. Fantastic.
Now, if you don't know, of course, I
have uh pearl python. You know, there's
a complete pro tutorial here.
Let's um you know let's squeeze few
minutes. Let's see what I can talk
about. Lots of updates. Okay. Softly
keys. I recently yesterday I made a
major kind of major is is change. So if
you don't know Safly Keys is a key
binding system in Emacs, the most
powerful editor. That's what I'm using.
key binding system. So the more it's a
more efficient than vim meaning that uh
for doing the same thing you have to
type less keystrokes than vim. Okay but
it's this is for emacs. You can download
it on github you can watch a video and
you can see the keystrokes. Now the one
change I made is that you see the those
number row. So originally each key each
number they they do something but now I
remove them all. So they they become now
merged to the you know the offer of you
know the letter key section because that
way you don't have to move your fingers
all the way up. In fact, that caused me
major and permanent
uh hand injury.
Uh especially because of the one, two,
and three keys since 10 years ago. And
it was it became permanent like right
now here is painful. Not right now, but
it, you know, last week, you know, it's
kind of permanent. Okay. So, if you if I
started to type too much, you know, it
hurts here. Why here? Because because I
use this middle finger to press the
number three key all the time and
because I'm a touch typer. So I just,
you know, flip that up. Type the three
key three all the time. Why?
Why the key three? Because three is for
unsplit window. Uh wait. Uh right now I
don't have that key anymore. So but but
I still press that. I have it, you know,
key three.
So, so doing that you know so that
created a permanent uh hand paint here
there.
It took a while to realize. Took me like
a year to realize that one. And before
the problem was key one and two on the
Microsoft natural keyboard because I I
have you know I got into a habit of
moving my hand like that and use the
index finger or the pointing finger to
press one and two and that created a
problem here. So that was 2010.
So the number row keys are kind of
nasty.
And I remember back in 1992,
actually 19 Yeah, I I started to touch
type on quarti in 1988.
[Music]
Okay. About 1988 on a on a electric
typewriter.
uh and I start to learn Vorac to touch
type Vorac in 1994.
Okay. So I don't have a problem until
2005.
Uh and uh then I started to have
problems like every few years another
new problem.
It began in 2005 because I was using a
laptop keyboard
all day you know like for for a year for
for two years that's that began all the
problem
uh copper I I you know that's very
technical I don't think that's copotonal
but capoternal is very technical name so
you know so I don't think it's proper to
go with technical names because the
repetitive strain injury there there's
all all kinds and kind of fuzzy. Even
the scientists don't know exactly why it
happens.
So anyway,
so this is the one of the change I made
to safely keys. So you no longer press,
you know, the number keys instead
instead you press the shift and enter.
Okay, that's one change about fly keys
and lots of others, you know, and lots
of other things I did recently. But
that's it for for this one. One topic at
a time per video. Bye, guys.