hello guys welcome to another episode of
sun talk show
uh so today we are going to unbox the
ultimate hacking keyboard okay
the Fantastic ultimate hacking keyboard
okay that's what we're gonna do we're
gonna unbox it
so on the screen you see there that's my
glove 80 keyboard okay glove 80
fantastic
I did a review of an hour also this is
Bluetooth so you don't need the cable
gravity keyboard fantastic
and we need we need the space to unbox
the thing you know I have a lousy camera
and setup but anyway so and here is the
my old ultimate hacking keyboard This is
Ultimate hacking keyboard version one
okay
I also did a review you can check glove
80 and ottoman hacking keyboard on my
website just search for Sally
ultimate hacking keyboard or sorry girl
80 okay so we're gonna unbox the thing
now so let's see
how we gonna do this
let's see I don't have this setup like
other people with fancy cameras and all
that
so but I'm just going to do this
the idiotic way
okay so unbox so let's see yeah so let
me just unbox it now this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard version 2. I got
version one about three years ago when
they came out so they sent me one thank
you you know thanks thanks to them
fantastic and I have been using the you
know the Can you see it actually
so I have been using my old you know I
have been using my Pokemon hacking
keyboard as my main keyboard for about
half a year
six months
am I going I'm doing well am I doing
well say hi guys for people watching say
hi
okay say hi and ask me questions about
people okay
so
so I got my ultimate hacking keyboard
version one about three years ago
and I used it as my main
for half a year
the version I have the ultimate hacking
version one it has
uh it has the key switch is Cherry MX
red silent I believe Cherry MX red
silent okay or no no no no no the the
the key switch I have here is Kyle red
pale red okay and that turns out that's
too heavy for me because I have RSI as I
have talked about many times I have isi
right here it's permanent it's gonna be
you know it's gonna be the pain gonna be
with me
until I go into the grade
so therefore I cannot this this you know
the Kyle red linear switch is too heavy
for me it's like 50 grams activation
Force
so so that's why I didn't use it as my
man so but but I use it as a macro
keypad as if you have seen my video
you have seen I demo ad many times macro
keypad and it's so you got something
like 70 macro Keys fantastic and the
ultimate hacking keyboard uses you know
it's programmable
in a firmware and it has the best
firmware to program the thing so I
showed it before I you cannot see my
screen I'll show you later so it's
fantastic okay so here is so today I got
the ultimate hacking keyboard 2 okay so
here is the main part
it's pretty small okay it's tiny
fantastic and it's very very sturdy
very sturdy bear so this is just empty
box let's see empty box
okay fantastic we're gonna open this
thing let's open this one let's open
this one first am I speaking yes
Okay so
so I got the version two let's see
what's new version two came out about a
year ago something like that and uh and
they also sent me all the modules now if
you don't know what that is you know
they they have a special design so that
you can attach they kind of have a
little widget here or on on the left
side and also on the right side so you
can attach
uh there are different modules you can
attach a extra key macro module and a
checkpoint module and a trackball mode
module a small trackball and also a
touch pad module you have to buy them
separate okay so this is the Box they
send me all of it fantastic
so they you know so I'm doing a review
for them
uh and uh I'm you know I'm this I'm not
getting paid for it though but I get the
keyboard
and uh you're gonna hear my honest
opinions as always
so hello guys any say hi okay say hi
comments and questions uh I'll get to
them this video is gonna be like
uh 30 minutes or something
now this is the time I need one of those
unboxing cutlaries like those cool cubes
on YouTube
this should be just like that
thank you
yeah my paint is open let's see Sesame
open
peanuts peanuts peanuts forms
okay let's see what how many boxes do I
get
this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard what module is
is don't know let's see
uh
yeah I damaged the box today
do this correctly I damaged the Box
now by the way there's a
key switch expert choir Sun 22 yeah he's
always
he he's got the best reviews on
key switches and he revealed like
hundreds of keyboards
see what module oh tiny this this these
are the trackball modules and okay so
this is the
go to my hacking trackball modules so I
don't know if you can see Tiny
can you focus please
they are trackball okay so this is the
track wall module
and this is the trackpoint module
this is a
what oh this is also a track point I
guess one for left hand one for right
hand something like that okay track four
two track point
and the key cluster module okay let's
open them up
see what we get
now this time I don't want to damage the
Box
hello Ethan Ethan and Hello friends let
me look up what you guys are saying
uh hello Jose Abel
have you tried all those custom switches
in the RMK Community you know since
about two or three years ago there are a
thousand switches like you know before
it's very simple classic
you usually usually based on the Cherry
MX you know so you have linear tactile
and
um tricky you know blue red Brown and a
few other colors white black and then
you have the Chinese made ones from you
know basically they copy it you know so
basically you have five or six switches
and maybe some variation but today you
have like 1 100 of it uh I can't I can't
keep up
so so this thing is a trackball module
okay
fantastic let's see oh it's light ah let
me show you guys so can you see uh a
great trackboard tiny tripod left click
right click and here's your how you
attach it magnetic okay actually I can
attach it to my old one okay so here is
a trackball module
pretty like a fantastic neat neat
okay so that's the trackboard module
let's see what's what are the others
yeah yeah YouTube
so let's see this one track Point okay
it's gonna be pretty much this
is basically the same now
track Point module fantastic so this is
for
what left hand or right hand so let's
check
this is going to fit
see okay so this is the right hand
okay so this this right hand track point
uh yeah track track pad
iPad module so let's put it back
oh I should do this faster should I
okay
I'm running out of space now what is
this one so that's the modular boxes
about this one this is a key cluster
module this is for the left hand
so you got
three extra keys for your thumb and this
time I mean sure they send me the key
switcher I have is called
pink or silver or something but it's
very light 35 grams Activation so I'll
be able to use this as my main okay so
so this is a module for you know the
thumb module for the left hand fantastic
[Music]
you watch this point oh then there's a
tiny trackball here and yeah there's two
buttons tiny treble and two buttons for
the left hand let's go this will be
interesting to try
so each of this module is how much is it
I don't know you have to check on their
website fifty dollars or something I
forgot
okay so here is the track Point module
the famous track point on IBM ThinkPad
okay so this is also for the right hand
side
so on the right hand side you have you
know you can choose from a chart
trackball track pad and track point
you know I Nick I actually never owned a
track point
so we'll see how it goes
so four checkpoint instance of one two
three four four modules
for modules and see where am I
so full modules and what is these stocks
this big box oh this is wait
okay this is the actual keyboard
the one thing before
this this is actually the
Palm rest so they have a wooden Palm
rest
this is the actual keyboard okay
so there it is so let's open it
fantastic
I'm up my setup all over
uh
200 boxes so let me put these spots away
it's empty
okay so here it is
ultimate hacking keyboard
uhk60 I guess they are 60 keys
and
okay so the Box looks like that
so it looks like that
okay so you can you see the modules you
connected so let me just show
fantastic
and this time I have the
dark red color fantastic maybe let me
show you so you see
fantastic and it's connected by
magnetics so I can just pull it apart so
you can tilt it tint it however you like
okay so you can see
on this you see over here that's how you
connect the modules it's all magnetic
okay so these are you can actually they
they push down
yeah there
so
yeah so it's all magnetic
I'm getting
old so okay there it is
because I have trouble seeing you know
and and you know I need my
old main grasses reading glasses right
now I'm wearing contact lens oh this is
an improvement
okay I still find this too short this
this you know this is
um wired ultimate hacking keyboard is
wired okay and this is connecting the
two parts
they use this kind of a phone classic
phone plug but they need to be reversed
it's called Twisted okay so you when you
buy a if you want the longer you have to
buy on Amazon
this is too short Okay so
yeah because my old one if you can see
my other one you know I try to pull them
longer so I bought a new one but I
haven't connected yet you know I wish
this could be longer but there's a
Improvement now it's
um how do you call it it's um
table you know it's clothes
surface it's not
can you focus
there it is okay now it's nylon cable or
something
yeah it's kind of too short
so
that's about it so here is the two feet
you can attach it to
um to to your
keyboard
two feet and two feet here four feets
total and here is the
USB A2 USB C
so it's they again it's a upgrade now
they use USBC
there it is yeah USBC
okay
and included is a keyboard puller and
that's it so you got keyboard cable for
heat keyboard puller
okay that's you know that's the main
thing about unboxing this thing
basically we done uh how long have I
been talking only 20 minutes okay so let
me gonna answer some questions and
that'll be braided that's a word thank
you Jose gradient cable
so here is this box is the wooden Palm
vest okay that's you know they also gave
me that but I didn't install it because
you know I'm not too big of a fan for
Palm rest
you know I prefer you see this
uh bath Towers that's that's the best
Palm rest you know thick you can see how
thick they are
it's about you know this thick so
comfortable and you can throw it away
you know throw it in a wash machine and
clean it and cheap you know two dollars
as opposed to a palm rest where you buy
you know in a store
twenty dollars you know and little no
good but anyway they have you know so
for the ultimate hacking they've gone
classic
so they actually provide you with wooden
Palm rest oh my God this is heavy wooden
Woods solid wood man this is this is
luxury stuff solid wood
uh yeah and here's a mental heavy metal
so you're gonna
screw it I don't think I want to use it
you know because this is the best Palm
rest
so here's a solid metal heavy
and the screws to attach it okay that's
that's it yeah that's it about the Palm
rest
okay any questions you guys have let me
answer the question and uh
and that'll be it for today so let me
show you more about the keyboard because
that's
thing yeah why don't we actually can we
turn it on yes let's let's do that
let's plop it in and turn on
so this cable they it's very nice
because they got this Velcro
attached to it and it's also braided
braided cable okay
yeah stupid camera you know I've been
shopping for a camera for the past three
months
I don't want to spend like six hundred
dollars for beginner V blogger vlogger
you know six hundred dollars begin the
vlogger camera but if I got that then
you'll be perfect but that's too much I
don't have that much donate okay
rely on you guys to feed me
if you like my stuff okay so this is
nice you can detach it you know
so braided cable yeah it's
let's connect why not
oh oh so it's that was you know this
extension
so on the cable
both sides both sides are are USB uh
wait
yeah both both are USBC
okay but then you got this extension
converter
from USBC to USB a okay let's try
there it is
see I do I have a hole here
no so he has to go back to my monitor
okay
okay so and then that means I also need
to connect this
I'm pretty sure I do not need to read
the manuals because this is simple
because I've had the version one
so is my voice coming through yes I
think so
so he just
click
click okay
fantastic
now where does the
okay so it's pretty much the same as the
old you know the version one is exactly
the same but except now they use USBC
Okay so
you know this part I don't like too much
because it's pretty
tight and you have to bend the cable uh
it wasn't so good then you have to push
this
can you guys see so you know there's a
you have to push the cable in but it's
not easy to do and it's not easy to
insert it but it's just too oh there it
is
okay so there's another upgrade now they
got
backlight
try this
let's try this
let's try this oh
fantastic now let's
now let's try to set it to Vol rack okay
if I remember the keys okay so the
layout
the layout is pretty much exactly the
same as the version one
you know with the function keys here and
Mark key space smart function function
Okay so
so by default there's a war rack layout
or you have to there it is okay this is
Improvement it lights up red so these
four five buttons
you can pick a layout this is call Mac
this is quality for Mac
this is vorac for Mac
comac for Mac
quality
Vol rack there it is
so can you see
you see it says full rack I don't know
you know if you can see it clearly
so now I can type let me try some typing
on this
BMX so
ah
whoa fantastic oh this fantastic this
this key switch is 35 grams
fantastic
test these Keys which is only
45 grams fantastic okay any questions
comments
and then then otherwise that's it for
today
so so this spec light is new
uh okay then and also they renamed the
key label for the window key it's now
renamed super and then let's connect
them
okay so you can see this key
is now super it's not the windows logo
they renamed it good thing the you know
okay it's okay
so you can see the layout is exactly as
before you got the mod key space then
function function
okay so let me go through my computer
screen and we we we are that's it for
today uh one more minutes
let me show you my computer screen
wait where is the oh
so right now I can't put the keyboard on
the because I have a drawing pad if I
put on there it kind of interfere with
the mouse
that's it
yeah
yeah you don't want to see here
oh yeah let's turn this off
Okay so
now let's go to
that's Linux key the super no that's the
Windows key
so in Linux that does Super exactly
so now let's show the screen okay I show
the screen yeah
Okay so
so you are looking at my you know my
review of the ultimate hacking keyboard
version one in 2018
December about three or four years ago
uh and uh
but now I'm on
let's try to type something can you see
okay can you actually see how you can
see there
now let's try to type something can you
see
okay something is interfering with my
mouse
and where did my mouse go yeah
okay I think these I need to
put this away
this drawing tablet okay unplug it
this is uh cheap China made drawing
tablet I have a review on it just search
for my website for drawing tablet
okay let's see
this is the hold on a second so where is
the
since I'm using starfly keys I need the
I need a home key to switch
so mod home okay so yeah so you do this
okay
so on home magnify wait cancel
Escape
mod Escape so there so I need to
yeah so let's make okay
Ctrl G
magnify
okay
so that you can see
oh you know this key
the typical cap locks position they have
the mouse there so when you press the
caps lock
they actually kind of turn it into a
keyboard mouse maybe that's why I was
interviewed you know I I had
interference
but
but you see I need to set up the key I
need to set up the key so that it can so
that I can develop my
and now let me show you I'm going to
show you typing on this keyboard
fantastic okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
if you like my stuff donate okay very
nice hello Ethan
uh can I have the packing peanuts surely
you can you have to you have to pay the
shipping fee
what's the interface on these modules oh
yeah so the interface oh yeah
okay I forget about
about this uh
so let me go back to
so these for example so this is the best
thing this is a unique for this keyboard
no other okay so yeah so we don't think
this is a unique for this keyboard
automatic hacking there's no other
keyboard
has this kind of thing so this is a
Innovation by them okay so you got this
uh this is for yeah so this is all for
right hand
track pad
Mouse I like them I I like the trackball
let's try the tripod here's a track
point and here is the left hand module
with a tiny tripod there
let's try it
so I believe you just plug them in
that's all so let's do it
no I don't know how to turn off the
light screen focus focus okay yeah so
yeah
there it is okay
so there it is attached
checkable module
and now let's try the
key cluster module plus a tiny trackball
okay
let's let's see let's try the mouse oh
oh fantastic
ah this this is great
and let's try the tiny Mouse
wait the
it is
there's a tiny Mouse no I don't see the
cruiser point
maybe maybe if when you plug this in the
left you got this about maybe I don't
know
but
let's try this button oh the button
works right click oh yeah so for example
let me show you
let's go to browser so
right click you see oh you cannot see
can you uh
hey let me show you
so go here go here
left click so now you can see my screen
go here
yeah so you see this is the right
track wall
and the left trackboard
oh this is Scorpion down fantastic
uh yeah this is very good so you have
you get two of them yes this is good
design so
right click and here left click right
click yeah so one is scroll
the other is
checkpoint okay
okay thank you guys for watching that's
it pay me if you like my stuff and uh
down the road I'll do a more in-depth
I'll do an in-depth review of this
keyboard
okay bye
and so okay bye guys