fantastic i'm alive
hello guys good evening
good evening to this 2021 november 21st
uh saturday and today we are going to do
emac this coding live okay emac this
coding live fantastic emacs so without
further ado let's begin okay and you are
looking at my keyboard kinesis advantage
2 keyboard that's this one red switches
and this is ultimate hacking and you can
find them on
keyboard blog just search for it you can
find my reviews of them kinesis
advantage 2 and ultimate hacking and i'm
showing my keyboard so that you can see
my workflow
the most efficient way to operate the
computer end so because we are going to
do emacs today emac this code is showing
browser this is today's uh talk show
page
for each video youtube video i have a
corresponding uh talk show page
talk show just search for it you'll find
it and today here is today this is uh
here are the past videos and click on
today we have the topics notes code and
so on
so in emacs and in the pink window you
can see all my emacs command cores for
example let's turn on global highlight
line smart
global highlight
line smart so you can see where is my
cursor
so for each key press you can see my key
press on the pink window and
the corresponding command code i'm using
sunflower keys and i'm using work
keyboard layout
okay so let's begin so let's see
comments questions posted i'd love to
see your comments
hello vietnam uh you are probably from
vietnamese right
okay let's begin so what are we going to
do first so we are going to so emac this
coding emaclis okay so
for this is this session is for you
uh interest you guys interesting emacs
coffee
dance emacs lisp coding that's what we
are doing that's what we're gonna do so
okay
so uh let me show you okay so modify so
first of all we're gonna modify these
html video file surface okay let me show
you so that is
html mod so you are looking at the html
mod so let's go to the source code
call describe key then press key press
the key that invokes
html mod the key is
bam bam bam
pan okay so that's delete space m h
delete is this key by the way so this
thumb key on my kinesis advantage to
keyboard so press that space
m h gets you the
html mod and tab go to jump to the
source code here's the source code
and uh
4600 lines go to
okay go to the top and here is the link
open the link shown in browser you can
find it on this website just search for
it html mod and you if you like it
uh you can buy it okay it's open source
pay me and you'll get it and now
so
so in html mod okay copy the link back
to emacs
open the bookmark fast open start talk
show page open that page and paste the
link here so we have a record of what we
talked about
so show in browser
there it is
now okay let me explain what is it that
we are coding so if you go to
html mod source code so let's do it
again
then search for
vdo
file okay there it is so you have this
function
this you can see let's magnify okay
let's let's magnify some more
okay so you can see
there is a function now what does this
function do this will return true if the
file path is a video file
return false otherwise let's do some
demo okay so
copy the copy the function name open a
new buffer paste the function name
uh okay i don't want to actually copy
the whole line instead so we do it again
magnify make a parenthesis dd that and
turn this
buffer into xr emac this mod so that key
is bam bam bam bam
so that's xa emac this mod you can also
pay me and get it
okay so now we have this function let's
say a path okay so what whatever path
let's say cat jpeg
cat mp4 let's say okay run the code
you can see it returns true now let's
show the
okay
you can see it returns three
which in emac this is true now in e-mag
lisp
the only value that evaluates to force
in a boolean context is
neo
or empty list okay empty list is
equivalent to neil so
these two values are false in a boolean
context such as if something then else
you know
otherwise everything else is true that's
emac this the the language okay so
anyway so we are running this function
and cat dot mp4 run it so the result is
three which is true okay now for example
let's say jpeg jpeg okay run it you can
see
the result is near false okay
uh let's say let's start move okay
movies uh apple's
apple's quicktime format movie so run it
you can see the value is three again
true so this function returns true or
false now
now
so here is the implementation of the
function
now you can see the implement let's
narrow to region so we only see the
function narrow to different okay so so
we don't get confused with other code so
you can see the implementation is
basically called string match so stream
match
with this regular expression and with
this file path so the file path is the
argument here
so if it matches mp4 or dot move or dot
mkb mkv
or webm
or m1vm4v
all those are movie file extensions now
what we want to do now is to modify this
so that it's not hard coded so we are
going to have a variable let's see let
me let's start to code it define var
okay
so let me show you what it is okay so
define bar
uh
html video file extensions okay so this
is going to be a list of extensions
initial value neo okay dot string
a list of
movie
of video file extensions
okay
that's the documentation for this
variable now let's give a value to this
variable okay set
size html video file extensions okay now
we are going to give a list okay so here
is this now what the what are they going
to be they're going to be similar to
this string okay so we're going to
modify this string so they become a list
so mp4
move
m mkv
v
m for v
this by the way this
this
uh
mp4 m1v m4v or
are variations
of the mpeg-4 video format
you know the video video formats are
quite complex you know because they have
the container
um
what do you call file format or protocol
container
what is the
anyway you got you got a container then
you got the
codex codex is the actual format the
algorithm that compresses video
stream
so you have a container which you have
several standardized container then for
each container they support
a set of compression codecs you know
compression algorithms so anyway it's
fairly complex and they are changing
every year
so anyway so back to our what we are
coding so we don't need that anymore so
this you each one of them needs to be a
string so each one of them to be to be
needs to be like that so
what i'm going to do i'm going to call a
xl command that does it to a whole bunch
of lines so do it
quote to use double yes
line separator none
okay so you see very convenient command
and that command name is subcode lines
you can just find it on the web
source code is available you can grab it
and use for your purposes okay now
predefine the code now i want to compact
the code into one line so this is uh
very simple
so now
html video file extensions we got that
so now we need to modify this
implementation to use that okay so let's
do
so why do we need a variable for this
because then it's easier for people to
modify because video file formats
changes all the time so right now i have
these few but for example some people
might have might want to add
uh
you know there are so many so many so
like tens of them
you know
uh what what um some of them are old
formats anyway you can easily search
wikipedia so anyway so people can edit
it easily
instead of hard coding so now we need to
implement
uh
we implement this line basically so what
we're gonna do
uh let's
look up
let's go to exa
practical emac this t uh practical emacs
lisp tutorial
and
you can
you know
this is how i use my own tutorial as a
reference so at the bottom you'll see
sequence functions okay and one of them
we want here
so we want
every find okay so there are many ways
to implement
it
so let's try
sequence sum
so sequence sum gives a function and the
list if the function
applied to the list return true any one
of them then the whole thing is true so
that's
what sequence
that's sequence sum
du that's what it does so we could use
these we could there are many ways in
fact there's more efficient way but
let's just try this okay so sequence um
uh so for example let's look at
documentation describe function so
here's a
documentation for sequence sum so takes
two arguments predicate and a sequence
okay
so
the sequence is that
html video
file extensions the predicate the
function that returns true or false
would be
stream match
yeah we can do that yeah so stream match
regular expression
yeah okay so
the string will be the path okay
so
okay so you need the lambda actually you
need the lambda here so let's do
lambda okay lambda x so let's put this
in a body so lambda x
so stream match
of these extensions
and match it again its path if it
returns true then stop and returns true
okay so that
predefined the code let's purify the
code
that should be it let's double check
stream match
x is the extension match again is the
path yeah
so compact this line
make it you know commented out
then here is our new code now let's test
it okay now first of all we need to
evaluate each of these because this is
variable it's a new any comment and
questions
webm yeah there's webm webm is already
here wait what
oh i missed webm oh thank you
uh i missed webm here yeah
okay let's paste it webm is from google
you know google about this um
av9 or something you know
it changes over the past 30 years you
know every few years there's a new one
better
that's a video compression algorithm and
formats
you know
i have a lot rants about this because
for example
for example mkv is the open
mkv
container format is the open source
however it's not supported by firefox
go figure but it's supported by google
chrome and
you know google chrome engine
so that includes
includes the microsoft edge browser also
supported but not firefox even though if
mkv is supposed to be the you know the
linux linux people or
chant about it
so we have created a new variable let's
evaluate it okay
evaluate it so emac knows evaluated so e
max knows and and this o and this new
function we just modified it's also
evaluated okay now let's test
let's test it if it's true
okay call this function give a path
let's say cat dot um
mkv okay that should return true let's
see if it's true or false
go uh turn on the video i mean go to
uh
the message buffer so you can see the
result now let's evaluate
evaluate
full that's true
correct great so now let's let's let's
add a few so let's um
dot move
um m4v okay let's try these three okay
so evaluated true okay evaluated true
they all return four but why they return
four because
it actually returns the position it
matches
matched in this string for example if
you have cat and dogs
then you evaluate this then you say you
see the result is 11 which is true still
so but now actually i found a mistake
let's say you know
let's say the file name cat move without
a dot okay that's so that shouldn't be a
movie file i mean because you need the
dot for extension let's run it
it returns true which is incorrect you
see so because we actually want to have
a dot in the path in you know so
so let's modify the code so basically
what we have to do is
concatenate a dot in front of the file
extension so let's change the x to ext
so it makes it more readable so we want
to let's copy that
we want to
concat
a dot
there okay so this line we no longer
need compact the code make it pretty
okay
this is a proper one now evaluate it
good now let's test this line again
run it
it will still return true which is
incorrect why because the
the dot in regular expression
is a meta character it matches any
character so that's not what we want we
want the literal dots so in this case we
need to add
you know the backslash backslash
so that means we want a literal dot so
let's try it again evaluate the code go
to this line evaluate it you see now it
returns near you can see at the bottom
can you see it yeah you can see right
there near
right here okay
so
now this is our correct code let's look
okay so let's show that the differences
so before
let's show the ping window d the whole
line uncommon so before it looks like
that
now
okay so this is before the code looks
like this
the new code the new implementation
looks like that okay
so the new implementation so the new
implementation requires these two new
variables now so people can extend it
can add you know
okay that's it now
expand the widen the you know exit the
narrow to window so we see the whole
file now we we don't need this test
code
delete those test code and this old code
we don't need it anymore so deleted
okay
shrink
so
so double check okay define bar define
this extension okay now you need to
modify the documentation so let's modify
the documentation so return true let's
say true if path has video file
extension okay
else new
now let's say
based on
based on this variable okay this
variable we just added so return true if
path has has video file suffix
now
i want to rename it i want to call it
extension instead of suffix so now here
is a part about the english literature
naming of things
so by convention
a file name let me show you by
convention a file name such as you know
html dot e-l
the e-l
that part is called extension that's a
convention
but however more generally speaking
that is called suffix okay so
naming of things
naming of things ex
file extension
versus file surface
okay
personally i always favored the surface
name because that is a general
word for
for kind of this purpose because it just
means the you know the ending
attachment dot e-l the the the ending
part er you know whatever is the last
dot something
you know so in english language we have
prefix we have suffix
which is standard
but however
the extension the the new term
terminology extension came up because
well
history because you know the dos era you
know back then a file name can only have
eight characters and also you cannot
have
meta information you know basically the
extension file extension is the
the meaning the purpose of file
extension is to indicate
what type of file it is for example dot
el means it's a emac list file you know
dot js means it's a javascript file so
file name extension in is is a mid is a
kind of a meta info it's called meta
info metadata you know if you search
metadata you know it's a long history
you know in the past 30 years in
computing industry lots of drama you
know for example apple computers
apples systems mac os systems they don't
have extensions they have a better
system to embed meta information but on
the dos on windows
you don't have that so
you use
you attach the metadata into the file
name you know by using dot something and
that became the standard you know this
is a very lousy way to do things
but however it became the standard
and on unix is worse okay unix doesn't
you know unix is worse unix and linux
but anyway so that's a digression about
the naming of things so
the traditional
standardized name is called extension
file name extension but however the name
suffix in my opinion is a better name
and universally understand understood
why because why do i think it's a better
name because suffix has a very specific
meaning and also it's the context is
very clear it's
in linguistics it means you know kind of
variations of a you know a verb or now
you know a suffix very standard
and very specific meaning and universal
in english language
while the name extension could mean
anything you know for example firefox or
browser extension browser extension
browser plugin browser add-on those are
variations of naming of the same thing
but
so the word extension do you mean
browser extension or do you mean file
extension they you know this completely
different things
so
in my opinion
suffix is a better terminology well the
extension is you know it's idiotic
but however given the how things are the
word you know the term extension is
already standard okay it's just how
things are just like unix many of our
conventions but such as you know
truncate lines
uh truncate truncate you know like
presser add a new line you know truncate
lines when it reaches 80 70 or 80
characters that's a convention but
that's a
begin from unix very bad convention you
know
so
so in my
naming of functions for example you can
see this function is named site html
video file surface
dash p now dash p's means predator
that's an emac this convention and
common lisp and scheme
uh commonly okay and and you know in
general it's
the dash piece from
this convention okay anyway
so anyway i was saying i i choose to use
suffix but now i think i change my mind
i'm gonna rename them just extension
because
people understand you know what the
extension means it's ubiquitous you know
it's um
it's in the documentation you know it's
documentation of bash python powershell
every language you know they nobody
calls it suffix
that's just my personal quote
but you know but it lost out okay so
so now
before we do anything let's go to talk
show today's talk show just add a little
blurb about what we talked about naming
of things file extension versus file
suffix okay
okay close that now close that now back
to the code here now let's
let's make the code work now comments
and questions i'm gonna
post it okay i'm gonna read it in a
minute
so now we have done this
now we are i'm going to
um
rename this okay i'm going to rename it
offline but for now
you know you'll see this kind of
inconsistency you know but anyway i'm
gonna rename them
okay now it's done
now
let me show you an example
of a function that actually cause this
you know which function needs this well
for example
okay let me show you okay so
let's go to a video now where do i have
video okay so keyboard let's go to
keyboard
now go to um
okay let's go to powershell let's let's
show you powershell
cd kasadi info
okay
keyboard
the lots of files now
the
recurs
include uh include
now let's find the file mp4 okay
okay lots of files now let's just um
uh
okay i have a kinesis
advantage keyboard this keyboard video
demo so
so let's um
yeah i know where that file is let's
just go to it then
actually let's just copy the file name
uh
copy the file
okay
so what page is this okay close the
keyboard blog
and go to talk show
open today's talk show go there
back to emacs
paste the file name here you can see
there is a file so now we want to the
the actual directory is
okay so let's go to
keyboard
oh actually i don't know what directory
what directories is you know one thing
knowing about windows is that it doesn't
show the full path okay but we can fix
that so
the way to fix that is you
you know dirt requests include mp4 then
then you pipe it to
a function
[Music]
pipe it to what function
okay dollar sign low line that means the
current
argument
dash
full name okay full name is a property
of the file object that's returned by
the dog okay
let's do it okay
[Music]
expression i only allowed us the first
element of pipeline
but
i forgot
uh what is it
hey jesus i forgot okay let's go to
powershot
so search for exactly powershot tutorial
you'll find it let's go to working on
directories
okay uh
let's go to working on files
create new file direct okay let's go to
list files these files
and
[Music]
oh yeah i forgot oh yeah for each how
idiotic i've been so back go back to
powershell let's modify these so what we
need is
for
each okay
why is the
tab doesn't work
yeah there it is for each object okay
that's the full name then uh that
under dollar sign underscore
dot
full name so for each object
print the full name okay enter there it
is
now so
so where is my kinesis uh there is here
is the full path okay copy it
okay close that close that
paste there it is so there we have the
full path of the
mp4 is the video let's open the file you
see
this is the content of the file now open
this in a movie player
i just press a key and it will launch
hi so i want to record some typing
and i'm going to type
type alice in wonderland okay chapter
one
that's you know you go to my kinesis
advantage keyboard sorry search for it
you'll find this file so
so if i show in browser
now you can see it's just a file path
but you want it to be a embedded video
so what i do you can i just press a key
you see it becomes that so the file path
now becomes the relative link a video
you know a video tag and with the
annotation of what it is figure caption
so go back to browser reload you see
there is a movie alright so i want to
record
so how does that work what the command
did i just call that command is called
um
html any to link so basically when you
call that command that command that emax
command will look at what what your
current line is you know and you'll use
the file name extension to determine
whether it should be a video tag or a
link tag or
javascript
you know source tag or whatever
so
that's all part of
html mod
okay
buy it if you like my stuff support me
okay so so in order to do that so that's
why we are you know that's why we have
been
uh
you know that's why today we have been
modifying this function you know this
function tells
emacs which file
is a video file
and if it is a video file then
you know wrap the video tag around it
okay
so i think so how long have we been
talking i'm gonna read the comments now
and let's see
yeah okay so
and let's do some more emacs basically
we finish this one and there's another
one but but um
okay so
let's uh let me read the comments
interesting unfortunately i cannot
understand any of these
uh well if you study emac this you know
just go to my website it should be not
difficult okay practical emacs tutorial
let's copy that go here
uh paste it so we have a record okay
and go back
you see practical emacs let's go back
here paste it
make a link make a list so we have a
record what we talked about
showing browser this is today's talk
show so you can see the code here we
just
we just modified we just changed this
part and there's another we we're gonna
do
yeah midi okay analytic method yeah
there was also the midi format which is
very sad story so okay
so we did most of the emac list for
for
40 minutes by now
um let's talk random a little bit
so kassadi
midi
so here
let me tell you what midi is okay buying
a midi keyboard the unfortunate fate of
music midi files okay let me tell you
what midi is
and then i have article piano midi notes
and audio recorder synthesizers midi
software that's the old
article
and these keyboard music lots of midi
files okay so what let me tell you what
is the midi file so
well here is buying a midi keyboard okay
um
so a midi file is basically
a file that's standardized
file for recording musical notes for
example when you
play a piano maybe it's a bach or
something
um
you know it's a bunch of notes how long
it's held down how hard you pressed it
you know a bunch of notes so a midi file
is a standard way
it began in 1970s i think 1970s 1980s
it's a it's a file format a standard
file format
that records what notes of music you
know maybe symphony piano guitar
whatever it simply records the notes the
notes you know which notes are being
pressed or which peach you know which
notes yeah
for western music mostly
notes duration how hard it's pressed
essentially those things
so the file is very small for example
you can play a hole in so this is a midi
file for example
today's browser doesn't support it
that's very sad okay
but anyway the file is extremely small
for example for five minutes piano for
five minutes piano box music
so you search for some music
so you can see several of my articles on
piano music
okay
page moved here okay i moved my domain
so that's my old piano i had a piano you
know i had a few
a long time ago 20 years ago so you go
to piano
you go to bach
[Music]
okay that's box music i don't want it to
i don't want to play too long because
google is gonna say censorship you know
copy copyright violation and so on
so for five minutes you know this one is
ten minutes
so this the file size is probably five
megabytes okay five megabytes but if
it's recorded in midi the file size is
just one kilobyte okay so it's extremely
compact
and once you have a midi file you can
play it through different instruments
you know so when a computer see a midi
file you know just a bunch of notes you
know tries to try to play it and by
using a synthesizer you know
when it sees a note is played it needs
to you know actually play the note by
using
uh some kind of synthesizer technology
or you know that's why these midi
keyboards are full
you know you know you guys probably are
familiar you know there's a lot of
videos about
midi or these are
uh done with midi so
so once you have a midi file you can buy
a midi keyboard and connect to it and
you'll just play it you know the sound
came from the instrument came from the
hardware
okay so that's what midi files are so i
have you know backed in two
20 years ago i collected i collected a
lot of them uh basically
copy none copyright okay so i have the
right
most of them i think you know i tried to
so i collected lots of them but then
unfortunately they you know the um you
cannot play them today unless you have
you have to install a browser extension
and so on um
no
operating system mac or linux or windows
by default support any midi you know you
save this in a file they don't play you
need a special uh software or
or a midi you know midi keyboard
so that's what my midi file is and
so what i want to say is it's kind of
unfortunate that you know for example
here is a midi file it doesn't you know
play
i believe
around the year 1999 on the mac
it will play actually
yeah
i don't remember it's via an extension a
browser plugin or add-on of or not i
forgot but
so that's about midi file
yeah rio audio is another very old
format real audio yeah
uh
okay so
maybe that's it for today i i want to
finish another another lisp task
okay we don't have much um
comments anything else
so
seven people six people watching okay
let me let's do another emac this let's
continue with lisp today
okay
so midi files piano is very interesting
you might you know go check it out
midi notes art so
this is very interesting because
yeah this is amazing okay piano midi
notes art this is amazing because
when you play piano
there's always the question
you know you know some piano pieces are
very difficult to play
so but what if you are superman you have
three hands or you have four hands okay
what will happen to the music you know
imagine if you you human animals or
alien
that you know have four hands
then how would it impact piano music
would it you know if you can play you
know 20 fingers at the same time would
that make music piano music certainly
better
okay that's the question
now that question is easy to answer
because we can have two people playing
the piano at the same time you know
usually cd you know that's very common
you see it side by side or you have
each person player plays a piano
but what if you have six hands or ten
hands you know what what if a human can
have you know
100 notes playing at the same time
how does it impact the music you know
so that's an interesting question and so
what what happened what happens if you
have 10 you know 100 fingers at the same
time available to you well we know the
answer
the answer is here
so these people using the midi
technology
you know you can easily compose music or
you know with midi and play it
you know you don't have to learn piano
because with midi you know it's just
notes you know the machine will play it
for you so you don't have to
you know take 10 years to learn the
piano so the midi so you can see here
that's like
like 40 or what you know 100 notes all
playing together at the same time
let's see let's play a little bit
[Music]
okay let me turn on
my uh
my computer audio see if that works
there it is
[Music]
you see that's that's like a lot of
hands playing piano at the same time and
they went crazy you know you wouldn't
believe like you for example um
for example you see this one
you know
each one of those stuff
[Music]
so this this is literally playing about
88 keys all at the same time and
meanwhile still making it musical you
know so it says bad apple super
synthesized version
two
245 million nodes
you know so so that's very interesting
midi
okay so
so that's about midi let's go back to
emac this let's
let's do the next thing
uh actually let's call it a day because
yeah let's not do another so let's
reserve the you know there's some other
emac this i want to do but
let's go back to the html file then then
let's do this um
so here is another thing i need to fix
so here is a
video so here is a function html video
file surface okay we already did that
but there is another one
so here this one html audio file servers
we're gonna do the same thing okay so
this time i'm just going to do it fast
copy it
paste it here
so
audio file extension create a new
variable
okay
html audio file extensions a list of
audio file extensions okay and what are
they so copy this here and
let's
create a new list here
okay so let's replace
by space
okay
and
watch this function space to new line
okay
and do that
that
okay so that is that
that so we did that
evaluate evaluate now we just need to
modify this line
so delete that
now we just
copy the
code here
and copy the file
name put the file name here that's it
so we need to change the documentation
return
true
if path has
path
has audio file extension
okay
that's it
so here is a new implementation okay now
okay basically that's it for today okay
so but um
yeah but you can see here actually we
are using a
a different implementation
we are using a different implementation
before because the the way we did it
here today okay let me talk about this a
little bit
so let me open the new buffer
set it to emac this mod
okay
magnify magnify
pretty uh god
and
okay pretty fine
pretty fine okay so we have now two ways
to implement the same thing
the first way we explained before you
know we use
sequence sum so sequence sum
maps the function
to a list
if the function returns true on any
element of the list then it aborts and
return true okay this is one way to
implement this function now the other
way
the other way is let's make this like
that okay so
it's okay so let me
pretty find the code the other way is
like that
so you do string match
so
you you call string match one shot okay
the string match takes two argument
a regular expression
then a file path
so what is the regular expression the
regular expression is you
you concat
the
list of file extensions
so that they become all you know regular
expression or which is the vertical sign
but in emac list you need double
double backslash in front
so anyway
so you
concat
you turn a list into a stream with a
bunch of regular expression all in
between so then you do string match one
shot
so this is actually the more efficient
way
then
what we just did earlier you know the
what we did is you know we map the
string match function
multiple times you know
so anyway that's it for today thank you
guys for watching um
you know if you like my stuff paypal me
patreon me uh you know or buy my
packages
bye guys
yeah we we did so now it's almost an
hour now we're gonna shut down in in
five minutes so let me just
do some clean up of my
post
video processing pre-post video
processing
let me clean up my code okay so actually
i want to use this implementation not
the laptop not the set queue okay so
change that here
delete that compact
okay so and now i'm going to change the
name so
search for surface okay search for
suffix
so we have all these functions
functions with surface name in them i'm
gonna change them all to
extension
okay so
first we'll make a backup show the pink
window go to top
credibly replace surface
okay extension one two three four okay
this is
html mod you are looking at okay
evaluate the buffer good okay
now
that should be good now go to the top
change the version date so we just made
a change now insert date this format
okay
version 9
and let's change the version number
let's see 16
okay that's that okay save it go to the
directory issue
uh git status
you can see
there's a modified html mod modified git
add
edit
git commit okay let's just say ado
okay
and this is part of my exam packages
okay so we
did modify that improved xsa html mod
okay close it
show in browser
yeah we modified this code
and that's it for today now i'm just
going to copy some of my
the things we talked about
into satoxi page
and
okay so let's go here
and this video we don't need it anymore
delete it
okay xr midi keyboard close
unfortunate fade of music midi files
okay copy and paste here
close
and the
piano midi notes are copy it back here
paste it
this is mario brothers fascinating
and this is
this is amazing
audio recorder synthesizers mini
software software now this i wrote 10
years ago it's kind of it's outdated
i wrote this article is because
starting about 10 or 20 years ago to be
to be
you know actually 20 years ago there's a
lot software based synthesizers so
instead of ins
instead of buying a hardware synthesizer
you can use computers there's a lot of
software synthesizers
so this is kind of my notes so for your
synth yeah
about some of them for example fluid
synth
uh let's see
you know
i was into synthesizers since 1990s
since late 1980s 1986 for a while
okay now copy it go here
paste it close it
this keyboard music okay this is my
favorite pianist
favorite piano composer and piano is my
favorite music okay make a list
close close
there is today's talk show bye guys