hello welcome welcome guys welcome to
another episode of star talk show
so today the first
10 minutes also we are going to i'm
going to give you a review of this
fantastic keyboard okay this is the new
keyboard this is not ergonomic this is
um
uh
this is the
key move okay keyboard so let's turn on
the light
so this is the key move keyboard okay
and uh
you know they sent it to me for review
and i think it's fantastic so i'm gonna
talk for 10 15 minutes about this
keyboard
then i'm going to let's turn on the
light fantastic color so you cannot see
so that's when we need to uh
turn off this
so we're gonna do the review of this
keyboard for 10 to 15 minutes then i'm
going to code emac beast okay fantastic
emac
you know you can see the topic in the
link in on the youtube okay so uh yeah
so let me get my tea be right back
video check audio check fantastic and uh
let's begin
so i just put this keyboard on my
desktop now so this is pretty new so i'm
gonna i'm not gonna i'm not used to it
yet and this keyboard is programmable so
it has internal memory which is the
important thing okay internal memory
um
so can you see it clearly let me try
this okay
let's try
now actually this is a bit of time okay
so let's try this
this camera
doesn't have autofocus so let's try this
uh
okay this is a lousy camera so any
anyway so this keyboard okay key move so
you can find it on my uh blog uh
if you go to study search for exactly
keyboard and uh it's under this section
no more
okay so let's go back
so under the section normal and the um
let me show you okay so there the first
one bluetooth okay so
let me let me tell you about the
keyboard okay
uh okay so
so it's
um
you know it's programmable programmable
and i'm pretty impressed you know
normally i'm an ergonomic keyboard guy
right as you know
you see
i have this bulky giant you know
you know uh advantage to kinesis
advantage to keyboard
but
i'm gonna do review so i'm gonna use
this one and this is the first time i'm
using it on my desktop this would be
great for me using light lighting that
this is red switch so
okay let me start from the beginning so
this is a bluetooth keyboard bluetooth
5.1
you can use it wireless or you can use
it plugging so it's got a
let me show you the cable
so this is the cable so on one side you
have the usbc the usbc goes to the
keyboard okay on the other side you have
the
the usb a okay so let's see usb
you know the standard usb a plug but
however there's a twist you can let me
show you the photo here
you see this usb a
uh
plug
they made it special so that there is no
uh sleeve so you can plug it in either
side doesn't matter you know so you know
no longer have you know that
side problem
so you can plug it in then it'll charge
it guts uh it got a huge battery
something like you know
the
3000 m
ampere battery you know i don't know
exactly what
how uh you know the relative size of
that but anyway that supposedly it's a
big battery so last one so you can use
bluetooth or you can plug in plug it in
and use it connected wired or um
wired and it will charge the keyboard
and it's it can connect to three
computers
uh
so let me go over you know the basic
features and and you can read about them
so
full
and key roll over so you have when you
are plugged in
uh
yeah when when you are plugging wired
then you have full
uh
anchor
n key roll over meaning that you can
press
you know 10 keys or 20 keys
simultaneously and you will be detected
correctly okay but if when you are using
bluetooth then it's six keys
simultaneous keys together maximum
so you can read about inc and keyword
roll over and go seeing what what do
they mean um it's very interesting you
know
it's one of this is one of the features
where gaming keyboards
like to talk about because
you know when you game
you want to press um
you know motor multiple keys at the same
time
and onboard memory this is important
this is critical that means you can
program the keyboard you know to do
macros
and then you can bring it to work or to
or connect it to another computer you
don't need to install any software or
driver all your markers will work
because they are stored in the memory
you know
firmware you know the programmable
programmable memory so onboard memory
this is important on the other hand if
you buy razer keyboard you know the
gamer idiots the gamers brand razer you
know
they they they they remove the onboard
memory and
and they require you to connect to uh
the internet and cloud you know
those are no good so you always want a
when you buy a keyboard you want it to
be programmable and you want it to have
you want it to have onboard memory okay
look for that feature okay
so onboard memory and fully programmable
and you can program key markers as well
and you have four layers but however i
haven't tried to install the software
yet you know you need to install the
software in order to program the onboard
memory i haven't done that yet i just
got this yesterday
i was pretty impressed you know and and
okay let me go over let me talk about
each one of the features one by one if
you have questions for me ask for me
okay and donate okay
uh put money in my pocket
so onboard memory and hot swap up
hot swappable get around mechanical
switches okay
and i'm not going to take out the switch
yeah you know you got um
you know i wasn't prepared to do a
review of this keyboard but i i was just
going to use it to do emax coding so
show you show you how i use this
keyboard live so is anyway it's uh hot
swappable uh get on uh key switches
uh right now i'm using gateway on red
you see because i require red
and the keycaps is
keycap is the highest quality
pvt double shot keycaps meaning that oh
god you know
meaning that you know i wasn't prepared
to do this but um
pbt
uh double shot keycap so let me explain
what it means so keycaps you know there
there are many different technologies uh
to do keycaps look at my screen okay
so the the most common and cheap is abs
plastic and when you have that you
you get this wear shine you know you
probably have seen it and and
in many bad cases it looks like that you
know so
you know this is apple keyboard you have
this situation severe very big problem
you know
and
so that's abs plastic you have that
problem okay
and but
but
pbt
plastic type of chemical you know
which is what this one have
you don't have that problem so this is
pbt keycaps that's fantastic
okay then let me show you about the key
label technology you know so when you
buy a logitech non-gaming keyboard or
microsoft keyboard you have this
technology to uh for the key label which
is essentially like a sticker so with
these it wears out
you know it wears out after half a year
if you type a lot wears out in a
year and then you have several other
technologies for uh key labels so for
example you have laser uh etched so
that's laser
then you have laser
so so this one is laser you just use
laser to burn it
but the problem the flow with that with
this approach is that you don't have
color you know sometimes you want for
example this apple to be red or
something or blue you don't you don't
have that you just
because it's just burned burned plastic
so another techniques
technique is you burn it then you kind
of paint
into the groove
so that's so this is what's a technical
name laser engraved and filled with
paint okay
so that's another technology for key
labels okay
then uh
then
thank you of lamio
thank you
so
uh key label technology laser etched and
the uh laser engraved with uh paint then
you have
dye sublimination okay that's another
technology this is superior then then
then the laser or the uh
stickers so dice of elimination is
essentially you
you um
you know it's high quality uh
you see i'm
right now what does that key do
because right now i'm
right now i'm you know in the new
environment so all my key markers is not
working
as i know them
so anyway so thai sub elimination is a
is a
quality
technology to do uh key labels okay
and this way it will not wear off
neither
then you have okay let's magnify uh
yeah i don't have my keys so
so that's dice sublimination
and so right now you can look at your
keyboard and look at them closely and
see you know the the key labels uh what
kind of quality they are so apple uh
also use
used dice of elimination
then
the
kind of the best and more expensive
technology for key labels is double shot
injection molding
so that means look at this enter key so
that means you know basically the key
label became part of the plastic you
know it's part of the plastic so it will
never ever
run off
uh wear off you know so that's
that's called
double shot injection why is it double
shot because you can see there's
actually two plastics you know they you
kind of merge them together so one is
for the keycap you know the key labels
is actually a plastic inside it you know
they merge them together so this
keyboard this key move is using the
double shot
so it's the highest quality okay double
shot injection for the keycap
so
in summary
the
key labels is double shot injection then
the keycap is using this high quality uh
pbt
um
material okay so let's go back
uh i don't have my
key markers okay so uh any questions
okay so
so that's the keycaps and key labels
okay it's fantastic
we talked about the label uh the cables
and there's a feed
yeah
so there's a feed
i i should show you
let's see
i'll just use this thing now just use
this camera so there's a feed it's
you know really high quality i was kind
of impressed
uh but of course i don't use the feed
because
from
from ergonomic point of view you want
your keyboard to tear this way not this
way this is traditional that's actually
not good because your hand is gonna bend
up you rather wanted your hand to bend
down so you
you know for for a real ergonomic
reasons you want the keyboard to tie
this way but this keyboard cannot do
that you know for the normal
uh
pc keyboard
so
so what's the next thing okay so let me
show you so next thing you got the
different keycaps i'm not going to show
it you uh
included is three extra keycaps remember
it's
hot swappable so you can replace it with
any key
key switch not keycap
okay that's about it for this keyboard
so you can just go to my website
um and
check it out okay
if you are if if you you know
i have to use ergonomic ones
uh so
but while in bed you know i i use this
because you know it's small and portable
and and the problem one of the issue
with ergonomic keyboard is that you can
barely you can almost never find a
wire bluetooth one they are all wired
except this one i talked about in my
last video this is upcoming this this is
coming out
uh you know this year you know in a few
months
and they are expensive you know 300 350
you know of course in kinesis advantage
which is what i have right now 340
something
so and they are all wired except this
one so
so that's why
you know bluetooth and also you need
bluetooth not just wireless because
for example
on a tablet i have a surface
surface probe i can show you
so
so you see yeah service pro you know
there's only one
there's only one usb
so
you know once you plug you know
it's a problem you know you walk around
you have to unplug and plug in that's a
problem and also only one usb port so if
you plug in a mouse and a keyboard then
you cannot plug in keyboard and so on
and
if you use wireless you know wireless
dongle that also occupies a
usb hole so
no good so you actually want bluetooth
so that's why bluetooth is very useful
and plus you know i just got a mac
you know mac
macbook air m1 so let me show you
uh
let's go miscellaneous tech okay macbook
m1
so what what why is this key you're not
doing what i wanted um
you know my key marker so by the way
this keyboard you see here i'm using it
for as a key marker that's uh
that's the ultimate hacking keyboard
okay
so but what is going on now so let's
let's look at it
yeah let me show you the ultimate
hacking keyboard software
so
i'm using yeah so right now i'm using
the work layout you can see because i
don't have this program for where i get
so i'm using the windows for borac
layout and when you do that
all your macros doesn't work anymore
because
you know they are they are still sending
qwerty keys so you have to create a
different layout just for work
okay so this key
so i don't know if you can see it here
so this key should press f11
oh i know why it's not working because
you know
fairly complicated because then i have
microsoft power toy
that is remapping the f11 key
let's see keyboard manager
yeah you see
so f11 is now doing control shift tab
no wonder
yeah
well
okay i'm not gonna
fix it now
you know let's get on to emacs i want to
do some emacs this coding okay so
uh
so let me tell you about yeah
apple m1 macbook air
you know i got this uh two months ago
and
there's only two usb ports there's no
power port so one of the you know two
ports those are usb c
so
even for power you have to use usbc so
once you plug in power you don't you
don't you got you don't have any uh
ports anymore so you need bluetooth it
becomes kind of necessary
and also there's no
anyway yeah bluetooth so
okay i think that's it for my review of
the
uh of the
key move okay
key move dk 61 keyboard
okay you go out and buy it
let's see anything i missed oh yeah the
light show let me show you some of the
light show
okay so you can turn it off
you can turn it on
then you can adjust the brightness
you see this is the lowest brightness
then you can maximize the brightness
so it's not too dark here so you cannot
see so well so then you can change the
color
white
this is a yellowish orange
this is
yellow
green
blue
purple
wow this is
purple and white
and rainbow
and red okay
and then you can change you know there
are so many flashy uh
flashy kind of things so for example
you know you press a key it stays there
for a while
then you
change another mod this is random color
i guess
let's see it's let's
show you here closer
so then you got this random
then you got this random
then you got this
random
then you got single color okay so
oh it breath
it breathes
then you got
you know slow shifting of colors
uh that's also slow shifting of colors
then you got
shifting of colors from the middle
okay each row has got a color then it
shifts
then you got
okay
rainbow color shifting from left to
right
then you got
rotation color rotation
okay this is none
then you got
yeah then you got the bomb kind of thing
okay that's the color
now i don't want any color i don't i
don't want any of the then then you got
you know
these rgb things got so many
god
yeah i want just stable okay
and turn it off now
turn back the light on
okay so that's it about the keyboard now
let's do emac list let's code emac this
let me read the uh comments then let's
call it emac list it's gonna be
fantastic
is called coffee house sounds like
logitech k845
i just bought last week oh okay
uh
so why do i want the keyboard with
internal memory i have just explained
that very that's that's actually the
most important feature for me
you know well i i want an ergonomic
keyboard but
but one of the most important feature is
you want internal memory okay i
explained that
uh
i'm using mx linux it can hold execute
marker okay so
mx linux no
just fine
no that's incorrect
uh what is mx linux
you know
so
let's let me talk about keyboard marker
why is the uh why is the internal memory
important okay it's actually critical
because okay so you go to my blog then
you can uh you go to
uh software how-to
okay
then yeah well you go to keybinding
design
why old tab is no good this is a new
article
on the page by itself
you go to
[Music]
layout
keybinding design
typing
software how to
um
[Music]
okay you go to
normal
then you go to let's magnify okay
yeah oh my oh my mark was not working
yeah okay let's just magnify this way
okay pc keyboard
switch mechanism keyboard firmware okay
so
keyboard firmware
this is all about keyboard firmware what
are the differences what kind of
firmware are they are there example of
firmware capabilities you know keyboard
firmware they they have many different
um
features
okay here advantage of firmware over
operating system remap
okay let me explain that one then we're
gonna get onto a uh emac basic coding
so
for example operating system software
remap for example among you know of you
linux or whatever
you know you can use operating system
right right now i'm using a tool called
power toys okay it's a great tool okay
you can also see on my website i have
article on that
and let's go let's show it so far how to
open it
so microsoft windows this is all about
software for keyboard for microsoft
windows and click on that you can see
microsoft power tool power toys so one
of the feature of power microsoft power
toys is it allows you to remap keys for
example for for me caps locks is now
home
all left is f9
you know and so on
so this is
operating system based uh kiwi map
and it sucks okay compared to from
keyboard firmware why because sometimes
it doesn't work okay for example i can
show you an example right now
for example um
let me press the app key okay so please
can you see it
yeah so let me press this key
what this key do
is it will send alt control tab
so it lets me to switch a program
without holding
the alt down so you can you see if i
want that program i just press a key you
see
i press one key
then switch to the program i want press
space i got it there so this this so
this is a keyboard uh key remap so i
press the menu key the app menu key it
sends
alt
control tab okay now
it doesn't work so in for example when
you uh let me let me start the task
manager okay so that's all control
escape okay
no
that's
ctrl shift escape there it is okay task
manager in in um in windows right you
are familiar with this
now let's try the
you know the menu app key again do it it
doesn't work you see
escape you see it's supposed to press or
tap alt control tab to allow me to
switch around
so that's a problem you know and that's
just one of the examples there's lots of
examples same thing on linux same thing
on linux 2.
lots of situations it doesn't work so
but if you have the if if i download the
software for this keyboard right now and
program it into the firmware you don't
have this problem you know the key you
programs program are always work the way
you expected them to you know even if
you bring this keyboard to to a new
computer at work or whatever it'll work
okay
so that is why you want a programmable
keyboard with a onboard memory
not
razer crap okay razer is the worst
offender
let me show you uh
so you go to
you know uh
never buy razer you know the razer
idiocy the razer you know the gamers you
know gamers who don't know nothing it's
pretty what they want the gamers want is
colors rgb rgb light what crap
so you go by razer and they require you
to install their software without their
software your keyboard just sometimes
doesn't even work well
something like that okay so you have to
install this software but you also have
to have internet connection otherwise
your keymap course doesn't work
and you also of course you need to uh
register a account you know give all
your personal information so they know
you know which application you are using
at what time you know
they phone home so razer is the worst
crap okay never never never buy raise
that so that is why you want
keyboard with uh you know memory uh on
both memory and programmable okay that's
it about the keyboard
okay let's let's code uh let's code
oh we talked already for 30 minutes
let's start to code emac list now okay
so let's go to
yeah so let's do emac this now so
now as you
i said this is all new to me so okay so
i'm using stuff like keys so let's see
what is the command to
show in browser okay
so we talked about
the k move k dk 60
k move dk 6
one keyboard okay
now let's do uh emac this coding okay
here's a few things i want to do okay
so
okay so first of all let me show you
javascript mod okay so you can
um
magnify okay
uh
javascript in depth
stuff like keys
saw javascript mod okay this is a
fantastic mod
yeah yeah god i don't have my keys set
up
so f11
okay so i need to turn off power toys
[Music]
turn off the remapping of f11 so
keyboard manager
f11
okay so i need to click on that
then
f11 dd that
f12
dd that
okay
okay now
f11 fantastic now i can
finally toggle first full screen okay
then yeah i can switch yeah good
fantastic
so
html so here's a javascript mod okay
and let's magnify so magnify yeah so now
it works
okay so let me demo demo so i want to
create let me show you okay so let's uh
create
uh what
okay so i want to
create a
okay i'm new on this keyboard
yeah
okay so now
let's say console.log three plus
four plus five okay
run it
you can see the answer is nine
why is it uh
i've got oh my god doesn't work so
so anyway here's the answer okay
so
here's the javascript code so the
command i called is um
run current file that's part of stuff
like keys okay so you can run any
program javascript python
uh ruby php you can just
run it
but now i want um i want
to add a feature to that okay so
why because let me show you a javascript
code
so uh let's see javascript yeah okay so
array overview okay so now
copy the url
back to emax well not that
gap
okay all the keys are screwed up
okay anyway so
copy the url back to here then i want to
do
oh god who is dd key you know f9
yeah okay so
expand window
now i want to do
oh yeah open the
file yeah
what is the key to open
open the file path
in the clipboard
so
space space oh there it is okay
so you are looking at the source code of
this html file so now
f9
let's see all the keys so this is
html mod
search for browser open in browser f9b
okay
now close that
f9b showing browser okay
good
back to emacs
now what i want to do let's search for
console
so
over here so you can see
this section
now let's press the key
to remove the syntax highlighting
so you can see
this
is javascript code it just um
console log
type of
type of array you know trying to see
what kind of thing is array the type of
array so let's magnify
okay
so now back to emax now let's
call command
okay pop that out into a window
uh into a buffer then magnify so now i
can run this command expand window run
it you can see the result is true
and this is
okay so the result is true
now but however
you know sometimes i don't want to
always type console log i i want to just
be able to type
this you know i want to be able to
select the region
and call press a key and have that the
value of that printed out without me
having to type console.log so that is
the command
we uh i want to write right now
okay so let's go back to
uh let's go back to exhaust talk show
i don't know where am i so
so now let's delete that delete that
pop this back
let's go to talk show
open it
f9b showing browser
this is today's stock show
jsmart so i want to write cassadjs eva
eval
line okay let's write it
such as eval line okay
copy it
so let's just do it
right now
so
emac list create a template then
open the buffer you know pop it out
then
d for default
okay then
uh what
paste paste paste yeah
javascript line okay and uh
documentation
for today's date
then uh let's say eva
the current line in javascript
print result in
messages buffer
okay that's the documentation
so
first thing to do is
to
get the line beginning position in line
position okay
so let's say
position one
position position two two variables okay
then set
set p1
to line
beginning position
okay that returns the position of the
line beginning okay
then similarly set
p2
to line end position okay then we want
another variable
let's just say line okay
let's just say code okay
let's say javascript code
okay
then you say
set
yeah
set javascript code to
um
buffer substring
no properties
okay
then
give it
you know i'm used to ogo ergonomic
keyboards so i'm not
used to this keyboard yet
so okay
now pretty find the buffer so we got the
javascript code so this
so this
this js code is a string that contains
the current line okay
now we got a code now we have to do is
create a new file
we need to create a new file a temp file
put the code there
then call a shell command to evaluate
the javascript code you know i'm using
deno as a shell command so let's can i
show you
yeah
all my keys doesn't work so let's go to
terminal okay
so you are looking at terminal so you
can see gcm
gcm which is get command name
get command
uh
gcm deno
d-e-n-o okay let's magnify
okay so deno is a javascript
uh
deno is basically the
the better version of not.js you know
it's created by the same guy after 10
years
you know he got you know not.js got
corrupted by a scum
you know
with mpmn stuff you know that guy is not
a good guy so but the original creator
of uh not.js
ryan ryan dawg
he created now he created deno okay
which is a much better uh javascript
runtime and also it also runs
by default okay
and one single binary is it's fantastic
okay get there no so
i use deno to evaluate javascript in
emacs so what we need to do is like you
you
you call a shell command and deno
with the file name that will run the
javascript code so
so now so but first of all we need to um
create a file okay
let's say
okay how do you create a file in emacs
well
uh let's look at my tutorial because
so jumper so
just search for xrd emac these uh
search for saudi emac this
tutorial
then you want to right now the problem
is to create a file okay
there are many ways you know i can do
fine file but it's may not be the best
way
um
let's just let's forget about what's the
best way this you know since i'm doing a
videos it let's just do it quickly
so let's switch back to
what
was our file
yeah there is our file so
yeah actually with temp file okay that's
how you create a file you can find the
tutorial
here read file
uh read file write file so
write file
create a new file yeah so this is the
best way
in emac list to create a file okay with
temp file so
and file name will be just a random name
in current directory for now okay
let's just say
uh xx
yeah
okay let's just say that dot js for now
and the body will be
ah let's create a file name okay
uh so we need a variable
fname okay
so
okay so this needs to be here
set
file name
um let's just say that
this is not the proper way because every
time you call this you actually need a
different file name but let's you know
but we are just prototyping this
so
yeah so now we got the file name
prettify the code
now with temp file file name then insert
so now emacs will create a buffer
that's what with temp file does so it
creates a buffer we need to insert our
javascript code
okay
so insert it into the buffer
then that's it okay emacs will create a
file with that content then the next
thing we need to do is called deno
call deno to evaluate this okay so what
we can do is share command
okay
then no i believe it's deno run
they know run
file name something like that okay so
output buffer we don't care error buffer
we don't care okay so
we have to check what exactly is the
demo syntax you know there are so many
ways to do it so we can see we we can do
dental help
okay so let's yeah so they know help man
so
to run a program
you
do you need to uh yeah so you have to
say run that's right
over here
okay so then i'll run and file name okay
file name is is is that is a variable so
we need to say format
okay format
and file name will be
a variable okay a placeholder
okay so then
you
say
yeah
right
what is the
my emacs command for hippie expand god
it's a new keyboard
everything it doesn't work
what
yeah
i
[Music]
what it should be this key
backslash what about slash let's try
slash
so the command name is tpx expand oh
ctrl t
not okay so let's just use that then
what
no expansion found what
oh f
n
ctrl t okay anyway
so format then or run ctrl t um
yeah i think that's it
format so you call deno and you run the
file name okay
okay let's let's do that okay you are
the buffer
now we just go to a
javascript file
let's go back to a javascript file
now we saw javascript file
let's pop this out
with javascript
okay so here
so we popped it out
and
what no
okay
so we
want to run let's say
three four plus
plus
three okay four plus four okay we want
to run this
this line okay so now we can call
javascript
eval line
please
do it
okay wrong type argument integer or
marker p
okay let's go back to our emac this
something is not correct
and
yeah what
let's go back to emac this close that
okay so
what's the message the error message
is
yeah so the image is set q wrong type oh
a set q
oh yeah the p1 here is a typo okay it
should be p2
okay eval the buffer
now let's go back to the javascript
code okay
magnify a bit
now
call the command xr.js evil line
please
command succeed without with no output
okay
now let's go to the message buffer
oh i forgot that's right so our command
works okay but why is it not printing it
anything of course because you don't
have a console log you see
this is that's why it's kind of tricky
you have to add the print statement
yourself so let's do it let's go back to
the emac this code
and
where's the e magnesium so we actually
need to
we actually need
to add a console log to our e-magnesis
code so
so here the insert
let's
make a format of it
and inside it it would be a console.log
okay
then
console.log something and that something
is the javascript code that's right
okay previous code that's
that should work okay
you are the buffer
switch back to javascript
okay
now go here
fantastic something wrong okay
it prints out some funky thing oh god i
know why
yeah they know uh you see here's the
output let me magnify
you see
you know we evaluated four plus four so
the result should be eight
now if you look at output indeed there's
eight over there but what's what's that
33 m and you know 39 m
that's color that's the terminal you
know that's the control character
as ascii control character for clearing
the output so you know the deno
the denote command is actually creating
a colored output
so what we do we
you know so we have to
find if there's option in in dental to
stop it
from creating color output because when
you create color output in terminal that
essentially means you are printing out
lots of control characters
in this invisible control characters
so let me show you if you don't know
what this means
let me show you this article okay
just search for exactly ascii characters
this article explains in detail what
what's what what are the control
characters means now if you are a
programmer unders understanding ascii
characters thoroughly it's very
important eventually you need to do it
you know
you know if you've been programming for
a few years you know eventually in your
third year or whatever you have to
understand in detail fully what ascii
characters are and what are what are all
the issues for example what what what is
a um code point
what is uh you know hexadecimal
representation what is a um
standard abbreviation you know what what
is uh
um printable characters or control
characters what do they mean you know so
you have to understand this you know
read it
so
because if you don't understand these
then today
i wouldn't know what the is this
you know i would just i would start to
google you know
33 m
and that likely you won't find uh you
know it's would be hard for example
let's do it okay so
yeah
which which is my key
oh yeah so this key will google that so
you see you are trying to google this
you know
it will be hard but because i have some
experience in programming so i know it's
uh
you know these
control characters are for coloring um
okay so so now actually we need to fix
this because otherwise it you know
this is not accept acceptable so we need
to
find a dental option to tell it to stop
using color you know it has been no
color there it is set to decibel color
fantastic environment beautiful
okay so you actually have to use an
environment variable
i don't want to use the environment
variable because environment variable
especially from unix linux is the worst
possible because that's that's
state you know that's
that's basically
everything functional programming are
avoiding
you know
and one
and the environment variable environment
variable is one of the worst problem
they are essentially global variables so
i try
to not use enviro environment variables
at all you know in bash in powershell
you know
do not use environment variables it it's
implicit hell
okay that's uh my advice to you guys
okay i think that's it for today uh well
except we need to fix this
so if you have a question for me
tag me okay
okay the
well one of the suggestion is set the
terminal
set the terminal to
interpret the color properly and output
it
okay that's not the correct solution why
because the terminal
well that's that's one of the let me
show you okay so let's comment this four
plus
four plus four out and let's just run
this you see run it
you see
now you can see
the answer here now let's magnify
nice and it's colored it's colored
yellow that's what deno is doing i don't
like it
so it's actually e max is actually
interpreting interpreting the color
code correctly
but however
however the problem is i guess
okay so what yeah i actually you know
good good suggestion we can we can do it
that way so there are two solutions
one solution is just use the environment
environment variables to tell dental not
use color but i want the option instead
is there one
uh let's see help run okay
they know help run
so where is it config cache only
quiet
seed unstable
va flag
watch okay so lots of features
um
we don't see a no color
yeah this is annoying
but anyway i
i very much respect and trust whatever
the ryan dahl is doing you know he's a
great guy and he's cold you know he's a
great very smart he's a mathematician by
the way
so anyway so we cannot find apparently
there's no
option no parameter
for then or run to
not use color
but there's an environment variable
instead
but
i don't really want to use that
anyway that's one of the solution okay
we have to
look into deeper okay so that's one of
the possible solution the other solution
is to
is to find out why is that e max lisp
is not
interpreting the color correctly while
in
a message buffer okay so we can because
obviously it worked here so what we have
to do is now just look at
xa run
file console run current file to see
what
is it doing
that works correctly so here's the
command console run curtain file
um
[Music]
it calls a shell command and it creates
output buffer okay i think that's why
so
shell command output buffer now where is
the output buffer okay so
okay here so let's let's
let's use a variable okay
so now let's go back to
to the javascript code to the emac this
code
and let's add a variable
output buffer and let's move um
and let's move this
set queue into into the variable list
okay so we can do that
so we don't need to secure a bunch of
secure here anymore fantastic
so
p1 we don't need p2 we don't need js
code we don't need fname we don't need
we have it here
so we this way is kind of more clean
code
whenever so here's a tip for emac this
whenever you have a bunch of variables
and they are kind of constant
and the code their value is very simple
you can
you know you can embed them in the
variable declaration you don't have to
use set queue so okay so now we have a
new variable output
buffer name
so now we can just say shell command
give it to the option shell command
so here's the syntax for shell so let's
let's copy it here so okay
so the syntax for shell then okay so
shell
command then output buffer okay there
that's it that's all we have to do is
just add it there so
prettify the code
okay let's purify the code
and
purify the whole thing okay
eval evaluated
back to the javascript
and
uncomment this four plus four
and uh
now called
js eva line
uh sim symbol's value as variable is
void okay we did something
okay we did some up here so you see
we are declaring several several
variables p1 and p2
but when it comes to js code it relies
on the value of p p1 and p2 so
but when you if you are using let that
doesn't work
the
latter values do not know the pre
previous value so you have to
use let star that's the difference
so when you use let's start then that
work okay
so evaluate the buffer
back to the javascript
code
now call the command such as
do it
uh it worked but same problem so why is
the output buffer not work
we have it output buffer let's see
[Music]
shell command
command then output buffer
oh so we have to
wait what's going on
let
with temp file so that creates a file
then we call shell command
then here's the command
then we say the output buffer should be
this
okay
now evaluate the buffer now go back to
javascript
now call
such as eval line do it
um it's not popping out output so wait
it is okay so let's switch to
xlr run output
yeah it's same problem you see
so why is it okay
so
why is it in
let's
call saran current file
so why is it work here so let's check
cause i run current file
shell command command string
output buffer
um
oh wait so this is javascript wait so
[Music]
so that's wolfram squid script or film
language
so we're talking about javascript
xiao command so
so if the file is emac list
then just call load
if the file is golden
then call xor run current go file
if the file name is wolfram language
script
wufang language mathematica then you do
you know you run this
code you know you call from
script to run it if the file is java
if the file name is ends in dot java you
need to do something special because the
file name needs to be the same as the
class name
now but otherwise
so otherwise this is a general so
otherwise
otherwise shell command okay
so
show command command string output
buffer so
so why is it
so why it's uh
why is it not work
they know run
name yeah so you run the file
that's a command okay
then output buffer so why is it not all
put into our buffer
let's change the name to
xx uh kk to kk1 okay let's see
learn it evolve the buffer
now call
xr.js eval line do it
same thing
now switch to the buffer kk1
you see same thing
yeah i don't i don't know i have to so
i have to figure out
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching if you like my stuff buy my
stuff okay buy my stuff if you have
questions to ask me ask right now okay
by myself patreon me paypal me by my
emacs tutorial
and we we shut down in five minutes
so but anyway so this code is not
but the problem is the output with the
color you know the curling annoying
um and there are other things we need to
do for example the file
name needs to be a random on the fly
okay let's just fix it now okay so the
file name needs to be
let me show you okay the file name needs
to be
format string and format
start with x
then
dot js then a random number okay then a
random number so the random number will
be
uh actually usually i put today's dates
but anyway so let's just say random
random
from 0 to
999 okay
then
yeah so
let's try to run that
okay let's give it to let's say
okay
let's say that run it
seven seven one five six five five five
one five five that's good okay so file
name
then once you evaluate the code you also
need to delete the file so
so you say delete file
what
is going on the
bluetooth problem what
wait
okay so
something is wrong i just turned off the
keyboard
but
so
wow windows screwed up
well windows bluetooth
screwed up
because normally there would be a on and
off button for bluetooth
but windows bluetooth just crashed
you see it doesn't appear here either
ah problem
bye guys