Morning. Good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Sonog
Show. Hello guys. Ultimate hacking
keyboard UHK80.
That one nia trackboard. I have reviews
on YouTube. Search for it. You'll find
it. Okay. We going to code uh easy one.
Emac bisp. We're going to code. Let's
demonstrate. Okay.
[clears throat]
So this is to today's talk show page.
Can you see me? Yes. Can you see my
screen? Yes. Can you hear me? Yes. And
start this. And if you are here, say hi.
Hello to N.
Sorry I'm late. And if you are watching
this offline, play at speed 1.5.
Okay. So now let's start a code.
JavaScript. Let me show you. Okay.
Console log 3 + 4. Okay, now watch the
pink window. Pink window shows all my
command calls and the keystrokes on the
left. So I press a key press. So you see
I just evaluated that JavaScript code.
The result is seven and the command name
is JavaScript eva region and the
keystroke is tab R. So let me do it
again. Okay, let's do it again. Tap tap.
Oh, tap. Wait, hold on. Tab. Ah, you
see? Fantastic. And beautiful. So, what?
So, let me show you the source code.
Describe key. The source code for the
command eval
js evar region is here in one of my
JavaScript mode. Kar JavaScript mode.
in Emacs. Okay, the most power powerful
editor. It's about 20 lines of code.
Okay.
Uh but now we need to do so let me show
you what we going to do. Okay. So go to
it, put it back uh uh syntax show
today's talk show. There we did that.
Now let's say I want to do uh uh F. So
create a F code and how do you print?
Okay, just print uh print 3 + 4. Can you
do that?
I don't think so.
Error because you need uh because you
need the d I think. Okay. I buffer
error. Okay. Int. Uh is it int or how do
you do this? Okay. So you need a par. Is
that right?
Okay, you need a parent and uh let's say
yeah okay in okay so that works but the
command I'm coding is uh close that
I'm calling this command okay run
current file okay so you can look at the
source code
run current file and you can get that
code at this URL showing browser search
for it you will find it Okay, that
allows you to run the current file of of
of uh many programming languages
including JavaScript, Python, Ruby,
Bash, Goland, and others. Okay, so you
can run quite a few. Uh so here's a list
including F, Golan, JavaScript, PHP,
Pearl, PowerShell, Python, Python 3,
Ruby, Deno, uh and Wuan language. Okay.
And you can also add closure has lat or
camel racket this racket scheme this or
bash and uh uh typescript and and and uh
v um visual basic
okay so and p so okay so that's the code
you can grab it
but that code is for running the current
file you see close it close But often
times you don't want the uh run the
current file. You just want to run the
current region eval the current region.
Okay. So in F I don't have that command.
Let's write one. Okay. So that is uh
today's job. We're going to write
Okay. It's um
the job is to write a
uh what is so let me demo again do it.
You see so uh describe key press. So the
command is this
JavaScript eval region. Okay. Close. Put
it back. write a um
f
that's the command we want to write.
Okay,
we already have
we already have that we want to write
that. Okay, now make them code and make
them the list and showing browser. Okay,
and page down. So the job is to write F#
Eva region. Okay, let's do it now. Okay,
so all we have to do first of all is
just copy the code. Okay, because they
are they would be almost exactly the
same. Okay, describe function
JS eval region. Go to the source code.
Jump to Okay, so here is the source
code. Copy it. Now go to the directory.
Now delete those backup files. Oh, these
are my code. Emac list. Okay. Search for
F sharp. That's there. That's where we
want. Now, where do you want the
function? Let's just for now add it at
the top. Okay. Paste it.
And now you can see
go up. You need to change the name. So,
this is F.
Okay. F. Very sharp. Okay. Eva region.
Now, let's see uh what things we need to
change.
check them meticulously
creation date
current date about the current region uh
in Denojs. No, that's incorrect. So the
we when we run F is going to be uh what
is the command? Let's see
fsx.
Now what is uh yeah okay so net okay so
the in order to run f programming script
you run it in net fsi okay that is the
so you have to say we are doing this uh
in net f okay
you are the current region in net fsi
okay then print result in buffer s f
output Okay, there is no text selection
eval text block. Fantastic. This is very
convenient. So every time you you you
want to run something. Uh let's go to
talk show. Where's where's my talk show?
Go there. So F. So let's say you know
let's say I want to eval
uh uh you know
you know some like like the code may be
uh oh let's let's do e let okay let let
x equals to three then here okay so you
want to select it right because you need
both of of the lines but
it's convenient to automatically select
whatever the current paragraph. So you
don't have to like uh go oh go up go to
the beginning start selection go to you
know you don't have to do that. Okay so
that is a very convenient thing you want
to do. So go back to our code that go
back to our code uh here. Yeah
fantastic.
Uh so if universal argument is called
first insert result below the region.
Fantastic. required. No require of
course require.net.
Okay. Now let's see check check check
those we don't have to change because
fantastic the power of experience
because I have experience 20 years and
plus so I can just multiply my code
without doing much. So this is the part
you start to need to change. Okay. So
the output is casad.net.
Wait, is it is it the net? Yeah. Okay.
Net FSI. Okay. So that's the output
buffer. Then call process.net.
Um,
okay. You need to know how do you call
net?
Uh,
I forgot. So let's look up my eval
region. Um,
so this is when you also need to check
like the net stupid. Uh,
okay. So let's
control scroll to magnify.
Okay, so we have net help.
Okay. Uh,
the boss. [snorts]
You see the reason we want to do it is
we we want to know how do you call
uh you know this is like very long Jesus
can you can c can we like increase this
okay yes we can
okay found smaller please okay and do it
again okay net help the reason we want
to know is because we are going to call
add fsi to co f
and uh there are several issues of
concern you know one easy way is just
you pass it a file name that's a the
most easy way you know run something you
know like f run file name JavaScript run
file name deno run file name notjs run
file name python sometimes you don't
have to have you have you don't have to
say run you just python file name that's
the most easy case but other times you
don't want to
um
pass a file because when you run the
current line it's not a file right so
you just want to pass a string
so how do you pass you know run this
command a string okay but other times
but usually you don't want to pass a
string because in EMAC you want to pass
a string to shell that's very
problematic because involves lots of
quoting back slash SL escape
That's from the Unix C They
created that situation.
A permanent damage to computer computing
industry. Okay.
Um so
so we so ideally what we want to know is
in how do you in in the net command how
do you run F with standard in? Okay, if
you can pass it standard in and evaluate
a expression that would be the best.
Okay,
so you see uh unt options. So actually
I'm not sure how the
I'm not familiar with this F command
line at all and the whole net because
you see you see this these so-called
hosted languages they get complex
because it's not just F you you you have
this net engine which also runs C and uh
net visual basic and possibly other
So you know so it's complex anyway let
let me let's try to fix make it work.
Okay. So here so wait so not software
keys. Okay. Uh let's say
dot
so that's how you run uh fn
net fsi. Okay. Uh and uh okay. But
that's a file. That's when you want to
run a file. Okay.
So, oh, let me let me show you guys.
[clears throat]
What is this Java? Okay.
current file descri dispatch. Okay, run
file. Okay, so that's run file and uh
you basically
the line that calls the command is this.
Okay, start process
uh fairly complicated. Okay.
So,
so that's how you actual
actually actually call the external
process. Okay. And what you do is app
string. So
uh so the external command name
run file map. Okay. So,
so what? So, what is the actual
command you called?
We can print it, you know. So, okay. So,
it's app command string
then uh
three string. Okay, you need you want it
to be a list. That's why then basically
file name. Okay. So it's
so basically
I can tell you what's running what.net
FSI
basically just runs that. Okay.
Um
okay basically that's running that.
Okay. But now
uh so what what are we doing? So okay so
let's copy that. Okay, cut now. Cut.
Close that. Uh, I'll put close that.
Let's go back to uh F. So, basically,
we want to run something like that. No,
wait. But, so, you see, this is for
running a file name,
but we don't want a file name. We want
to just run a
run a run a string. and prefer
preferably
pass the string from standard input.
Okay. Now, does anyone know how to do
that? So, let me check the comments.
Will this function only be found in F
mode? What function? Why not Linux,
Emacs, on Windows? Interesting. Uh,
that's a frequently asked question. I've
been talking about that for like five
years every few months. So venv
you will be surprised like why not Linux
you know because those people you know
that's frequently asked question and
those people who asking that are idiots
supreme
okay so you might be surprised maybe I'm
not the right guy for you to watch
actually I think I am because
but anyway so you have a lot to dig into
why Why not Linux? So you going to have
Linux.
So next question ACP do you write to a
temp script and execute the script or
pipe the buffer to stand in of the F
interpreter.
So I have explored all these
possibilities. Okay. So there are few
tips for those who want to do this.
First of all,
avoid file if you can because files are
very slow. So you don't want to write to
file. First of all, you don't want to
run a command from a file because when
the command run runs from a file, it has
to read a file which means load the
disk. Even if you have you know flash
drive or before flash drive you have
spinning disc. Those are slow. Spinning
disc is super slow like 100 times slow.
Then flash drive is also very slow.
Okay. So avoid reading file
if you can.
Now writing to a 10 file is worse
because you you you you not only have to
read a file but you also have to create
one you have to write to disk. So that's
like twice twice as 100 times slower.
Okay. So avoid file if possible at all
and don't do uh and also especially when
you do temp file that has more problems
other than just slowness because then
you have to manage your tempter like are
you going to clean it up like after a
year you going to your script creates
hundreds of files you know actually I I
have such um
I have such um
okay so this is Microsoft's operating
systems tempter. Okay. So you can see uh
okay this is not many 63 but you know
and I also have my emac tempter. Okay.
So
wait what's going on?
What open? Yeah. So emac d okay go there
temp. So this is my own tempter. This is
what you know whenever I evaluate the
line. So you see javascript f
golan uh wufam language that's wam
language that's eag this okay so that
you know so when you create a temp file
then you got extra problem you need to
manage it you need to like maybe once in
a while delete it it's a pain it's
painful because then you have to decide
how you going to check you know and and
which file you gonna delete
Are you going to delete based on access
time or are you going to delete based on
you know a time stamp in the file name
you know you have to manage it so it's
like a headache
I mean so you have to delete it once in
a while then then people wonder you know
why do I when I run this command
sometimes like every week it becomes
super slow well because it's trying to
delete your your temp you know temp
files it creates right so but user will
have that reaction.
So temp file
you don't want that.
Avoid it. Okay. Files avoid it. So the
ideal the best way is just to have Emacs
send
uh from memory the current region or
whatever the current text send it to
standard input and have the terminal the
external program pick it up from the
standard input which is kind of like a
it's a a buffer in memory. Okay, those
are not files. So it's like buffer in
memory. So that's very fast and then you
don't have to clean up you know uh temp
file and and so on. So that's the best
way. Okay. So that is the uh because I
have because I have lots of these script
for different languages I explored
uh their options. So when you want to do
this the first thing important is you
want to know
what you know the you have to rely on
the exter external command like do they
accept
an expression from standin that's the
first thing you want to know because if
not then like some of them only accept
files then you have to go with files
right
it it does happen you know that does
happen. Some of these um you know
Python, Deno, NodeJS,
uh Golan, Wuang language, they all have
like variations of options. So anyway,
right now we want to know
uh right now [clears throat] we want to
know
uh here is a here's a thing we want to
know. Okay, let's see. Let's write it
down.
Right now we want to know if the
net fsi whatever that is I don't quite
know
accept a f expression
from standard input. Okay,
that's what we want to know.
And what is the syntax? Okay, of course
that's the most important. So I don't
know. I don't know. Uh so we have to
spend
10 minutes to read about that or
something you know to read about this uh
net command.
uh
back
net runtime options path to app
applications. So you know there are many
way to go you can first you can read the
net help directly or you can read from
website you know may you know so this AI
provided some answer or you can read the
official documentation their reference
on interactive think you know so there
are many
approaches to understand how this works
so you'll take some time.
Okay. So, let's let's see the help first
here. Okay. Do you guys know?
Okay. Do we do we have people watching
me? Say hi. Okay. Let's see.
Seven people. Okay. So, you so we're
going to read. Okay. So, let's see.
Runtime option execute a net
application. Okay. That's what uh
execute a net application.
So, so FSI
apparently is a runtime options. Oh,
wait. What is it? So, run time runtime
options. Additional
additional
probing
probing path. [laughter]
That's so funny. Funny. Look at this.
Look at this option. Two funny aspects.
One is that you know it's all lower
case. It's like just run on word
additional probing path. Okay. Takes a
while to understand. The second
interesting thing it says probing probe.
[laughter]
It's like a pro a probe.
So path containing a containing probing
policy and assemblies to probe for what
the
probing policy. What the
idiotic? You know this this kind of
technical docu documentation is worst
because when whenever you see the word
policy,
it means like the corporate corporation
thing like corporation baggage. They
have to word it that way. Oh, it's a
policy. A idiot.
Then then then then it's spectacular.
They you know they have now they have
now the phrase well beinging policy like
what the does it mean and assembly
you see this is this is the lawyer this
is the beginning of the lawyer jargon
you know whenever you start to see you
see policy you know that's the beginning
you know they they becoming more then
they then it's going to be like legal
lease you know like full words you don't
understand what they talking about like
path containing probing policy and
assemblies to probe for what the
does it mean? Idiots. Okay, this is a
example of idiocy in technical
documentation.
It's you know this kind of uh idiocy
came from corporations like Java
enterprise and net you know the
Microsoft the huge corporations this
this type of idiocy they rarely they
almost never occur in the Unix and C
hacker idiots community such as Unix
command line you you will not see this
policy and assemblies you know What?
Whatever that is. But but the Unix
and C idiots, they have their own
idiocies like like juvenile juvenile
humor like grab cat, you know whatever
Okay. So we are exploring looking into
um
technical writing aspects. Okay. Which
is part of human endeavor.
Okay. So we got additional depth uh path
for additional uh depth JSON file depth
file FX uh version
uh version of the install shared
framework to
to use to run our application rule
forward. Okay. Did they anywhere mention
FSI
F runtime config? I don't think so. So
path to application. Oh, okay. The path
to an application DL file. Oh, okay. So,
so I believe FSI FSI is a is a DLL
file.net. That's right. Right. That
makes sense. Just like Java.
Okay. So,
so well the question is then how do you
um pass in standard input? Okay.
Okay. So this net is too much you know
it's not really relevant to F. Oh there
it is additional commands from bundled
tools. FSI start F interactive execute F
script. So let's see
dot.net
FSI help. Let's see we can do that.
No.
Uh quit quit.
Let's see.net
help FSI. Let's see if that Oh, it went
to the browser.
Okay, let's see.
So basically all I want to know is if is
how do I pass a expression to standard
input? I mean does it does it accept a
expression from standard input?
Does anyone of you know?
Hello buddo.
Again the question is I want to call net
fsi
to run a f expression.
How do I do it?
So I mean okay so she so what what is it
interactive programming in C? Does
anyone know like what is the command
name syntax
to accept a expression from standard
input? Let's ask AI. Okay,
let's ask AI
how to get
to accept a F expression
from standard input. Okay, let's ask
guac.
Gawk, help me
help.
Magnify, magnify, magnify, magnify,
magnify.
Okay. Now you need to old space
size expand the window length so you can
see
mommy I cannot see make it larger. Okay.
So okay to evaluate a single F
expression or small snippet coming from
standard input with net FSI the most
reliable and clean way in 2026
are
oh
you see I it's part you know I don't
want to write a script
oh wait oh triple dot
Okay. So
triple dot. That's like
that's bash, right? I don't want
Okay.
So you can pipe to it. Oh, so if there
is standard input that will directly
work.
Fantastic. That's it. That's it. That's
it. That's what I That's what we're
looking for. So now go back to the code.
We can do this right away. Okay. Close
that. Close that. go to right away. So
call process.
God, the file is too large.
So you let's uh let's see
okay co process region okay co process
region let's
highlight all the word demo okay because
we need to change it
highlight all the wordn net Okay. So,
so if you want to print it out,
if you don't don't want to print it out.
So, let's see.
Net FSI
new I'll put run. No, not run. So, this
this needs to be here. Okay.
net fsi and uh no dash directly work
like that actually I think that's it
that will work and also here
uh this is not eval this is fsi
and uh not here you don't need
So
co- process and co process region. Okay.
Why do I need that? Because JavaScript.
Let's use them. Let's do both. Okay.
Uh
if it's true,
I don't know you you why you have these
two things. You just need one thing.
Okay,
that's the that's the thing. Okay,
beginning, end, and what is the
beginning, end? That's right. Beginning,
end is a beginning and end position.
Okay, I think that's it. I think that's
it. Let's just write eval buffer. Okay,
now oh, now you need to give a key. So,
let's give a key to this command. Let's
say search for key binding.
Okay, let's give a key and see what keys
you want for that.
Let's say
let's say a okay now eval that eval the
region go to uh okay that's done now
let's try it
search for pre let's uh pop out so
now press tab R that should evow this
region okay let's do it tap are
fantastic. You see it worked. However,
you see there is seven. It worked. But
this is not ideal, you know. I just want
the output. I don't want this. Uh, okay.
Let's try this part. Okay. Have our
Yeah, it works.
Okay, it works. We But we need some fix.
Do I make sense?
Okay. Okay. I think maybe that's it for
today.
Night people. Okay. So, I think that's
it for today. I mean, our code works. We
can evaluate, you know, but
but it returns this
Who cares on the copyright
copyright and registered trademark?
[laughter]
Well, it's not it's no worse than by the
way this is Linux.
Oh god. So, okay, we got this problem.
So,
so how do you solve this problem? Well,
the well you have to basically
the problem is about
the problem is about you need to fully
understand
how this net
command works. You know, you need to
fully understand
and you need to fully understand how
this net works.
So right now we are just
put FSI
uh
But uh so there must be some option to
FSI. So let's go to AI. You know AI is
fantastic. AI just let's see if you copy
that and run this in shell. What do you
get?
Idiotic. Okay. So you see that's why
so but I don't want um
just show the result
fs ancho usually uh Uh
okay. So basically
what I need to do is just carefully to
read about this.NET net command line how
like how the whole thing works
like FSI
um
you know I I don't want this interactive
thing I just want the output can you
actually do that
okay so or do I have like wrap I have to
wrap in some code then that's that's not
That's not good, you know, because then
I have to, you know, write some code
here.
Um, like F# code, like generate F code
on the fly, like generate,
you know, gener generate um something
like um
yeah, generate, you know, some some F
code on the fly as a wrapper.
Uh
so anyway, here's the code. Okay. So,
let me let me copy the code so you guys
can see what's going on. Copy it.
Go back to uh talk show and uh let's
paste the code here.
Emac paste it. Syntax color showing
browser. So, here is today's talk show.
Our job is to write a F eval region
command in EMAC.
We already have JavaScript evol region.
Okay. And the main issue, the main
question is about
h how does the net fsi you know how do
you make that command accept an
expression f expression from standard
input.
Okay, that is the main question. And we
asked guac
and guac told me all you have to do is
pipe it to net fsi. Okay. So we did it.
The result isn't so good. It you know it
actually started the interactive
Okay. So is there a other way to just
get the output without this pre this uh
prelude
copyright stuff? So that is a question.
Meanwhile, here's a code you can look
at. Uh it's not not not difficult. It's
very simple. The first part is just get
gets the beginning and end position of
the current block. Okay.
So that's the first part which I've done
and explained a thousand times in the
past five years online
and the second part the critical part is
this part the core process region. Now
that is fairly complicated. Okay
meanwhile let me show you one more
thing. Okay, you just go to my uh just
search for Emacs blog and go to
Emacs list this
tutorial. Then there's a section text
processing
uh writing a command and uh
copy cut paste get buff a string work
with lines things add point get text
block there that's about how do you get
the beginning and end position of the
current paragraph okay that what that's
part of our command now the other thing
we want to know is uh cursor position
uh and so on is write file, read file,
close call shell command. Okay. Now
there are many ways to do it. Now
one way is simply pass it to a shell
then the shell bash or powershell will
start then run your command. Usually
that's no good.
What you want is directly start the
command the external command such as net
or whatever without
starting a shell like bash or powershell
then start python orn net you know so
you directly so there are many ways to
directly call external command okay so
here is the explanation not this okay
the start external process
so that's one way call process and you
also have other ways called process
region. Okay. So in fact that is the
command we called today is it
is it
is see process region.
So, so if you want to learn more about
this even this technicality,
read my
tutorials. Okay.
Okay. Bye guys. Bye guys. Now if you
like my stuff, pay me. Okay. Go to go to
my homepage kasali.info. Let me show
you. Go to homepage. Homepage here. Here
kasali.info.
Okay. So go up kali.info. info and go
all the way to the bottom like that,
like that. Math, JavaScript,
programming, technicalities,
and you see Amazon, you see PayPal, you
see Patreon, you have to click them,
click them, go to their website, they
have https,
then you can,
you know, buy and uh put your credit
card or whatever. Okay, thank you guys.
That's it for today.
Bye.
But does the copyright message go to
stand out or stand arrow?
I think it goes to stand out.
Yeah. So that's the output.
Okay. Bye guys. That's it.
So show uh yeah that's today's talk show
there's some things to fix.
Okay, so this basically means for me it
basically means I'm going to like take
an hour to read about this whole
net command line thing just as you would
if you're going to you know read about
mpm
or nojs or deno whatever new languages
you have to read about all these
details else.
So, this is a full.net thing.
Okay.