for
one
what for
that
hello guys welcome to another episode of
c talk show we're going to code imagis
on image getting the image width and uh
height okay so let's
see so if you here say hi if you are
watching offline play at 1.5 speed and
uh skip around because I Rambo okay
today's topic is emac disp let's see
video check audio
check all good okay so emac is so
getting image size so the job what we
want to do is to get the
image uh height and width okay so here
is a image let me show you okay so
actually let's just copy that okay so
you got the image there okay let's go to
uh pictures directory and
screenshots and uh we got some image for
example if you want to know the
dimension so typically so you can you
know if you do it manually you open
image application so you can see this is
um
784 by
662 okay so um close that
and uh you can do it in multiple ways
you can do it in command line uh you can
also do it in
uh many ways okay but anyway let let me
just start to show you we want to be
able to do it in emac so for example we
um
actually H
what so hello guys hello shrimp hello
blue good evening from
UK the man from Germany hello the man
from
Germany have you tried the other text
editor like
like helex or
Vim well Vim I tried like 25 years ago
30 years ago in the year 2000s Vim is
the okay digression okay
Vim emergency Vim VI is one of the Unix
[ __ ] sometimes in a emergency
situation you are forced to deal with VI
and [ __ ] Unix admins refuse to
install emac okay then what you do in
Vim this is the the fundamentals
okay so I've been using them like in
year 2 1999 but it's a [ __ ] um back to
emac so let's let's focus on the get
image size
okay okay so I want to show you yeah
yeah let's just let do it okay
so
uh okay go to pictures then go to
screenshots so so I got one screenshot
we got two screenshot we got three
screenshots okay and I have a command
that um we'll move that to um let's
let's do it again go to pictures open in
uh Windows browser so you can see the
commands SAS show in desktop if you
search that you'll find a source code it
allows you to open any directory in in
Windows uh Explorer or on the Mac finder
and so
on okay so s show in desktop actually
you can do it and search you'll find the
code Kar show in desktop now in
Microsoft Windows highlight the file
what the [ __ ] is that oh that's part of
CA FL Keys okay so you can see that's
what I'm using sfly keys uh and you can
get the source code
um what is this S Talk Show okay I
talked about that a while ago but where
is the command by itself you know Brave
browser is not so good okay so let let
me just
um I'll show in
desktop yeah we digressed over so you
want to find that so search Google I
look up and then Google requires want to
know where you live and stuff very
annoying back to emac so search Google
again showing desktop so Google is
actually better at search uh so there it
is the source code so you can in any in
any file in emx you can you can um press
a key right press a key to to show in
the current um operating
systems file managements
fi file manager technically that's what
it called on Microsoft it's called File
Explorer on the Mac it's called finder
on Linux it's just file manager but
depending on which Linux distribution
you are using you have different um uh
ones such as notilus and uh you know so
anyway this command showing this up okay
U okay copy the URL back here paste a
URL make a link uh actually I don't want
that I want to go to the file so you can
see the local file there copy the file
path close it paste it here make a link
make a list then delete that then cut
that move it to uh move it to somewhere
here okay that's a digression but we are
going to do image okay
so so you can see so so uh so let me
just call the command Okay so press
press uh let's go here uh actually let's
go here let's go here press press press
That's one image press press press
that's another image press press press
that's another image showing browser so
you can see this command what I just
called
is um HTML move image files so that will
move move certain files in your pictures
directory or download directory or
documents directory or desktop you can
set it up by you know you can have a set
of list of directories to check it will
then you call this command it will
automatically move them into the current
buffer with the link so for example open
open that open that uh so open that
that's a screenshot we just did we don't
want it so delete the image then delete
this tag so showing browser again so you
see so it will automatically move the
file to the directory your current
directory but also you can see you you
got the width and height so how is that
done so that command I just called
um okay that command I just call this
some move uh HTML move image file let's
go to the source code then you can see
the source code let's expand it so the
source code has a list of
um list of directories
here by this local variable you can
change it you know and then it has a uh
Target directory
like like uh so this is relative to the
current file
so I set it to I so whatever my current
file then there's a directory named I
the image will move there okay that's
just my blog structure that my website
then you got this uh variable which is a
regular expression list and they are set
here so whenever a file name start with
TT move it or start with E move it TT
and E are the index finger on the V
keyboard layout which which is what I'm
using okay or a known. JPEG that's
typically uh when you save some file on
Twitter or something I forgot then
YouTube sometimes they have HQ default
that you know that's just some of the
default image names so when you save a
file from Twitter or YouTube or do a
screenshot you know these names Untitled
you know they they will be moved so this
you can set yourself and and on Twitter
they have this pattern for image default
and G they have this pattern and uh then
then old trer has this pattern uh eBay
image files they have this pattern and
then screenshots depending on different
operating system sometimes you have uh
you know screenshot with a space or no
space or lowercase and if you have
photos from your digital camera uh
usually they are IMG you know or DSC
something something and then uh there's
pmm that's for Mac I believe so then
there's Amazon image pattern so this
command allows you to whenever you save
image from different websites then you
press a key if you are writing Blog then
they automatically
become this figure tag very nice so see
with the image size and height okay so
go back go back to the code so the code
the code itself is this okay so this is
about um copy new buffer paste 80 lines
of code syntax color iMac this mod so
you see so is this command available to
you yes go to this un L open it showing
browser fantastic so you can use it
free okay so copy the file path close
close close the source code uh reopen uh
Untitled yeah we don't care close close
close oh by the way that's
um uh there's more to that command okay
let me show you but first of all make a
link show there show there there it is
smooth image file fantastic
utility via the power of emac
lisp uh so what is this uh yeah the
brave search not too good I
mean usually if you search common things
it's good but I'm searching SAR emac
commands so that's rarely done so that's
why Brave doesn't show my um my website
on the
top so we demonstrated we demonstrate
this uh image move command but there's a
much more to it so let me show you okay
let me explain and get to today's topic
so describe key this key uh wait
describe key uh wait describe key that
that that okay then jump to the source
code
so oh not convert to jpeg that's another
one so wait
uh
what oh okay
so move image file right so let's go to
the source code so you can see this
command actually it will
do quite useful it will
do uh optimize
PNG you see it will automatically
automatically optimize PNG and if it's a
JPEG file it will also remove the
metadata so for example you take a photo
it records your location the GPS
information you know on many phones you
can do that but when you write your blog
you don't want usually you don't want
that information there so you have this
command diet remove all metadata and you
have optimized PNG so all these commands
let's see uh optimize PNG is it
available to you no URL I'm sorry you
have to pay okay so this is part of my
uh diet package
so okay so anyway so this is very
convenient you just press a few Keys you
move images to your blog you don't have
to worry about removing the metadata or
or optimize the PNG file that makes a
significant difference so let's see the
metadata commands do we have it um no I
don't have it on my website why because
some of these command if you I want to
make it on my website sometimes they
require uh other
things uh but in not in the oh wait uh
yeah they call exit tools
okay you know sometimes I don't you know
anyway I don't I don't have it uh on the
website so yeah image move data I can
demo
them uh I can demo them for example
let's do another screenshot okay there
it is a screenshot now close that now go
to um go to the pictures directory
screenshot uh there it is the
current we the screenshot we just did
did okay so go to the directory so you
can see here's a f file size now make a
backup here's a back uh F backup now
let's view the meta data of this image
file so press the key there is the metad
data in this case there's not many
actually okay and uh press a
key that deletes the meta data meta data
so let's view it again uh in fact it's
one line shorter or something okay and
uh what about optimize so if you refresh
the the ad you can see the file size is
slightly smaller than the orinal compare
see and then the optimization okay now
let's make a another backup okay now
let's optimize this this image uh wait
let open it this image is not optimized
so let's do it press
press you see optimizing it's done
refresh now you can see now it's
23k kilobytes 23 kilobyte it was 33
kilobytes you see
fantastic same image now you see but
when you call this move image file uh
you don't even even have to call those
commands it's just all automatic That's
The Power of emac disp provided that you
have to write them you have to know emac
disp uh like me I spent like 15 years
coding emac disp so
powerful and uh okay that's
demonstration of some of these command
but we haven't get to the main topic
which is how do you do it I mean how do
you get the image file side image width
and dimension that's actually a tricky
question so I can show you so for
example so let's let's start to talk
about that let me show you okay so how
do you actually get the W uh width and
height
okay you you you you know um you uh
so okay let's uh let's go to that file
again I mean that's go to the source
code again cuz I convert to J now this
always got the wrong key uh describe key
that will be that that that uh
what okay there HT um got not that one
describe
key that that that yeah HTML move image
file okay go to the source code now you
can see so the part of the command will
call get image width and
height uh well you don't see it here but
uh okay let me show you another command
Okay so this file is image I want to
copy the file path so press a key it's
done now go here enter paste that's a
file path open it fantastic close it now
I want to make this into a image tag
when you have a image path turn it to a
image embedded image okay so that will
be tab I
I okay actually tab II does something
else undo okay because tab II actually
does the figure tag so let's see tab I
uh wait
okay so let's do it again t uh e i there
it is it became a image tag open it yeah
and show in browser so you can see this
image is duplicate twice but however you
can see the formatting is a bit
different because the second one got the
shadow on the side can you see that well
the first one no shadow why is that
because one of is one of them is simply
a image tag while the other one is
figure tag with figure caption okay and
then via CSS go to the top you can go to
the CSS search for figure f i u r e
there it is there it is so you can see
figure tag has a box
Shadow so that is why you see the
difference in fact there's more
difference u in fact the
um
anyway so we digress a little bit now
let's go back so you see that's a
command to make a turn a image path into
a image
tag now this command also need you see
this is one of the the the simplest
command that we requires the width and
height you see but how how does it know
how does it do it so let's look at this
command so describe key uh then tab
EI so HTML image to image tag jump to
the source code open it there it is copy
it new buffer paste 50 lines of
code now make it iMac list mod fantastic
beautiful syntax coloring go to the top
okay so this command so you can
see HTML image at with and height then
UHA then
thisa get image size okay so let's look
up that
command Target image size defined in
elip ut there it is now this elips UT
let's go to the directory elips
utilities this file is available for you
on this page you can click it and here's
the whole source code so emac this
utilities so copy it close now let's uh
paste the link here
here linky
okay uh but so we don't need this close
that now go back to the source code now
go back to that position IET image size
so you can see here's how it does so if
system equals to Wind by the way this
code is also here okay so you can grab
grab
this if the operating system is Windows
then you call get image size via image
magic okay look up the source code that
function is also defined here get image
size via the image magic utility which
is no good because that's two gigabyte
of download okay close
it uh by the way so this is uh this is
optimize PNG file output close it close
it so let's return here uh image to
image tag yeah so you can see uh let's
go back to the
um Clos
Set uh linky so where's the utility so
let's uh see so what is this command
image to image tag yeah so image to
image
tag H God I went all over but we haven't
get get into the image um size yet okay
let's get image size go back to this
okay so basically I have several
commands you can call image magic if
it's on the Mac then you call Image you
call the sips utility that is bundled on
the Mac that come with Mac OS that this
in fact is the best utility okay so you
can look at the source
code uh source code is it's also defined
here okay and if it's on Linux then you
call Image get size Linux which is um
you can see it here actually so image
get size sips on the
Mac this code is using image
magic this code is using
Powershell this code is using
Linux without image magic or anything
extra in stored so and then finally you
got image size using emac disp so
ideally this is the best solution
because then you don't require users to
have image magic installed or or
whatever
external programs this is pure emac
bisp okay so but it's got a problem
because I realized about few months ago
the image size obtained via emac this is
incorrect so let's go into that let me
show you that
okay so
um reopen close close close close now
switch showing browser okay we back here
so I have already written and linked
here so emac BG get emac list get image
width and height uh appears to be a bug
so let's
demonstrate so again using this sample
image by the way this this sample image
is how many websites are not using
https this is AI bot gr answer turns out
there are some 20% according to G that's
not https so how many is that 20% would
be
8 96 million wait 224 million
websites are not using https and they
are banned they they got censored by
Google Chrome and
Firefox they censored 224 million
websites that is whenever you have a
link that's not https you click it in
Google Chrome browser
the Google scum and the Firefox scum you
click it they will automatically change
that HTTP to
https automatically even if you have
setting settings turn it turn you have
it turned off okay then the website will
say error okay that's what Google and
Firefox is doing
so they are nasty this happened about a
month ago
so what you want to do is use a brave
browser Brave browser or Safari that
doesn't do that okay so we talked about
this yesterday this was yesterday's
topic so anyway so here's a gbot you
know image so you know
so so this image uh open it uh wait open
it again this image what uh so you can
see it's here what we want to do now
yeah we want to get the image side so
let's try the varieties of solutions
okay so let's um okay let's start a
let's start a emac this
code okay paste that pop this out okay
then what we want to do we want to call
those image functions okay
uh get image size describe function
let's go there okay
now let's uh let's copy okay so let's
copy the whole thing back
here okay we want to uh show the
varieties
of ways to do that
okay okay we got these functions
fantastic and Beautiful by the way this
is tedious so you can just do
that parent
let me try again okay undo undo undo so
copy that
wait okay anyway you got so you got this
you want to turn into parent so call
this command p r and parent and the
separator line separator
none fantastic and beautiful power of
emac V are coding s quot lines if you
want that command you can search it it's
on the
web okay let's just search it anyway uh
not atmology so we want uh search Brave
please Brave show it okay there it
is so that's command convenience for you
free of
charge now you should pay me okay I you
should if you enjoy
my talk very much okay so back here so
you can so we want to get image size so
each one of them will take a
um f
path okay so uh you know so then that
okay so for example let's try that one
so is that all you need let's look at
the documentation I'll get image size
image
magic okay all you need is the file path
okay now let's run
it identify
unable why because this is a relative
file path and right now this this temp
file is in the temp that's why you get
[ __ ] now so therefore you either need to
run this code in the proper directory or
use a full path so let's use the full
path that's a proper way
so so get the so is this the image yes
copy the URL and back here paste that's
a full path okay so let's fix that let's
fix all
this and uh this this us something
that's annoying let's just change it to
T the Unix AB bre
um okay that's better so you can go here
open it that's the correct file yes
close it now let's run this run
it identify unable ah God we cannot use
this shortcut okay let's undo okay now
okay now let's run it
there it is okay now that's using image
magic now if I call the use the Linux
one it won't work because I'm not on
Linux let's we can try it you can see it
returns Neo okay now uh oh Linux why is
it repeated okay so not that so on the
Mac this won't work neither because run
it NE because I'm not on the Mac I don't
have the sips
command oh but yeah we forgot the powers
shell okay so so let's do the poers
shell one Powershell native to Windows
pwsh describe function do we have the
name correct yes okay so now run
this there it is power sh is actually
much slower so why do you have all these
because depending on what operating
system you are on you know basically
you you don't want people to install you
know you don't want to rely on you know
external extra installation as much as
possible now there's one more thing we
forgot to show emac this version okay so
let's try it here so image s let's
completion I forgot to use completion
there it is emac this okay the
okay now let's try
this fantastic you see you see the
difference now image magic says the
width is
784 Powell says the width is
784 uh Linux says uh Linux and Mac I I'm
not on so ignore those but emac this
this says the the width
is 1,3
333 so you
see emac
Lis get image D Dimension got a problem
here is the code okay very short
code that's it so first of all you check
what image type by file name extension
so that's file name extension then if
image type is
available meaning that if ma this this
support that image type then you clear
image cache then you call image size
which is a buildin emac this function
you know then you have to create the
image first you know then you call image
size you get a size then you return the
result okay this is emac list get image
size but you got a
bug that's a problem
uh which is very annoying
because otherwise emac this would be the
best solution because we are working in
imag Le you don't require any external
[ __ ] such as image magic 2 gigabyte
installation it's going to install a
bunch of font and the font system you
know like and image you know like
character recognition
[ __ ] despise you know image magic was
from Unix like 20 20 years ago it it's
it's one of the worst design the worst
command line let let me explain that
okay so anyway we I think we finished
one one um section of the talk that is
demonstration of the varieties of ways
to get image size using different
commands on different operating
systems and we demonstrated the emac
list
bug that's quite interesting because
then you look into what how do you get
the image file size
exactly that's another topic okay
because a image size depending on what
type of image it is PNG or jpeg or uh or
you know or
um PNG jpeg GIF and uh web web webp you
know Google's new format and jpeg 2000
you know each one have different um
specification where they embed the image
width and height and it turns out at
least for some of these image types the
embedded width and height may not be
actually
correct it may you know it may not be
just a header you know one of the header
but it may not be actually up to date
you know something like that so to
actually look into this is quite getting
quite complex because then you have to
look into each image types file
specification and there are so many PNG
jpeg jpeg 2000 and and and this quite a
few new and apple has a
heif then there's GIF and uh then you
know so so you have to look into the spe
specification for each one so it gets
very comp complex and the other thing is
to check why is emac this have this bug
okay so let's sum summarize what what we
did syntax color it showing browser so
that's we talked about we talked about
the variet you know the iMac is you know
different ways to get image size we
talked about and demonstrated the emac
LBG
then this image magic tutorial which I
wrote like 20 years
ago uh but they changed you know so I
was saying it's one of the worst okay
the worst Unix [ __ ] [ __ ] possible
the image ma
magic and then and then because the
syntax is so
lousy uh about 10 years ago they started
to massively change the syntax so before
it was convert something something so
now they just say magic which is
actually better fix this Unix [ __ ]
sloppy [ __ ] problem you see the
Unix people they don't care you know
they they prefer short names man CP grab
you know cryptic names they they enjoy
it they love it because it makes them
like more man you know something I
understand you know
understand they like that so and and the
image magic they choose the word
convert for their name you know for
converting JPEG to give to PNG you know
to convert so so they this this is
another um very common
nasty Behavior among the Unix Community
okay image magic is kind of in a Unix
community so what they do is that so the
problem is that you want the command to
represent your program right to convert
images but then if you choose the word
convert that means you know like like
you can also convert HTML to text you
can convert latch to Mathematica syntax
you know W language you can so convert
can mean many other different things not
just for image
but however if you are the Unix [ __ ]
type you don't care you are selfish you
want a popular word you you want just
like steal it you know you let's just
use the convert to be our you know to
represent image magic so that other
programs cannot use the convert so this
convert you see that's a
problem so this kind of behavior is very
common among the Unix community in Pearl
especially in Pearl you know very common
this Unix
fuckets so but they got a problem
because now after 20 years you know your
program spread and you got windows in
play at you know and Mac different
operating systems Android so your your
command convert it's got a problem you
know and not just that you know it
doesn't represent your command at all
because it's a generic generic English
word but
also also that this word you know like
if you want to find the image width and
height using image magic you you cannot
use convert you have to use the identify
another [ __ ] generic English word
command name you have to say identify
Okay so um let's see if I still have it
available
GCM
identify okay it's good because image
magic so that's why they Chang you know
they massively
changed their command name so now the
new syntax is that every image magic
command will just start with magic much
better okay that should be the case back
then but this Unix [ __ ] you know
they they don't you know so why you know
like one obvious question is that why is
that 20 years ago they choose the word
convert and identify how is it possible
that's a question how is it possible
that these Unix fuckets never thought of
you know if you use the con convert word
it doesn't represent your program and it
also
encroaches the vast you know
much many other uses of the word convert
have you ever thought about that use
Unix
fuckets Unix
fuckets this this are design issues and
and also part of it is social issues
okay so image magic this very annoying
change so I have to you know this is
good to know this is just not my rent so
if you are using image mag you also
might want to know because this change
is not Backward Compatible
okay so now for backward compatibility
they made it so that you can say magic
Then followed back convert you know
that's what they do what they did it's
not exactly Backward Compatible but but
feels good Backward Compatible you know
you say magic then convert your old
way um okay so that's that's about that
image magic syntax change which is very
confused me for a long time for many
years then then one day you know in
20124 December about three month ago I
really started to look into what the
just exactly is it is the magic just for
Windows or is it what's going on I'm
used to the convert right
So eventually so I found out they they
did a major uh upgrade you
know okay that's about that that image
magic and I I think that's about it
today we talked about um yeah we talked
about all these things and you know
getting the image file width and height
that's it thank you guys for
watching do you like it is this fun
yes image magic is 2 gigabyte or was it
one gigabyte I forgot but at least one
gigabyte why because image
magic you know that's another like scum
tactics you see 20 years
ago is there any other question okay I'm
about to close
down and pay me okay don't forget you
know I don't get paid go to a.info
my homepage all the way to the bottom
pay me patreon Amazon GI card PayPal
okay I prefer Amazon gift card or
PayPal okay cool fantastic thank you
guys for
watching uh so let me answer the
question yeah so image magic let me
explain that
sh so image magic you see 20 years ago
this open open source [ __ ] it you know
so the thinking is that you know I'm
going to create a tool I'm going to help
Humanity you know that's what they think
they are thinking I you know I'm so good
I'm a good person I'm a hacker I'm a
ethical I I I'm going to create this
program image magic to benefit
Humanity a lot of them are like that
they
think you so they create this program so
typically they they have these
characteristics they grow and grow so I
my program is going to be the best of
them all I'm and my program is going to
convert every possible image in on Earth
so that I can get more popular I can
become more
famous that is the thinking behind the
scenes okay that's is sing so but so 20
25 20 25 years ago
you can kind of do that not today
because today you know the exponential
growth of Science and Engineering like
most of the things you don't even know
what it is like for example in
JavaScript you know 10 10,000 Frameworks
every year you know you can even
understand you know you can only be no a
little niche okay so anyway image magic
20 30 years ago you can kind of like
know all the image formats
but not today unless you are wam
language wam language can still do that
you know you at least like all possible
formats of images or videos or HTML Tech
L Tech it supports or 3D formats like
AutoCAD you know and audio format as Al
also so video format audio format image
format they have so many and also
3D 3D graphics
3D modeling formats there are so many
wolam language actually support them all
and robustly so but anyway back to the
image magic so back then they just they
want to support you know they want to be
the most popular they support all
all so today over the years so what
image magic does it actually can does do
a text recognition Okay let me demo that
because you know so we talking about 30
years of progress so today on Mac or
Windows on Mac at least you can have
text recognition so let me show you okay
so for
example uh yeah so we got this example
let's just not this one okay
uh by the way that image you are looking
at this is the this keyboard automattic
wait am I showing yeah this is uh wait
wait not
God close
that uh yeah show open it okay magnify
this this is the ultimate hacking
keyboard okay that's updating from
whereare
screenshot ultimate hacking keyboard got
the best software okay and they kept
they keep updating every year fantastic
so I you know I want to give them give
them a shout out very good you know um
kind of expensive but you know but they
are very very very high quality the guy
they are from like I think Ukraine or
something Eastern Europe you know
so you know there there are so many
keyboards competitors but anyway
ultimate hacking keyboard is very high
quality okay so um close that yeah so
let's get back to the image so this
image yeah so let's demo demo the uh
text recognition Okay image to text
so open
it so now I press the key
um
uh Windows shift
t Okay and then I can
select a section there okay then now
close this Escape close it close it now
I go here paste you
see
that's that's classically called OCR
optical character
recognition back then you know like 20
years ago but today it's just called AI
image to text image text recognition
Okay so you can see it grabbed the text
from that image
now if you want to do that you need to
install auto hard key uh no the you need
to install power uh power
toys okay I have a block about it power
toys that's from
Microsoft okay you have to install this
uh at least for window 10 now I don't
know what's uh what about window 11 but
anyway power toys okay on the on Windows
on the Mac it's building you can you you
know you can do the same thing in fact
the Mac version is much better because
one one time I Tred to
um okay I digress a
lot uh you know the a month ago I was
trying to image recognize my old codes
of screenshot for the HP
lisp language
hp28 uh calculator and uh that is eight
Queen problem there you see yeah so I
was trying to wait do we have no I
removed the image but anyway it was like
30 years old image and uh of this code
you see
so when you have nor more text it's
easier to recognize by statistic
patterns because they are all English
words right so if you you know if the
image is fuzzy but you can kind of tell
p o g something n o m but
statistically the program would know
okay it's probably p o g RM you know
program right so if you have English
text or some human language text it's
easier to do image recognition uh text
recognition of image but if your text is
code then that's rare so the program can
can't make sense of it especially if you
have
this you know this uh this
double you know double correct uh that's
called gulat that's a French quote okay
this this this is French quote
convention but it's used
in uh hp28 or HP 48 calcul calor
programming language okay so so the
Microsoft power toys image recognition
got a problem they can you know they
they came out kind of gibbish half of it
is gibbish but on the Mac that's why Mac
is like twice as expensive in everything
but mac Apple actually have quality on
the Mac you don't have to install
anything you can just text recognition
and most it came out mostly correct then
I just edited a little bit then you know
turned it into a text
fantastic okay so that's a demonstration
of image to text image a text
recognition in image okay copy that back
here showing browser back to emex paste
a link here link F make a list sh
showing browser okay that's it for
today so oh yeah so we were talking
about text recognition so that is part
of the reason why image magic is like 2
gigabyte because image magic they want
to do that too you know we cannot lose
to Apple so they they to they want to do
that but in order to do that you have
the you have to have the entire image
recognition AI system building then you
also need to install a bunch of fonts or
font technology so that it recognize
different fonts I guess you know you
know like it's extremely bloated image
magic two two
gigabytes
[ __ ] if you're dead we are X HTM why are
you guys asking that questions
[ __ ] annoying question you know like pay
me you know if you like my just pay me
to get it because it was free for like
10 [ __ ] years and nobody give a [ __ ]
and I was dying of hunger and then you
become tech support every every day
everyone is asking you but thank you
kasab but how do you do do this or
attacking you your code is [ __ ] you know
you know things like that that's open
source
fuckets um well I don't I don't mean I
don't mean you okay I don't mean to
attack you but that's kind of the kind
of the
situation so the back the the background
I mean the the code I use to optimize
image let me show you okay that's
another topic so search just
search
optimize PNG okay there are quite a few
so this this one oxy PNG is currently
the best okay I recommend copy it back
here back to emx uh let's paste it there
link list okay
optipng so I recommend it it's written
in Rust [ __ ] [ __ ] R anyway it's is is
currently the best okay over the past 20
years there are different stories so it
was you know so you
got you know you know you know so you
got
optipng which is pretty popular but
before Opti PNG there was um another
okay so they kind
of anyway so that's the story
okay uh then you got this PNG Quint
created by a idiot because they are
trying to what they do is they optimize
PNG but make it lossy so you lose a
little bit information but to this this
guy this this idiot they think you
know he thinks that it combines the best
of both words you know you got PNG high
quality but also kind of small size like
jpeg this
idiot who created Opti you know PNG
Quint it's a fantastic incredible idiot
this but you know so but they they grab
the people like the today's generation
the Zoomers don't know you know the
Zoomers think oh this creates smaller I
just going to use
this do you have an article about mro
keypad
uh is it the most used uh you mean uh
yeah okay so go to keyboard
that's it that's it for today thank you
guys for watching about 1 hour fantastic
so uh keypads so you could just go to
keyboard block keypads so I got some of
the best keypads here but it's kind of
outdated outdated because in the past
five or 10 years there's new keypads
programmable keypads coming out every
year especially from China like today
90% of all these keyboard Are For All
from China and they are better than half
of the time they are more they're much
cheaper like you know and and the
practical
too so but if you want the ultimate
keypad then ultimate hacking keyboard is
great okay like the way I'm using if you
want the ultimate keypad you know like
spend $200 just for a keypad okay this
so timate hacking comes in
two you know modules you can disconnect
one of them so one of them you still
work so if you don't need the other you
know I can still work kind of expensive
though you can customize the color you
see you see my keyboard the color
actually mean different things you see
and you can change the color you see so
that is a luxury for rich people if you
you know if you okay Google you can get
this ultimate hacking for just for
keypad uh then or or you can use you
know Apple maker I don't have these okay
so so these are the some of the mark
this this is China
Cheapo uh it works you know cheap and it
works fine you know for for several
years um then you got yeah another China
China Chapo we you know
my my tablet is who okay I also have
article then then this General genation
is I don't recommend it but this is
Classic this is like from year 199 you
know 19 '90s or early 2000 that's kind
of classic before you know before you
have today's like 3D printing or
popularity of mechanical keys so anyway
this is classic and
today is kind of outdated because they
are still using their software like
typically for Windows only you know for
Windows 98 you know like all very Asian
okay and you know so anyway that's
classic and this x Keys is also classic
from 1990s okay uh so today they are
kind of expensive you know
like uh do they show how much do they
actually
this one I guess it's not even selling
anymore yeah okay so this one 280 Keys
that's 200 Keys 80 keys
$259 what anyway yeah
so you know this like this incredible
you know this
$260 for the 80
keys in that case you want to get timate
hacking keyboard about the same price
but much more uh better
okay so anyway so you know so and there
are some old reviews uh then you know uh
but my page is not that um to up to dat
because you then there's elago among
very popular among the gamer idiots
gamers are typically they are all idiots
they don't know what's quality and but
they you know so it it
Elgato I wouldn't recommend you know
it's nice to have displays but they are
you know so there's a taken you know
some people take it apart it's very
lousy you know mushy keys and and on and
on so I don't recommend
it uh very popular among the YouTubers
and Gamers and the Zuma idiots okay then
then you you know
so uh then there's some classic like the
razor you know this kind of
thing uh well speaking of that then you
got into then you got into
um then you get into uh like fancy
devices like um track ball pain input
knobs joystick act so you got a bunch of
joysticks you got bunch of knobs you
know like you got this for Photoshop or
video editing or image editing this
would be
suitable uh then if you are like really
professional video editing you want
something like this
$2,000 actually this one is like few
hundred like they they are doing
something called uh color grading okay I
don't you know so I have like examples
like I looked into what the [ __ ] is
color grading this
dainy you know thing cost few hundred
few thousand dollar
you know like the this tangent Ripple
panel okay
350 uh and there's one selling for
$2,000 okay so anyway go back then you
so then you got this uh and by the way
look at this professional
panel and then you got um you got um
joystick uh the one I'm looking for is
coding uh
wait not here this one called Aron okay
so where do I put it there Aeron keypad
then you got something like that I don't
have it
so you know but but those are not good
for like marro Keys those are dedicated
for gaming and
stuff okay bye guys
yes timate hacking keyboard support
Linux you know it's it's all good
yeah uh but you double you you know but
don't take my words for it okay go check
their website I'm pretty sure I think
they do and uh yeah