Hello guys. Good morning. Welcome to
another episode of Xah Talk Show. So,
today we are going to do
uh I'm going to show you regular
expressions in Emacs. Regular
expressions, okay? So, this is going to
be a full tutorial on regular
expressions
um
covering Emacs regular expressions. Now,
Emacs regular expression is a little bit
different from other
regular expression in other languages
such as Pearl, Python, Ruby, Java,
JavaScript. You know, every language
since about 2005 have regular expression
built in because it's a very powerful
for text processing, for doing, you
know, manipulating strings, find and
replace and so on. So, every language
has it and it's extremely useful, but
regular expression is a bit hard to um
understand. Take some experience, okay?
But, I'm going to show you. So, I'm
going to show you uh
teach you Emacs regular expression.
Okay, from the ground up.
How to call regular expression by
command line, you know, lots of tips.
And also for Emacs these programmers,
okay? So, we uh let's begin, okay? So,
if you have a questions on Emacs and
stuff, just post in the comments, okay?
And support me by my tutorials and you
know, buy my Emacs tutorials. You can
find the link on my website xahlee.org.
You'll find it.
Just search for xahlee Emacs. Okay, so
so let me so let's begin, okay? Let's
begin quickly. So, I'm using Emacs, of
course, and show today's talk show. So,
this is today's talk show. That's what
I'm going to cover. What's regular
expression? Why not use wildcard, you
know, glob pattern? What's you know, why
not use wildcard? What's what's the
difference? Examples of regular
expression and Emacs regular expression.
Using Emacs regular expression by
command interactive command. And then
the best way to test regular expression
because regular expression is fairly
complex. So, I show you how to the best
way to do to test it, you know, when you
have, you know,
lots of complex patterns. And uh
then I cover some Emacs regular
expression, you know, the syntax.
Then I talk about I'm going to talk
about Emacs Lisp
uh regular expression, which is a
string. Okay, so I'm using the keyboard
Kinesis Advantage keyboard. You can see
if you just search for uh Xahri
ergonomic keyboard reviews. So, I'm
using this one is Kinesis Advantage, my
favorite
one of, you know, my main drive one of
my favorite. And the other one on top
here is Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. Okay,
that's the best keyboard macro.
Um the greatest macro keyboard macro
features. So, I got both of them.
Fantastic. Okay, so so let me talk about
So, let's begin uh Emacs regular
expression, okay? And here's a funny
picture. You see those things, those are
regular expressions. And in this case,
it's complex ones. Complex ones, so you
have lots of these
uh so-called toothpick syndrome. Okay,
so and we have a record here. So, you
can see the complexities here.
And then you can see this one, this
part, you know,
uh 10 backslashes.
And you can see uh there there is more,
there's a record and
10, you know, so what's the record? 10
17 17 there. This is a code, actual
source code in Emacs.
You know, if you, you know, in this
file. We we, you know, we can look at
it. Y-
You know, if you go to this website,
Emacs Lisp toothpick syndrome, just
search for it. You'll find it and you
can y- you can
uh see the source code where it to find
it. Okay, so that's really good. So,
let's begin. So, what So, let me Okay,
so let's begin regular expression. My
keyboard is okay. So, regular expression
is a uh
is is a is a syntax to match patterns in
a string. Okay, so let me demonstrate.
First of all,
you are probably familiar with uh
wildcard, for example.
Okay, so let's turn on Let's go to
PowerShell. Okay, Let's magnify. So,
uh okay, so let's let me adjust this a
little bit. So, this is this is
PowerShell.
Uh so, let's list directories, okay? Duh
recurse, we don't need recurse. Okay, uh
and filter, okay? Let's say filter, I
want to list all HTML files. So, you see
that
star sign, that's asterisk, that's a
pattern. That means any file name
zero or one more character followed by
HTML. So, enter. So, you can see a whole
list of South Talk Show. So, let's do it
again, okay? So, let's
Let's do it. If you um
let's see recurse.
Uh recurse uh re
curse, yeah. Recurse.
Filter, recurse, then
So, if I don't do If I don't use the
filter option, you are going to see a
lot JPEG files, PNG files, those are
image files.
So, let let me show you, okay? So, for
example, open them in desktop. So, you
can see
this is the
you know, uh lots of past talk show uh
stuff.
Image files, okay? So, JPEG and PNG. So,
let me focus, okay? So, So, now we do
just these HTML files and let's say
recursive, okay?
Okay? So, now it's just HTML files. Now,
what if Now, let's try JPEG, okay? JPEG.
So, it lists on only JPEG files that
file names ending in .jpg. Now, what if
you want Let's try PNG, okay?
So, all these are wildcard wildcards.
They The purpose of wildcard is also to
match patterns, okay? Let me get go go
get going faster. Hey, Reaper.
So, PNG so So, we can list PNG files. We
can list HTML
files. We can list JPEG files. What if
What if you want to list
either PNG files or JPEG files? You
cannot do that. You cannot do that with
the
wildcard. In Unix, this this kind of
pattern matching is called glob, g l o
b, okay? That's a Unix name for this
type of pattern matching. In in
Microsoft, it's just called wildcard
patterns.
Okay, so let me show you, okay? Um
PowerShell. So, you you search for Sandy
PowerShell tutorial and you can search
for uh
wildcard string wildcard. You can So,
you can see these are the patterns. So,
you can have asterisk that matches any
character zero or more times. So,
So, this is this is wildcard pattern.
Now,
but there's a limitation. There's a
severe limitation. You cannot list, you
know, either JPEG files or PNG files,
okay? So, what you do? You can Now, you
can do regular expression, okay? Let me
show you.
So,
So, here's article um
Let me copy that to to my talk show,
okay?
Talk show. Uh today's talk show. Go to
today today's talk show and uh let's
post the link here.
Okay, PowerShell wildcards. Then I'm
going to show you um
uh yeah, this file by pattern, okay?
This is uh PowerShell, okay? So, you can
do it by wildcards. We we demonstrated
and
and here's how you do it by uh
um
by regular expression pattern, okay? So,
so let me let me show you.
So, because then we want to pivot to
where, okay?
Pivot to where
where object and the file name I match,
okay? So,
yeah.
You want to to Okay, so
where
Okay, so let's let me just copy it.
Okay? So, you So, now we modify this.
And let's see.
JPEG or PNG, okay? So, now we do it. Now
you can see this is JPEG files and we
also got PNG files. So, again, here is
the syntax and this part you are seeing,
that's regular expression. That's the
power of regular expression. You cannot
do it with wildcards, okay?
So, that's why
you know, you need regular expression.
That's uh you know, and regular
expression can do lots of things, okay?
Let's let's get on quick quicker, okay?
So, I have an article here explaining
what's the difference between regular
expression and wildcards, okay? Then
Okay, then Emacs, okay? So, let me show
you, so
Okay, so go to the file name directory.
So, again, this is a bunch of image
files. Uh let's hide the So, here you
can see a bunch of image files. Some of
them are PNG, some of them are JPEG,
okay?
Now, suppose so
So, I want to list all lines that
ends in PNG, okay? So, I do it. This
command is called list matching lines.
You can see here list matching lines,
okay? Do it.
Um
PNG, okay? So,
you give a regular expression. Uh
Uh backslash uh backslash.png
and uh give a dollar sign, that means
match the end. Okay? So, you
um
Okay, so my window is uh
let's do it again, okay? So, you can see
you can see here are all the PNG files.
That's using a regular expression, okay?
Now, let's try
let's try again, but this time
JPEG, okay? So, you can see JPEG. Now,
what if you want both JPEG and PNG,
okay? Let's do it. Let's do it again.
So, JPEG and
and then uh then you want to say all, so
let me magnify so
if you can see it.
So, you can say JPEG
backslash
vertical symbol then
.png,
okay? That's the syntax. We are using
regular expression, okay? So, you can
see list matching list lines matching
rejects.
Okay, so here you can see that's PNG
files uh
uh
it's all then there it is, JPEG files.
There it is. So, that's demonstration of
regular expression, okay? Very very uh
useful. You should uh master it. It
takes a bit time to learn, so you know
uh
um
because it's uh
slightly uh complex. Okay. So, regular
expression, we're going to cover the
syntax, but first of all, so you can as
you can see already, you know, the
syntax is not too intuitive, you know,
because you have the backslash, you
know, if you look at
if you you know, you have the backslash
and and things like that.
So,
one of the easiest way, okay, cancel.
One of the easiest easiest way in Emacs
to test regular expression is by using
this command, list matching lines. Okay.
So, there's a full article on that. Um
list matching lines um
Uh
search text in current current file.
Okay, there's a Okay, there is a
uh there's a separate I should relink
them.
Anyway, so this article explains list
matching lines command, you know,
is it has an alias. It's an alias of
occur command, so you can use also use
they are the same thing, occur.
So, this command is the most easy way to
test regular expression. So, what do you
do? So, if you have a bunch of files,
let's say let's say copy, close, new
buffer, paste, and magnify, and let's
remove all the
all the line beginning, I mean, all the
Unix stuff. Okay. So, you see now we
have a bunch bunch of files, some of
them are PNG, some of them are JPEG.
Uh search JPEG. Okay. So, um
So, now we want to So,
So, yeah, if you want to test regular
expression, just put
that's too complex. Let's say let's say
this, okay?
cat
caught
uh
sit, there's no such word, I don't
think. Cut, okay?
You know, so you can test regular
expression by calling list matching
lines and you know, and then you type
your regular expression. So, it doesn't
match anything. So, let's try again, but
this time
we want regular expression to be c
.t. Now, in regular expression, a dot
means any any character, just like the
on oh
uh almost like the
uh asterisk. Like okay, so c.t enter.
So, you can see it matches all these
three lines.
Uh but let's say let's put a dog.
Okay, and do it again. List matching
lines c.t. So, you see it doesn't it it
didn't list dog. So, that's regular
expression. We just extracted lines
containing those words. It you know,
that that So, this is a this is the best
way to test regular expression, you
know, remember that. Okay, because
uh when you use Emacs it
eventually you'll have complex regular
expressions involving programming
language syntax and uh backslash, you
know, escape. So, anyway, so list
matching lines, this is a great way to
test regular expressions, okay?
So, close. So, close. Uh and uh let's
see what's next. List matching lines.
Okay, why not wildcard? We explained.
Simple example of regular expression, we
explained. Now, Emacs regular expression
by interactive command, that's list
matching lines, that's the example. Uh
and there is also um
and if you are programming Emacs Lisp,
you know, in my tutorial in my in my
video I talked about coding Emacs Lisp a
lot.
Of course, you can use also use regular
expression, but
in there you have to uh
turn the regular expression into a
string.
For example, for For right now we are
trying to list, uh let's let's list um
uh
let's say
But anyway, in Emacs this you need it
becomes a string. And when you have a
string, you need to do a lot escape,
okay? That's so
so that's the thing to watch out. I'm
going to explain that later, okay? So
then next Emacs regular expression
commands, okay? Best uh uh
regular expression commands, that's
that's list matching lines, okay?
So let's go back show here show it
again.
So list matching lines is one of the
most frequently used and it's a it's
it's a it's the best
command to test your regular expression.
Now, the other
Now, the other most commonly used
command interactive commands in Emacs is
query replace regex, okay? So let's say
I want to replace all the words wildcard
by
regex, okay? Wait, let's say I want to
replace all
all the word regex by regular
expression, the full name, okay? So what
I do, I just call
query replace regex, okay? You can see
cancel. You can see in you know, that's
the command I called. So call it and
type regex.
Okay, enter. Then type
regular expression.
Okay, do it what?
Uh
okay, wait. So we don't want the P at
the end. So replace regex by regular
expression. Do it. You see? Yes, yes,
yes, yes. Do you want to replace? Yes,
yes, yes. Okay. So cancel.
Okay, that's that's one regular
expression. That's uh so this command,
query replace regex, very useful. So
these two commands, remember this, these
two commands is the most useful and most
frequently used commands in Emacs that
involves a regular expression when you
want to find some text or replace some
text, okay? These two commands.
And they are the most useful if you want
to test, you know, when you are going
about learning the regular expression
syntax, okay?
Now, let's go on. Next Next is let's
cover regular expression syntax. So,
what is the syntax, okay?
So,
So, let me let me comment. So, hello
guys. Hey, hey Justin.
So, regular expression
is is somewhat complex, okay? You know,
I I had I have by now
20 years experience using regular
expression in Pearl, in starting in
Pearl, in Unix grep, in you know, in
different languages, in Python, in
Wolfram language.
Um
You know, a few few weeks ago we I
demonstrated Wolfram language regular
expression in Wolfram language. And
okay, so regular expression
So, I I I want to tell you it's not
very
easy to understand, okay? You You'll run
into frustrate frustrations for sure. I
can tell you that. But, you you'll
gradually learn, okay, over over over
the years, okay, over a month or so.
So, let let me demonstrate some So, so
regular expression syntax, okay? Let's
let let me see where how do I want to
cover that. Um
It can get quite esoteric. So,
So, I'm not going to cover the whole
thing because the whole thing we would
um
You know, you have if you are seeing
regular expression for the first time,
it's no good to learn the whole thing.
You want to learn some simple ones. So,
let me just cover some of the simplest
patterns, okay?
So, the simplest patterns in regular
expression, let's write it out.
Most simple re uh regular expression. I
have a shortcut. So, most simple regular
expression, okay? So, show the pink
window. Uh
most simple regular expression
syntax or patterns, okay?
So, dot Let me just write it out, so
it's
So, you can easily uh everything I
talked today is all in my tutorial. So,
you can, you know, just search for study
Emacs regular expression, then you will
find a a series of articles like all the
way um
down here. You see this section, this
box. So, this article is regular
expression, what is what it is compared
to wildcards, the syntax, and how is
Emacs regular expression syntax differ
from Python, Java, JavaScript, okay? For
you programmers, you can read this page.
Then there's a regular expression, how
is it used in Emac Lisp, and so on,
okay? So, let me right now cover So, so,
you know, you can just read my tutorial
if you are just want to read it. So,
right right now, let me cover some of
the most used patterns in regular
expression, okay? So, a dot Now, a dot
means any character, okay?
Uh then
then you have the most common pattern is
the square bracket. So, the square
bracket, so let me actually
add the
You will see what I'm doing later, okay?
Uh
So,
a square bracket a square bracket, then
0 to
then uh wait. ABC
any of the chars ABC, okay?
X, for example, you can put any
characters here. So, if you have a
sequence of, you know, any character you
want to match,
you add a square bracket that they'll
match in. So, these are the most simple.
So, next
Now, when you use a square bracket,
there's a special syntax that allows you
to say A to B, I mean A to Z. That means
match anything from A to Z, okay?
Any of the chars uh A to
Z, okay? That's a like special case with
the square bracket syntax. That's why,
you know, regular expression is slightly
complex slightly complex. Okay, so
So, A to Z, then you can also, of
course, you can do zero to nine.
Any of the digit.
Okay. Uh zero
zero to nine, okay? So, that allows you
to So, so now, so okay, so so next, we
have a um
So, so far we covered uh certain
patterns that allows you to either match
an arbitrary character or a a set of
characters or, you know, a ordered
sequence, you know, of characters.
But But now, let me introduce another uh
symbol uh
uh syntax in regular expression that is
the plus sign, okay? Plus sign means one
or more of the previous
pattern, okay? So, for example
So, for example, if you want to match
um
Let Let me Let me Let me give you this
example, okay? A to Z plus, okay? So,
what does that mean? That means match
one or more. That's a plus sign. One or
more of the previous pattern.
Now, the previ- the previous pattern is
any of A to Z. So, this basically means
match any
match a word, basically.
So, match a sequence of lower case
English alphabet. Okay? So, let me
clean up this and let's view them in X
view them in HTML. Show it in browser.
So, here are the
regular expression patterns we have
covered so far. And these are the most
frequently used. Okay, so begin learning
by
you know, trying trying regular
expression commands with these patterns,
okay? So, let let's demo. Let's start to
demo. So, let's say if your buffer has
lot lots of this. So, let's begin.
Uh let Okay, so let's open something.
Something.
Magnify.
Uh
997 cats
and
uh 70 dogs, okay? So, I want to extract
all the numbers
here, okay? So, what you can do is um
uh
Let let's say I want to put a quote, for
example.
Uh for example, this part I want it to
turn into that.
Okay? And suppose I have thousands of
these lines. How do you do that? Regular
expression, okay? So, so what we do is
query replace with regular expression
query replace rejects here.
Then give you a regular expression. Let
me
Let's demonstrate this, okay? So,
magnify the mini buffer.
Uh
the mini buffer. So, I want to say
Okay, this involves capture, okay? So,
Okay, capture is a new concept we
haven't introduced yet. Let Let's just
list the all the lines containing
numbers, okay? So, list matching lines
then square bracket magnify then zero uh
zero to nine, then add a plus, okay? So,
that will list all lines matching this,
you see? So, we are look we are, you
know, so here's a result including the
double quote lines.
Okay?
So, we have demonstrated
this one with the plus sign, okay?
So,
Okay, so that's so far so good. So,
that's the basic, you know, that's some
of the most simple patterns, okay?
How long have I been going? Uh 27
minutes, okay? So,
we got I'm going to cover up cover and
you know, we are hopefully 10 more
minutes or
20 minutes, then
that's it for today.
Uh okay, so regular expression, the most
basic patterns, okay? So,
So, where is the syntax here, okay? On
this page. So,
yeah.
So, so far so good. Now, let's Let me
introduce
So, we got we covered many of these
patterns. Let Let me introduce
capture, okay?
Now, for example,
we want to replace this line by
by let's say adding a quote
around
around the pattern we want. So, what we
do is So, there is a pattern. So, let's
go back here. Let's write it out.
So, there is the syntax where
you
you put um
backslash backslash
parentheses
pattern, okay?
That means capture the pattern, okay?
So, this pattern should be a regular
expression, okay? Whatever it is. You
know, this regular expression can be
anything we covered before. So, that
means capture the pattern. So, what what
does capture means? It means that when
you want to do replacement, you can
refer to the pattern and add some more
text.
You know, surrounding it, things like
that. So, let's let me demonstrate.
Okay, showing browser first of all, so
we can see there it is. Uh actually,
I want to add. So, this is just
So, that means the pattern, okay?
Capture, okay? So, let's demonstrate
capture. So, delete those. So, I want to
add a
double quote, okay? So,
call
query replace rejects, okay? Now, enter
regular expression, okay? Now,
let's magnify. So, backslash
left paren
then
a square bracket left square bracket
then 0 to 9. I want to match anything
any digit 0 to 9,
okay? Then
backslash, then paren, right paren,
okay? So, I So, I'm going to capture
this, but we forgot we need to say one
or more, so add a plus sign.
Okay? So, now this is uh
Let me Yeah, so
now you can see.
Okay, so that's the pattern
with the parenthesis capture, okay? So,
enter.
Now, Emacs asks you what do you want to
replace it with, okay? So, let's say
a quote,
then
backslash one. That refers to the
pattern we just captured. It's one
because it's the first pattern, okay?
Then
then uh quote again, okay? Enter. So,
Emacs found it. It asks you if you want
to replace it or not. So, type yes, type
Y to replace, type N to say no.
And uh type A
exclamation to replace them all. So,
anyway, let's say yes, okay? Yes.
Yes. Okay, so you see
this is regular expression. We are using
a pattern that captures and replaces.
Now, let's do it again.
So,
this time
our regular expression is going to be
instead of the quote, let's say
Okay, wait, wait. Let Let Let's do this,
okay? So,
in programming languages, many
programming languages uses double quote,
but some programming languages use
single quote. So, this time, let's say I
want to cut This is a programming
language, let's say I want to convert
double quote to single quote, but not
just every
quote because uh hold on a second.
For example, some other words are also
uh quoted. I only want to
replace
digits that has a quote to change this
part to single quote and also this part.
Okay, let's do it.
Let's say change double quoted
numbers to single quote. Okay, that's
what we want to do. Okay, so query
replace rejects
and the pattern
the pattern will be
uh
You want to capture it? Yes.
Okay, so we need a double quote there.
Okay. That's the pattern.
Enter.
Now, what do you want to replace it?
Well, I want to replace it by a single
quote. Okay, so just type single quote.
And also Okay, so we just want to
backslash one. Single quote backslash
one. That refers to the capture. Okay,
do it.
Yes, yes. You see? Fantastic. Okay.
Uh and
Okay, so now so far so good. So that's a
basic introduction to regular
expressions. So you learned you learned,
you know,
a set of characters or a wildcard
and also repeating a pattern one or more
times or and you also
learned how to capture a pattern. Okay.
So let me demonstrate the next thing.
Okay, so let's copy that. Close that.
Let's put a text box
and so we can have a reference later on.
Okay, so now let's So so far that's some
of the
some of the regular expression
um
syntax. Okay, there's there are a lot
more, but I'm not going to cover them
all
today.
Let's go on. Let's go on to but that's a
basic idea. Okay, let me show you one
more thing. In Emac that this is
important specific to Emacs.
In Emacs, if you want to replace
if you want to include a new a line
return in Emacs, you have to type
control Q enter, okay? For example,
uh let's copy that, okay? So, let's copy
that. Let's Let's paste it here. Let's
In Emacs, if you want to include a new
line char, you cannot use backslash n,
okay?
Uh
you
have to
use
You have to press control
plus Q
enter, okay? That's how you do it. So,
let's For example, let's try something.
cat
dog some, okay? Now,
let's try it.
So, now let's say I want to replace cat
dog in two lines into one single line,
okay? Into one single line with a space
in between, okay? So, I call
query replace rejects, okay?
cat
backslash n dog enter.
You see, it gives you an error, okay? It
gives you an error. So, cancel. So, now
let's try again.
Uh query replace rejects
cat Now, I want the enter, so
a line return, so I press control Q
enter.
Um actually, that's control Q control J.
Let's try again. It's a bit complex,
okay? So, let's try again.
Query replace rejects cat control Q
control J, okay?
Uh
what?
Oh, I pressed the wrong key. Uh
so, that's why it's a bit complex, so
try it again.
Cat
control Q control J, okay?
Dog. Now, you can see in the mini buffer
uh the mini buffer is kind of
it doesn't show both lines, okay? There
it is. Okay, so you can see that's how
you enter a line return. Control Q
control J, okay? This is a bit
um
different. You cannot use backslash n,
okay? Enter. Then, replace it by
cat space dog, okay? Do it.
Yes. Okay, that's how you do it.
Uh what if you have uh more So, what if
you have um
what if you have anything? So,
So, what if you have What if you want to
replace anything that's Let me show you
a more complex example of regular
expression using capture, okay? So, if
cat and uh
let's say tiger
uh cat and uh let's say
uh rabbit. You want to replace any two
lines
Let me write it down.
Replace any two
such that the first line
is
cat, okay?
And the second line is anything.
Okay?
Replace them into one single line, okay?
That's That's what we want to do, okay?
So, let's Let's add some more examples.
Cat
something and something, okay? So,
and uh let's say A, let's add some more
random text, okay?
So, now let's do the regular expression.
Query replace rejects.
Okay, the first line is cat, then
control Q control J for a return.
The second line, we want to capture it.
So, that's going to be backspace
backslash
backslash and uh
left paren.
Then square bracket because we want to
capture A to Z
or space.
Okay, or
zero
to zero to nine or capital A to Z.
Okay, any any one of those characters.
Then
one or more plus, okay? Then
backslash right parenthesis, okay? So,
that captures whatever is on the second
line, okay?
Double check, is that right? Yes.
But the first line must begin with cat.
Okay, so do it. Now, what do you want to
replace by? Replace by cat. Same thing
as the first line.
Then
control
Q control J to
add a line return. Then
backslash one. Okay, that's the pattern
we captured. Okay.
Enter.
So, found one instance. Yes Yes or no?
Yes, replace.
Oh, we don't want
mistake.
Anyway, we the the second the second
the replacement we don't want the new
line, we want the space. But I entered
the new line instead. So, okay, let's
try again.
Uh actually, so this So, this time it's
easier because you can just modify it.
Okay.
So, like that. Okay, enter. Yes yes yes
yes. Okay. That's how you do it.
Okay. So,
Okay, so now let's let's see next.
40 minutes. Okay, so So, now let's talk
about
So, those are some of the most
frequently used patterns and examples.
Now, let's talk about
um
regular expressions in Emac Lisp.
Okay, so
So, let's any any comments and
questions? Are you guys six people
watching?
So,
let's cover some regular expression in
Emac Lisp. Okay, so the
Yeah, let's do that. So, the most
frequently used regular expression
functions in Emac Lisp is are these.
Okay. So, you have
research-forward
that we are searching a regular
expression pattern
to the right forward.
And uh
when it's found, it will return true,
and it will also move the cruiser to to
whatever the pattern matched uh place
position.
So So, these are the most frequently
used regular expression functions in
Emacs Lisp. Okay? Research-forward.
And by the way, research-forward is a
has an alias, more intuitive name.
Search-forward-regexp.
Okay, that's a more intuitive name, but
they are the same function. It's just an
alias. Okay? So, research-forward, then
you also have research-backward,
then you have
skip-chars-forward
and skip-chars-backward.
And
Okay, that's skip-chars-forward and
backward is a bit variation. Okay? I'm
not going to explain now.
Then you have the string-match. Now,
string-match is
is when you want to match a string with
a regular expression. Meanwhile, the
research-forward and research-backward
are trying to match the text in a
buffer. Okay? Like, right now, you are
looking at a buffer. It's So,
So, because Emacs Lisp, you know, unlike
other languages where you just you don't
have the buffer thing. You don't have
the, you know, text editor. It's not a
text editor. In In Python, in PHP, in
Java, you have a string instead. So, you
always basically you have functions to
match,
you know, a regular expression in a
string.
And in Emacs, that's this command,
string-match. Okay? But
most of the time, you are working with
text in a buffer. Like right now, you
are looking at the buffer. So,
you you you know, there's no string to
match. I mean, actually the whole text
in a buffer are kind of strings. So, so
you want to match the text in a buffer.
So, most of the time you want to use
research forward and research backward,
okay?
Uh okay, so there's a lot to cover and
you know, and uh
Let Let me just uh show an example,
okay? So, let let's try to show some
semi example.
Uh
okay, so let Let me quickly demonstrate.
Okay, so let's go here. Let's paste it
here and let's open that, okay? So, same
thing we like before. Now, this time
uh this time we are going to use a
We are doing it programmatically
using Emacs Lisp. We want to replace any
number quoted with double quote by a
single quote, okay? Uh
in Elisp, okay? So, now what do we do?
We do uh like this, okay?
Uh first of all, turn this into a Emacs
Lisp mode, okay? So, hold on a second.
Uh
Wait.
Uh okay, so hold on a second.
Uh
So, we start a new Emacs Lisp block,
put it the put the text inside, then
start a new buffer, okay? So, now we are
in Emacs Lisp. So, let's do research
forward, okay? Now, regular expression,
we want a
0 to 9, a digit,
one or more digits, then we and we want
to
uh
one or more digits, we we want to
capture it. So, to capture, you need
backslash paren.
But, here is a complexity. You need
actually two backslash, because normally
a regular expression, you know, to
capture, you use backslash parenthesis.
But, now in Emacs Lisp, regular
expression is a string, so you can see,
you know, it's a string. And inside the
string, a backslash
is a escape mechanism. So, in order to
add a backslash, you need backslash
backslash. So, so this is when you
started to see
lots of the backslash, okay?
So,
this is how you capture
a sequence of digits, okay? One or more.
So, once you capture, and also
also, you need to add that double quote,
because you want to capture, you know,
double quote, then digit inside. So, you
need add a to add a double quote here.
So, how do you add a double quote?
Again, backslash quote. That's how you
add a double quote inside the string.
And same thing here. So, that is our
regular expression. So, we want to
search forward by that pattern.
And optional bound no error, we don't
care, okay? Come on, we don't care about
those options, okay? So, now this is the
code. Now, we just
evaluate it, and it should move the
cursor to to the place where it matches,
okay? Now, let's evaluate the code. Do
it. There There it is, you see?
So, for example, let's change
this add more number, okay? Okay, so
let's add some more random number, okay?
Now, let's try again. Evaluate it, you
see? It
And we can
you know, we can add lots of things
here. Let's try it again. Do it, you
see? It always
you know, it it found a pattern. Now,
what if you want to replace it? Let me
show you, okay? So, replace so let's
group the whole thing.
Let's group the whole thing into one
block of code like that, okay? Then
so to replace, what you do is
uh
replace match, okay? So
So, here you want to put what you want
to replace by. So, you want to replace
by
\1.
I think that work, okay?
So
Okay, so let's let's don't care about
the option.
So, now if we call
let's make it clean, okay? Now, if we
call this command
it should replace the first occurrence
of this thing.
Replace the double quote by a single
quote.
Okay, let's put the cats before, okay?
Um
so that let's put more double quote, so
we can
let's put the double quote here.
So, we know that the command skipped
that part, okay? So, now let's evaluate,
okay?
Do it. You see?
It did the replacement, but we make made
a mistake. We need to add a single quote
here. So, undo single quote. There it
is, okay? Let's do it again. Watch this
line, okay? Do it.
Fantastic, okay? So, that's a
demonstration of regular expression in
Emacs Lisp. Now,
the few things you want to uh know,
important tips, okay? So, first of all,
the most important functions in Emacs
Lisp for regular expression, that's uh
research forward, research backward, and
also skip chars forward. You can read
about it later.
Skip chars backward and string match,
okay? And what if you
Excuse me. What if you want to get the
matched string or patterns? So, those
are these commands.
And uh we have demonstrated one of them,
uh which is this replace match, okay?
That's how you replace,
which we have demonstrated, okay? So,
these are the most important regular
expression functions, the most used
by far, by 90 over 90% are these, okay?
So, you are learning Emacs Lisp, these
are the functions you want to master.
And also, this is how you test regular
expression, the most simple and
efficient way, in my opinion, how you
test regular expression in Emacs Lisp
code. Because the pattern can gets very
complex, you know, especially with the
backslash. So, you can just type, you
know, research forward,
then put whatever whatever text at the
bottom,
then you
you try your uh pattern here, regular
expression,
then whatever that then you just
evaluate this code, you know, by calling
eval-last-sex.
You see that? So you see we made another
change, you know, 70 becomes single
quote. Okay, that's the
most used regular expression functions
and
how you test regular expression in Emacs
Lisp. Okay, that's that's that.
And let's see what what what's the next
thing.
Find replace string in a buffer. You can
read that. Lots of examples. Uh
Okay, I think that's it for today. So
yeah, so you know, basic coverage of
regular expression in Emacs Lisp.
I hope I'm not too repetitious. Now, if
you like my stuff, okay, look here. Buy
Kxai Emacs tutorial. Okay, so click on
that. Go to PayPal, pay me, or you can
pay me by Patreon.
Uh or you can just PayPal me or Amazon
gift card. Okay.
Kxali.info
Show JavaScript. Turn on JavaScript. So
I did a lot tutorials in different
languages and at the bottom you can see
Patreon me five bucks. Five bucks.
Amazon gift card me.
PayPal me.
Or Bitcoin me. Okay? Thank you guys.
So let's see questions. How come your
tone is what you stay consistent? Yeah,
today I try to be
calm
instead of
instead of something else.
Uh
okay, so
Okay, so thank you guys. Hey Justin. And
hey Reaper.
Leaning toothpick syndrome. Yeah, so
that's it for today.
So the leaning toothpick syndrome, very
interesting, you know, it's uh
happens with Emacs regular expression.
Okay, so I'm going to shut down in 2
minutes or so. So, let's look random a
little bit. Random, okay? So,
uh random, for example, what is this
keyboard blog? I want to uh tell you
something about regular expression
related uh yeah, the difference
of Emacs Lisp regular expression versus
uh
other languages regular expression,
okay? It's
Here are the main major differences. You
see, in most other languages
when you capture, you just use
parentheses, okay?
But, in Emacs
you have to use backslash parentheses.
Now, because Emacs
string Now, Emacs doesn't have a
separate syntax for regular expression
string versus a regular string. You see,
in Python, for example, in Python, in
Perl
in JavaScript, and uh I think in Java,
as well. In almost all the other
languages
a regular expression is a string.
However
that string has a special semantics than
a normal string.
You know, because the regular expression
string the backslash has a special
meaning. For example, backslash d means
a digit, okay?
But, in Emacs Lisp, there's no separate
thing. Everything is a string, okay?
String is a data type, and regular
expression is expressed in a string.
So, in a string
backslash has special meaning. So, if
you want a backslash, you have to double
backslash, okay? So, anyway,
so Emacs Lisp, you know, parenthesis is
literal. So, if you want to capture, you
have to backslash parenthesis.
And because it's a string, so therefore,
you need another backslash to escape the
backslash. So, that looks like that.
So, this is the most This is probably
the most important difference. Okay?
Then there are others. For example, in
other languages, you have backslash D
for digits.
But in Emacs Lisp, you don't have that.
You either use, like we showed before, 0
to 9, or you can use this kind of longer
syntax. That's POSIX syntax. Okay? And
similarly for word and whitespace. Okay?
So, that's some some of the um
that that's the most important
differences.
Okay. Now, yeah, I'm going to shut down.
So, let me show uh
Perl style. So, what There's a question,
what regular flav- what regular
expression flavor do you prefer?
Um Perl style. Yeah, so regular
expression, you know, over the past 30
30 years, they are
uh
there are a handful of variants.
Obviously, Emacs Lisp syntax is very
different from all the others.
By the way, there's some more
interesting things about Emacs Lisp
regular expression we haven't covered.
Uh for example, in Emacs Lisp regular
expression, you can have
uh where is it? Syntax regular
expression syntax in Emacs regular
expression,
you have certain regular expression
patterns that's
that's
associated with the Emacs Lisp
um syntax table.
You know, that's getting esoteric
because in Emacs Lisp that the language,
you have the concept called syntax
table. Okay. Uh which is very hard to
work with, but the basic idea is that
every character
in Unicode
is categorized into
a class. So, you have like for for
example,
alphabets, you know, A to Z and any
letters in Russian alphabet or Chinese
characters, those are
Let
Let me Let me show it, okay? So, you
have this
Uh okay, so let's see uh syntax table.
This is kind of esoteric, so
Let's see, where is it?
Yeah, syntax table. So, you can see
So, here on the left, you you are
looking at some of the regular
expression syntax in Emacs Lisp flavor.
That does not exist, okay? Starting from
here. That does not exist anywhere else.
Okay, this this this are Emacs Lisp
specific. Okay, and they refer to the
syntax table. Their meaning is connected
to the syntax table concept. And what is
the syntax table? That's a special thing
in Emacs Lisp in Emacs, okay?
Which basically categorize
characters according to their type, like
punctuation, symbol, word,
things like that. So, syntax table is
uh
is specific is buffer local. It's
specific to each buffer.
Which means
depending on what major mode you are in,
your syntax table,
which characters belongs to what class,
may be different.
For example, in Emacs Lisp in Emacs Lisp
major mode, so you know,
a dash
is considered part of the symbols
syntax.
But in
in in Goland, for example, a dash is a
punctuation, you see? So, when you use
So, that means when you use the regular
expression in Emacs to match a symbol
such as that one,
you know, that matches the beginning of
symbol you'll you'll fail.
It will behave differently depending
what is the current buffer's major mode,
whether it's, you know, because the
syntax stable are different, okay? I
don't know if I make sense. So,
so, the point is that Emacs Lisp has
regular expression has something
particular to Emacs Lisp.
It's not in other regular expression.
Now, as far as your question, you know,
the regular expression variations, let
me show you some
um
So, search for Xah Lee regular
expression index, so you can see
I have written a lot a lot
uh
tons of articles on regular expression.
For example, complete coverage of
JavaScript regular expression, more than
10 articles.
Uh you know, what function to use.
Uh complete coverage of Python regular
expression. Uh you know, 20 articles.
Goland regular expression, Perl regular
expression, PowerShell regular
expression, Wolfram language regular
regular expression.
And Emacs Lisp regular expression. So,
and uh
but but the question about, you know,
which one I prefer, usually
I don't use the two, you know, the two
advanced regular expression such as
backtracking and stuff. Like, whenever I
need to do that, I simply
I simply manipulate, you know,
do more more than one pattern instead.
Like, if if if I found this and check
whether some other condition is met, you
know, you just have two if statements.
Uh that make thing thing that make
things much more simpler
and much more flexible.
Instead of relying on a specific
variation of a regular expression to
have a particular feature. Because when
you started to use backtracking and
things like that,
the syntax gets complex, you know, um
okay, that you know, that's kind of
advanced, you know, and uh
Okay, that's it. Um
Oh, yeah. So, yeah, so good point.
Justin says that a nice function in
Emacs, a nice command
to test regular expression is
highlight-lines-matching-rejects.
Yeah, that's that's fantastic
suggestion. I should add that.
Thank you. I should add that to my
tutorial. So, let me show you. So, I
want to add uh match
uh let's say I want to match a sequence
of digits, okay? So,
I just call um
Yeah, rejects-to-highlight. So, the
command is called uh highlight-rejects,
okay? That's the command name. So,
I press a key. So, so by default, you
know, so 0 to 9
plus, okay? Do it. And what color?
Yellow, okay? There it is. So, this is
fantastic. You can You see all the
numbers are now colored. I I can easily
see if you are in a programming source
code.
Okay, thank you guys.
Okay, another question about
command-line calendar. Okay.
Well, that's another another day, okay?
So,
thank you guys for watching. I'm getting
tired. It's 1 hour. Thank you guys for
watching. Donate, okay? Donate. Thank
you.
And uh share my videos, okay?
You know, you might like it. Click like.
You know, that's a YouTube controlling
things, but
uh you know,
if you like my video, share it.
Thank you. Bye.
Uh Shut down. Shut down here.
Thank you. Thank you.