welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is 2019 December 17th Tuesday
11 o'clock in the morning San Francisco
time and we are looking at Emily so
today I'm going to talk about sundry
topics hey there we are
Emily the yeah you carry Kimiko kimono
Yukari Yukari okay here is a Japanese
kana 101 now these now stop looking at
her boobs okay now look it okay these
words Yukari Yamuna that's how they
reach those Japanese characters and in
Chinese it's parents
now do you know Emily how do you
pronounce these Chinese characters
because the Japanese is so very
complicated because when they you know
they also use Chinese characters and for
the Chinese characters the pronunciation
for the Chinese characters is is like
they have several different
pronunciations so and they are usually
different from how we Chinese read these
characters so her name yukari yakumo in
chinese is we pronounce it parents and
do you know how it is pronounced do you
know Emily do you know do you do you do
you okay Alan Alan do you know Alan is a
Alan has a degree in linguistics Alan do
you know how do you pronounce this Oh
Alan must know because Allah knows
Chinese but how do you pronounce this in
Japanese like give us a introduction of
the
country in Japanese the Chinese
characters how are they pronounced like
I think they have like two or more
systems but in Chinese it's Bagginses
okay let me paste that here and the good
morning part oh hi you touch ahah ahahah
so punctual yes indeed I'm in a actually
I had an argument with my roommates my
roommates well I'd rather not
talk about it by you in so that's
Chinese right but but in Japanese how do
they usually how do they usually
pronounce the Chinese characters
onyomi onyomi chinese derived
pronunciation okay well okay what is
their normal so in Japanese you know
when they encounter Chinese character
which they call kanji they have
different set of pronunciations so one
is called ano me which is the Chinese
pronunciation okay so but I think in
general it's the cono me which is the
Japanese native pronunciation yakumo
mara sake these three characters really
that's what Emily says but and then
there are lots of idiosyncratic reading
so oh so you just read that as almost
basically like the Japanese hmm I don't
know because well this this three
Chinese characters you know that's three
characters okay so let's move on to
today's topic okay that's a preview and
we are going to talk about Emily there's
a fascinating topic the combinatorics
and we are going to
why we are going to buy dive by no we
are going to like go into linguistics
history and yeah god I need to remember
the words I need to remember fancy
exotic words this is when I want to be
Jordan Peterson Jordan Pederson or any
of these academics where you just you
just mouthing mouthing jargons like that
people don't understand so I'm going to
type the wait again remember the word
okay give me a second
okay palmistry numerology fire okay so
those of you help out you know at least
like this is a puzzle of analogy where I
speak words and you have to come up with
the right word okay I mean there's a
word I'm trying to get and this word may
be okay so let's play a game
I describe the definition and you give
the word okay
the definition this is about
fortune-telling okay this is about
fortune-telling and there are many type
of fortune-telling from Asian from 2,000
3,000 years ago
there is palmistry okay in Chinese
Chinese people love it they they get
crazy palmistry and in Western societies
there's astrology now as you know you
probably know if you are not you know
you know Astro astrology
sorry Unicode okay we talked about a
Unicode astrology stuff yesterday so you
go to saw Unicode and you go to go to
like G ot Oh like programming you go to
astronomy and astrology okay so hold on
a second so let's see where is it we
want math we want common symbol which
cultural cross games shapes common marks
math font APL we want stars courses no
oh there we go science is it
astrology there it is prominent in
prominent position so in astrology
astrology is one of the you know what
astrology is okay but instant in a seer
countries they are crazy about palmistry
you know what is palmistry where you
have your palm and you have lines on it
okay so every every person's lines are
different you know you see you see these
lines and
and you you know so that you're they you
know the fortune teller look at your
palm and this supposed to tell what's
what's your future and who you should
marry to things like that it's over over
Taiwan and Hong Kong I'm not sure about
China because China during the Cultural
Revolution they kind of wiped much of
that out superstitions so you have
palmistry you have astrology you have
geo men see Geo okay there it is so do
you guys know the word I'm looking for
the word that describe all these things
okay geo men see is one of them
where you draw geometry figures on the
ground and things like that and you try
to tell your fortune geomancy okay
geo man see let's go to Wikipedia geo
messy astrology palmistry numerology not
numerology is another big thing okay and
we have okay here is ji oh manseok
geomancy by the way this is pertinent to
today's topic we are going to talk about
this combinatorial exploration
combinatorial patterns
okay so geomancy is one of the ancient
technique of
fortune-telling and there are many you
know you thought dice and you know
things like that there's quite a few you
know esoteric stuff you can look into
let's see they okay there it is
the bagua the eight trigrams we're gonna
talk about that today and it's used for
fortune-telling it's useful each in you
know you western california people who
are into buddhism who are into yoga who
are into yoga and buddhism you're gonna
love it okay throw away physics what the
is physics throw away quantum
physics
you don't you don't need that okay you
go into the okay so you go to into the
the Geo man see numerology astrology
that is the future that is literally the
future and you have pyromancy you have
you have a bunch of menses here that is
the word okay Mansi means magic some
sort of magic so you have it there it is
so they're okay they got a list so let's
read it okay so you see in Renaissance
magic geomancy was classified as one of
the seven forbidden arts who along with
necromancy oh my god necromancy
hydro-man see a Roman see pyromancy
chiromancy palmistry
so palmistry is also known as chiromancy
i didn't know by the way do you know
what cairo means cara means like the the
way things it turns that's well and
spatula man see Oh
when did I start to have no audio when
when's the last word I said that no
audio God let's see
no audio 1112 so I've been talking for
two minutes without audio how is it
before ah it's okay so I've been talking
for this makes me very sad I've been
talking for fourteen minutes without
audio Jesus he said oh did I turn it off
somewhere before
c-can you never like I had audio before
sound come out for everyone so that is
11:11 okay not too bad
I have no audio two minutes ago
two minutes ago that is not too bad
emergency since forever Jen know what
general good morning general
okay spatula man see how did I get into
know to go I don't understand
Jesus no I'm all like okay so Amy says
after I talked about chai robe okay
anyway
I missed two minutes okay so you so you
guys know all these men see words okay
so geomancy you know necromancy is
fortune-telling kind of by the dead nico
hydro water arrow air pyro is
pyromancies by fire chiromancy palmistry
and
spatula man see spatula man see I didn't
know what that is like what the heck
that is
and it turns out it's like you take your
shoulder bones shoulder bones basically
you tell a fortune by the shoulder bones
okay so that is interesting and then I
was saying you know when you are looking
at into these kind of things then you of
you California people timber can come
booting okay so let me make sure I see I
have audio on this idiot god okay not me
the idiot technology technology idiocy
the idiocy of the technology we live in
that Google endowed us so anyway so you
have so you have phones way okay this of
you California people of you hallmark
whole food market people of you so you
boy people of you organic people okay of
you of you diet diet this or that diet
or something dier dier dier dier dier
dier diet diet diet everyday phone
straight okay you got a good look into
this for your life and forget about
physics
forget about quantum physics forget
about engineering this is what you want
phones way okay because you can tell a
fortune by arranging your house and
stuff and in by the way in Taiwan they
are crazy about this you know it's a
like a different culture of you American
people especially you California people
you don't know you go to Taiwan you go
live there you see this every day on TV
by the celebrities they talk about it
they invite expert ok phones way expert
they tell you how what's the proper date
to get married what would you know
things like that arrangement of your
buildings arrangement of your house
where you should have a tree where you
should not have a tree where that's that
that kind of thing and you know so that
is a big thing in Taiwan and also
palmistry remember palms the lines on
your palm okay so that so yeah so you
you know organic people you know
no and you animal rights people this is
your thing
go into it dive dive into like like like
you know diving dive okay so why are we
talking about these speak oh by the way
by the way Taiwan the big you know the
the the the the beautiful form art for
Mossad you know the who harbor who
protects the traditional Chinese value
the Taiwan people they they they want to
chant about this Taiwan 101 which is the
tallest building about 10 years ago you
know for us for several years so you
know you have this Taiwan 101 skyscraper
it pokes you see that that thing that
pokes the sky by the way that
architecture is very interesting you see
this is in Taiwan where basically
Chinese so this style is actually
modeled after pagoda now pagoda is
another fascinating subject but if we go
into there we are not gonna get out so
let's skip that topic pagoda okay let me
show you some pictures but go down for
gota is the traditional Buddhist
architecture which originated from India
but once in China they become something
else kind of they change a little bit
and by the way this is a Japanese pagoda
okay Japanese style is quite different
from Chinese style like you can tell
right away like if you ask a nice people
we Chinese people look at this picture
we know right away it's not Chinese
because okay the way you tell you
because Japanese pagoda they have square
shape square you see it's a square
square square square square that's
Japanese style you never basically never
sing square shaped pagoda in China okay
so that's a pagoda japanese-style okay
and that's
what is this this is South Korea again
square but that's a small one but let me
show you some interesting pictures okay
so so these are some some of the okay
they had so this is japanese-style
I mean it's showing okay they are
fascinating
I mean well they have you know I was
going to say they are beautiful but
beauty is in the eye of the beholder
because if you are Westerner you never
seen this you don't think much of it
just as I wanna see Islamic stuff like
Islamic buildings I think it's
interesting but you know but okay the I
actually don't they don't have a lot of
pictures of Chinese ones but let me show
you okay so this one is kind of very
traditional pagoda and pagodas they are
not residents you know in in modern
jargon residency they are not you know
you don't go live there but actually
they are they are kind of like temple
they are kind of temple related you know
Buddhism temples like Church like the
Western mean for example in the white
people's country white man's country you
have huge gigantic
churches you know the Catholic Church
how is he a proper name for that they
don't call it Church Cathedral yes
Cathedral which is grand you know
beautiful so it's so pagoda is religion
related kind of building okay structure
you don't you know it
they usually the inside they have like
they have Buddha inside basically you
know they store you know they stole
Buddhist scripts inside often so so here
is a japanese-style you can easily see
because it's square you know which is
far into me because when I look at that
it's like why would the back its this is
wrong yeah just like when you you know
this is
- when you see English alphabet like if
but when you see you started to see
Spanish or French where they have
accents and your reaction is like good
what what what that is wrong you know
because that's foreign to you in the
same way we Chinese when we see some of
the Japanese characters it's like what
what others that's just wrong so anyway
so this Japanese style pagoda then
another japanese-style pagoda again you
see it's a square made a square shape
and this one this looks like Chinese but
it's also square okay no okay where is
it
kya and it looks like Chinese ok so
again you have some squares and this one
is Taipei 101 it's a giant skyscraper we
seen before and this is this is I think
this is original India India's pagoda
that because they let's see where is
this form okay we we cannot get out of
this because we are not going to begin
to talk about our topic for the tip for
today proper so Buddha Tooth Relic
pagoda in young Kong so I guess that's
in China and this is Indian style pagoda
we don't you know this is really weird
okay to me so okay so let's close that
by the way some of these are very old
1000 years old
especially Chinese ones some of them are
made of stone 1000 years old or more so
pagoda okay copy that close that go back
to the Emax and we are going to pace it
here sidetrack pagoda okay and close
that okay tie base so why why am I
talking about pagoda
tibe a one on one you can see this
skyscraper is modeled after pagoda Asian
style but you see the funny thing is
when they build this building they have
to consult Fung Shui experts member Fong
shui France way is is fortunate have
anything so they have to they have to
consult the phone say expert for example
it's actually mentioned here let me show
you okay you know they the government
you know Taiwan government you know the
celebrities the big shots the you know
the you know they have to they have to
talk to the phone so a expert so that so
that look at this one okay phones to a
fountain outside Taipei 101 so right in
front of it there is this fountain and
it's called phones very fountain phones
wait you know so you need this without
this the body the building's gonna fall
so that that is the that is a example of
the significance of Fung Shui in Taiwan
a certain Asia culture just like you
Americans have astrology okay it just
just like don't don't don't think too
fancy about it just like you guys have
astrology and so on so phone's way okay
let's copy that and phone say by the way
it's a big thing you in California you
know the in California you go to
downtown you eat at fancy restaurants
you know all the fancy restaurants and
you take a stroll then you cannot run
into modern bookstores you know the yoga
bookstores the yoga then and phone
saying in that sort of thing and
geomancy okay copy that and we haven't
got into num not numerology and um e ro
l gy numerology which is also agent
where you use numbers to tell a fortune
okay that's getting a far so let's close
that number numerology which is also the
origin of number theory for you guys
math oriented programming oriented or
the origin of number theory numerology
okay geomancy so let's close down
geomancy and let's talk about today's
topic proper properly we need to do
things properly and my concern is my
concern is looking at and okay who is
she let me tell you who is she okay so
MSUM boys check I'm alive okay I'm not
dead yet that's good and perhaps I
should read comments lest I a lien ate
my viewers let's see how that's checks
checks Addis Houston what's your status
Houston status report status we have
been talking for 30 minutes non-stop my
mouth smoothly done stopped for 30
minutes okay let me sleep a drink and
let's see the comments hello beautiful
people hello beautiful person good
morning hello beautiful people to pack
and let's do raw account okay so
speaking at the beginning good morning
Emily to UK come on in part to Germany
good morning Alan to Sacramento okay Cal
California okay
the Dwight big white California and good
morning to Eduardo
which is from Brazil correct me if I'm a
college wrong gay
some of you frequenters good morning to
Nabby from California good morning to
you all
okay and let me start to read the
comments okay and char and char Roth
sheriff his Emacs can be C++ IDE so
charas question is can a max b c plus
plus IDE yes it can but in general among
Emacs users it is agreed upon awake
C++ yeah Emacs can do it it's not bad
okay yes but I don't know it because
hello beautiful people thank you so much
thank you hello beautiful people this is
my big donor okay so so holy friends
howie from France France Steve so good
morning Steve
so Freddie okay so we got so many people
so let me read the comments okay
comments from the beginning then we're
gonna talk about the topic proper which
today is the hexagram trigram diagram
the mystery of these things and what do
they mean okay that's an important thing
because now here's my grape juice for
the day the meaning of these things and
you're gonna touch lots of things really
Asian stuff and we also gonna talk about
Frederic godfrid Lebanese do you guys
know who he is he is one of the greatest
mathematician the inventor of calculus
together with Newton okay both of them
Newton one of the greatest mathematician
and the father of logic okay that is
this guy guys godfrid Lebanese the
father of the father of formalism the
father of a computing machine that can
decide on everything he is the father
okay Fred
God Fred
and he has something to say about
hexagram which is this this beautiful
patterns on these girls attire you see
where I look at beautiful girls I cannot
stop staring at their tits but that's
beside the point
there's something else I'm focused on
okay this is rock star so I'm going to
become a baby I'm the star so let's see
the comments okay we were talking about
those her name but you into back into
okay yukari yakumo yukari yakumo yukari
yakumo you have to you see if you want
to learn japanese you have to stop
reading the English transcripts you know
you cannot start to read these Japanese
characters like over here and those
characters are you copy
yakumo okay remember that characters now
Emily's got a method of her own a
methodology of how to remember how to
memorize these Japanese phonetics okay
you have to ask her for the details
explore the realms of linguistics and
Bart says my mom did palm reading when
she was a teenager
hmm that's interesting so that is why
you are here because if she didn't do
that you may not you know she may not
have a child that's how serious this
stuff are yes II so by the way part
Bartholomew are you a mix
race are you I like how you know are you
a mixed race there's a there's a bunch
of terms for that are you mixed like is
your mom Chinese or something Asian I
haven't seen your face before so
therefore by the way guys so join this
code okay that that is why we are here
we are here to know each other to talk
to each other to get intimate with each
other okay not not some random
online chat okay like reddit anonymous
everyone is anonymous or the hacker
news or the chant channels
everyone is bullshitting mouthing
everything every day like you don't know
nothing you cannot you cannot trust
nothing over here you can develop a
trust you know who they are you know we
you know we people you see photos you
see stuff you know you talk to people so
that is that is San talk show I mean
that is the sadhus code oh by the way
you can see the disco link in the
description YouTube description okay so
go there and join a great face and
varied people okay so let's see mystic
Emax hermit okay
moves text with his mind okay Japanese I
don't understand and each in each in the
book of change the ancient thing can you
even read it cover-to-cover
yeah I can read it but the thing is you
don't understand it and that's the thing
each in each okay that's that's that's
let's look up okay so yeah so okay let's
look a book of change book of change
because when we start to talk about
hexagrams let me show you so many
interesting things so I close my unicorn
sorry Unicode so you have to go to Mike
sorry Unicode
Paige you so you go to it then you go to
cultural symbols okay then then let me
begin this important subject so you have
the most familiar to you is these chai
grams
okay so let's magnify let's see if we
can magnify so you have these trigrams
then you also by the way you also have
diagram and they then you have also
monogrammed you have three possibilities
in this case by the way there is a bit
difference between them you see all
these are combinatorial patterns but
what you see when you have monogrammed
you can divide a line by into two or
three so therefore you have three okay
so I'm not sure how do you characterize
this but let's let's talk about the
trigram okay the trigram is three
horizontal bars for each bar there are
two possibilities the whole line or
divided into two so altogether you have
eight possibilities let's try grab now
for the diagram it's a bit different you
you can see because now for the diagram
you have two bars but however each bar
has three possibilities the whole line
are divided into two sections like that
or it can also be divided into three
sections you know like that and and then
combination thereof so there so you see
so you get what I'm saying so this this
system of diagram and this system of
trigram they are not the same they are
not exactly the same then you have this
monogram you know I'm not sure what if
the position count or not these are
Unicode characters by the way so you can
copy them for example I copy so you go
through
my website you copy and you can for
example I paste it here
wait let me show okay so magnify magnify
massively and let's remove the English
we don't want we don't want the English
words we just want these grams okay so
how do you do in Emacs text so Emacs
chip now so I'm going to call I'm going
to call query replace rejects you see
you see the commanding on the left
window query rejects with we query
replace rejects and I am going to type
these two pairs of square bracket nested
together and I'm going to type colon
ASCII okay and the end for the first
time you see the mini buffer at bottom
okay so I press ENTER replace with
nothing okay so it found one I say yes
press space for yes or press or press
the band to remove them also you got so
now we got popper so you see those are
monograms then then we have diagrams
then we have sexy grams then we have
sexy grams and more okay tetragram let
me show you tetragram actually let me
show you oh let's just copy them all
okay put it here and let's repeat the
last command again replace all ASCII
characters by nothing okay before I do
that this in this command is important
so guys look at it okay so this command
is called the repeat complex command
what it does is that it will call
whatever command you call before but
without you having to answer questions
so you just repeat the last command but
with all the you know the prompt
answered
by the same way you used last time so
that that is what that command for so
we're gonna call that okay so we place a
ski bye-bye nothing yes
okay do it for there we have it so we
have so you can see these complexities
so this so we have four paths then we
have six paths and then we have those by
the way this symbol is interesting this
is Japanese beginner this symbol you're
looking at that is that symbol is Japan
Japanese symbol for beginner new okay so
if you want to indicate to others that
you are a noob you put this symbol and
you know and they me and and you know
and let me show you another eMac tips
tip okay you call describe character so
now you can read about what that symbol
is so the name is here Japanese symbol
for beginner so in Japan when you see
that symbol that means oh this is for
beginner you know for example Japanese
have lots of these kind of symbols they
have like anyway so you have these these
six grams and tetragram and six a gram
so let's go back to what were we talking
about forty minutes 18 people Wow 18
people and I made four dollars thank you
hello beautiful person and then we have
let's see Ubuntu okay so let's see what
we have there is something I want to say
then then we're gonna close down we I
have 10 more minutes or 20 minutes so I
want so we were beginning to talk about
that and
oh yeah book of change book of change
did we already look at that
let's see book of change so this book is
Asian about 2,000 years old it's a
Chinese book and it's basically it's
used for divinations okay it's for kind
of divination so each in the name
doesn't really mean anything
anyway English you call each in Ching is
kind of like book chin means like the
Bible like the scripture so it's a II
scripture so that the name means it's a
scripture of II and that word e usually
means easy but however in this context
you know because this is Asian so it in
my means something else I don't really
know so this book is written by oho 1000
PC so this book is 3,000 years old guys
this book is 3,000 years old so here we
have a copy that is from year one
thousand year AB 1010 so this copy is
from year one you know one one one
thousand years ago let's see if I can
read it okay so Alan asked me if I can
read it more or less chant
- whoo - so II sung Ching chants 1te
okay so it means some kind of manual
annotated I guess and I don't know what
that means so so that is a book name and
the scripture you know and then
something the first volume something
that okay so let's get to so actually is
this the change some time he found in
yen yeah you know I can read most
Chinese can read the characters and
however to understand them is entirely
different thing now there are two
reasons why you don't understand it
because one is that you know this is
written 3,000 years ago so there's a lot
of changes you know but you when you
read it the meaning okay the words the
characters they still have more or less
the same meaning us today because when I
read this for example I can tell kind of
what is about you know I can tell what
is like roughly it's maybe talking about
you know I can know roughly what it is
about but however I cannot know exactly
what they are saying because it's 3,000
years old you know anyway so yeah most
Chinese you can read it but so let's get
on to you know this is over Capone from
a big turtle okay so here we have the
whole thing we have we have what is this
this is a hexagram each one of them
actually have a name okay so this
hexagram came from this book okay the
book of fortune I mean that well the
book of change and the interpretation
and so on but I can tell you what it is
it is superstition okay it's basically
superstition just like astrology you
know it's like when you study you know
as an analogy when you study astrology
you could dive into 2,000 years old
probably yeah you know then there's lots
of things you to study anyway
so so what is it let's get into
something interesting we've been talking
about this for a while and let's get
into the interesting parts and let's
wrap it up okay so what are you okay so
let me show you okay so so the
interesting things is about each of
these has a okay turn javascript please
okay so each of these character have a
name you can see and I mean they also
read about name for example let's go to
the first one six bars so this is
hexagram for the creative heaven okay
and this one is hexagram for the
receptive heaven okay this one is
hexagram for difficulty at the beginning
difficulty at the beginning so this is
related to the Japanese beginners symbol
okay so remember this one you have to
now you have to memorize it okay I'm
gonna create I'm gonna do a crease this
is your homework so this is hexagram for
difficulty at the beginning so next time
when you aren't on twitter or online you
want to tell your friend oh I have some
difficulties in learning a scowl you
need to post this symbol they will
understand okay difficulty hexagram
difficulty at the beginning let's see
next one hexagram for youthful folly
[Laughter]
this this is all the Chan people the
charm people for Chan people and the
social justice people the Millennial
people hexagram for youthful folly
hexagram for waiting this one hexagram
for conflict oh oh my god this is
serious this this one is US versus China
this one hexagram for the army your oh
oh oh you know anyway so hexagram for
the army okay so you have you got a
hexagram for the army
this one hexagram for holding together
okay this one this one hexagram for
small Tammy okay so each one scatter
name is very interesting oh this one
this one is for me hexagram for the
wanderer okay this one is gonna be
symbolize is gonna be my badge hexagram
for gentle wind so it's quite
interesting okay
so and this character she wears this
clothing by the way this is a game okay
this character is from a Japanese skin
cord well that's that's allowed to go
into and there is a great story about
that but maybe we should skip it but
anyway it's a it's a Japanese Emily
knows about it Emily so it's a Japanese
basically a 2d shoot-'em-up game but
however the game has kind of characters
and each one has like elaborate story
background story so she's one of the
character and she you know the
background story is so elaborate such
that they even have a character attire
so she is wearing for example if you
search for her name Yukari
wait.you yukari yakumo you you you will
find a whole lot of pictures and some of
them are drawn by fans that javascript
and stupid DuckDuckGo okay open again
paste enter so you will find you know
great a wait wait i need to turn off the
okay save such moderate you don't want
to look you don't want to search this
when the safe search is not on okay I'm
pretty sure so her name anyway so you
see this elaborate costume you know they
this this is a character design and okay
so so this is I guess this is the that I
mean the the one of the you know
representation of her so her her attire
you'll notice has this hexagram
and it's not just any hexagram it must
be this one it must be this one
specifically okay this is actually part
of you know this is part of the
character design you want to be very
specific
you-you-you think you don't want to like
just wave hands okay so on this
character whose name is you Yukari
and this is her attire okay and on this
attire it has this hexagram it must be
this specific one and that one has
meaning like we talked about okay you
can read the text but that one let me
tell you which one that is
because by now I have memorized to that
one that one is it's open close close
and or close okay so open close close in
Oh close
open cross cross or cross okay how do I
find it now now now the other question
now on my mind is how are these ordered
now we have to explore the mathematics
of ordering are disordered so the one we
are trying to find is open crows crows
and okay wait let's look at it again
okay let's are go at her Oh
open open close open open open okay it's
double check oh wait there is a conflict
wait this picture is wrong God who drew
this Emily there is a conflict this this
is wrong so one of the picture is wrong
so this one is open close close open
open open and according to her wiki that
it not should be the one so therefore
this picture away wait I did I was I
confused open close close open open open
okay yeah so this picture is wrong this
Emily so we got a problem what do you
think you know tell me what you think
we've got a problem
so anyway that that's you know she's got
this clothing and okay so open closed
closed open open open
so that character is open close close
open open open
god I need to find this open close close
I found it before this will not stand by
it good morning dear
I guess the artist didn't do her
research properly okay we must find i1
and we are about to shut down okay open
crows crows open open open so anyone did
you guys found it yet there it is okay
geez there okay so it's like I need to
fix my website so that
there this one hexagram for gathering
together that's the meaning of her one
right side three from top okay Freddy
has found it yeah okay so we change
anyway so this this is her her symbol
hexagram for oke for gathering together
that's her that's her destiny something
like that okay okay I think that's about
it this one more thing there's one or
two things yeah let me just okay we Oh
God
there's a lot things okay maybe we
talked about tomorrow there's a math the
math of combinatorial problems and
unsolved problems which is very ill
doing so but let's let's see how long
I've been talking one hour okay so let's
go back to the okay so here is a Chinese
movie okay so let's go here let's go to
you
let's go through chrome so we have
JavaScript now this is the Chinese
kung-fu movie if you like kung-fu movies
it's it's a good one okay that is if you
like on few movies but and there is a
classic music playing in this scene that
in that classic music classical music
it's an opera and it's fantastic okay so
you know you might check out this the
link will be shown on a YouTube
description later on oh you can just you
know use the link right there you know
just type it yourself so anyway so this
movie and and what they are doing is
that you know it's a kung-fu movie so
they are fighting and one of the kung-fu
style is spock wa so what is paka paka
is basically
trigrams okay so in this this trigram in
Chinese we call it ba gua okay so let's
go back to trigram so you see this this
the most popular are these trigrams and
in we call those spark wah
so in Impa Gua ba gua means eight eight
symbols okay eight trigrams basically so
in but in but in kung-fu there is a
style of Kung Fu which is very big that
spark wah
and that's you know that's you know the
it's a thought
kind of related okay ba gua which is a
tricot eight trigrams you call it BA kua
meaning eight trigrams okay it's used in
eaching as you have seen the book of
change and it's also used in Taoism like
tight you know it's part of it it's a
fundamental call and you also see the
yin-yang symbol the in young Simba okay
so where is it you see the young symbol
here there you see so that young symbol
which which means negative and positive
basically the two forces of nature
that's what it means in Taoism the union
symbol and the the eight trigram are
almost inseparable they are you see it
everywhere okay and they are so they are
part of Taoism and Taoism is also a part
of kung fu
you know they are kind of intermingled
okay so she's practicing this style of
kungfu and you know so of you can fool
of us martial art art you know guys you
can watch this this fighting scene and
so on so there it is the ba gua and by
the way if you go to China especially
Taiwan you see this every day you see
this like literally every day or almost
in every home you will see they will
have this
in front of their door is it functions a
sort of talisman
okay talisman what is an example of
western counterpart where you have Jesus
okay
in many Christian homes you have Jesus
on course right almost you know in
religious phrases you will see that in
almost every household you'll find that
Jesus somewhere you know across
especially let's say 50 years ago so in
but in Asia in Taiwan in particular you
go to every house almost your CDs in
just about every house every or every
other and usually it's part of the
mirror and by the way you can buy this
in Chinatown you go to you know San
Francisco whatever Chinatown you can buy
these cheap cheap you know so this is
all part of culture thou ISM you know
it's all tied together but okay let me
read a part of it okay so did let me
read a verse I think this is from from I
forgot where is it from but maybe it's a
one of the Taoist script so this is
Chinese let me read in Chinese then let
me read it in English okay let me
magnify so this this paragraph this poem
this verse describes the bagua the eight
trigrams
so he says gucci son yo g yo G Taiji
Taiji son Liam e G in young Liang ISA G
so in tying so Yong Tae Yong su Yong
Yong Papua Papa Dios quoi okay that's
Chinese so what does it mean
so here's English the limit the limit
less produces the delimited and this is
the absolute
the Taiji produces two forms named in
and young the two phones produced for
phenomenon named Lessig in greater in
this a young greater young the full
phenomenon act on the eight trigrams
eight eight are 64 hexagrams
okay so this is this is steep and and
it's quite interesting you know so we
here we are touching on culture history
and linguistics there we are here is
linguistics guys if you are interested
in writing if you are a Haskell
programmer if you are interested in
technical writing if you are excited by
growth about how he wrote a book about
how to write technical stuff if you you
know if you need help people here we
have linguistic s-- translation and
stuff you can dive as much as you want
diving okay and then then then there is
mathematics we haven't touched
mathematics yet you see this these are
combinatorial patterns it's not just
linguistics if you look at them from a
mathematicians point of view if you have
a heart to do that
you see math that's what you see thank
you see mathematics okay then
and here is a quote let me finish today
by let okay before we go go there let's
go let's go look at a South Korean flag
okay
wait actually Nabi showed us one let's
let's go to Nabi showed us South Korean
flag how they use the trigram so we have
beautiful people here and we are
shutting down in two minutes okay so
where is nabis picture
there it is you see this is Korean flag
so they are using full of the eight
trigrams now for the meaning you go to
Wikipedia okay for meaningful Y you go
to Wikipedia and now let's go back to
what we were talking about we were
talking about yeah so let me leave you
with this godfrid Lebanese okay
the in 1646 that's the year he was born
he is an inventor of calculus and father
of computer
he said hexagram is a base for claiming
the universality of the binary number
system let me repeat that okay one more
time
histograms hexagrams
a base for claiming the universality of
the binary numerical system your
homework is why okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching so yeah
that's it for today and have a good day
and we shut down in one minutes okay one
yeah one minute for sure so we're
Lebanese okay you go so today's homework
you want to find out why Lebanese said
that okay what is the reason what is a
mathematical reason so what are you guys
saying foot stuck in the system now so
how can I get into your discord there is
a link in the description in the YouTube
description or you just go to my youtube
channel I mean I have links everywhere
in my website sorry down info okay thank
you guys for watching say goodbye okay
say goodbye in a chat and that the Viet
thumbnail of the video thumbnail of the
video that's my food ok and you can see
by the way so join this code ok there is
a lot things we are talking about about
about keyboard you know we talked about
also you can see also love fancy
keyboards ok there's too many I cannot
show I can I'll show you on the video
but there are tens of and people you
know and many of them experts here they
talk about it so bye guys
and about my food you go to the real
life section and you can see oh this one
is seats CID seats food let's look at
this ah go it's it's food he is a
mathematician and right now he's in
Japan and he's doing research on I think
this is public information so because he
talked about it
he's doing research on the quantum he's
doing research on crypt crypt analysis
after contem ok you know do you know do
you guys know what that means that means
the quantum computing is coming guys
however quantum computing poses a giant
threat to crypto cryptanalysis
cryptography like right now so
apparently he is you know we are already
studying crypto analysis after contact
that is what what we do not do what you
gonna do you know when we have come
quantum computers so we are going to
have a crypto system that is you know in
in venerable to the quantum computing
even quantum computers so we are
researching on that and he is in Japan
so look at his gorgeous sushi food oh my
god is gorgeous
sushi food and lots of others people's
food here okay so crash hacker he is
also in Japan he's doing
a I research on image recognition then
we have a George who is in Australia
George is not here today and you know
quite a few and there is my food okay
so join this code and thank you guys bye