good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show
we are going to talk about JavaScript
and Emacs
so today's method so I'm life could
today's May 3rd Friday 2019
this is captain's log and we're gonna
talk about JavaScript iterators now
javascript is a extremely complicated
language even with 2015
I mean it's convoluted language and we
gonna talk about Emacs long line
problems and Emacs community you know
these bad things then we're gonna talk
about some coding practice so let's see
how many people watching 0 okay let's
begin you know we have to begin
somewhere beginning at the beginning now
let's stop talk about so which one to go
first
there is the okay why don't we so we got
two guys two people here say hi saw
talk-show and let's put today's date and
let's put the topics here okay
so that's a topic but my neighbor is
making his moon morning that is flowing
the grass let me let me turn off the
closer window on a sec
Superman
so now we are talking so let's begin
talking about let's begin talking about
Emacs so Emacs in JavaScript and coding
practice
yeah let's begin with Emacs now Emacs as
human no it has a long line problem that
is if you have a line a very long line
you know like thousands of characters
you know usually the the programming
advice is that when you have lime lines
should not be more than 70 characters or
something like that which is one of the
most extremely idiotic concept okay the
reason it we have that idiom you know
that practice recommendation is because
it came from punch cards you know punch
cards in punch cards from 1960s so this
is what it pants card is like you know
so before we don't have digital we don't
have computer I mean we don't have
digital computers we don't have
electronic we you know you know in in in
the beginning we don't have that you
know computer calculating machine good
morning Victor is like you know in the
beginning computers are like mechanical
devices with gears you know gears you
turn this gear that you know the in turn
makes another key or turn then you know
then you have you know algorithm you
know these all these skills then then
then eventually you look at the last
year
that's your result you know so that is
basically the whole engine of computing
machines you know mechanical for example
well known is the the something machine
anyway then we have punch car
which is you know a card and you punch
holes you know in these positions and
you place this card inside a machine you
know that's how this so this is like
today's source code you know you you
feed this into a machine and originally
the punch card is like 70 horse you know
70 or 80 horse so so that is the
arrangin of the recommendation of 70
characters per line you know so this is
you know I don't know I don't know I'm
not you know I don't know the history of
the punch card detail you can read on
Wikipedia but basically that is the that
is kind of the engine of the 70 lines 70
characters per line and you know why it
became popular because UNIX UNIX the
most idiotic crap in compute computing
industry because UNIX in the 70s and 80s
they tell people to cut lines they
enforce the idea that lies should not be
more than 70 characters because if you
have lines more than semantic characters
they simply truncated silently like they
just cut it off so terminal sides are
also were 18 by 24 something like that
last name as to hope first name last
name okay anyway so yeah terminal well
yeah that's that's true that's a good
reason terminal so we have terminals
which only can display you know no more
than 80 characters you know so anyway so
as everything goes you know you have you
know you have to follow I mean there are
constraints you know it's like in a
ATS for example you cannot say oh let's
just have you know you know technology
advances slowly and each time step by
step so you have all these constraints
from from the past you know today you
know so that is reasonable so what I'm
trying to say is that the lines at 70
Charles you know practice it's actually
still you know recommended by idiotic
programmers all over like on kids match
it in Emacs match it they won't you like
if you have more than 70 like you if
your lines is longer than 70 characters
but those are the most idiotic thought
but what I'm saying yeah so I'm saying
that these came from the UNIX idiots
okay the UNIX and Linux idiots and you
know typical hacker you know so-called
hacker culture you know elite hackers or
you know it UNIX philosophy or those
kind of thing and so that's what I'm
saying
but there is the good point that
terminal terminals in a you know back in
the day so let's go to the keyboard
let's show you some terminals so this is
my keyboard blog and you can go to
history history so here we see several
terminals
you know from 1965 1969 1970s you know
over you know in 1976 this is how then
the VI editor began 1975 some of these
are very popular this one pt 52 and this
one
ADM 3a and this one vt100 you know most
older programmers like today in their
50s 60s they they have they have found
memories of these terminals but anyway
so so you know you have these terminals
and they can only display 80 characters
so why 80 well
that came from punch card as well no no
I'm going to I'm just giving the giving
you the general kind of history okay it
in many details I don't know the very
hardcore details you know but if you
want to study that you know but you can
go up to me doing that anyways my
thinking is that it is true on one hand
that things evolve slowly so you cannot
just suddenly for example if you have a
terminal
you cannot say oh 80 characters stupid
you know let's not do that you know
because it's you cannot do it because
you know these are very expensive back
then you know you have engineering cost
and you have that your screen sizes is
only 80 characters so what if you have
more than 80 characters well you could
maybe you know write programs so that
they rap or something but but rapping is
an algorithm by itself so it introduces
delay it costs CP you have to computed
so you know it may it's probably it's
not practical you know so that is true
you know so we you know we cannot just
you know thinking back and you know
about how things are stupid because they
don't have today's background you think
you know that it's not like today but
however on the other hand we must also
realize some of the practices such as
keyboard our keyboard and many almost
all practices much of it is from history
is due to history including English you
know English language when you if you
are study linguistics you you will find
that English language including French
or Chinese that they are like a whole
bag of garbage you know the grammar it's
like extremely convoluted and illogical
okay
the reason it said is it's that way it's
because history you know you you don't
like one day you are a god designing a
language like this is English for you
know you
guys are gonna speak it you don't design
from there it's evolved you know
beginning we don't have like imagine you
know ten thousand years ago we don't
have a language we just you know like
chimps or monkeys you know then
eventually maybe we have you know we
carve on stones you know making some
characters then eventually we have
languages then then we have words you
know then we then some philosopher did
you know look at the thing and they
created grammar okay so you know some
guy says okay this is the English
grammar you have you know you you have
tenses and so on so almost all things
like that they are if you look at from
you know logical point of view they are
not logical they are not efficient they
are not logical they are not almost in
every aspect they are not necessarily
good but however however they are
evolved you know programming languages
and natural languages or the keyboard we
use you know the input systems and
programming practices they are evolved
you know piece me piecemeal and they
they evolve to satisfy our requirements
and needs you know over the years or
hundreds of years and so on so in some
sense they are actually a good I mean at
least they are a workable system so so
so so what I'm saying is that but if you
think about it but you have to be a lot
you you you you know if you are a surfer
or you know you study history you do
know that you have to understand what I
just said you know this came from
history or that you know when you want
to study some subject you know for
example should we should programmers you
know have lines no more than 80
characters any particular issue
you study it you know you think about it
you think of you know you study history
use you know you study all the things
then you make a good decision okay so
what I'm saying now okay my point right
now is that the vast majority of
programmers are idiots because when they
think about they don't think actually
you know the the the weather line should
be more than 80 characters they don't
think they don't know where it came from
they just think oh it's good because
longer lines is harder to read you know
extremely idiotic for example if you are
in a word processor you know any editor
this is Chinese
okay so let's turn back to English
okay so any any processor okay so for
example it's you know this is you know
any this is a word processor actually
it's just a simple text editor and this
one is called text edit it is the
default editor in Mac in Mac OS the
operating system for example
did I ever press Enter no is this line
more than 80 characters yes but is it
easy to read yes because there's an
automatic wrapping
you know you don't have to press Enter
so but programmers they don't understand
that they don't they do not realize this
like when you for example if I if right
now I treat you know I'm treated all I
should not be 80 characters then you got
the army like a whole bunch of
programmers
oh no but but it's not easy to read you
know it's extremely idiotic and this
idea has is deeply seated in in program
must mind they don't never think about
it okay now I know a Emacs guy okay he
say agent you know like older than me
actually I mean he is me you
the max you know for a long time and let
me let me show you which is this guy
this guy's name so this guy is Emacs
Lisp
let's see Emacs miscellaneous okay and
let's search for IC e IC I tell it's
such for screen shot Nick o'clock this
guy okay so this guy Nick o'clock he say
old Emacs
out P you know he's he's been using
Emacs since for 30 years something like
that so he he's actually a great guy he
knows a lot he's a C program he's a C
expert okay
anyway we digress and also he is a user
he by the way he uses the Icicle package
from Emacs which is one of the package
that few people you know not many people
uses and he also is a motor on keyboard
user so he uses this keyboard for like
20 years you know before there is a fat
you know today about you know oh go dogs
or split split economic he was but
anyway he's been using this keyboard for
like 20 years in fact there's a picture
let me show you a picture of this is his
keyboard he sent me a picture
this is his mohchung keyboard so this so
this guy is NIC o'clock Oh NIC a
what a strange name is in UK okay so
he's one of the old P okay so so I have
you know we were met him
Google Plus which Google killed you know
a few months ago so I made him a google
class you know and he he's a great guy
because I like often I hide Nicolas hi
guys
often I you know I I despise you know
the typical programmers so I have a lot
of huge amount of articles of rent so I
post on Google+ and he and most of my
comments okay like 99 you know night 95
percent of comments are idiot you
idiotic programmers but however you know
once in a while there are few people
programmers I really respect because
every time when they make a comment I
mean it's it doesn't matter they agree
with me or they do not agrees with me a
good comment is square a comment you
provide solid great information you know
you know oftentimes some of these people
they do not agree and they but they
provide great information that such a
bit you know I learned something or
sometimes I see oh I never thought of
that you know so that and and and and
sometimes it may change my mind and yeah
it has happened you know and I go you
know oh my god I was totally wrong you
know because you know so a handful of
people really great they give you great
they think you know they they all know
they have experience you know they are
you know they are great programmers I
respect so Nick o'clock is one of them
he's one of the great because I post all
my rants on Google+ but every time he's
reply ok his reply always has great
content I learned something from it you
know so anyway so he's he's a great
great guy he doesn't have like he
doesn't have a blog blog he doesn't you
know had the social networks you know he
doesn't like those so
a lot great programmers they don't have
you know blogs or you know social
networks like most of the bloggers a lot
of it is like idiots okay but but they
became famous you know they tell you
what to do
anyway Nick acog the reason I mentioned
him because so I have written I have
written tens of articles about the line
rap okay hot red lines okay I'm
digressing actually or engineer I wanted
to talk about the Emacs long line
problem that isn't that nature of
startup show so I have this article
program programming the hum of hard rock
rapping lines okay so you know they are
like okay and another one and another
one that like there are ten articles
also written in the past 20 years
so the hum of hot rapping lines you know
this Arco is from 2005 and this one is
you know so I study the issue you know
let me tell you what you know originally
why it happens the UNIX ok the
UNIX the programmers here the UNIX
philosophy scans ok those people
Voodoo's they spread Buddhist you know
today they type you know today the UNIX
fast we you don't hear it much anymore
because the you kind of went away and
you know and Perl people went away but
anyway so the UNIX people back then in
1990s ok and also early 2000s they tell
people to cut their lives because they
are email you know they decide RFC you
know basically in UNIX when you have
lines more than 80 characters all the
backs of the shell programs like PS ok
the virus PS and the tar and a bunch of
like they almost all of them they just
truncate their your lines they just
the truncated that's how UNIX is and
UNIX email programs also truncate lines
so that is why this the idea of cutting
has become so deep seeded and UNIX
people they they they they actively go
out and harass any other programmers who
do not truncate their lies there's a for
example there's a famous programmer who
is doing that you know like back then
you don't have hacker news you know back
then it's a new scoops ok so they are
you know UNIX programmers they tell the
people you should cut you should
truncate your lines like if you if I
write the email let's say this this you
know this one for example open new
buffer so you know normally it's all in
one lines right but if you email that
you know to the new scoop you will get
framed they want you to tell you know
you want to do it this way you know with
let me show you the white space so you
can see the white space characters you
see so so this way you can see there is
a newline character you know this is
called hard rat you know instead of
instead of
yeah instead of it like that but we can
create a soft rap so soft rap is like
this you see right now it's still one
long line there's no there's no new line
in anywhere here but however it's it is
wrapped you know over the window in fact
you can do a margin you can see the
marching in emacs
I'm not going to show you it but you can
such you know sorry
Emacs margin you'll find you know you
can so you can have a you can actually
set the margin just like a word
processor so anyway so so this is a
issue okay so and you know so so it's
deep you know the idea of cutting lines
is very deep in programming languages I
mean among programmers yeah Google Plus
is dead you know but anyway so so this
idea is a very bad idea in fact you can
see one of the is it's it has huge
consequences and it also influences how
programming language is designed so the
you know this is one of the most idiotic
like I have so many articles discussing
about it you can see here it has huge
bad consequences in programming
community okay and I'm going to show you
one today but by the way you can also
word wrap okay so let's see you see now
it looks better
you see they so this paragraph still I
do not have any line I do not have any
newline character but yet you can see
it's you know it's you know it it's it's
wrapped you know so so anyway the the
line coding has lots of consequences
[Music]
let's see and I'm going to show you I'm
going to show you one of the very bad
consequence today that is in Emacs okay
I'm gonna let me show you then yeah so
first of all I talked you know I so it
came from punch cards then that then it
became a tradition then the UNIX people
you know the Voodoo programmers they
spread it they insisted so to this day
we still have this convention you know
you know a lot of programming styles
tell people to do it but it's we should
not do it today okay it's really bad
okay
instead you should insert a you know a
line return only a logical places such
as when you finished a sentence then you
know just just like word processor when
you finish the sentence then you add a
return then you begin you know start the
next line same thing in the programming
code when when you have a code
programming code let's close that so for
example I have code here let me go to
this window so this is my code you see I
do not realize this is one line you know
it should be that way and when you have
code for example this long line code to
do not write lies rapid only way it's
logical it's a logical unit you know
that that's how things should be then
because another consequence of this line
rap is you have you begin to have this
counting programmer
counting software size by by number of
lines you know extreme idiotic
for example this for example this list
this list is normally how things are
done but however you know I can you know
I can do it this way then my program you
know I can make my program you know
10,000 lines or 1 million lines you know
just this kind of thing
see extremely idiotic then the another
consequence is you know so programmers
focus on this you know kind of when you
can't program program size you want to
focus on the unit like algorithmic unit
unit that is the proper way so you might
want to count you know how many
algorithmic unique unit there are in
your software you know that's a proper
way to you know that's a proper idea to
judge the size of a software not lines
of code you know but but because of the
line you know it you know 70 characters
because of this habit and thought it in
fluid has lots of consequences one of
the consequence is that programmers do
not ever get the idea that software
should be algorithmic unit the instead
of they just think of lines lies
you know you know it's arguable you know
whether this anyway so it's a problem so
because everything you do your reactions
your decisions you as a person in real
life doesn't matter what issue whatever
you do depends on two things okay one is
your heritage you know your DNA whatever
you were born with okay
the other one is your environment how
you grew up what you see what you have
seen your experiences you know what you
have been taught you know so if you have
been taught you know from what the first
day you start to learn programming that
you should cut lines then that becomes
part of your experience you you know you
you never think of it because most you
know nobody ever think about everything
we are being taught you know because if
you actually do that you became a
philosopher
that's what philosophers do you know you
you you know you are just thought of you
know your culture whatever you know you
just do things because that way you are
efficient you don't have to think you
know so but if programmers are taught
you know you
you know we it is a fact that
programmers are taught to this day that
you should cut lines then it becomes
part of your you know thought so so that
you know prevents you from you know you
don't have awareness of this the issue
so that influences your other thoughts
in programming languages in other you
know things so that's one of the hum so
that that is why I say you know the
algorithmic unit you know programmers
this concept is not popular you know if
you ask you know programmers like ask
your friends ask those people at Google
idiots at Google you know ask them what
is a perfect algorithmic unique there
you go huh huh what do you mean but you
say you know number of lines
oh yeah number of lines you know they
are talking about oh oh there are these
tours you can count the number of lines
and there's another tool you can you
know remove the comments and you know
these idiots okay so you know so so let
me show you start to show you a problem
real problem Emacs because due to the
the habit of you know you know Alliance
it's no more than 70 characters you have
this serious problem in Emacs so let's
go to JavaScript okay javascript ACMA
SPECT okay I'm gonna demonstrate the
long line problem in Emacs so there it
is standard Ahmed 262 a comma 262 is the
the name of the standard for JavaScript
the language okay and the language the
the name of the JavaScript language
officially is Ahmed script the
organization that creates this spec is
called ACMA's it's very complicated so
anyway so we have now Ahmed script 2018
language spec okay now there's a HTML
edition let's open it now this file is
like six megabytes okay
now that it takes a while to load it's
still loading so meanwhile it let me
read some comments so
good point about wrapping lights we take
it for granted am Anderson I saw her
knickers Finch - ch excellent point
about commenting with you thought and
value about commenting with you thought
and value okay oh go say Sikes ah do you
like do you like ultimate hacking
keyboard yes I do it's a great keyboard
okay this page is still loading okay
okay ultimate hacking keyboard if you
guys don't know let's give them a plug
you know they sent me a copy for review
and I did review it I have a video of it
and it's a great keyboard I talked about
this quite a few times and in fact
yesterday there's a video the whole hour
is about keyboards so you might check it
out so isn't Google+ dead yes
Finch says I actually realized that I
hadn't given much thought myself okay so
so let's let's go back to this way this
is still loading come on so anyway this
is the ACMA script you know the
JavaScript standard let's try to save it
let's save this file okay
let's save it as okay I want to xxx
okay so let's save it as X it's it's not
xx because that's as connotation to it
it's because but I back on a second okay
now it's finally finished loading so
let's save it as TD T okay save it you
know save the whole file then I'm going
to go to my download folder
but and actually I don't want to show
the directory so okay let's go to San
talk show page and let's magnify so
let's put it
possible topics so let's put it here
okay
so I have a command that actually just
do it for me yeah so actually I have to
go to the download directory but you
know I don't want to show my download
directory but who knows what's there
because downloads X X T G ok let's let's
so let's page down ok so actually it's
page down let's go down ok
now you start and let's go down you know
it doesn't work anymore wait it still
works ok let's go down but basically
what happens what happens right now
maybe oh it will happen like right now
I'm stuck um you know I'm trying to
scroll down and it's not going a max has
a problem with long lines when you when
you have a line that's very long ok
Emacs becomes extremely slow how slow it
becomes to be ending how long is your
line so if you have a line that's few
thousand characters such as this file
which is very common you'll find long
lines like this very common in today's
web you know front end you know HTML
pages or CSS it's you know because they
put everything one long line without
space when possible and with our new
line line break character so that they
save you know they save the file size so
so now I'm like stuck let's see
like let's describe key let's see
I'm surprised thank you I can call the
command core command because normally a
command will not work neither like you
cannot even call command you know okay
actually it's still working
Wow so let's page down page down okay
yeah so depends on where the kusa are so
the cruiser if the cruiser is at line
the line that's you know a few thousand
characters into the line the most low it
becomes so right now it it froze you
know I'm trying to page down so oh it
still wins its page down one more no it
works but yesterday you know so so this
is a major problem you know yesterday I
spent 30 minutes to work this file so
what can you do there's like nothing you
can do
yeah so we are few pages into this long
line let's let's get done so so that is
a problem so so when you have a file
like this it's impossible you cannot
walk with it in Emacs so what you have
to do is that you have to actually
replace you know remove these long lines
like like you know we place so that when
there for example when there's a comma
this is JavaScript in this coma you
replace it by coma new line so you know
but however to do that in Emacs is
impossible because every every keystroke
you you type your take you know one
minute to update the screen so you have
to write you know use another script
what's going on
suddenly went to the top for some reason
but anyway you have to use another
script what
you have to use another script - let's
close it let's close it you have to use
another script find/replace script - you
know - to remove the long lines to cut
up the long lines then then you can work
with the Emacs so right now I just I
just try to kill the buffer it's not
okay finally it's done it's cute okay so
so that is the problem you know so why
so you know imagine the text editor
cannot deal with long lines you know so
we have a lot a max fans they are like
like us you know we say you Max is great
this or that but you cannot deal with no
nice I mean that's that's a major issue
then we have Emacs tab in Emacs deaf
community we refuse you know who refuse
to say you know who deny that Emacs has
this problem and one of the guy is is
this guy
le you know he's he's probably the guy
who most Emacs users or developers has
problem with he always he always writes
the most contrary opinions like like
everyone something everyone believes he
doesn't believe but anyway yeah he is
that he's a guy who who deny who kind of
denied this this Emacs has this long
line problem because you can give you
such reddit okay you search his name and
my name you know Eddie the risky and
sorry you so traded you'll find the post
you know he he tonight everything you
say it did not know him access I have
this problem
oh that's because you didn't disorder
that incredible flux by the way he's
he's one of the main Emacs developer
okay he's been using Emacs for like in
30 years or something and he's one of
the his
you know he's probably the topmost the
Emax the developer today you know in
terms of you know how many code you've
done contributed to you next one of the
top let's say the top ten you know so so
we so you cannot like I cannot like
whenever you frame him you run into
issues because he's actually a great
country buta you know in terms of
contributing but he's got problems you
know he's you know he he always denied
all the problems eMac have you know so
this is this is the issue because then
Emacs do not progress you know because
every editors like like we are in the
Emacs community we love Emacs all day
and night that's fine but once you go
outside you know Emacs users are very
small compared to all the in the real
world you know look at the real world
Emacs users are like 1% of all the
programmers probably less okay and then
then you you look at vs coders or you
know atom users or they laugh at the EAD
max editor you cannot open a file that
has long lines you know this extremely
stupid okay so if you are a Mac user you
have to spread this this is because this
is true that this is this kind of things
is what hums Emacs it stagnates the
progress of emails and okay back to my
topic so so Emacs is is this way because
of the idea the deep deeply seeded idea
by the UNIX you know people that lines
should not be more than you know 70 or
80 characters because of that you know
tune internet you know it's been
generations you know 20 years 30 years
you know programmers has been fed that
that idea so so basically if you look at
all the source code out there they
always cut you know programmers are you
know taught you know to to truncate
their lines so you don't you do not run
into files
has long lines you know that is why you
know so yeah Emacs you know has this
problem you know but not today because
things to improve slowly even with your
your garbage UNIX philosophy you know
Perl you know programmers is lazy is a
good you know aspect of programming
something like that you know slogans
chance this Voodoo's these patterns you
know patterns programming or you know
something something injection all the
Audis scrap at you know extreme
programming all this crap they they
thrive for a period of time then they
die off no today in order in slogans and
concept you know that there are more
than one way to do it from Perl which
you know for for 10 years you know for a
period of 10 years that's spread by
every programmer they disappeared you
know then the the UNIX philosophy you
know small it's beautiful and all that
crap they disappeared you don't hear it
you know every day we still talk about
it you know because you know we guys are
thinking from this niche group but on
the average you know you you go to
hacker news you don't see that much
anymore you know it's like that's also
dead
so this voodoo in patterns programming
patterns anti patterns well you know
through our two-year mm that's hugely
popular every programmers is like oh you
should do this pattern that that pattern
you know do this this or that that that
also passed away you don't hear about
patterns much anymore but today's got
new things
today's things which we you know I may
talk about but anyway so that is the
issue with the long lines I think that
let's go back to startup show that that
kind of concludes my talk about that
issue the long lines problem you know
this know like Rob well I have like you
know so let's close this
you know I have you know it's tens of
articles about that you know I can like
go on about because there are many
issues to it there is many like this
article some of them are practical like
they tell you they teach you something
in emacs how to rap lies you know how to
toggle what rap how to how to create a
margin well the code changed it no
longer uses margin now but anyway so
some of these articles are tips about
related to long long lines and you have
visual line smart okay and in Emacs so
let's see okay so and in some of them
are rents but anyway so that should be
about it for that topic so but this one
is a rant from 2002 because UNIX you
know they because over there code you
know cannot deal with long lines so they
created this so-called RFC so RFC if you
don't know is comparable to today's
language spec standard you know like
html5 you know from this what the
you know group of w3c or the JavaScript
egg mass spec or you know the you know
so IFC is back thing is you know one of
the standards you know supposed to you
know deemed to be the good guys from the
programmer idiots
so UNIX you know so they wrote RFC so
they in RFC email about email protocol
for example they they tell they say that
email you should lunch should not be
more than 80 characters you know so they
they kind of enforce it to other to all
the other you know protocol so at Apple
or Microsoft so that was so today you
would call
this history it's a piece of history you
know and the guy who pushed for
truncating lines in this guy Tom
Kristensen he is a very famous extremely
well-known every it is like every
program must know him back in 1990s and
in early 2000s ok he's a pro programmer
so he's he's spread you know he he
actively tell people to truncate lies
like like like he wrote programs you
know to automatically find posts that
that does not truncate lines and then he
frame people you know he's one of those
you know today you you might call it a
troll or some something but he
disappeared you know he died along with
Perl many of the very popular Perl
programmers they they like they are not
talking anymore you don't see them
anymore he stopped you know being very
active since around maybe 2010 or before
and he's like 56 year old 56 that's not
too old so so I don't know what he's up
to but he but he is one of the most part
you know most famous celebrity
programmers celebrity back in you know
late 1990s and early 2000s so so these
are about programming fashion you know
so they come and go and today by the way
today I discovered a new thing today
let's go to programming blog I
discovered a new thing which I'm about
to I'm going to read basically this
article says that the if statement
basically they they they it's like if
statement considered harmful so they
they want to push a new way I mean they
kind of talking about you know how you
should not write many if statements I
think it's crap okay in some way they
make sense
it's the the thing they say is fairly
complicated so I haven't actually you
know go into detail yet but I can you
know I can tell by the way it's it's
it's another you know it's like a new
idiom the idiotic fad fashioned by these
programmers and they you know and the
thing is about this Alico is that it's
hip you know the word is hip like it's
you know I just saw a hack a new spot
post on Twitter so you know all the
programmers start to read it and they
talk about it oh oh yeah this is then
they they start to tell other
programmers you should you know this you
know he's wrong you should do it this
way ok that's for that let's go back to
read the comments yes white space smart
yeah that's one of the Emacs mod taneli
to be fair niobium doesn't deal with
this well either oni whole thing doesn't
you mean niobium has problems with long
lines long lines that's surprising
because we we I does not have a problem
with that as far as I know
both are usable in a gpu-accelerated
terminal emulator which probably would
be the solution to the problem about
about files with long lines I don't
think that's the issue I think the issue
is is primarily primarily due to how the
editor is coded I think that is the
issue it's it doesn't really require GPU
accelerated you know things so how long
have I been talking so let's see 15
minutes so what's up so maybe that that
concludes one topic from today's talk
show today any any questions and any
comments any new things type it so
Victor says have you heard of cat V
website no what is that cat V
hello
cat V oak random contrarian contrarian
insurgent organization
so let's magnify so Kathy or Grandin
contrarian in such an organization the
internet is not for sissies okay so what
is that site about
okay it's a site like considered you
know parable by Google because if that's
a case I don't want to you know link it
because you know Google these days
YouTube is spending things so if it's
you know if the website is out there you
know
don't engage people no anyway by the way
you know can't be whoever you are
interested you can just go to can't we
you know you
you'll see in the website so let's talk
about maybe I'll show you one more thing
about the idioms well that's another
topic so maybe that's it for today so
what's what's up guys so anything else
ask me questions questions so you yeah
maybe you have 10 seconds to post
questions
oh so it's a bunch of people who who add
idolize UNIX philosophy okay so it's
magnified
Wow okay that's
yeah well that's a lot to read no so
colon colon is great I like : harmful
software page so home for software har
in this one
anyway you know these kind of things are
getting old because I know okay I don't
know what what this website is about so
I take your word for it
that oh I take your word for it that is
kind of for you know it's trying to
uphold the idea of UNIX philosophy kind
of thing you know but to to me I you
know it's not it's its niche okay it's
not worthwhile to go to you know because
you know realized like today we are into
AI technology you know other people
young people the generation I'm talking
about machine learning or other AIS
machine learning is kind of in a fashion
you know fad okay because machine
learning or neural networks is one of
the method of doing artificial
intelligence okay as opposed to the
other you know ways so called symbolic
AI which kind of fell out of fashion now
I'm rather more interested in symbolic
AI because machine learning and neural
networks lead they don't teach you
anything on the other hand the symbolic
AI is more of like math oriented you
have a foundation you have logic you
study the logic ox they are like
statistical methods you know that you
just throw a bunch of huge amount
billions upon billions of data into it
you know and it uses statistics to you
know to decide automatically which way
is the answer so so but for the whole
thing is like you do not learn anything
about it you don't you don't learn any
fears theories about it you don't learn
anything you just saw you know questions
added and it uses patterns like
statistics
I'm past data you know you need periods
upon billions of data then it's spewed
out an answer but you don't know why you
know you have you it's impossible to
learn anything you know you can't you
cannot learn a new theory from it you
know nothing like that
for example playing go OK you can today
it can beat any world champion of go
player but however it cannot tell you
like what are some theories about go it
can't you know on the other hand if you
have the symbolic based AI approach if
it's successful you know you it can tell
you what are some new theorems and you
know you can tell you why you know a
certain move are good you know because
you know things like that so you know so
what we as I'm saying is that you know
so as technology advanced advances in
science you know they are advancing
exponentially that means you know it we
are at the point that we cannot possibly
keep up you know even we cannot possibly
even know what is going on what are the
new things like we don't even know what
our new programming language is like you
cannot keep you cannot keep up you
cannot know what our new programming
languages what our new protocols what
our new fields for example a new field
in programming is we have block chains
block chains is kind of new technology
you know and if you haven't studied it
you know then block block chains itself
is like this huge things going on there
you know so in all the sciences and you
don't even know math you don't know
physics you know all the sciences they
they grow exponentially so even as a
programmer you don't know you know
what's going on in gaming you know the
techniques you know the advances you
don't know you not even knowing a bit
because that's the nature of exponential
growth so we are at this stage of
society and then we have this website
you know I suppose it's like
old fashioned you know going back to the
UNIX philosophy which is about you know
telling you about how you should think
about how you program things things like
that you know it's like it's kind of in
terms of effectiveness and in terms it's
kind of becoming a CD it's not you know
I don't you know I don't think it's
worth your time to and by the way this
is just one of them right there there
are a lot other you know approach kind
of things then and by the way the UNIX
the whole thing about UNIX philosophy is
that this is not science is this zero
scientific basis it's more like the you
know the what what you would call the
law of hackers you know it's kind of a
code
it's kind of a community you know it's
just a belief certain beliefs you know
it's like a code this zero scientific
basis that's what it is you know on the
other hand they are quite a few science
scientific based programming paradigms
in you know methodology where for
example there's a well-known book code
complete which is one of the early days
where you actually use statistics to
talk about you know software size how it
affects people how it affect design you
know you actually measure you know you
use statistics to measure all the
software their size there and what it
what happens you know a variable name
size you know things like that to study
so you that is one of the approach of a
scientific basis for software
methodology okay or you can say
philosophy where how you you know as a
programmer how you should think or code
you know or idioms watch idioms should
be good you know and things like that
UNIX philosophy is not you know it's a
it's not in any way a scientific based
one that that's why I think it's very
bad
me men take so Tinelli says computer are
by nature manic mimetic field and it
will take hundred years for people to
learn I'm not familiar with that phrase
pneumatic feel what does I mean memetics
I think some of these are you know they
are Voodoo's these memetics okay
memetics also referred to colloquially
as me me me ology okay pneumatics is the
study of information and culture based
on an analogy with Darwinian evolution
proponents describe pneumatics as an
approach to evolutionary models of
cultural information transfer critics
critics regard pneumatics
as pseudoscience medics yeah I think
it's pseudoscience I can I can I can I
judge just by the word memetics and you
know what it is about evolution approach
to evolution evolutionary models of
cultural information transfer what the
is the information transfer is it
pseudoscience ok it's it's it's like
mini it's like I would say it's like
UNIX philosophy it's kind of like what
is thing first of all evolutionary
biology you know they don't even mention
evolution by biology but it's a
evolutionary models you know you know
it's like from hard science to less hard
science through less and less hard
science to listen in less less a science
that's what these things are about you
know first of all evolutionary biology
is is kind of it's not hardcore science
ok it's like psychology
you know then then you know so let me
read some more comments and and that'll
be it for today let's see
okay you know it's just a bunch of
people my showing that okay
oh so Murr says so Tong Mercier's
thoughts on programming paradigm
functional versus imperative so and and
it links to one of my article okay so
this article let's see how long I've
been talking okay maybe ten more minutes
in and that'll be it for today okay so
anyway so so I have this article so what
is the question
thoughts on programming problems
functional okay I'm I'm gonna quickly go
over this article functional programming
is real-world stateful okay this is this
Arco is a is my reaction when reading
rich Hickey the designer of closure
he's a bunch of lectures and essays
about about functional programming
actually he still is that he he created
closure one of the primary reason is
that he is for concurrent programming
okay so his design of closure is
primarily the impetus okay that the
major thing he wants to tackle he wants
to solve his concurrency that is the
primary kind of thing in of closure
closure but if you don't know closure is
a lisp based language that is
implemented on top of java java virtual
machine okay i have actually studied
closure for like full time for a year
and i have a tutorial that that is
incomplete but i did a project for this
great guy David David
I can't remember his name but anyway the
David guy what's his last name
he is a you know if you call Java and in
Java community Java let me actually talk
through this okay Java framework there
is one Java framework Java web framework
that's extremely popular okay and that
is created by him
David David something 100 best Java
frameworks okay so let's look at does
anyone know one actually one of the most
popular Java web framework in Java is
created by him David something so let's
see it's not spring it's not JSF it's
not struts it's not HIPAA Nate it's not
free
what where's no wicked no yeah it's not
here
it's odd
well there are a lot Java frameworks now
does anyone know okay let's just repeat
that's just you know these websites they
all copy each other busy CAC okay I
remember David busy cat he is also a I
think co-author visi Karthik he's an old
guy
busy
I cannot find his name but VC like maybe
this one busy guy
Hey Ibaka Dory's
yeah this guy okay now he is a great guy
okay he is a TPP he goes his handle is
DPP okay and damn I want to get to him
okay so let's go to him David
click doesn't work how long I been
talking the rainbow of death okay so
let's go back here so anyone of you code
Java it doesn't come out it okay so I
want to go through this guy's name but
somehow knew it
David Pollock that's a guy okay
David Pollock now he is a old B okay
he's been programming for maybe forty
years or thirty forty years okay and he
helped me financially greatly few years
ago so you know I want to thank him
so David Pollock he is also a creator of
this Java extremely popular Java
framework let's search for it
lift okay so he created the lift
framework for Java
okay I think it was the most popular
framework but somehow it's not mentioned
in these you know
new websites but anyway lifts so he's a
you know you know well-known program one
of the great programmer and he so why
are we mentioning he came there's a
reason
oh yeah so he he had me walk out closure
for some closure project so that's how I
learned closure so I walked on closure
for close to four altogether about a
year and so I created I wrote this
tutorial it's not really complete
because I stopped working with closure
so anyway oh yeah so back to closure you
know the David the the the rich Hickey
guy created closure okay and many of his
essays and lectures you know YouTube
lectures he the primary reason he
created is is to solve the concurrency
problem and he kept talking about
he kept talking about States okay so
this article is basically you know in
functional programming you know in first
of all in imperative programming such as
Perl Java JavaScript or P you have
States for example a class a object by
definition is a state you know when you
have an object it has internal variables
you call members of the object or fields
you know divin your language you call a
member or field or a class variable or
you know or instance variable you know
anyway look object basically has
variables inside it you know and those
values can change so the object actually
represents some kind of a state you know
so so on the other hand functional
programming
you don't want States there's no States
so it's always function function
input/output that that is it that is the
pure form of functional programming
programming world everything is just
first of all first of all you have data
values okay that's that's input data you
pass through a function you can think of
a function as a machine then you have
output that is it that is the whole pure
functional model then you take the
output then you have another function
feed out the output as input then you
come out and another result so you just
have all you have to do in a program in
functional programming world is you
define these functions or from libraries
you have functions then you data as
input you just fit input to a bunch of
functions I put up a decent result that
is all there it is that is a pure form
of functional programming all other
things are kind of just consequences in
secondary such as curry being such as
monads such as you know all those fancy
jargons you hear about functional
programming all those all those are
rather secondary the most important
thing is just for
functions do not have state this any
given input it has output and given to
same input it always come out the same
output okay it purely depends on nothing
other than just input the arguments okay
that is a functional programming now so
functional programming do not have
States your data is a state you know the
you know they don't mean you don't do
states so so how does how does basically
the question is how does functional
programming handle concurrency basically
so I wanted his real world stateful I
want to talk about this article but
basically the rich Hickey guy he has a
lot lectures okay and he's talking about
concurrency and he he's saying that he
is saying that a state is just a matter
of time you know it's easy I don't know
what I what I'm I have to actually I
have to be concentrated and actually
prepare to talk about this because right
now I've you know yeah I have to be a
little bit prepared to actually talk
about this thing so let me just read it
then okay in philosophy this - there is
- oh there's a typo there's two opposite
thoughts idealism and materialism
so it's either mind exists only that's
idealism or matters exist only that's
materialism by the way there are many
different schools of idealism also there
are many different variations of
materialism but in a classic philosophy
ok
classic philosophy you have this
idealism and materialism
they are like the opposite now idealism
is that you know you think about the
word like the idealism idealists believe
believe that nothing exists except your
consciousness because you know I have I
have a pen but how do I know it exists
you know I cannot possibly prove they
exist and but they say that the only
thing I can prove to be real is is my
mind you know like I think therefore
exist you know something like that
that's that's you know the only thing I
can possibly believe is true is my mind
because how do I know the pen do not
yeah I mean they say I cannot prove the
pen exists because how do I know I'm
dreaming because if you are dreaming you
know although it's so real but you can
either but it's actually not be oh oh
you know in a matrix movie how do I know
I'm not living a matrix you know maybe
I'm just a computer program you know I
you know but there is one thing I know
like I can prove you know according to
idealist is that my my consciousness my
thoughts oh I have this mind that that
is real okay that's that's that's the
basics of idealist idealism meanwhile
materialism thinks that nothing exists
is except actual materials you know like
things so your mind is just actually you
know they say you're mine is just it's
just a consequence of you know
neurons and stuff it doesn't actually
exist like for example when when you die
you are gone there's no soul okay so the
real actual real thing that exists is
the physical stuff your body your you
know your blood your the meat you know
in your brain because for example if you
are dead you are good there's no like
the only thing is this is physical stuff
okay so so I say so if you go the ways
of idealism
then the problem is everything becomes
mental a sort of Taoism mumbo-jumbo gets
difficult in the ways of Sciences that
is true I mean that's what I think okay
the idealism is great but then okay but
on the other hand if you go the ways of
materialism then you have a hard time
conceptually conceptualizing the mind
consciousness and can never tell if you
are in a dream yeah that is true and
also that is a problem of AI right now
we have the problem of trying to define
what is artificial intelligence you know
what is strong AI now MST or alive okay
I'm talking too long I think fewer
people are watching so let's go back to
the article then we'll be done so yeah
right now we have a problem in AI which
is how do you define how do you actually
define when AI is here you know there's
a true human test but actually that
doesn't do much you know so it's a
problem and you know if you if you
believe in materialism you know the mind
doesn't exist then you have the issue
with defining you know consciousness
because first of all you don't believe
they they exist actually yesterday I was
I was you know yesterday I was watching
this Luke guy you know a lot a lot of
you guys tells me to watch his channel
so he says yesterday I watched one of
his one of his YouTube video and the
subject is actually interesting to me so
he was talking about the Chinese room
problem let's see Luke
what's his name no not Luke
so what's his name guys MICR talk
talking yeah this is so
Luke Smith yes that's a guy but SMI SMI
th stupid stupid YouTube 3d with this
other comment recommended Luke Smith
this guy okay so he made a video about
Chinese room problem well actually
that's a quite interesting to talk about
such Chinese yeah consciousness
computers in the Chinese room let's see
yeah this video so I was watching it I
have my opinions about it but anyway so
yeah but he's a cute guy so that's why
he's got lot tens of followers by the
way I'm not gay okay if you if you guys
are gay don't come to me I'm not gay
okay
but anyway so he's talking about that so
that issue is about philosophy about
about consciousness okay
and in fact when he mentioned you know
one guy he one guy does does not you
know he mentioned one of the philosopher
or scientist you do not believe
consciousness at all you know and to him
he's like that's kind of strange that's
like odd I don't find that odd actually
you know so so there's a difference
between our opinions about AI probably
because I don't think it's odd to to not
believe consciousness exists okay so
anyways so the issue is about
consciousness so so it traces back to
idealism and materialism you know how do
you and you know one of the question is
how do you define
when AI is you know strong AI oh you
know when we actually have a machine
that can think you know like today
machine can play chess can beat humans
but we know you know we kind of say oh
but yeah but it's your machine it
doesn't really actually eight know
things but the the issue is when when
can you actually say machine actually
know things because twenty years ago we
think if a machine can play chess speech
humours it's actually intelligent but
now it can but we don't think it's
intelligent you know but at what point
then you can think you know machine
actually you know is smart you know a
like has conscious consciousness and the
the in fact that actually is a unsolved
problem you know we don't know you know
all the scientists you know the physics
the neuron neuron scientists the brain
scientists no philosophers or
mathematicians you know you can computer
scientists you may have your opinions
but the fact is nobody actually can have
an answer that everyone agrees you know
we don't know when you know we don't
know how to define consciousness in fact
consciousness itself is a question like
what like we don't know what it is and
you know so that that is the issue so so
back to this article so I'm saying we
would say we would intuitively think the
word is one word with States but if
functions you have parallel universe ie
parallel programming okay yeah that's
the issue yeah so intuitively we think
the way we think that you know when you
know a lot articles when they talk about
programming we talk about state you know
state machines especially opie and so on
you know you you want to model States
for example you go to a bank
you would deposit $100 there's a spate
because it holds a variable you know the
state is 100 then you you you you want
to we throw $200 so now it's negative
$100 that's a state now if if you have
another person you know who also go to
your bank for example your family shared
bank you know he also withdraw $100 so
you tip has a 100 he withdraw let's say
100 there's a there's a concurrency
problem because the bank has no who did
it first you know but if you have if you
run two programs at the same time it's
it's hard to know you have the issue of
concurrency it's hard to know which one
is actually you know control the state
you know you have what's so-called
what's a race race problem okay because
if you want your program to actually run
in parallel which we do want because
that that means you can run programs
much faster on different CPUs but if you
do that then you have this bank account
race issue you know problem who who has
cut the control of the state because
only one only one thing can control it
at a time you know
then you have maybe you have a key then
that's no longer parallel so you have
this concurrency programming problem so
so a lot of people most people think of
as a state okay like like time time is
linear you know you know time is linear
it at one point you know this process
holds the state and you know things like
that the state changes over time but
however rich Hickey I don't think you
know he stuck his lectures is kind of
hard to understand and closure the
language is also when it comes to
concurrency closure
the language is kind of very hard to
understand as opposed to goal and
Colin's model of doing where
Colin's method of doing concurrency is
very simple and great you can understand
within you know 10 10 minutes like what
1 hour but closure it's like you spend
days and you don't understand what what
it is trying to do you know what is what
it is uh it is you know the way it's
trying to do concurrency well anyway so
rich Hickey in his talk Sita he often
talks about something I don't quite
understand but I think but in one way it
comes down to you can think of state in
real world as parallel worlds that's
kind of the way he is thinking so
instead of this you know one word where
you have time time is linear and things
change so you have states that changes
on your hand which Vicki he he kind of
think think of a waters parallel words
so so states do not change instead of
you have you know different words you
have different states in each would I
think that's the way he thinks so that's
why I wrote this article talking about
that anyway that's it for today I kind
of dragged down so so anything else yeah
I think that's it for today I don't know
if I answered your question
avocado Russ but ok so see you guys bye