good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sod talk show
and I'm sorry hold on a second because I
got all these stupid things going on
okay so today we're gonna talk about
actually over here and you can see okay
so yesterday actually I want to do this
oh no second yeah that's good so
so hi guys so today I'm going so
yesterday I did a talk show with I
chatted with Israel of Emax expert and
we and it turns out my audio is
extremely bad I'm sorry about that
yeah and so you know the audio is
extremely bad because because I haven't
you know figure out how OBS works you
know I need to read the manual okay
that's one thing then the other thing is
okay so this guy so this is guy who
showed me this page let me show you guys
so it's a font so this is he created I
found like that and you know you can you
can set to this fund and you have that
follow is text for screen readers in
search engines you know yeah so if you
want you know if you like this you can
you know download the found here it's
open source and let's see let's pop this
out
okay so that's font but there is
something I want to show you yeah
for example let's say San talk show Oh
actually before we do that we need to
update that copy so create a new buffer
paste in our switch window make it that
some start command lock mod okay and
adjust the window now there's this thing
I want to show you okay first of all TV
dad did that and so now shall switch
window put the title here okay
and switch window copy the URL put it
here make a URL link copy it switch to
browser and paste it here so you guys
can see it so anyway so I want to show
you this so you for example I have this
text I select go and call the command MX
gothic so I'll convert Latin alphabet
gothic you see you see these are
actually Unicode you see for example I
put the cursor here and it's magnifier I
put the cursor here
okay for the cursor here and core
describe cha and you can see the code
point is you know this and in
hexadecimal it's one D five three five
and the character name is mathematical
Frankfort small X so that's useful but
you need a font though
so what fund is used okay the font use
is this one but but basically these are
actually unicode characters so it's not
you see okay so these are unicode
characters so this is this is for
example the the folks first character is
not X for example let me do that ABCD
efg okay copy that paste it here and
select this and I call so I'll convert
Latin to alphabet gothic okay and you
got that then you can see and if you
check the first character a described
cha and you can see the character is
9700 point 97 and the name is not and
small letter a however if you put a
character here and you you call this
scribe cha and the code point is
actually this it's not 97 and the
character name is this mathematical
Frank Frank too small a so you see these
and and these are different characters
in other words these are different
characters so when you have this
character this is a character from
Unicode let me show you you can see here
some talk show okay so you go to sorry
unicode and you can see the unicode
characters here and you scroll down you
can see math so on this page i explain
what they are basically unicode created
all these characters that are commonly
used in mathematics so including
mathematical Franko mathematical board
Franco you know quite a few and also
Mathematica mathematical board for
example this character is you know you
got Unicode code point so so this
character is not just simply capital a
it's a different character so you got
all these unicode characters you can
type you know including like the bold
stuff now once you type them for example
you can I can copy them let's see copy
copy go to Emacs go here paste okay
okay so so once you so so these are
unicode characters but to display these
characters you still need the proper
font you still need for example this is
a Unicode character you need a font for
this character so where do you get a
font you can you can get the phone well
you can actually you know if you like
you can use his fund his fund is this
style is New York Times masthead okay I
think I think this fund is a variant of
the variant there's a fund called factor
a very end of this Franco so you can
download his font but alternatively you
go through this page you can see browser
this way blank problem yeah download v
unicode font I believe it's in okay I
think there is a math font called sticks
math fun STI X you can download
I believe it's open source yeah sticks
fonts let's see
okay they are taking a while to load
let's see maybe they need JavaScript on
you see this this website is anyways so
there is this fund you can download so
anyway so this is interesting so the
code is let me let me do this again
ABCD efg you today selected call song
convert latin alphabet to gothic and you
got that and the command let me show you
the command this is a Emacs command it
basically changed the character from
Latin to - this unit through this
Unicode so the code is here you can see
okay so
and the URL is here so you can get it
from my website if you want to use it
it's it's fun you know okay so that's
that's that that's the Emacs command
let's see let's say these
okay let's go back let's see what's the
next night
so I mentioned the font Emacs font a
more Latin - gothic yes and math fonts
yes those are unicode and Emacs demo
okay let's do email another Emacs demo
two more Emacs demo then we're gonna
talk about Google+ hey Duke on home
greetings how are you well York where
are you from like which location what
region what country so okay let's do the
next one
so if you guys have any questions any
opinions just type it okay I like to see
them because it tells me whether I'm
going in the right direction
now let's see how many people watching
three okay good
now is my voice coming out alright yeah
let me let me ask you a question let me
try this okay and tell me if my voice is
coming out all right okay now test test
do you guys can still hear me okay
Scarlett
okay so so did you guys hear me okay
back then you think that go was Scotland
audio is good okay
Scotland 1 p.m. lunchtime I see ok so
right now it's 5 o'clock 5 a.m. here and
Scotland he saw his Scotland is like 7
hours faster okay so that's Emacs let's
see so that's my in Xcode let's go back
to talk show yeah so let's talk about
this HTML link to dead link okay so I
created so I'm gonna do a Emacs demo and
let's move it here so what is - so let's
copy your website URL for example so for
example I copy actually not this page so
for example I copy that page I got back
to Emacs I create a new buffer I switch
to HTML mod I paste a link now let's see
okay HTML okay so I'm creating a HTML
page save it as X X dot HTM how now
opening browser now it looks like that
magnify magnify back to Emacs and I just
I have link here I want to make it into
a link instead of instead of you know
text so I just
I just press two keys and it becomes a
link showing browser you see now it
becomes a link back to Emacs and make it
a paragraph showing browser so that is a
command in the command name is actually
that's not the one I want to show but
let's go to my Emacs blog if you open
the file my Emacs block and you can see
here is the code this code will turn any
text like that into a HTML link with the
date the link is added you know data
exists you know and today's date so that
is a example that is the command and if
you know if you write HTML you might use
it so the code is here it's all
independent I mean that this is the code
all you need and also this is a great
snippet of code to learn Emacs Lisp so
you know you know you can use it now
once you have a link let me show you
let's go back now you see we have a link
here right now when you are reading
blogs you have you know after a few
years you have hundreds of links now
some of the links go bad let me so for
example so we have a link here it's copy
and paste it here and you know suppose
okay look
suppose you know the link is dead and
what you want to do is you want to
change the link into let me do it let me
show you okay you encode a command
hmmm a clink defunct okay hinter it
becomes like that and showing browser
you see it has a line across okay but
the line is pretty bad
okay the line this is okay let's try
this
it's let's try this okay yes no sir echo
instead attack yes sure okay yeah this
is not good because you see the S tag is
a strikethrough it means strikethrough
and but on the page is somehow it's like
too low
let's copy the path it's showing Chrome
browser and see what happened yeah this
is better okay so it's a Firefox but
then Jesus I cannot believe it a Firefox
bug you see
yeah so you guys see what I mean we just
run into a Firefox bug it's impossible
these days you know you know anyway so
so what I wanted to do was you know when
you write blogs you have lots of links
sometimes when link went dead you want
to change them into you know you know
strikethrough and a handy command is is
what I just caught and the code is let
me show you the code okay in a way let's
show the message buffer okay Q so Q so
here's the code
besides Jimmy I make link defunct and
and here's the UI you can go to the URL
so here's the code wait that's not the
code okay so I actually I need to change
something in my code because because the
make link define defunct you know used
to be on this page but however today I
just created a new page I moved it to a
new page so the code is actually here
it's shimmering to depth think hey
Israel
Firefox bug impossible is Israel so yes
I was talking to Israel yesterday and
the audio is pretty bad yeah sorry about
that we need to fix that and you know
then I think maybe we do another one
you know like in two weeks or something
so
so link dead okay so that's what we're
gonna do is finish let's just fix that
so okay so anyway so let's see it's try
another one so for example copy a link
here back to Emacs paste a link make it
wait make it a link and I want my own
website let's go to this website okay
this this is a beautiful architecture
and this this this place is in this
country I just I kind of just discovered
Kazakh umm Qasr stuff and it's this
country is pretty big
you know like between Russia and China
Duncan says nice when text markup
language provides strikethrough
in addition to the useful bold and
italic yeah okay I want to actually come
here link so actually this okay this
keyboard is interesting I just
discovered a few days ago and you see
because this is the it's this this is
like a dream keyboard you know imagine
you have two of these one for each hand
you know you can have all the keys you
can have them you know they are you know
one hand each each and they are inclined
and then you the the thing about this
one is it's got all these knobs
you know these wheels you can control
volume you know for 100 you can control
the other one for page up and down you
know you just rotate it yo you know I
think this would be great the idea like
that but anyway let's copy the link so
copy the link here so we can link show
browser okay back link if I make a
paragraph showing browser okay now okay
now I discover the link is there now
let's just put a cruiser there q okay a
change to that showing browser so its
course out now let's go to the location
of the file open it so you see I had so
so here is the code to make a link
different and the URL here is wrong
because I just discovered this is the
correct URL so copy that paste it here
copy paste you see you see
so this one is wrong delete it and
that's good and actually I should make a
commit of this file so let's do you know
it's a good opportunity to show to demo
the magic mod Israel say is expensive
mechanical yeah it's mechanical I'm yeah
I'm pretty sure but oh what u.s. 252 576
very expensive yeah the Aliexpress I
think that Express is is is from China I
think oh but however all the text here
is Japanese so do they do they actually
deliver to USA I'm not sure I don't read
Japanese you know so but yeah
hey Green Tech come on in quintet
quintic is in you know that this
cuttlebug place you can change the
language oh ok so where does it say I
don't think I have JavaScript on its
turn JavaScript on ok
he's like the country you want to ship
from United States
now
it's very popular in Russia what what is
very popular in Russia from China Oh Oh
Ally Oh Aliexpress is from China and it
is very popular in Russia oh I didn't
know so they deliver to Russia your URL
start with J a oh okay yeah but if we
change that okay I'm not sure you walk
by because we kind of to guess I think
let's just try it I just go to J yeah
maybe they do have okay go to the global
website English yeah there it is okay so
USB PR editing all their screen custom
keyboard dream premiere final coalesce
all those are keywords [ __ ] by now and
to cut its kind of too expensive for me
but also I got you know like I'm happy
with the Kinesis so you know so I think
you know this is truly a great idea
I really think so because big you know
because specifically because all these
knobs you know very employers the
rotational cylinders and stuff the these
rotational knobs devices they are they
are the most fitting input physical
input mechanism for anything that
requires that has a direction like
forward and reverse you know forward
backward word previous tab next tab
previous tab previous page you know next
page you know browser forward you
so in page up and page down lying up
lying down or Cuza right
who's left you know so there are these
pairs of commands that you that that are
used often you know page your pitch down
kusa left
cruiser right kusa of cruiser down so
they are all paired and in different
direction and and I found that for these
kind of operations the most that the
most fitting device is some kind of
wheel because with a wheel you can
control the speed you want to go into a
direction you can like you can control
the continuous variable instantaneous
speed you know meaning that you can
change the speed any instance in time
you know you know like wheel like if you
do it video editing you know you know
you have chalk where those are extremely
useful if you don't have that wheel
they insert pain so in a similar way
mask we owe it it kinds of mouse wheel
works the same same way but the problem
is that with even programmable Mouse's
you cannot control the function with a
wheel it's very it's very hard he is
almost impossible I mean you cannot set
the wheel to to do things like for
example cruising right well you can't
but the thing is if you you only have
one wheel you know if you change it to
something else then you don't have screw
up and screw it down anymore so so
that's the issue but anyway so anyway so
the video is the most fitting you know
physical device for for any command
that's you know paired up and down left
and right so this is great I think and
yeah so
but I mean if I were actually using
these or you know use you know design it
I probably would have just some of the
position so you know yeah anyway so
let's let's go back to yeah let's go
back to Manchester so how long we've
been going 30 minutes that's good
so this is my HTML mod first of all I
need to change the date version number
usually you know usually what I do is I
use the version I started to use the
version the last part was kind of a date
stamp for example today's let me type
that control you control you the insert
date signs the date choice number two so
this is 2019 April 3rd five o'clock 34
minutes 40 seconds so I just remove that
that's old one so let's go through the
previous position okay copy that
so I call magic status I need to you
know update so it says so it modified
yes so I'm gonna save it stage for
change see for commit paste fixed URL
okay
control C control C okay now it's
committed now capital P P push
okay now it's pushed to my github okay
that's good so that's that's that for
these function and so you you know you
got this URL you can you can get a code
for my website as well so because that
cause that what is this we don't care
cuz I you know it's knowing that that
magic left these these buffers you know
before the buffer name start with a
asterisk sign you know before the buffer
name looks like that but since about a
year ago you know in Emacs when you have
a buffer whose name start with a
asterisk
it means the buffer is created by Emacs
usually is some kind of temporary you
know like messages log and so on so
match it used to have this you know
buffers name starting with the asterisk
but about a year ago they changed so
it's very annoying it's annoying because
I start to see them because usually my
switch buffer like I'm using this
command you can you can look at the left
panel panel you see exam
next use above some previous user buffer
what what it does is that it skips or
Emacs buffers
you know like messages in logs in stuff
but
but now since the magic buffer
doesn't have the star sign so it becomes
it's it becomes like a user buffer so
it's kind of annoying so anyway so
that's that's the two commands Emacs
demo URL to link and link to strikeout
okay Google first let's talk about
Google first maybe so any any anything
any questions anything interesting
okay let's talk about Google+ Google the
evil empire so Google let's go to like
confirming blog Google just shut down
officially today so if you go good to go
Google first you cannot you know all the
website he's done so they began Google+
speaking in 2011 and I so I just changed
679 links in Google has changed them to
you know dead link so for example let's
go let's fine okay let's search for
first start Google calm okay
such undock sorry info okay so I changed
all the links to dead link and you know
so now you can see closure miscellaneous
let's see what it is so this is closure
code let's look at the page this page is
working process okay few years ago I was
working with crochet you know I say and
I wrote this bunch of tutorials
so anyway so OSHA Google first is okay
so there is actually something I'm
discussion
okay let's okay that oh yeah so this is
rich Hickey you know he created closure
so anyway let's not go into that let's
let's get back to the Google+ issue so
if you know let me know how am i doing
okay just say something you know if you
wanna if I'm talking about Google+ or
something else you like to see but what
am i doing a closure protocol okay let's
look at this one yeah this would be
interesting [ __ ] this is another paging
part progress it's it's it's difficult
to write tutorial but anyway closure the
language actually has a what it calls
the protocol actually it's just like you
know the you know how javascript has has
Jason you know like Jason you know the
format which is you know becomes
universal today but it was basically
just JavaScript syntax so closure you
know the guy rich Hickey
they he also created version basically
you know just like the Chasen of
javascript so he created a format that
is intended to be you know used you know
be a universal some kind of format and
enclosure syntax
wait no no sorry I got confused with
something else
okay Google first looks looked cool but
turned out to be useless yeah let's go
back to Google person Google press yeah
did it's one huge chapter of greed you
know I would mark Google first began in
2011 and I would mark that as the date
when Google became evil so let's go back
to some word huh
okay so Google Google became in 2011 and
so there is this you can see you know so
I have this page and there's this girl
let's go troops
let's go through over here so Duncan
says I know you like visualizations
wondering why you don't seem to have
gotten into web WebGL with JavaScript I
love to but I the the the the thing
about OpenGL or something something Glu
know that technology that's the
technology I hated that because that is
very low level you know every time it's
like okay it's like when you want to
draw a cube okay or cube let's say it's
just a cube that's all you know one two
three four five six seven eight how many
lines is a cube you know just like
twelve lines or something a cube that's
suppose that's what you want to draw now
in Mathematica it's just one single line
okay so let me show you how how it is in
Mathematica so you just say cube okay
let's magnify magnify actually
so cubes zero zero zero okay and let's
say hold on okay so this is actually a
mathematical code this represents a cube
with the opposite corner from 0 0 0 to 1
1 1 okay and this this is like a
primitive you know and if you want to
display it you do it like this graphics
3d copy that and so so that represents
the graphics and in these graphics you
have one cube you know and but but but
this does not display it yet you want to
display it you know on your screen then
what you do is you have display graphics
okay and that so if you put this in
Mathematica he will show you a cube and
if you want to rotate it in real time
you say something like manipulate okay
manipulate that then a second parameter
something like something like view angle
something like 0 to 360 degrees okay 0
is a variable it should be somewhere
here okay let me let me try it then this
very graphics graphics 3d
reveal angle okay so and here is a point
in space which is basically angle I mean
where you want to view at and let's say
1020 degrees just some number okay so
this is a point where you are looking at
the or engine okay so let me let me okay
so I don't have intent here I'm trying
to get the intent right okay
okay it's something like that then wait
okay so you see here's how you display a
you know real-time rotation of a cube
and let's say this is X okay in
Mathematica that's it now but in OpenGL
in we're in open G oh it's gonna be 1000
lines decorative three lines versus
super imperative yeah exactly I you know
it's like back back in 1990s you know
it's like you know I learned okay all
these are related tied to how I hate C
and C++ in UNIX those those [ __ ] all
these are tied to that too because you
know for my experience okay I came from
a math background so you know
programming is great I love it I start
to learn it you know but every step I
learn I encounter this this this this
was [ __ ]
technology like hack incomprehensible
and extremely convoluted unnecessarily
so that is see you know this is kind of
like that anyway so I'm interested in
visualization you know math graphics so
so I heard okay you got this company
SGI okay SGI
okay we we digressed from the Google
Plus but that's that's good so you know
there used to be this company SGI which
is the most famous company for computer
graphics you know so they have their
logo looks like that and this is
actually a real sculpture I went there
and took the photo down the street but
the company is gone you know the company
is gone like 10 years ago but anyway
back in 1990s is it
it is the the most famous company in the
biggest company for computer graphics
for example alias wave you know many 3d
modeling a Jurassic Park for example is
is created in the 1990s by by their
company but you know special effects
anyway so I am interested in graphics so
I you know so I learned about SGI they
are very famous you know I love it you
know and I I start to learn their
technology so one of the technology they
have is the the GL it was it wasn't
called OpenGL before when you have
OpenGL
the SGI company already kind of went bad
you know already so you know so anyway
opengl you know I'm interested so I try
to learn it it's extremely complex you
know very extremely low-level and then
you know I learned power of gaming you
know all the gamers are excited about
gaming technologies can can you know the
then you start to learn you know studied
the game programming stuff you know
their graphics pipelines and stuff
[ __ ] you know it's just the bunch of
[ __ ] why is it that way
this one reason speed they need the
speed that is the one and only one
reason but however it's like okay it's
not like just yeah we need speed so
therefore let's try to design a system
so that it's fast it's not just like
that if it's like that I'm totally fine
but they but it's like we sacrifice
everything and anything as much as
possible to get the fastest speed
possible if that's like see you know
that's what see does it say unix unix in
seefox let's see
so I don't know what's you guys
background and experience I suppose many
of you you know see is the one of the
very popular language and and among
hackers so you know I think many of you
find my opinion kind of weird and
disagree okay introduction you look at
this this these facts you know they copy
my page they copy my page in it says
sauce a chicken our introduction to 3d
graphics programming yeah but don't we
just copied my page and what is this
quote base you had another [ __ ] [ __ ]
rocks our resume great
so anyway I have actually written an
article about how you know you see so
these are 3d modeling software I have
always been fascinated by them but I
actually never I tried to learn them but
never right I never got gotten into so
there's guitars and but you know I'm
just I'm very much fascinated by these
3d graphics play anyway
okay surfaces we don't want that cuz cuz
okay this this is a great article I mean
this is this article is got serious
stuff this I wrote in 2004 yeah so
because that close that
logos of Sofia industry
this page is about logo design but there
is say anyway I got an article about it
should be here let me just find it then
semantic noodle search for graphics yeah
I don't know where it is but yeah take
awhile to find it yeah so OpenGL is
extremely low level and actually I want
to talk about that because there is a
sign sorry whole Pangea
there it is this one graphics
programming pains you know okay this is
not even oh yeah yeah this this article
I wrote in 2007 because I'm just very
frustrated every time I it begins I have
a problem I want to do 3d geometry
visualization programming but there is
no appropriate tools oh [ __ ] the
industry you know let me tell you let me
tell you a story okay I want to write a
GUI you know GUI you know like menus
tabs we know windows now in Java you got
this fact is this Java comics swim you
know this is incomprehensible [ __ ] like
three four five thousand five hundred
lines what did what they do they do
nothing
five hundred lines just to you know just
just to begin to have a GUI kind of the
very basic nothing actually this code
demonstrate creating a GUI app with a
menu bar and two menus okay each having
a few items but no actions 509 you know
so the the question is you know how do
you imagine you know is it really
necessary
I mean imagine you are designing you
know foreign language and graphic system
this is really I mean to what degree it
is necessary that you end up with
something like this you know Java X swim
you know you know that's what you wanted
to think about it
think about you know in my opinion in a
same way of my opinion with C&C first
first and OpenGL I think they are all
[ __ ] and also you know today you know
how today the web programming is the web
you know hdmi hdmi in java street
script and CSS is extremely convoluted
right that's not even a controversial
point of view that's universally agreed
so but you wonder why is that you know
you wonder why is that a night
today I begin you know this you know in
the past few years I begin to realize
it's always going to be like that yeah
and in the industry and why because
these things are created not by you know
some some nerd you know who sit down in
designing designing a system it's not
that that it's not that what you see in
an industry is the result of different
companies fighting you know to get money
that's that's that's a result that's
what that's why you know like when you
code today you know it seems news bugs
everywhere you know this the the
language is lousy everything that's a
result that's just a result of the you
know the other companies the evolution
of you know the environment and I'm
thinking it's not it's never going to be
clean yeah so anyway so back to these
you know graphics for and so so here's
an example of GUI you know thing you
know you got these 500 lines just just
for empty menu then you have the 3d
programming pain okay so that's about UI
bit but what about geometry
visualization programming the answer is
pretty much OpenGL Mesa 3d direct3d okay
this this this is written back in 2007
now canvas canvas HTML cameras is also
the worst [ __ ] created by Apple you
should have you know the SVG instead
that's yeah that's another topic you
know actually I do have so many topics
canvas versus SVG so here's a article
where I talk about canvas versus SVG
kind of in detail but basically my
opinion is is so you have you can see
comparison canvas in SVG and the code
comparison but but in general my opinion
of cameras is is [ __ ] is it ok canvas is
kind of in the same same mode of
thinking with the opengl ok that's kind
of like that while SVG is the the more
mathematical simple you know the the
kind of design I want to this day we
still don't have a system like that for
3d but people have tried you know let me
let me go back to the article here
people have tried because I'm going to
show you a few old history history of
the 3d ok so anyway this article right
this Arco is my experience of you know
the pain of trying to learn graphics
programming you know mathematically I
understand it you know I know
computational geometry I know
differential geometry I know you know I
know math ok so you are thinking you
know is it because I'm stupid you know
I'm not stupid you know I know math you
know differential geometry you know they
are very difficult topics but then you
get into programming you got this
they are just like the OpenGL Mesa 3d
they are just [ __ ]
they are just crap they are extremely
complex almost for no reason okay you
know it's just like you know you did oh
you know you you know it's like it's
like a mouse you know going around so
anyway so I
okay so I was trying to learn you know
programming 3d you know gaming stuff so
I start to learn you have the graphics
pipeline you have the sing graph you
know sort of the scene graph you know
the space partitioning shade shade of my
ass z-buffering you know it is very
extremely complex bunch of things okay
then but let me get to the anyway to
this day you know I still don't know a
thing about game game engine for example
how do you actually do OpenGL like to
this day I don't know I hope someone can
teach me though you know I always you
know I'm very interested in learning but
when I talk to other nerds or hackers
like most of the time like they are not
interested I mean they suck for some
reason I don't know why they just we
didn't you know a few people think like
me like for example if I know someone
okay you know you know there are some
people on Twitter I know I want to learn
something I can they can teach me okay
they you know because they've been
working on this let's say again writing
your game but however I want to video
you know I want to like it's talking
video because but usually they don't
want to because they they are like not
okay the like they are they think the
way like the typical you know elite
hackers which are I despise okay they
think in that way
why how is that because they when they
when it talks to you know communication
they want they don't want you know video
they want like just type you know to
them you say
oh I don't want video I just let me just
teach you you know they just type it you
know to do this you you do you know you
code this you know they want to type but
there that's that's idiotic
you know because human communication
when you can see face to face you learn
it's ten times more efficient than
typing you know so I mean so I got this
friend
okay online you know so we agreed that
we want we like to each other right and
we want to you know I can teach him
something he can teach me something so
let's get on video then no they were
thinking just don't turned it they you
know partly it has to do you know with
privacy and party has to do you know
maybe you don't you feel nervous I mean
I I do too you know I'm a nerd you know
I don't you know I don't feel so ready
to show my face but but anyway so so
there's this frustration yeah with many
of the you know nerd programmers I was
talking about
yeah graphics pain actually there is
another article I want to show you quick
draw where you know because during your
time there is a talk created by Apple NH
HP where they want to actually create a
high level mathematical system graphic
system 3d graphics system that is
actually actually high level and also
very fast to replace OpenGL but that
just failed you know the thing about
OpenGL in the canvas you know this kind
of [ __ ] is that they don't you know that
they don't capture the essence the math
the math essence of things rather they
always go under like like the
implementation they bring out the
implementation nitty-gritty things to
the programmer
so they don't you know what I you know
what I really for example look at this
Mathematica is a great example okay
suppose you want the mathema is suppose
you want draw a cube now what is the
mathematical essence of a cube let's
just you know one two three four five
six seven eight you know eight corners
or rather it can be reduced to just two
corners you know you just give the
coordinate of two corners for a cube
that is the mathematical essence of a
cube nothing nothing more and nothing
less that's that's what math is when you
study math it's all about that you
reduce everything relevant to its
essence so a cube the essence of a cube
for programming is just two points you
know two coordinates like that so when
you so then you want you want to make a
graphics you know you just wrap you know
your function then you know another
function to display it the rest the
computer can do machine can do for you
your programming language can figure it
out
you know but if you do this in OpenGL
it's like I tried you know it's like 500
lines
10,000 lines you know background
lighting the ambient lighting then you
know okay so here's another question you
know OpenGL they do it that way because
they want it to be fast but this way you
can make it fast - because I mean we we
are simply separating the issues you
know it's not it's not necessarily true
that you cannot be fast when you are
high level you know the point about
those OpenGL low level stuff is that
they they bring a necessarily unless you
know they unnecessarily bring the low
level stuff to the programmer you know
anyway so I think maybe that's it for
today
one hour and when it's am i doing good
guys say something you know so should I
go back to Google+ oh that's about
OpenGL and 3d graphics programming yeah
I wish I wish to learn something about
game programming or 3d engine you know
like I spent four years in Second Life
you know I talked about this last in
UEFA sewed before you know Second Life
is a whole bunch of you know in Second
Life it's very interesting in Second
Life you find a lot more than half of
the people in Second Life are women okay
and most many of them are older women we
are in Second Life to look for you know
the youth they they've lost you know but
in Second Life they are all like
beautiful princesses you know every one
of them you know so I spent like yeah
okay Second Life is the another story
it's a worst hack in the universe so
anyway I spent like four years every day
like five hours a day in second life
part of the reason is that I was hoping
to learn 3d technology you know 3d game
engine technology or or how to write
games you know things like that so I
spent two four years and yet learned
nothing because well what I learned is
basically it's just hack created by
second life used in second life and not
nowhere else
Lindell scripting language instead
but anyway anyway so um second life so
where are you people say something in a
guys watching so I'm thinking maybe yeah
that's it for today let's see let's wrap
it up yeah let me maybe I can just close
3d engines so Duncan do you agree or not
agree I like do you kind of see you know
at least I mean not necessarily agree
but you see kind of my point of view see
second life canvas versus SVG graphics
were in pain 3d models this article is
great though I actually I should I want
to talk about it some maybe some other
day because this is about algorithmic
like first of all I give a survey of the
algorithmic mathematical art you know I
kind of give a survey of all the types
then I discuss I discuss something
important an idea yeah the idea is
algorithmic mathematical art now this is
not just any art created by computer but
rather it's about you you want to create
first of all I explain what it what what
does mathematical art means okay it's
not just any art you know that the
typically called mathematical art you
know it's not that but also I then I
explained what algorithmic means it's
not just using a program to create
images math images or factors no that's
not it but I have a specific meaning
and I should talk about these some other
day okay great to see you Scott goodness
what are you doing up at this hour after
I shower up and watch the recording what
what today's topics all right I'm almost
done though I've been talking for over
an hour now so I was talking about well
yeah earlier I was doing some demo about
Emacs and C so I for half an hour or so
I did several demo about Emacs
interesting things about math font then
I was going to talk about Google first
but Duncan turned me around into talking
about computer graphics technologies
like OpenGL and canvas 3d so so Scott is
in East Coast and now it's nine o'clock
for Scott so Duncan says I agree it's a
general problem of making things
unnecessarily imperative when they could
be instead be decorative yeah yeah you
know I always know when you think about
these things like the history of you
know for example the history of OpenGL
you know I always like for example I you
know history of an OpenGL I want to know
okay but usually these kind of things
you find no information it's very hard
and you know even he very very very few
people actually know answered you know
through things like that for example I
mean history of OpenGL okay for example
history of open
for example my question is you know why
is it designed that way you know you
know like all the frustration I talked
about so I want to look for you know so
is it something wrong with me or is it
why is it this way you know that that's
that's where I'm going you know that's
what I want to find out but but as it
turns out usually you cannot usually
find answers for example like today's
program you you might be wondering why
is HTML Javascript these complex you
know seems you know for that question I
know the answer but I guess in anyway so
I'm open G on history of open Jia okay
so yeah so for example you have these
links but you go there usually they
don't they don't really give you actual
histories I mean they explain you know
which companies began what but they
don't actually tell you the history of
the design you know why is it that way
you know you know why is it that way you
know design of the things usually
usually do not find that information at
all in anywhere because you know
actually only a few people actually know
it you know you have to be in a company
in your team you design it at the time
you know during a decade where other
company is doing competitors you know
then you kind of you have to be like
that in that time at the right place and
person to know the history of the how
the design becomes you know in certain
way so Scott says I was and it was just
an API divided by its GI Hindon later
open-source as they eva okay so Scott do
you know SG yet I mean do you know the
oh the OpenGL in detail like I mean
Scott okay so Scott I know Scott is
working in
should I say semiconductor industry like
you design CPUs right something like
that okay so so you and and your you
know you program in C right so you are a
C expert so you but you also know OpenGL
becomes GPU design oh we found the right
guy GPU right there okay so Scott you
know maybe you can teach me something
about that actually yeah actually maybe
we could have a you know chat where you
talk about things we actually yeah we
should have you know having what asking
you and what I be mentioning this a few
times we will have will do Google
hangout and possibly also broadcast it
you know you know put on you know
podcast live stream or something yeah
yeah I'll think about something and
contact you so you will context texture
engine okay yeah that's that's very
interesting you know the other thing
that annoys me so much as I learned
about graphics you know like when you
look at 3d games they usually you know
okay here's the thing like we we the one
thing I I find extremely annoying it
turns out is that when you have let me
try to show
with like when in the game in the second
I've screenshot here like in gaming they
have this what what is a good example
anyway textures you know like and that's
not a good example but textures so
basically everything you know it's like
they saw textures is just an image
you know they plaster it you know they
displayed on a wall so it looks like
bricks for example this floor he looks
like tiles but actually it's just an
image you know fasted on it so that when
I learned about that in computer
graphics it was like it was a hack I
mean that the very idea is a very
extremely City hack you you just you
know faster something so it looks like a
break or you know a texture you know
it's called textures and textures turned
out it's critically important you know
in computer graphics because almost like
everything is the texture you know so in
this scene for example you have
thousands of textures you know going on
it's just images like image files you
know you have thousands of them display
you know they they are just displayed in
different angle yeah so anyway so so
what does texture engine do I mean so so
actually the the the the the in the
topics is becoming interesting but I've
been talking for over now I think I
wanted to you know we
so Scott any anything else interesting
teller tell us or we're gonna close down
because I've been talking for like 18
minutes see history of OpenGL sauce casa
is for every pixel to be rendered the
text engine texture engine computes
where it would be in the texture and
blends the appropriate Texas from the
image I see I kind of see what you mean
yeah it's yeah it's very complex I can
see yeah we scale the coordinates and
fetch the texture data and blend and
filter it yeah yes yeah I know what you
mean is God you know but my my feeling
you know I know it this is not practical
but my king good my initial reaction to
my why I found out about this texture
and all this thing is the my reaction is
that it's the whole thing is like one
[ __ ] hack you know it's so in elegant
you you you try to emulate all the you
know my idea you know suppose you know
my idea is like you wouldn't have
textures you just have mini impedance
you know gazillion polygons and with
colors on them just like real life you
know that's that's like my ideal you
know I don't want not no textures I want
the real thing
you know the real you know rendering or
polygons maybe ray tracing or whatever
you know not just you know plaster
picture on top of something to like like
a tower you know
so these like it you know this this is a
tower but you know in computer graphics
I suppose it's just a texture you know
look it's just
so iam asked Scott Scott does Qualcomm
have a different memory chip for
textures Scott says in most games now
there are a lot of triangles in the
objects so yes it's a approaching your
idea yeah I hope so
well I guess you're never really
actually happened because then you have
hairs right you have my green you have
water that's you know then it's almost
impossible to
okay I think I'm gonna shut down for
today you guys can keep chatting but I
think the video when I shut down the
video yeah I think you guys can still
chat right yeah I think that's it for me
for today I'm gonna go to sleep and
great to see you guys
thank you for coming by