hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today we are going to
code emac lisp emac this coding so emac
this live coding and if you have
questions in comments say hi okay
whoever you are five people say hi and
ask me questions about emacs or emac
beast I'm gonna code it today but first
of all let me tell you about my
keyboards this is glove 80 keyboard you
can find my reviews on my website I did
the review uh about three weeks ago
could have 80 keyboard and over here is
Ultimate hacking keyboard version 2.
fantastic I just did a review yesterday
or two days ago okay so that's my
keyboard and let's start coding okay
let's start coding e-maglis
okay so let's go to sound talk show and
today's page showing browser so we're
gonna uh first of all what what is it
are we going to code so we are going to
write a command such that you know uh
for example I write keyboard blog a lot
for example let me show you uh windows
okay Windows shortcut
okay show in browser you can see there's
a lot keyboard shortcut markup here so
this page is about Windows shortcuts and
you know I write a lot about keyboards
and so you have all these windows this
almost this is a complete list of
Windows shortcuts okay and the point
here is that you if if we open the page
let's put the link here
showing browser so if you open the page
you can see let's go look at the HTML so
you can see these are the markup you
know
kbd you know kbd something something and
Escape you know so lots of
HTML markup you have to do so what we
are going to do today is we're gonna
write a command let me show you so
suppose I want to say Ctrl W I want to
write that in HTML so normally you it
would be Ctrl capitalize then
keyboard tag then uh wait that doesn't
work okay so you have to select it
keyboard tag then you say Plus
plus then basically then you say w okay
okay showing browser so normally that's
how you do that tedious
so I want to write a command where I
just use the emac syntax so I just say C
Dash W the first character stands for
control then press the button then it
automatically become that that is what
we are going to write today okay so
let's begin
comments and questions okay post it and
pay me if you like my stuff you can buy
my
emacs tutorials you know emacs packages
and emacs tutorials recently and a lot
of updates so my packages you can you
know go to emacs blog and buy it and pay
me okay
so now let's uh so let me let me double
check if my video is going audio check
video check okay
good
ah wait uh
recording will be shut down do you are
you sure you want to exit now
oh okay so yeah press the wrong key so
windows down so okay so now we what we
do now so we are going to write the
command okay
uh so emac this so hold on a second
where is it so this is my emacs block
close close showing browser so we got
I'm going to write the emacs command so
start
show the pink Windows uh uh okay
oh uh
wait what happened
oh yeah so you have to press it twice so
we're gonna
um
emac this code okay so we begin uh we
begin okay so start a Emax this code and
Define I'm using sa emac this smart you
can see here so type D press space and
expand so this this is emac this mod you
can buy open source okay so so
yeah let's be in code okay so dark
stream
version today's date uh and uh
turn text such as uh such as e x x
so let's let's
um
it's document So to that okay that's the
documentation
text
and the cruiser
two
HTML markup
okay something like that we have we have
to fix the writing later but that's
basically what we're gonna do so we
start to define a function so the first
job is get the text under the cursor
let's get the first line okay so we want
the first line so let's define let two
variables xp1
x uh
P1 and P2 this position 1 position 2
okay
Cruiser positions which is a integer
which are integers so I start my
variable names with the X that's my
convention so that you can tell right
away or
identifiers that are variables local
variables okay so so you want to get the
position of the beginning of the line so
set
set xp1 beginning of line okay
so that that function will return
oh wait that that function that's not
the right one that will move the cursor
to the beginning of the line rather we
want the beginning position of the line
so uh line beginning position
okay that's a function we want that
returns that returns a number let me
show you let's eval evaluate you see one
five three that's a position of the
current cursor and the Ping window by
the way the pink window shows all my
emacs command cores and the keystrokes
as I type them so you can see the
command on the right and the key I type
on the left I'm using override keyboard
layout
okay we we haven't done emac this coding
for a long time so now next let's let's
get
xp2 line in position okay line in
position okay so that's the two
variables then what's next so we got the
beginning position we got the end
position we want to grab the text in
between so okay so so let's declare a
new variable
uh X text
okay so set that to
how do you so you got two positions you
want to get the string between them so
that command that function will be
buffer substring
okay that is a function but that will
also grab the coloring so instead we
want buffer substring no properties okay
so this is some technical detail the
difference is that you know you see in
emacs everything you know text is
colored syntax clean that is done by
having properties of the text so for
each text in a buffer it actually is
attached certain properties such as what
font to use what color to use what
background color font size and so on
behind the scenes you don't see it but
it's you know it's it's a data structure
embedded within any certain text you
know you can add to them or you can
remove them so that's called text
properties that is how you get the color
now
if we do this you'll grab the whole data
structure including the color and found
and font size and so on but usually you
don't need that so usually if you don't
want the color you just want the string
so you can then you say buffer substring
no properties okay
so that is what we want and this is our
variable names Okay so
so now let's purify the code okay let's
shrink a bit
okay now we got the text now what to do
with the text so it's a string now uh
let's remind ourselves what does the
string looks like okay so for example
the Stream
uh
C
W okay so CW becomes
let's do some magic here so you can see
showing browser so CW becomes that
magnifying okay magnify
so
but it can be more complicated for
example you if you have for example
let's say
CW
uh
let's say you know
let's say cwct
okay yeah let's just do that see you
know the two keystrokes now let's make
let's change it to something more common
so c a
c c so that's select all and copy a
sequence of shortcuts
that happens very often so select or and
shortcut
select or encode and that will become
uh let's just write it here so that will
become
that okay so for example uh wait here
yeah so here are two examples you know
so the first example is simple the
second one is sequence of key shortcuts
so you want to emacs to turn that into
this markup okay
easy okay so now let's let's go back
here so now you get a stream of things
like that first of all you split
okay
split string okay that's the function we
want split stream and you want to split
the X text stream optional separators
yes separators is gonna be white space
and uh one or more so that's a very good
expression omit news
um
no we don't care I mean no one's Neo
Okay so
so then you add a new variable list okay
so something like that
Okay so
so set list to be that
okay
comments and questions okay
okay next
so now we got the least so now we have
split screen split this into a list so
now we can process each one by itself
okay
so let's say
X temp okay key let's let's see um
X
temp okay something like that so now we
we want to so we now we got a list of
shortcuts we want to process
them one at a time
so
so the way to do that is is you map
C
that's a map function so you map to the
sequence X list okay and here Lambda is
a function that's what you want to want
to do to each one of the shortcuts
okay now you map so what we're gonna do
so so suppose the input is gonna be uh C
A for example that's that's a sample
input so X you know the x is gonna be
like that a string so once you get that
what you what what to do you want to
split string again
uh this is gonna get tedious
more tediously I thought okay so you
want to split stream
so okay so but before we do anything you
want to declare some variables okay so
the variables you want to declare is uh
uh
X key okay so first of all
sample x value okay so now you want to
um
so now
you want to so we have a variable X key
and what we want to do here is split
stream
split the X
into a list okay so let's say
Keys okay
so set queue keys keys will be three
string okay
in this case we can have a syntax
shortcut
let's do this okay so we just put it
there so simple so now what we do so now
we got each key is one of the letters c
and a
so
so we can here's what we can do
so we split them
okay so uh
so far so good
comments guys comments okay so we
split them
let's do this okay let's do
let's just assume
you know there are many different
variation cases for example the input
could be something like
um
you know something like that that means
control meta a
and it could be some other case for
example
um
so actually the split string here will
be split by a
Dash character
okay and uh yeah let's just do that
and then there are some other examples
for example you might have
uh you know the meta is usually
considered you know the Windows key so
the question is how do you represent the
Windows key or the old key so old key is
typically a and the Windows key here we
can device it just say let's say w is
Windows key
so something like that so this all these
are possible inputs now we split them by
a hyphen okay then for each one of these
the first few characters we need to
change them into a
you know C needs to be Ctrl
okay getting complex but but let's let's
just uh simplify and push through for
now then fix it you know
later improve it later so
because I'm doing live stream you need
to get going to show results
so
so what we do now is we
let's just add
let's just add the keyboard tag okay so
for each key
so
okay so before we do this map let's say
delete region
okay so once you get the text let's say
delete region delete region
there okay so you deleted the current
line then you insert them here so you're
gonna insert
uh actually
not insert so we want to
so each of this character is the item in
a list
so you want to so actually I know what
to do so instead of that you use
sequence contact
okay let's look up the list
documentation so go through my website
because our email list Basics then you
go to this Basics then you go to
these lisp data structure then you go to
list okay
and okay go to list and then you go down
it's magnify okay
then you go down at the bottom there is
a
so here is all the lisp related topics
convert join list or vector or string
that's what you want to do
so
V contact okay showing any sequence type
and return a vector okay that's not what
we want
we want to turn the list to a stream
and also add strings in between okay so
append is not what we want a pen returns
a list
but map contact that's what we want map
contact
okay
so let's do it here
uh
yeah so actually do it here
there's an issue with my keyboard This
Bluetooth reconnected
Okay so
so now we map contact
okay map contact function uh
function sequence separator
function we don't need so
identity
okay identity function and the sequence
is X keys and the separator is
okay the separator is this
keyboard
Plus
backslash okay
that's what we that's what we want then
you want to
actually insert
okay insert that
then
insert this thing
you insert the ending keyboard tag is
that correct yes
yes okay
so
hello Akon first
a first comment
Okay so
so now
let's eval the function okay that's I
think I think that should do
uh that should give us a Basics okay so
let's rename the function
um
let's what what should we name it let's
open a new window okay because I have
written this function already 10 years
ago
so let's go to
PSI HTML mod uh actually let's just call
this command so the command is called
site HTML keyboard shortcut markup so
it's defined inside HTML mod so here is
a source code so I wrote this like 10
years ago but over the 10 years I made
some changes and I also made some
careless changes and now it's not so
good you see what it's doing you know
it's
the keyboard notation you see because
for example the control key some people
might say CTI or some some people might
type the full control some people with
lowercase you know sometimes it's with
capital case you so you want to
normalize it have a standard keyboard
notation across and also across Windows
Mac and and the
Linux so
so anyway so that so that's uh so let's
focus on what we are writing today so
let's so right now the question is what
command to name this okay so let's
what what is the name okay
let's say
let's just say that short okay because I
shortcut markup
okay so now
are we done
is this good let's see double check one
last time
so
let's just say let's try it okay eval
now
now we go to uh HTML page
yeah so now we go here so now let's
let's try let's try on this keyword okay
okay meta X
sound shortcut markup do it
fantastic it worked okay undo now let's
let's let's try this one control select
all and the copy okay meta X consumption
code markup to it
fantastic except that you need a space
here so you see
that's right so you need a space here
okay so let's fix that
fantastic so
how long did it okay in 20 minutes we
did it
so we now uh you need to add a space so
where do you add that
great uh okay so now you yeah it's a
missing a space in between here so
where do you add that let's see
Spirit stream X text
so this x text should be named
shortcut
okay so let's change change let's rename
the variables so they make better sense
X should cut
okay that's one single sequence
so I mean one one connected shortcut
okay a string that's a string
so
oh all you have to do is add a space
here that's right
okay even on the buffer go back here and
do undo and do and do okay let's try it
again meta X essential code mock-up do
it fantastic okay now let's put a
paragraph and go to browser and see how
it looks like that fantastic okay so
that's one step done now
you know no more people don't know what
the is C so you know because the
capital c that's a e Max convention that
stands for control but
outside of emacs you need to say you
know control see usually Ctrl this is an
interesting question by the way because
you can look at the official
documentation for Microsoft and and see
how they you know do they use the
forward control do they capitalize the
first word uh you know you look at you
know and yeah and things like that so
keyboard notation that's a topic by
itself very uh fairly complex and
interesting because on the Mac it's a
different way and also old key you know
do you say alternative or sometimes you
use a symbol for example on the Mac you
have the command key
okay so we digressed a bit but the the
least code is basically done okay that's
what we have so let's digress for five
minutes let me talk about the keyboard
notation because it's very interesting
so so so okay so for example we showed
now this is the keyboard notation okay
so let's go to yeah let's let's talk
about keyboard notation a little bit
so you have Windows keyboard shortcuts
you have then you have the windows logo
keyboard shortcuts okay Windows logo
Windows screenshot shortcuts Windows
File Explorer shortcuts Windows
shortcuts to launch or switch
application Windows keyboard shortcut
frequently asked questions and so on and
other shortcut tools now if you look at
you know each of them
you know that's interesting for example
the Windows key the Windows key the
windows logo also changed over the past
30 years so
um that's another interesting topic let
me show you okay so let's search
logo okay uh Windows okay Microsoft
Windows logo history so you can see
Microsoft Windows you know they their
logo changed over the past
30 years and you know for a while on the
keyboard you have this logo black and
white you know this one but now since
about five years ago they changed for a
few you know they changed to this you
know this this one
so that's about keyboard notation do you
use symbols or not so okay so let me
show you let me let's let me go to show
you the all about keyboard notation so
keyboard Blog then design key caps keys
so this is all about keyboard keys
um okay so let's see
so for example this key is a manual key
that's also interesting you know
sometimes they use a logo a glyph or
logo graph like that originally then you
know then simplify it some keyboard uses
that or you might think wait what about
just say menu or is it is this key code
menu or is it called app that depends
because by Microsoft official
documentation it's
um what do they use exactly but anyway
this key is officially known officially
known as either menu key or app key
which name is used depending on you know
who is writing the documentation so
that's so that's a interesting issue so
for example me I'm writing a you know
keyboard documentation or tutorial or
discussion philosophy about keyboard
which you know for example I choose
in my case I choose the menu to be
labeled this way menu with the you know
kind of
symbol but how should you do you know
for example if you are a Microsoft if
you
are documented you know documentation
writer for Microsoft or if you are
working for Apple
Which choice should you do you know so
that's a lot consideration you know the
terminology consideration which one is
more recognizable intuitive and things
like that and and which one is more
unique so there's a lot issues if you
actually consider about these kind of
things and also
writing documentation about keyboard
shortcut that's one thing another thing
is the documentation the the menu you
know so you know what should the
shortcut show in a menu command you know
in a menu in your application because
sometimes that's you have different
requirements from the documentation
uh so for example I can show you some
differences uh you know be uh
can I
um
so anyway so so so so so this is a
Windows case
on the Mac you also have quite a few
interesting cases you know Mac have
their different way of keyboard notation
and in fact over the years they also
change slightly you know it's at one
period uh they only use
symbols they don't have the words and
the other issue is is on the actual
keyboard what do you print them with
label do you just use symbols or do you
use full word
anyway I'm going oh I'm kind of lost and
going over all these issues
um you know so we are looking at the
documentation about this basically the
whole thing is is about keyboard
notation the keyboard notation in
documentation the keyboard notation on
actual keyboard labels which one should
you use should you use symbol or name
and the keyboard notation on menu for
example here's the example from Apple
you know in here in this case they don't
use the names they they only use symbols
so this is kind of more elegant and you
know you can also see apple
did away with the plus sign
you know using the plus sign is standard
in Windows documentation but before you
know in year 2000 and in year night uh
90s 1990s the windows keep on notation
they use a dash instead of a plus
but I guess they they realize the minor
sign is kind of confusing because when
you use the plus sign then it's more
intuitive meaning that you have to hold
this key and press that together plus
you know so
so they they change the minus to a plus
on the other hand Apple simply you know
remove the personal mind they just put
the keys together the apple way also got
issues
it got issues when you have a sequence
of keys that are that are not pressed
together
for example on a Windows old old space
for example I can press Alt
and release the release the key and
space
wait hold
space okay that doesn't work there let's
try here old space wait
okay old space you need to press
together one shot okay but there are
other things for example old F old F to
open the files menu okay let's try it
alt F you see
okay escape to cancel Escape you see odd
you know don't hold it release it and uh
F you see so in this case you are
pressing two keys one is a modifier but
you press them as a sequence not as a
combination so if you have that kind of
shortcut then this apple notation is
going to be a problem because there's no
way you know unless you put a space in
between so it you know it becomes a bit
ambiguous so they are so you know these
are some of the keyboard notation issues
on the other hand in emacs for example
let's go to emacs emacs standardize
their keys for example we can show here
emac standardized their keys simply you
know control is just capital c and a
Dash means press them together you can
see
um you know so
so this is some of the issues about key
keyboard notation in different
applications in different operating
systems and in different places such
such as documentation or applications
menu and or on the keyboard and also in
different era so for example the Emax
notation they came from the era of 1970s
okay my image is Frozen What uh
oh
when did its when did that start to
happen
okay but I think maybe that's it for
today uh I don't know what's what's
going on with my image Frozen
okay so but maybe that's it for today so
let me toggle timestamp
so my image are frozen about a minute
ago
I don't know what's going on though
let's see
11 minutes ago
uh okay so
hmm
so it looks like
okay so wait
so my screen is not frozen right it's
just it's just my video
yeah so somehow my video the camera
is
up
let's try this
okay it's it's still frozen
okay I'm not sure what's going on
okay but that's a nice photo though
that's a nice capture
uh
why is my video Frozen so something
wrong
you know apparently the camera software
the Camera Part got frozen so let me
close
all a necessary applications and see
maybe
um
yeah but anyway that's it for today so
we we kind of finished the
list code yeah let's just wrap it up
okay we finished the list code anyway
and then we started to talk about
keyboard notation so here's the list
code it's not complete though because
now the next step is that we need to
change the capital c to you know the
Ctrl
but
okay so here is the code let's
syntax color it show in browser
so here's the code today
uh
puts my okay so now so it okay so that's
it for today thank you guys for watching
uh and now I'm just gonna do some random
let's see what what is going on with my
video why is it
why is it not
showing anything
let's see what happens now
okay that that just froze
so
so it must be a bug with the
either with the OBS or
with my camera I don't think it's a
camera because I have two of them
and both of them froze so now let's
control shift Escape
okay let's see the
tax task manager what does it say
okay task manager
God
wait it's back
wait the Logitech
the Logitech camera is now working
but not the speedo not the China cheaper
my face
the camera for my face is
yeah so the camera for my face is stuck
okay so we can
try to unplug that one
okay
that's not fixing it
okay we're gonna I'm gonna restart the
OBS and let's see if that will fix it
otherwise that's it for today bye guys
you mean let's see
let's see okay we are back are we not
I think so
it's good okay so now so what we took uh
okay so we are 47 minutes what to do
fixed yeah so
okay so
um you know so I talked for 10 minutes
about keyboard notations and I guess you
guys missed all that
um
but
okay let's forget about it let's let's
so now we got this code to work okay so
so it's
let's try to get to let's try to improve
it okay
so pop this out so here's the code and
we can
uh let me let me do this again so
okay so let me Demo so here is the text
put a cursor there pull the command
exception code marker meta X do it and
there we have it and put a paragraph
showing browser go down there it is so
now the next thing we want to do is we
want to change the capital c to ctil to
the standard notation Okay so
so um so what to do so
map contact
so so yeah so we put a function here so
let's let's write
so you see here the map can cap we have
identity mean which means do not do
anything but however in between elements
we add the keyboard
markup
but now
we want to change the capital c to Ctrl
so so
we add a Lambda here okay so
so we add the Lambda here
okay so Lambda and if
X okay if string equal
X is equals to C
then
we want to change it
we want to so we want to Output
ctil
otherwise
just return C itself okay something like
that about the buffer
let's just try it okay but we don't need
this line
Eva the buffer go back here and do undo
and do okay now let's try it
sound shortcut markup
do it
nothing is okay it changed here you see
uh
yeah it's it changed there it's a
problem we got a few things to fix it's
a problem because if you show in browser
you can see
you want to make the change only if it's
the first character
I mean only if it's you know the first
part of the shortcut
so okay and the other thing we need to
fix is that
lowercase C should also work okay so
here will be if all that or Capital C
okay now is here a
um
so you can say low low case lowercase so
what's the command
for lowercase so in e-max it's called
down case Okay down case
down Case Case X
okay so actually so that
so even the buffer let's try it again
okay
midax do it
you see now showing browser go here
refresh now it's better now
now the next thing we need to do is that
we only want to change the front we
don't want to change the last
key
Okay so
so we can do that by
this is so we need to drop the last
basically
I can hey can are you the can I know
long time no see long time no C I'm
gonna call you okay
I I think you are the are you the can I
know I think so I'm not sure
but I'm gonna call you okay offline
so uh
so what are we doing now so we have we
need to fix this
we need to fix this
so how do you fix it
okay let's fix this and that'll be it
for today maybe 10 more minutes okay
so
now let me uh let me repeat what's going
on so we got a sequence of shortcuts
like that okay one two three for example
each one is a shortcut Okay so
magnify so each uh wait
each one of these is considered a
shortcut so we have a list of them you
know a list of them and in this part so
the Lambda
the x is one of these okay for example
uh wait
for
you know for uh so let me let me explain
Okay so
sample X list
value
so
sample x value is like this okay
so this is a like a sample input
uh
wait that should be your parenthesis
yeah okay so
Okay so
let's do this again
okay so that's better so this is a
this is this is a example value of the X
list
a list of shortcuts
and uh
and then we map
to the list
and each X is one of these you know
example
but right now the problem is we don't
want to deal with the last element you
know we don't want to make any change to
the last one of it
so
so here we split the string
okay so now we split the string and we
want to drop last so how do you drop the
last item in a list now this is gonna be
inefficient because list in lisp is a
linked list
and linked to the last part so you can
drop the first item easily and
efficiently but you cannot drop the last
item efficiently
so but here we do need to drop we do
need one to drop the last so one easy
way but inefficient is just reverse the
whole
drop the first item
then reverse them back
okay that's that's okay so so that's
very inefficient so we can what we can
do is we can look up
the this documentation for sequence
functions let's see what's the best way
to do it okay sequence functions
so here is you have a bunch sequence
functions so there it is reverse we can
use
um sequence element sequence length
sequence take while
you know for now why don't we just do
the Innovation Way
you know that would be much faster
instead of we thinking and talking about
this
uh
uh yeah let's just do the most dumb way
okay
so let's do it
okay so here we got the key
so now let
star so that later variables notice the
value of earlier variables Okay so
uh
actually so X keys
this let me just um
okay so we got this bunch of things
so okay copy copy
set reversed equals to
reverse
X Keys okay
then
last item so you also want last
uh
so reverse it
set
last item
car
that so that's the last item okay
then you want to reverse it back
so in fact you don't want
to rest
so last item
yep what yep
okay so last item will be
so okay so you got a list you want
you actually want to drop the last item
because the last item you do not want to
process at all
so
you do no need to know that what's the
last item but also you need to remove it
so
so that's easy okay so
so last item
then you also
set sense last
so wait
reverse and
[Music]
here is what to do cutter
that okay so
so this senseless is basically the
original list in the original order but
without the last item
okay so it's double check
yeah so we got the last
Okay so
predify
okay
[Music]
okay and here we just process instead of
the keys we just process the reverse
last
then once that's this once that is done
we add back
we add back the
insert we will add back the last item so
so that would be
uh wait
where would that be
yeah we need to add it here somewhere
here
foreign
okay so last item goes here
then
I'm not sure the logic is correct but
something like that okay
okay here's the whole code let's just
try it
okay undo so let's do it here
comment do it
perfect
one shot coding
showing browser
perfect oh you missing the space again
you missing the space again
Okay so
oh yeah so the space needs to go
wait so the space needs to go
here
but what is this wait so we go back here
keyboard
keyboard keyboard keyboard
um
it feels like we added a extra
oh yeah that's right
so
begin
and
so begin in the keyboard that that that
and end
and
end
here okay
and do and do and do call the command
meta X sound shortcut markup enter
perfect
and a paragraph showing browser go to
the bottom
perfect
okay now let's try something else let's
you know we got this perfect
copy paste do it do it
and make it
uh list showing browser go to the bottom
that's perfect now let's do another
example okay so this time the example
will be
um
control
s okay s will stand for shift just like
the emac summit convention Okay so
so here
if
so here instead of the if expression we
need a we need a conditional
so okay so copy that so let's write this
okay
condition
first condition that
mean that okay and the last condition is
true
uh
true and do nothing return X itself okay
so we don't need this if statement
anymore
do you need it okay but now we need to
add several other conditions okay so
this one will be S will be shift okay
and uh
a will mean hold okay and uh
so let's see
W will mean Windows okay let's you know
this is not emacs convention it's
something we make up we made up
windows and in this case Windows let's
be fancy and let's add this extra
um
symbol for Windows key
okay Windows shortcut yeah so let's add
this
you know this is my own convention
okay
and uh yeah
so W is for Windows and uh and uh what
about command command
uh
there's a conflict because if you use C
to stand for command for the mag it
conflicts with control
so
so there are these situations
um
so what key do you want to use for
command yeah I don't know
it's not let's not worry about it now
let's just do this okay
and let's let's make another
another
it's just that like let that be okay
so there it is Eva the buffer so we have
Ctrl shift alt okay
so
so this will be Ctrl shift a
and let's see Control Alt a let's make
them a lowercase and let's say
Ctrl shift Alt
okay
and let's say windows
windows
s
okay and let's say windows SS that's for
screenshot Windows shift s is for
screenshot okay let's let's try them
and now let's do this okay copy it
so
do it Ctrl shift a fantastic
do it Ctrl alt a fantastic
do it Ctrl shift alt a beautiful
Windows is beautiful
window shift s fantastic perfect
make a list showing browser
fantastic okay that's that's it that's
what we wanted to do
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff buy my
emacs tutorial okay buy my emac this
tutorials you know everything you need
to know for from the beginners to you
know
to as a reference for your Advanced
coders
uh okay so that's it
bye guys
okay we shut down in one minute uh let's
now do some cleanup of the code okay
some cleanup
so this x list you are the goat what is
what does the goat mean what does goat
mean
uh
good yeah so that's uh you know idioms
and slan or something
greatest of all time oh I see thank you
so let's clean up up the code we you
know that's it for today I'm shutting
down so but clean up the code so
so this x list should be something more
intuitive you know so
shortcuts
okay so X list these shortcuts
wait
this this is
text okay so this should be input text
this shortcut should be input text
okay rename that
okay then X list is shortcuts
okay
then this x is
is one shortcut okay
okay something like that and this mess
you know this inefficient mess it
doesn't matter actually
actually this form
is probably the best code
because if you want to consider
efficiency you know we are doing reverse
list
we are doing reversing a list then take
the you know that you know the first
item then drop that item and reverse it
back that's what we are doing
so it's inefficient but however
you know at least the length of our list
is at most four
you know it's not 100 or 1000 so in fact
this is the most simple and
pretty efficient you know
you know
um if you have you know more than 50
items or something then maybe you don't
want to do this but for our case you
know the max
number of lists is just four you know
because you only have four modifiers or
five you know six at most shift control
or
shift control
you know shift control super old
that's it four unless you consider left
or right old left shift right shift but
there's no shortcut that
practically there's no shortcut that
considers different left hand and right
hand differentiation so this is actually
a good code
okay
so okay that's it bye guys
thank you