good morning good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of s talk
show today's
20204 January 1st New Year happy New
Year guys so we are going to code Advent
of code uh we're going to continue this
is take three Advent of code 2023 three
day five problem okay take three so
nobody's here uh you know so we did a
vote and eight
votes wanted me to uh code a vend of
code but now nobody showed up one concur
viewer oh God let me remind
everyone streaming now join okay
uh okay so we're going to start Advent
of code day five okay so let me show you
my keyboard This is kesis
360 wired not the pro version okay and
this is Ultimate hacking keyboard okay
and uh let me switch to my desktop so
you can see and let me talk about
keyboard for two minutes
okay uh those people so you if you are
here say hi okay you voted to want me to
uh watch theable code but you are not
here that's no good so keyboard I did a
lot update you know the glove 80
keyboard a lot update on my review and
also glove 80s carrying case I showed
this in my past few uh live stream two
of them uh so this is actually part of
glove 80 now so if you buy Glo 80 key 80
keyboard this nice specially designed
carrying case come with it free okay so
that's fantastic gl8 thank thank uh
thanks to Moo who gave me who gave me
one so glove 80 keyboard and you can uh
and kesis 360 keyboard okay um I also
have a review uh but I'm going to update
that article and I'm going to do a new
one so you know so you can check out my
website for the greatest ergonomic
keyboard which one you should get which
one is the best and so on I have you
know tons of info there okay so now
let's start Advent of code day five okay
what is
this okay let's let's just begin it okay
s keyboard block close close what is
this page okay so day five hello Thiago
from Brazil I think so day five okay we
we we did two of them like like 5 hours
uh and uh failed even passing the first
one oh [ __ ] so day five problem is that
you got a input a text input like that
let's see double check last double check
video check audio Check Yes okay day
five
now continuation of
drink drink driving well not yeah well
drink driving the
code for the
occasion Happy New Year's so you can
sell me your ultimate hacking keyboard
one uh yes I can yeah I I have the
ultimate hacking keyboard one so get
onar Discord okay you can find my
Discord ons.info there's a invite link
so get on there and uh and talk to me
okay good good night German German where
you
from this is uh red wine red wine Plus
orange
juice okay happy New Year dude Nick
colan I think I've seen you
for
sh
hello uh so get on Discord if you want
to know people okay so anyway it's back
to so day five day five is a problem the
first part is you got you got this input
a text input which has two parts one is
a bunch of numbers that's called seed so
think of each number as a seed ID okay
so it's just a number an
integer then you got a bunch of maps
okay now these
maps are like hash table or dictionary
so they turn a number into another but
however this Maps is specified in a
special way so that for example in for
example
each map has multiple lines each line is
three numbers uh triplet okay and so
what does the three number mean it means
that so for example 58 982 what does it
mean that means this is a so that means
you start with
98 and you there are two of them so you
you know there are two of them meaning
98 99 okay that's the
source of the map okay then 52 is a
destination okay so also two of them so
you got 50 and 51 so these three numbers
the first number is the destination the
target the second number is the source
the third number is how many items are
there so in this case it means 98 maps
to 50 and 99 maps to 51 okay okay so
they specify a map in this weird way and
uh each line each each triplet means the
same thing so for example here 52 50 48
that means there are 48 pairs starting
from 50 and 51 52 and so on 40 of them
48 of them and the destination is 52 and
51 I mean 52 53 54 and so on 48 of them
so you create a bunch of 48
pairs from destination to Source okay so
this is one map the first map you know
it's called seed to oil map soil map
seed to soil then you have another map
soil to fertilizer specified in the same
way by
triplets
arrange by triplet triplets then you
have another map and uh you have several
of them so you have total of like seven
of them so your job is that you take a
seed number let's say 79 then you go
through the first map you get a
different number now by the way uh if
the number does not appear in this
dictionary then it just return you
supposed to return a number is itself
okay
so you go through the first map you get
a different number pass possibly a
different number then you take that
number you input into the second map you
possibly get another number then you do
that again again again until at the end
you get a number possibly the same as
the original but anyway you get a number
so you do this for each of the number in
the seeds then out of all the numbers
you find the minimum the smallest one of
them that is the answer to the solution
okay so we started to C
that in two live streams and we F I
failed because the first live stream we
passed the you see what's interesting is
let let me just repeat okay uh for those
of you haven't watched before let me
just repeat what has been done so in the
in the first video I finished the
problem the to problem no problem
trivial okay but however the users's
input do we have the user input yeah so
you see the user input is
this you know this hundreds and each
number of items is 100 Millions so when
I did this
one the my machine ran out of memory
because for each of these triplet I'm
generating 100 million items very
inefficient because I thought I'm just
quickly going to solve the problem but
instead you know this is when I you
actually need to look into efficiency
okay because each of these array is 100
million items then you have like
almost 30 of them so out of
memory George thank you Happy New Year
so big gift thank you George ching ching
fantastic
so so yeah so and so we want to so the
first
day let's run let's run the let's run
the code okay so actually let me let me
let me start to code it and run it so
you can
see okay
so the first day yeah let's go to it
let's start coding on the pink window
you can see all my command I'm using
emac and all the commands I call will
show up there and also you can see the
keystroke I call on the left side so
let's magnify it okay so for example uh
next next line of block you can see the
command is there and let's say delete
this block you can see the line the
command is s delete current text block
okay now undo you can see there it is it
is undo okay so I'm I'm using soft FL
keys and Vora keyboard okay now begin
the code okay so what is
this so I want to show you yeah so I
actually need to do a lot clean up we
are going to do okay so so let me just
start to do
it this huge map let's not use them okay
so actually
put it back and
uh we have another one okay so
God
okay let me just do something okay
input yeah let's do that copy
close and
uh
okay I'll show you what's going on in a
bit okay yeah so this so this
code
what so this code you are looking at
that solves the problem okay which
include expl explanation so here's a
code you can see here is a input here's
a seed number input is a text file then
what we do is that
we did you pass it no so wait so
actually hold on a
second
uh oh yeah we need this so we
manually turned this text input into the
wolam format so let's grab that yeah
let's grab that close that and uh go
back
here put it here okay so now copy all
select all paste so you can see here is
the text input okay but we didn't pass
it we because Advent of a code doesn't
require to so instead I just manually
created
this this uh maps of S A Triplet okay so
then we turn each triplet into an actual
dictionary or hash table map okay
then then this last line basically give
use the solution okay so let's run the
whole
thing so run it so you can see the
original seat
number the seat number 79 14 55 13
becomes this sequence 82 43 86
35 okay and you go back to the Advent of
code day five the toy input you can see
our solution Works 82 43 86 35 okay but
if you run this on actual you know the
users input where you have millions of
it you know hundred millions items then
out of memory that's spectac spectacular
because wol is running take all the
memory I have uh 16 gigabyte RAM it suck
it up right away then OBS crashed so my
live stream crashed and I didn't know so
and crashed twice eventually I looked at
what's going on you know uh it's because
in this in the real input they sneaked
in this 100 Millions
items of array so this is when you have
to consider efficiency because on this
day five I was because previous days I
was thinking too much I was thinking of
most efficient code and the most elegant
code and
shortest kind of characters so day five
I was going like Let's ignore that just
just just get the quickest problem the
quickest solution and Bam ban
stuck okay so I'm just gonna go slow
there's no rush I'm not gonna you know
because every time I Rush it's not so
good good night nick uh and the
colia Colombia wow German Molina is from
Colombia that's in South America right
wow amazing that's
a North part of South
America okay so what you going to do so
okay so we got the let's it's uh clean
up it's so we got clean up the code so
here is a
solution uh let's annotate it so we got
clearly we know what's going on so the
code day five part
one
solution
Works however
when taking the user input it run out of
memory
because the user input
each
triplet is
100 million items okay that is a reason
but otherwise this is this code works
this is Brute Force Brute Force solution
is mathematicians favorite solution you
see mathematicians don't care how you
going to get there they only care if
there's a solution or not you you know
theoretically the rest is your Cod
coding monkeys
problem your coding monkey monkeys dling
dling with memories or memory malac
whatever so so anyways but yeah but you
know it's not practical I mean a
mathematician mathematics is not
engineering okay when you code that's
part of engineering so when you do
engineering you need to cons concern to
be concerned with practicality you need
to be concerned with memory dling how
much memory you need to concerned with
garbage collection you know this what
gets you know the C and C++ coders
excited and Unix this type of people
compilers because they usually they hate
garbage collection and or they love it
but they have to dto like how is it done
this way or you know sweep and whatever
mark
idiotic
[ __ ] you know this garbage collection
this kind of thing you know it's um so
mathematicians concern is Theory the
computer science or theoretical computer
science okay cellular automata Lambda
calculus tuning machine
computability complexity of the
algorithm you know the Big O notation
and algorithms
uh and
the uh
combinators logic prove Theory okay
that's what we are concerned about we
are not conern concerned about
C++ pointers pointer arithmetics memory
diddling bit manipulation like let's do
a bit manipulation so it can do OnePlus
One
faster bit shifting bit bit
[ __ ] okay so anyway
let's not get too angry about this okay
so so let's uh so that Solution that's
the first solution now it works so I'm
21 minutes in no problem uh relax okay
don't get too angry about this relax and
uh the problem will be solved
now now this is a second chice so so
that was the first days attempt you know
for 2 hours you know the system crashed
so the second day I know better so you
don't want to so for each each of these
triplet which represents two
ranges so you know uh uh one range maps
to the other a range of numbers uh
consec consecutive numbers range so
instead of creating a hashtable for each
one of these triplet you don't want to
do that because each one of these
triplet is 100 million items so you
don't want a you know hash table for
each one of them
instead because it turns out this this
is a idiotic map because it's a map all
right but they just map you know
like 58 maps to you know 98 maps to 50
maps to
51 you know so it's like just it's not
really any complicate it's a linear kind
of very linear map so basically you just
add you know the difference you add the
difference between the first number and
second number for the rest of it okay so
it's not really uh so we do not have to
build a hash table all we have to do is
to do this okay so what to do so yeah
so if Source begin and let's say you
know if Source start if the seed number
is between Source start and
Source wait why is this Source start
yeah so if the seat number is basically
be between the source start number 98 or
the source end the source end is Source
start plus number of items minus one so
if the C is between them
then that number get gets basically get
transformed into this this difference C
start and Des destination start so in
other words Des destination start minus
Source start so
50 um plus seed okay so night so
basically
destination start minus sour start so 50
50 minus 98 plus the c number that gets
you the
solution okay
so so so this solves
this you know going uh taking a number
going through one of this
triplet okay that the code is that one
it's just here okay but now there's
another problem because for each of
these map you have not just one range
but you have two so this gets into a
slight
complication there are two questions
first of all do these two maps overlap
or not
because you know if they they
overlap you know so if they overlap that
means there's a conflict you know one
says 79 should be 80 the other one says
79 should be 100 so which one to take do
you do you always follow the second one
if there's overlap or do you just ignore
the second one or third one right so
whether they overlap and uh there is
another issue is is uh what is the isue
did I last time I wrote it
out uh did we did I delete it I think I
think so I forgot
[ __ ] what is the other issue so whether
they overlap the other issue
is right the other issue is that once
once a
number is found in one of these Tri
triplet do you continue to the second
trip triplet obviously no you don't want
okay so once you found that number is in
one of these
triplet then you don't want to continue
okay even if they overlap okay so so
that's a thing so we kind of stuck the
other day on that
problem does wo language has a bing
range type yes of
course uh so there it is 3
29 okay so you see 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 and you
can say 329 in increment of two okay you
got that
3579 or you can say 329 in increment of
1 over three there you have it you got a
bunch of
fractions okay and uh what about in
increment of pi
over
four symbolic computation far superior
than the python [ __ ] what if you want
32 um 30 to9 but in increment of
negative pi
over4 there you have it okay what what
what about decimal you want you don't
want symbolic you want decimal numerical
solution so negative pi over 4 dot that
so that gives you a bunch of De decimal
numbers okay so range
is you know in fact wam has table table
is far more powerful okay I'm not going
to expain but at this opportunity let me
show you go search for Wam Language
tutorial so you can find where to
download wolam engine for free so that
you can use
it on my uh on on a terminal so for
example let me show
you okay you start w script then we can
do exactly the same thing let's copy
that uh let's say copy something simpler
okay paste it there paste okay control
control shift V oh wait right click okay
there it is range okay so what about
this more complicated
paste there it
is okay so you can get this free that's
wo script you know you can find the link
froma F Language tutorial and you can
see my tens of video tutorials in the
past uh the best ones kind of are
collected here on computer Graphics you
know this one fantastic so you know
anyway so now but we are here because I
wanted to show you a
powerful uh
function that generates arbitrary nested
array or nested list okay and that is
called table so you look at creating
list there it
is so let's show one example so you it
this can generate arbitrarily
multi-dimensional tables okay so for
example okay let's copy
that uh
okay so that's
like this is a three-dimensional array
and you can
M percentage sign means the last output
then you can say tree form okay so we
can show them as a tree so there you
have
it okay or we can show them as Matrix
form or
array
uh okay things like that fantastic wam
language so this table form is extremely
powerful uh and basically it is similar
to Python's list comprehension okay so I
have article on Python tutorial of list
comprehension if you you can search it
if you don't know what that is so but
basically this table function in a
functional form this table function is
equivalent to
Python's uh list comprehension okay or
hascal anyway so that's about range so
the I mean what so what I'm saying is
that this table is like more powerful
form of the range because range can only
generate flat list onedimensional list
although you can have symbolic you know
you can have like arbitrary function let
me show you okay um
you can have for example let's say this
one okay
so let's
say uh let's say three times three times
F some function
f four okay 29 uh can you do it actually
I'm not I don't think so yeah so anyway
use table okay range is for flat list
but if you
want sometimes two dimensional or three
dimensional or nend dimensional array
you use table okay that one okay that's
about that so let's go back to solve the
problem I I will finish it okay today
and we'll finish this at least the part
one no problem so so let's go so that's
a bit
uh digression now let's go back to this
problem so where were we yeah we want to
go through each of
these map but as soon as we
found that one of the map applies to the
input we exit we don't want to you know
go through the first triplet got the
number then we pass that number to
another triplet no okay so each one of
these map even though they have several
triplet just as soon as soon as you
one of them applies you
exit then you go to the next line okay
so so last time we were stuck there so
what we want is
um select okay so we just want the
select function
select uh take uh let me tell you what
select does so in wam language
everything you do is a function call the
whole there's no object there's no
directives there's no statements there's
no special Syntax for for Loop for print
f for there's no methods there is
no you know all the class object method
instant
instantiation you know whatever finalize
any [ __ ] like that okay in wolam
language everything is expression like
1+ one then function then everything is
the in this single single syntax nothing
else there's no object nothing just core
functions apply it to some expression
you get the output that's it that's the
entirety of wam language okay no no
object something something methods or
something okay 7,000 functions out of
the box you don't even need to even
import regular expression import reading
a file import working a
directory idiotic [ __ ] the industrial
programmers so anyway so
select what it does is that it takes a
two arguments one is a list of items
then the second part is a function
that's a criteria so that basic it's
like a filter okay in it's called filter
in Python and other languages in Pearl
it's called grap because then it's
analogous to grab certain lines you know
anyway so it's a filter function so
select then the criteria is for example
here is a uh example of Select okay so
let's let's show
it so select you of this list of list
and the function is so the input is 79
that's one of the c number so what we
are doing is that if you know um so
basically we are doing this if if this
number is between one of
these range okay so let's run
it
so it returns this range this triplet
that means this number is this triplet
is applicable for this SE number okay
but not that not the other one so so
this select will help us
find you know there are many Triplets of
a of a given map it will help us find
the first map okay now if
it returns more than one then we just
select the first one if it returns more
than one that means this range overlap
okay we don't want we just want the
first
one okay what's the question is uh does
it have multiple Frances hi Frances does
it have multiple representations of
lists
so so that so that range calculation are
efficient no uh well
internally okay so basically
no so let me explain that one so in
Python for example you have
this is the part I hate okay I forgot
what is so let me explain that one let
me digress uh let's who who else are
watching say hi okay if you don't want
me to digress you got to say something
okay put my name you know shout out kadi
say something otherwise I'm going to you
know take it easy and go where we are
and but we we all finish the problem
okay so in Python and many other
languages for examp example
um JavaScript 2 you know you started to
have
generators gener what the [ __ ] does that
mean anyway so in Python let me show you
so in Python you have a list right then
you have
um then you started to have what what
they call it
python
[Music]
uh
okay I need more
drink list methods let's have a look uh
pin to list insert item so find item
this is my Python tutorial go read it if
you don't know so
wait sorry to the derail no problem this
is what that that this is what talk show
is
about a show of talk
Talking uh this comprehension so it is
that's python this conf they they
generate a what's the word iterator the
[ __ ] most idiotic [ __ ] these
industrial programmers you know they
don't understand the thing anyway so in
Python you iterator the word iterator
can mean many things depending on
language okay don't get confused okay
but in Python specifically python an
iterator means means you have a list
okay you have a list like thing maybe a
million items or even a billion but it
actually is not there so it's like only
when you need to to get the value then
it comes out so this concept is iterator
so the the reason for the existence of
this complexity is
that is that for example sometimes you
know you want to generate let's say one
to a you you want to do a full loop you
want to generate a range of one to a
billion and then you want to go through
each one item so before Python 3 you
first of all generate the list of 1
billion
items then you do a you know enumeration
you know you go through the iteration
then you you know go through each index
of this range of building items right
but the problem is that you don't don't
want actually want the billion items
because when you actually generate a
range of billion billion items you run
out of memory okay or 100 milon right
you run out of memory so there's this
concept of iterator this is a computer
um kind of programmers concept or
computer engineering in other words this
iterator concept is a
byproduct of Computer Engineering okay
okay you don't really need it because
mathematically it it doesn't mean
anything it's just a Leist it's it's
just a way so that for you for
programmer for or for implementation or
for compiler to avoid this aut memory
problem you know so it's a intermediate
representation for like lots of items
but you get complexities of course
because now you have iterators then you
a list is not list unless you turn it
into a list you got you know several uh
in fact I have a article on that in
Python 3 you map something it [ __ ] up
you know you you got things like that
actually should I show it uh I'm I'm
starting
to I'm starting to get into a rent but
should I show show it or not yes of
course why not let's just take the time
to show
it because uh you know because this this
is actually I need to explain this well
because otherwise people will just they
don't understand they'll just say oh of
course you need to you know concerned
about memory what you're talking about
this is not pure mathematics right so
anyway so let's go back to
Sali doino uh my website then there is a
section
called why python SU
okay and I did a few live streams about
that and uh so one of the article I want
to mention is related to this iterator
thing because it creates complexity and
it
creates certain
intangible
Concepts you know in the programming
language
okay uh also this comprehension there it
is okay so Python 3 map with side effect
doesn't work if result is not used okay
this happened in Python 3 because of the
iterator thing okay so in Python 3 map
the function map now Returns the
iterator kind of abstract list instead
of a concrete list okay but now if you
use the map function to map a function
to a to a iterator or list that that's
not a you know the function doesn't
return any any value it just want to do
side effect then you got a
problem uh you see if you use map with
side effect it doesn't work if you don't
use the result so for example here's a
function uh what does this function do
Global a so it just increase Global a
and return n + one okay then
map the function 2111
and print a is
zero okay we you see we said Global a we
want to increase a by n okay uh but
however the result is a
z a
z you see
but it [ __ ] up you know so what
happens is is that the result is
contrary to your intention because this
function we explicit said we want a
global variable a and we want to
inclement it a equal a A+ n okay but
python [ __ ] it up but now if you turn
the thing to a list then it it does the
increment you see so this is a one of
the result of introducing this iterator
thing okay
okay anyway that's
um so the obvious question is how do you
solve this kind of problem if you don't
introduce
iterators
um I don't have I can
um I cannot tell you now I forgot what
was the uh uh proper solution but I
don't think iterator is a thing okay so
again remember it iterator the the
meaning of iterator can mean a lot of
different things or slightly different
things in different languages so right
now we are talking about Python's
iterator okay so you got this problem
okay so in wam language you don't have
that um no you don't have that okay so
and by the way the this kind of thing
also happen in in Java they call it they
call it um
they call it generator okay kind of also
I have a tutorial on that but let's um
let me show you in a bit okay so hold on
a
second so we went uh digression into the
iterators thing okay let's copy that put
the link here uh and uh let's go back
yeah okay so we want okay let's show
JavaScript okay so JavaScript you have
JavaScript in depth let's say search for
generators now JavaScript is even more
complex okay jav JavaScript is even more
complex the way they do the this kind of
thing even more extremely complex
generators okay let's uh let's just
let's not talk about it let's go back to
the coding of the wolam language okay so
to answer your question
the wolam language does not have um that
kind of thing
so it doesn't have you know like the the
Python's iterator okay but I believe
they are they are trying to introduce
that idea I'm kind of
against yes I believe they are trying to
in introduce some some kind of generator
idea uh and but however wfam language
does have Spar arrays meaning that for
example you have a matrix of 1 billion
items but however vast majority of them
is
zero let's say only five spots are
actual some number but this 2x two
Matrix of 1 billion items most of them
are zero so that's called Spas rate and
that's very often used in linear algebra
in in in actual
engineering you know when actual data so
that is supported so you have that kind
of thing so you don't so so but so what
I mean is that you don't actually create
a array with 1 billion entries you know
row column one 1,000 column 1,000 rows
but rather you have a special
representation for Spar array you just
specify which you know index which index
is what number so it can represent Spar
array array and you can turn it back to
a normal array but if you do then you
got out you know then you you run out of
memories things like
that okay so you know you can search for
for example uh let me show you Spar
array okay just search for spar so you
can there it is Spar AR
okay uh there it
is okay so we kind of digressed a lot uh
let's really quickly go back
because we are 50 minutes already uh
because we are starting to get into a
situation that I will not finish it
today so let's let's get back and uh
let's do it okay so let me get back to
it where is it okay so I want to Sol the
problem
okay so we show this uh we show this
select how it works it's just a filter
okay so let me get back to the
focus what do you think about Goan I
love Goan read my website okay I talked
about a lot and join s Discord because
we be just talking about Goan in the
yesterday one big
argument yeah so there's a question how
do you deal with infinite
iterators well in general you don't deal
with it okay you you don't deal I mean
so I can't tell you what is my ideal
solution right now because I forgot I
don't remember so that's what I'm saying
I cannot tell you what
what what I think is a propose approach
to the you know infinite item infinite
number of item situation so I don't know
but but I don't think I it's not the
generators and iterators okay now let me
get a drink and uh I'll be back in two
minutes and focus finishing the
problem
e
cheers orange
juice
R why of a red
variety but anyway to answer your
question I think wolam language about
few months ago I saw them you know wolam
stepan wolam they does they do online
design so you can watch them wolam and
his team and actually talk about the
upcoming features you know they actually
do online what he call online CEO so
he's doing the design you know
discussion uh in real time so one of the
the video I watched is that they are
introducing lazy thing which I I don't
think it's good idea because wolam
language has always been opposite of all
the this you know all
these Computer Engineering byproduct
Concepts okay like long int you know you
like you have this int long double thing
and or reference you know every list
every array is a reference to something
then when you update you actually
sometimes you are changing the reference
or you know you tic crap okay wolam
language has is entirely different from
that so I do not
know
how will happen you know if they
actually introduce this kind of lazy uh
um you know the generator and iterator
thing how do I feel about
rust any programming language that does
memory diddling is [ __ ] okay now we are
starting to get into you know the common
questions I've been talked to death in
my past three years of live
stream
uh so rust is [ __ ] I recommend go land
okay whenever you know you are probably
you know many of you guys asking that
because they they love rust or or C C++
see this type of people they love rust
because it allows to them to TI with
memory you know they love that I don't
love that okay any language that does
that kind of thing
[ __ ] okay finish the problem
so then you know my wife is home we
going to uh uh do dinner so so so now we
got we select one of the range so select
if so let me quickly finish okay so we
have function here what is our function
so how big is this function okay it's
just there so
select select
if okay so we
need
if I need to do this quickly okay so if
select
returns returns a empty list then
say three okay let
say else say yes
okay now let me just need to work on so
this doesn't return empty so what if
it's um 799 okay 8 okay so now it's so
if select none of this range applies
then it returns empty so empty
okay okay so now we got this uh
if so we want to apply this to let's
see okay so we need to create a function
so uh we need to create a
function
that that go through each one of these
okay so we need to create a function so
let's
see create a function the function is
going to map to each one of them okay so
function
okay
function and
uh the function
takes the function actually needs to
take a seed
too
so yeah because otherwise how do you get
the seed number so where where do we
have the
seed yeah so we got the seed here and
what is X
range okay that X range is the full
thing okay so
let's keep Focus here now let's see if
this
function no you copy that oh nice format
so you see this is before this is after
takes a trip to the wol F front end
which you have to pay to get it so
without W Front End I don't have nice
formatting I'm using W Wolf
mod which I wrote which is free on
GitHub okay so you go to this source
code this is a homepage so wam mod it
allows you to code wam language in
emac what's the benefit why do you want
to do that because then you have all the
power of manipulating text in
emac instead of the wolam front front
end uh so that's s wam mod it's free on
GitHub you
can grab it with a G GitHub link yeah
download gith Hub okay
there okay fantastic here's a source
code in emac disp of course okay close
it now why do I yeah
so but right now I don't have a feature
to reformat the wo wo language
syntax so instead I copy it to wolam
then copy it back
then I got this nice uh but I can write
it it takes more time it takes a
day to figure out how how to do that
anyway so this is our function now let's
use the new formatted one now um so this
function takes where does the map to
okay
let's let's see where does that okay so
here
fold yes okay so we are
using let's see this fold takes a seed
and flatten no we don't want to
flatten no we don't want to flatten
because we need to go
through we need to go
through you know
any set of triplet we need to go through
one of them not all of them so we don't
want flatten okay so but we still need
fold fold is like python reduce okay I
got to finish this quickly because my
wife is waiting for me for
dinner oh [ __ ] you cannot see
[ __ ] ah [ __ ] just wasted another 10
minutes
when did that happen oh [ __ ] I gotta
really let's show time stamps
so
656 okay only 5
minutes yeah okay so anyway we were
talking about w f so here's Sai mod and
here's
the download uh GitHub okay s mod uh so
okay so back to we need to finish the
code
so so this we don't want and
uh so the maps you know the maps is this
seed I mean this Maps Okay so Maps is
the right word okay
let's we don't want that okay so this
just the map we don't want flatten okay
so read of that so we map that to seeds
Okay seeds is a list of seeds numbers
okay and uh and instead of this
complicated syntax let me write it in a
way one can understand okay so map takes
two things now this part is seeds the
first thing is a function okay and the
fun function will
[Music]
be okay the function will be
actually a seed okay so a seed is the
argument and what you want to do with it
you want
to fold Okay
so
yeah so you want to
yeah so we have a function here it takes
one argument a seed am I am I doing good
yeah okay another sip for
health ching ching ching ching if you
like my Stu pay me
okay um got to finish this problem
code you need to Brin to work okay
function you take you map you map this
function to the number of seeds so each
time this function gets a seed number
once you get a seed number you want to
do fold which is python or JavaScript
reduce okay so you fold fold
takes two or three arguments the first
argument the first argument is a
function that gets the seed ID uh we
have written here the first you know get
the seed ID and the range
okay so wait
uh so you map to the map so actually
this should not be the function okay
this be something we need to work
on and and the second argument is
the fold seed map right so you so you do
a fold each time you take a
seed and uh then you
you you go through the seed to each set
of triplet so you first do this triplet
this set of triplet then you do then the
result
is a number then you take that number
then you go through this another set of
triplet returns a number then you do
repeat to the next set of triplet okay
so that is what this fold
does okay so the fold does takes a seed
now what is the function what is the
function that is a question what do you
want to pass the function okay the
function will take two arguments of
course course because fold you know so X
and Y okay so the first
is seed okay so let's uh X seed okay the
second one
is
triplets okay remember there's s
because yeah but because each time you
are given a set of
triplets meaning a list of a list of
triplets okay and uh the expression
that's what we need to code find
out okay so the expression so let's uh
kind of format it a little bit okay
so is quite tedious to format so I I
really need to find a way so I can press
a button in emac and have it formatted
well um you know wam language is superb
let me mention this thing you see you
see this thing you see they have special
like kind of like unic code characters
they and you can adjust you see as long
as you let's select it you can adjust
the window width in real time and they
will wrap
appropriately you know they they will
wrap at the
logical unit semantic unit positions
they will not
just cut into arbitrary characters okay
so you can see this is the power of
wolam language and in contrast to the
Unix and python this coding industrial
coder idiocy cc++ you know they tell you
please format your code so each line is
17 character
[ __ ] okay if we expand this window you
can see this whole thing is one single
line you know and they can it's not just
this it can be arbitrary mathematical
two-dimensional formula with involving
nested radicals or nested fractions you
know and you have this on the fly in
real time
Dynamic formatting okay
you know I have shown a nested
fractional kind of complicated math
formula before but I'm not going to do
it today so back to finish the problem
okay
fold so the fold you want So you you're
doing a fold and
you the fold the function so what's the
function for fold reduce you take two
things right a seed and a triplet and
what is the expression okay the
expression is
is is what we are doing here okay so
kind of like
um function expression okay we don't
need that so let's take that okay and
this four y out we don't need because
that's the last time we were trying to
do
that uh so we want this thing okay let's
see where do we put it properly
okay so function now takes an
expression and this is the expression
okay so this
expression it's a triplet so we need to
format to Triplet okay so the seed is
here okay and the
triplets
is
that
that that okay I believe actually I
solved the problem
already it's all
here let double
check so the function the take while oh
yeah we forgot the if statement where is
our if
statement oh yeah so if statement so
if yeah we forgot the if statement so we
need to put that here somewhere okay
so okay not not done yet okay so bear
with me so
this
take this is the triplet take the
triplet
then if
that
returns wait do we have select oh wait
why are we take while
[ __ ] oh we shouldn't take while we
should use select
[ __ ]
so this select this is the triplets
select from the
triplets and uh
if okay select from the
triplets wait we getting confused
here so this function takes a seed and
triplets a bunch of
triplets okay
and
then you let's focus on the select so
select from the bunch of triplets and
uh and this is a c number and what are
the others so the others
are select from the
triplets yeah so this is a like a
function by itself
so to write this in a simple way okay
let me show you how to write this in a
more easy to understand
way okay
so kind of like that okay so we don't
need
this so select takes a triplets a set of
triplets okay then apply this function
what does this function do this function
takes one triplet
okay okay takes one triplet
then then
uh
then
then check if the seed is the in this
one triplate and did I [ __ ] up
somewhere we don't need this okay yeah
so
what yeah so select to select takes two
argument the first argument is a list of
triplets the second argument is a
function a criteria kind of to filter
out okay and how do we filter out so if
the
triplets uh let's let's put this XX
okay so that is shorter we don't get
confused
this is a function okay so this way is
easier to
understand so in fact maybe make it one
line
that's okay so
if select that that that that
that and
uh and uh only take the first result
okay don't if there's more than one
ignore it just take the first one if it
is equal to an empty
list
then then we
say then what you want to do if it's
empty this then you return the seed
itself
okay oh
God
otherwise wait what what so you don't
need this take while remove the
complexity okay so XC triplet so
if so if it is empty then return the
seat itself what if it's not empty well
in that case you do get destination
ID in that case you call get destination
ID uh with seed and range okay
so exceed and
uh
oh but how do you assign it but you see
so select
function you need to assign this
okay so you need to create a
variable
God because right now you need to get
the value of this
select so if
that equals to that so you need to get a
value of this okay so if that is empty
then return the seed by itself
okay H there are so many easy ways must
be got to finish this got to finish
this
what is f doing here we don't need the
fold okay not too
bad function a
seed okay we don't need this this fold
thing okay
so a
function gets one argument a seed that's
one number then you do fold okay then
you do fold you pass it first of all a
function okay then you pass it a seed
which
is a seed okay then you pass it Maps
that's right Maps is a bunch of maps
okay okay and within this function what
you're going to do within this function
well this within this function
you uh with within what function oh
within this function you then call fold
okay and
fold now takes three arguments
okay uh so let's see if I can cllean up
let's just press
it let's see if W oh yeah W [ __ ]
format so nice so
nice okay so then so fold you need a
function
again a seed and triplets okay and in
this function if select
and I want
to if select by this function returns
empty then it's seed okay so fold
function
triplet fold function tripletes function
if if it's
empty then the seed
otherwise
no no that's not what it's not to
the let's not do it this way okay we got
a better way because this way is
problematic so actually this is
confusing I don't want to use this
syntax so let's do
another thing
syntax this represent our function okay
much shorter so if
select select that the first item
okay you do that
then then
you then what is a just gested function
okay let's try
it okay we have the function now get
test ID now apply
79 79 and the second part will be
uh let's
say that
okay it it works what if what if this is
empty do you get a
number okay so we need to kind
of fix that okay so get the get
destination
ID
if x range is equals to empty list then
return
seed
otherwise otherwise do this thing okay
okay so
uh copy
it there it is this is
uh you see nice formatting for move F
language delete that okay so this is get
destination ID so in
now now if it's empty it just return
itself so now we it's
better so now we just go back here so
select that okay
cut we don't even need to test the if
here okay
so remove that remove that crab so we
simply call this
function simply call this fun function
seed and
that okay
beautiful beautiful okay so remove the
if
statement in fact we are done copy
it paste here copy the code so we got
the beautifully formatted code we don't
need that we don't need this select test
okay so this is our solution this just
to this thing BAS basally I'm pretty
sure it works okay let's run
it ah part for [ __ ] part two the that
does not
exist
[ __ ] okay let's see where is wrong fold
seed exceed
triplets
get
why is that uh part two of 20 5250 48
does not
exist part two that's right we got
something here
[Music]
so select
triplets this should be applied to one
of
them select triplets so
triplets
so where is that select doesn't
work X in triplet
fold fold we need two
arguments
okay
[Music]
so so here is a
function here is a function that takes
two
arguments for the purpose of
fold Okay so
so this is a function that takes two
arguments for the purpose of fold and
uh so two argument so the first argument
is the
seed
so so fold right
so the triplet so each time the
triplets is a bunch of
triplets so here you select the
triplets and
uh tripletes has three
items two two three wait nowhere is one
referenced is somewhere should be
one
no wait so 22
three so why is that I don't
understand
so
exceed so if that's in between second
one second one is
the source beginning second one source
beginning plus the third one is range
minus one okay so that's pretty makes
makes
sense okay so this is a function that's
how you select so and uh return a
maximum of one item oh yeah so once you
got that you need to you need to take
the first item okay right I got it so
that's why this this is this is what you
want to do
okay
[ __ ]
God select all let's select all paste
restart okay still got a problem so
seats it's a list of numbers that's
right
Maps that's a set of
uh
a set of triplets
okay and we don't want to table so what
that's the first one the second one got
three numbers the first one got
two
triplets okay so you don't want table
form you want
uh yeah okay maybe that that's better
okay so you the first map two triplets
second map three triplets third map four
triplets fourth map two fifth three okay
anyway so that is the maps okay
then so you map the whole thing
to
Fe
so what is wrong so this that's a seed
then you
fold okay this fold part is where it
gets really
complicated so let's try just one of
them so this fold is where it get really
complicated so so this here the seed is
okay so something is wrong there 79 Maps
fold F through the
maps Okay each time you
get
triplets each time you get a set of
triplets and
then but you select it what's wrong with
selection God this is not
good what is wrong with the
selection
okay
so so that returns
empty what
if so that returns
one
or it may return empty okay so
wait oh so okay so I got it so it may
return empty so I got the if check is
incorrect okay so this fold function it
May return
empty select triplet okay select
triplet and you don't want to take
one
because it may return empty
so yeah part one of empty does not exist
that's what happens so once it the the
re result of Select
is either one item or a empty list
okay
so
so all you have to do is
you just flat flatten it
okay that's it I think that's
it I think that's our solution
there it is
8635 8243 8635 fantastic how many people
are
watching Four okay pretty bad and
fantastic money from
George we solve this problem okay I
think I'm pretty sure this is the
solution now copy it go to the trip of
wolam then copy it back so we got nice
formatting okay now this is the entirety
of of our solution
okay copy all select all paste okay
that's
it run
it okay now let's try the user
input okay the user
input mod so what is the users input
code oh God we need to
pause it but last time we did the
passing let's not pause it so let's go
back let's cheat and let's use this you
know we already passed the input okay
let's use that copy close that now back
up do this again now this time just
paste that delete delete
okay
copy select or paste run it okay so here
is then you just select minimum okay uh
minimum mean okay mean are you sure yeah
I'm sure shut the [ __ ] up there a code
uh paste it
submit that's the r right answer of
course okay that's it for today we can
so uh our code is just these two lines I
can shorten it I can make it one single
line but anyway let's let's forget
it that's it I'm going to go to dinner
Happy New Year to you guys
2024 and uh good
night okay so
back uh uh
What uh wait what happened looks like we
have a control key stuck ah
[ __ ]
what
what and hope I didn't erase our
solution what's going on wait so live
recording
research yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah
yeah yeah
[ __ ] oh okay then yeah the code is here
so make it pretty showing
browser there it is our
solution thank you guys for watching
bye-bye fantastic