Good morning, guys. Welcome to another
episode of sound talk show. We are going
to code Wolfram language today.
So, this is uh boring probably boring
for you. Uh Wolfram language, we're
going to write a custom function to
convert SVG
uh 2D graphics to SVG.
Uh we did we did a two videos before
coding session.
Uh episode 697
and 701.
Both of them are not successful.
So, both of them are 1 hour each. So,
this is going to be a long-term
uh this is going to be
several hours, okay? So, probably boring
for you. If you are here, say hi. If you
are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed or higher.
So, we just I'm just going to code,
okay? But, if you have questions, going
to ask me, okay?
So, Wolfram language, if you don't know
already, search for Wolfram language for
programmers. I have a complete tutorial
uh on xahlee.info
http no s, okay?
Search for Wolfram language for
programmer and you can download it for
free. Just follow follow the link.
And uh we we did I did
like
about 100 or over 100 Wolfram language
uh tutorials in the past. You can go and
watch. Wolfram language tutorial by
video on my website xahlee.info.
Okay, so we So, now
let's code. Let's just start coding,
okay? So, we're going to write So, let
me um
Let me Let me just explain what we're
going to do. We're going to go this
slowly, okay?
So, let's see. Um
SVG tutorial
for the break. Um
write a custom
function to convert
Wolfram
Wolfram language 2D graphics to SVG.
Now, the reason we need to write this is
because by default there's a export
function. You can do that.
Um
let's start Wolfram language.
But, however, it creates
kind of bloated SVG files. So,
what should be 1 kilobyte SVG file, it
creates 10 kilobyte or 50 kilobyte.
So, 10 times more.
So, that's why I want to write my own,
okay? So, let's evaluate three shift
enter to evaluate it to start the
kernel.
Let's magnify.
Okay, so that's Wolfram language. And uh
we write a custom um So, let's keep the
documentation.
We can
uh Wolfram language
Wolfram language has
export
function that can export to
export to SVG.
But,
for 2D graphics,
it
creates a file
large file.
Okay, unnecessarily so.
Uh
So, we're going to write one. So, So,
let's start, okay? So, let's um
Now, I'm using Wolfram I'm using coding
Emacs. You can see Emacs. So, um
So, let me show you a Wolfram language
graphics, okay?
Circle, we want a circle. This is
This is xah Wolfram mode.
Okay, so you can see xah Wolfram mode,
it's free.
Here's the source code. 3,000 lines of
code. Most of it is
uh most of it is the Wolfram language
functions. By default, there's there are
7,000 functions building, okay? So, you
go to this website. So, you can see xah
Wolfram language mode is on GitHub. You
can download for free. It allows you to
code Wolfram language in
Emacs. That's what I'm doing.
Uh so, circle
So, circle, you want circle at 0 0 and
radius 1, okay? Let's say radius 1.
And you want graphics 2D.
Uh
Uh graphics 2D is just just graphics,
okay? Then, put that there.
So, that's your circle. Then, then you
give options. So, let's say
axis.
Okay? So, you copy that.
Run it in Wolfram language, shift enter.
So, you got a circle, okay? So, you want
to export this to SVG. Now, I can show
you
export.
Uh export, then what is the uh
Let's see the documentation. The file
name. So, file name then expression,
okay? So, what you do is
simply
So, if you are here, say hi, okay? So,
what you do is simply um
So, let me show you, okay? Export.
This is the graphics. So, export takes
two arguments. The second argument is
the expression you want to export. The
first argument is the file name. So,
sample.svg,
okay? So, copy that.
Back to Wolfram language.
Paste it.
Uh delete that.
Okay, shift enter. Shift enter.
Okay, it's done. sample.svg. Now, you go
to documents. It's saved in documents
file. So,
documents directory.
So,
sample.svg, open it.
So, it's going to open in
in uh SVG viewer, Inkscape, I I believe.
Okay, Inkscape takes a while to launch.
Now, you see that's a Inkscape file.
SVG. And uh let's open it in browser,
okay? So, open open the folder that
shows it.
Okay, and the SVG
sample
and we can just
drag it to this. So, you can see it's a
SVG file.
So, let me copy the file path.
Yeah, copy it. So, let's go back to uh
xah talk show.
And uh let's paste the file path there.
Can you guys see it?
Am I missing? Oh god, you guys are
missing.
Okay, comments.
So, sample.svg, linkify.
So, we made it into a link figure figure
caption showing browser. So, you see
that's export by default.
Okay, so um
expect expect a left angle bracket. So,
we got a um
incorrect ex- ex- incorrect HTML syntax
because we got Wolfram language code
there. So, you need to syntax correct
and turn the
uh turn the right
greater than equal sign into the
um
ampersand encoded. So, showing browser.
So, now you can see. So, here is a 2D
graphics. Here's a export by default.
So, now let's look at the file, okay?
The file it creates. So, open it showing
Emacs as SVG. Now,
you turn it into xah HTML mode. Show it
as a text. So, this is what you get. So,
a circle becomes
um
you know, a circle becomes this
complicated
path thing.
So, the file size is 15
kilobytes.
That's not good, okay? We just
Well, actually, so you got a circle, but
you also got the axis. The axis
adds lots of things. But, anyway,
but if you
just export the circle, let's do it
again, okay?
Uh
copy the last expression.
Remove this axis equals to true.
And uh let's say sample two, okay? Shift
enter. So, it's saved. Now, go to the
directory.
So, you can see sample two. Now, open
the file. So, it's just a circle. Now,
turn it into text. Show as text now. So,
you got these few lines, okay? Now, make
this line multiple lines. So, make this
line multiple lines, okay? So, you can
see the whole thing. So, you can see
Now, it's gray. Can you see it? So,
let's turn it to uh fundamental mode.
So, now it's uh
So, you can see
Uh let's let's go to XML mode, okay?
Okay, now it's colored.
So, you can see it defines the circle
using this path expression.
Uh which is not very good because
So, anyway, so save it. Show them in
browser. So, you got
kilobytes.
I mean, bytes. 869 bytes
for simple circle.
No axis, okay?
But in SVG
Let me show you. So, if you search for
practical SVG tutorial on solid.info
http no s
then you can see there is a circle
primitive.
Basic shapes.
So, you go down go down. You see circle.
So, circle is actually just one single
line.
You specify the
coordinates for the center of the circle
and radius and that's it.
But however
However, this in this file you you got
this uh you know, you got this this this
long line path instead of this.
So, that's kind of inefficient, okay?
So, that is why that is the reason we
want to write our own export to SVG
command, okay? I want to do it, okay?
So, save this
uh
close it. So, what we going to do now,
okay? So, copy the file path. Close.
Close, okay? Let's put the
put that there.
Sample, okay?
Now
Now, let's rename, okay?
Circle
with axis.
Today's date, okay?
Then
Let's rename this to circle
simple.
Okay?
Now
move it to the directory I am in.
Do it.
And do that there, too. So, we are in in
the directory. So, in the direct current
directory I search for circle. So, you
can see circle simple, circle with axis.
Okay.
Close close that. So, showing browser
again. So, you got
that, okay? So, actually we let's
rename.
You see, we rename it properly.
Okay, refresh. There.
Okay, now we want to write a code.
Um
Let's begin to write a code, okay? So
So far so good.
Hello Geo no.
I'm missing Mathematica to support
evaluating expressions and cursor
staying on the same line.
Uh
Yeah. So
So, you mean so for example, my cursor
is here. I can scroll up to somewhere
else, but if I press right arrow, it'll
go back to where my cursor is, which is
not the case with Emacs. For example, I
move the cursor to the top
and I scroll down
the cursor just you know, the cursor
just
keeps moving within the visual range.
So, the cursor moves with whatever you
can see on the screen. So
that is the case with Emacs.
However
uh in Emacs, if you want you know, kind
of
What that does basically is basically
save position. You can easy do that. For
example, if you move to let's say here
you want the cursor to stay there. So,
you
uh you
mark it.
A mark, you know, you just mark it. Then
you go go go go somewhere. Then you can
um
uh jump to previous mark. So
that would be press press press. You
see?
So, you can see the pink window.
I have a command called
xah-pop-local-mark-ring,
but you can also do it without my custom
command.
So, Emacs allows you to save positions
in a file.
In fact, multiple of the of them. Like
by default 16 positions. You can
increase it if you want. So, you can
actually keep jumping
um
For example, yeah I can
You can you can keep jumping between
locations, okay? That's um
Okay, I'm I'm not quite sure what you
mean.
But anyway, so let's go back to the
code. So, we we want to start to write
the code, okay?
Which is not trivial.
This is my uh
my suffering of typing too much for the
past 15 years. This pain here.
Okay, let's get back to code. So, what
we want to do now is
we want to start to code
turning 2D graphics into a basically
into a text
the SVG uh format. So, let's let's So,
here is SVG.
So, do I have Yeah, so there's SVG
tutorial. SVG is basically XML, okay?
Uh just simple XML. So, essentially you
want to turn
For example, here is the Wolfram
language syntax for graphics.
Circle is a primitive.
Now, in SVG
you also have a circle primitive.
You know, so in SVG it looks like that
syntax. In Wolfram language, it looks
like that.
And this graphics is just a wrapper to
represent that the whole thing is a 2D
graphics. And in SVG is just a SVG tag.
So, you want to convert them, okay?
Um you know, it seems simple, but
actually it's quite a lot things
involved. So, let's begin to code that,
okay?
Uh okay, so what we going to do now? So,
let's plan the so
So
Okay, we going to start coding. Start
coding is always
then it becomes
difficult. That's the hard part.
Okay, so we
um
So, let me just write down my thoughts
because that's my habit.
Essentially
essentially
turn
Wolfram language
graphics syntax to SVG
text. So, first of all, let define the
function. Um we want to write a function
that
So
Let me comment it, okay?
By default, you can export to SVG like
that, okay?
Then
Okay, then we Okay, to close that.
Um
Okay, so let's go let's begin to write
our function. So, here, okay? Wolfram
language code
and
some
comments here. Essentially, turn Wolfram
language graphics syntax to SVG text.
That's right. So, we we Okay, syntax
correct.
Now
open it. Now, we write write a function
X
Okay, so to X SVG
string. Okay, let's say that's what I
want for now, okay? That's the function.
So, that's the function.
Clear.
Clear that symbol first. Then we
So, um So, this function basically going
to look like that. Then here is a code,
okay? That's how you define a function.
And here is parameters.
Is Wolfram language
uh So, question. Previous cell and
edited. further in notebook Jupiter or
Pluto, I have noticed problem.
Uh what?
Is Wolfram language or some
three-letter sequence Wolfram language
done by AutoHotKey?
Uh
I think what you are asking is this
feature W L U.
Space, it become Wolfram language and
go to my Emax abbreviation file. So,
search for
Wolfram. So, you can see
those are defined here.
So, that's just abbreviation.
Uh you can set it up by
going into this tutorial. Just search
for oxali.info
Emax setup hundreds of a brief.
Okay, I talked about this many times. I
like um
few years ago, I did a video more than
one video. So, I mean, I talked about
this more than one time. So, you you
might check it out or simply just go
through this page uh and you'll find
in 5 minutes, you'll have it. Okay?
And by the way, this feature today is
also on the Mac and also on Windows. You
can define
um on the Mac, you can define a
system-wide abbreviation. So, if you
type U, it becomes Y O U. If you type
BTW,
it can become by the way. You know, or
how are you or whatever you want.
Or your company name.
Uh you know,
you know, so very useful.
So, you can check out this page. Okay,
so let's close that. Uh that's
abbreviation feature of Emax.
But available on the Mac as well.
And I I believe in Windows, too. Uh but
I I don't know in the Windows case, I
don't know if it's system-wide or not.
Okay? So, let me paste the link there.
Okay, showing browser today's talk show.
So, we started to code here.
Uh let's go back to code and uh so
So, the other question is
uh previous cell and added it further in
notebook Jupiter or Pluto, I have
noticed problem.
Uh I'm not sure what you mean. So, I
guess you are using notebook Jupiter or
Pluto. So,
in anyway, I yeah, I'm not sure you're
talking about
Is is it a problem in Wolfram notebook
or is it a problem in
Jupiter?
And what you mean what what exactly is
the problem? So,
So, anyway, let's go back to the code.
So, this function
This function, now let's write a usage
example. Okay, so um
E uh yeah, if you want to define a
inline documentation, this is how you do
it. Okay?
Uh so, let's write the documentation.
Um
2D
return a string
that is SVG
representation
of
2D graphics. Okay?
So, that's a documentation.
And this 2D graphics
Um so so wait, it's just say graphics.
Uh let's say let's say X. Okay, so X
graphics.
Now, what is X graphics?
X graphics is any expression
with
head uh oh god.
Head.
Okay, so that's
Basically, that just means
any graphics something something. Okay?
So, that's our documentation.
Now,
so we need to start to write it. Okay,
so
So, first of all, let's take the
simplest example such as this.
Uh
god.
You know, we have to begin somewhere
because the whole thing is fairly
involved. But you know, let's break down
the problem and solve one thing at a
time. So,
So, first of all, let's try simply just
convert this example, the simplest
example.
Uh and this this option graphics true,
let's
So, wait. So, let's let's not worry
about it now. But how do you do it?
Okay, so
Let me think.
So, first of all, you have to look at
how do you represent a circle? Okay, in
in our example.
So, what we want is
you know, something like that. It needs
to become that.
Now, forget about
the header, but let's just focus on
that. Okay?
So, when you have that turn into a
string. So, circle
the
gist of a circle primitive is
the coordinates for the origin and
radius. Okay, that's the
essence. Okay? So, that's that.
Then style.
Style, you need to worry about later
because because then you can have
colored circles and and and thickness of
the circle.
So, you worry about that later. So, but
first of all,
you want to convert any
circle
to this string.
Okay, so
So, anything
Let's say anything
graphics. So, this part
This part is a pattern matching.
What this means is
the underscore means match anything.
Now, underscore followed by something,
that means match anything
that
has the head graphics. So,
So, that means like that.
So,
So, this you know, this will match
anything graphics bracket anything
inside. Okay?
Uh
then
the GRA in front just give it a name.
So, once you match it, that expression
you can refer to
by that. That's a pattern matching.
Symbolic pattern matching in Wolfram
language. Okay? So, here you can just
refer graphics. So, if you do this, if
you run this code, it just return
itself. It does nothing.
Uh but you can say graphics plus two or
whatever, then it you know, that's how
you do it.
So,
Okay, so we got So, um
So, the graphics is named graphics. You
need to turn it into a string. Okay?
Now, remember you need to turn it into a
string. So,
Okay, so question, in Wolfram problem, I
can evaluate some expression.
It automatically creates new group where
typing cursor
jumps. And if I want to continue on the
expression, I have to manually go to the
previous cell.
Why? What What do you mean? What do you
mean by that?
So, in Wolfram problem, I can evaluate
some expression.
It automatically creates new group
where typing cursor jumps.
And if I want to continue on the
expression, I have to manually go to the
previous cell.
Well,
for example, I type three,
press shift enter,
the cursor position is at the bottom.
So, now if I type four,
it creates a new cell. You see, let me
magnify.
So, I'm not sure what
Have you been using Wolfram notebook for
a long time or like what Like are you
new
to Wolfram language or are you
experienced Wolfram language and you are
making a complaint? Because
Because if you are experienced Wolfram
language, then
then
you know, you probably know what you're
saying, but if you are totally new,
maybe there's something you don't
understand. So,
then my answer would be different. So,
you know, whenever you type something 3
+ 3, shift enter,
the cursor
now become you see you see that
blinking
the cursor is is at bottom. So, if you
type something new, shift enter,
you know, so you don't have to I I I
don't have to go back like
Okay, you are not the new, but I don't
know exactly what you mean.
Create a new group where typing cursor
jumps and if I want to continue on the
expression, I have to manually go to No,
for example, let's say here.
So, right here is a three. Now, I want
to edit it. I just click there and let's
say plus one. Okay, now I shift enter,
then I I got four.
So, obviously, if you want to edit
previous cell, you have to go there,
click it, you know, click there or click
here or click here.
If you want to modify previous cell. If
you don't want to modify previous cell,
then then the cursor is always at
bottom.
Like if I edit the first cell, let's say
plus two,
then shift enter,
then the cursor is right below that
cell.
Obviously, because I just modified it.
So, now if I type again, it's going to
begin a new one here.
You know, for for three, right? So, if I
want to modify this part, I go there.
So, I type 3 + 3, it up outputs six. I
want to type in the same cell 3 + 3 + 3
in the above cell.
I need to go to the previous previous
cell.
Okay, I don't quite understand what
you're saying. I haven't used Jupiter,
okay?
And so, I type 3 + 3, it outputs six.
I want to type in the same cell 3 + 3 +
3.
Okay, so basically you want to modify it
in above cell. I need to go to the
previous cell. Yes.
Jupiter has control enter and shift
enter.
And one of them does not create new
cell.
Okay, so you are saying, you know, let's
say Let me try to understand.
So, 3 + 3, shift enter,
right? So, the cursor moves down. Now,
what you are saying is that you want to
continue
mother you know, continue your previous
cell.
So, in Wolfram language, you just press
arrow, you know, go back or or click on
it. But you are saying
you are saying that in Jupiter
it has control enter, so
Well, you know,
what you are saying you know, is not
complete. So, I'm not sure what you
mean.
But basically, you are saying that you
want to continue
modifying the previous cell without
having to like go you know, press arrow
up or click it.
You are saying something like that.
Uh and then you can type expression
continuously. I don't get it. What Why
do you want to type continuously? If you
want to type expression continuously,
you don't you don't evaluate it.
You know, you you don't evaluate it.
Let's say that. You know, so once you
evaluate it,
now
if you you want to Okay, maybe you made
a mistake or maybe you want to see you
know, change a value to see something
different, what's the result? In Wolfram
language, what you do is you can press
control L.
Okay, control L will copy the previous
input.
Okay, and and
yeah.
So, it's just different wo- wo-
different workflow. Okay.
Uh yeah, I hope that clears it up. You
know, I guess it's just different
workflow.
Okay, let's go back to this. Uh
we not going to finish this in 1 hour
and in fact, so I plan to
to do this
you know, in five five hours maybe or
more. So, 1 hour each
live stream. So, I I will stop
you know, I'll stop maybe in 30 more
minutes, then
it'll be next live stream.
And maybe even today later today. So,
this is going to be a long session.
So, we haven't we haven't even
got started, okay? So, okay.
I need to think about these, okay?
Because
So, right now I have hand surgery hand
pain.
Okay, so you got a expression
and basically you want to
replace
part of the expression by a string,
okay?
So, let me let me just let me just start
to code and see what happens.
Uh what the hell is this done?
Let's just look up random, okay? Let's
look up my uh Wolfram language tutorial.
So,
what you want is basically this is
pattern matching. How you going to do
this, okay?
So, graphics.
So, graphics graphics
In fact, inside it it may contain
hundreds of circles
and other things such as line or
rectangle or whatever.
So,
you want to
you want to tie it to text
um
s-
So, you don't want to Okay, so how do
you So, let's look at pattern matching.
It's Let me just uh refresh.
Uh I forgot.
When
coded Wolfram language for a while, but
so let me just do something random here,
so I can kind of
so that
maybe I'll get
it, okay?
So,
s- so, circle
circle, if you do that,
uh
Okay, so circle
uh circle is al- always got two
elements, okay? So, two elements
X
Y, okay? And this is the radius uh
Okay, so
that's right. So, circle is typically
So, here is a pattern to match any
circle, okay?
So, when you see that, you want to turn
it into
You want to tie it into this thing,
okay? So,
Okay, so you need to
feel yellow, stroke blue, feel none,
okay? So,
stroke width, okay? Those are annoying,
so
you need to escape the string.
Okay, yeah, now that's better.
So, if you So, what this means this
means replace all, okay?
Okay, look up the documentation for
replace all.
So,
>> So, hello GCS.
Uh
so so let me show you guys what's going
on here, okay? Replace all.
Now
Now replace all took takes two
arguments. One is expression
one is rules. So, it will replace
part of the expression or whatever
when it matches rules. Rules is a list
of like
left-hand side and right-hand side,
okay? So, and this replace all can also
be written
like this, okay? Let me show you.
Okay? So, these two are same are exactly
the same because whenever Wolfram
language sees shortcut like that, it
turns it into this fully nested
expression, okay? So, this slash dot is
a shortcut syntactical shortcut to the
replace all, okay?
So
Now
what I want to do is let's solve this
this So, we're going to call replace
all, that means whenever you see this
pattern, circle
braces X something Y something then R
something, then turn it into
uh turn it into actually
Actually, this should be uh wait.
This should be here, okay? So, this is
the rule, okay?
And uh here is expression, okay? So
Okay, this replace all any expression
then whenever you see your circle of
this pattern
change it to that, okay? So, actually
here is
incorrect because this is hardcoded. So,
oh god. So,
we not we need to do um
some kind of string template and or
concat.
Okay, because this 50 needs to be X,
okay? So
uh string
Okay, you can use string join, yeah.
Okay, let's use string join, okay?
So, now you need to
unescape quotes, okay? Now we go back to
this.
Y
R
So
right
So, now or you can use string template.
Uh
let's focus
one thing at a time. Let's not get too
complex, okay? So, but let's copy it so
we can later on try string template. But
for now
uh for now this is So
Uh if you use string join, that's going
to be tedious.
So, you're going to say something like
that
then X, okay?
Then
uh
Okay, then X actually then
then
And this is not good. Then Y
something like R
then R
Okay, then you need then okay, then
did it then you got style.
Uh okay, so
Okay, then that
Yeah, wait. Can't
uh Uh so, why does this Okay, so you
need to remove that.
So, something like that, okay?
So, whenever you see the circle pattern
like that
you want to into a string
like that.
Does that actually work?
We we can try it, okay? So
Let's just try it, okay? So, there. So,
run it.
Let's see what's the output.
Probably maybe wrong.
Okay, so general stop for the output of
string join, string will be suppressed
during this calculation because
string string expected at position six
in circle, okay?
That's right because
Okay, several errors. So, the reason is
because this X is not a string, it's a
number, it's zero.
So, string join is not a good solution.
You want to use string template.
You know, and also string join is ugly
because you got this, you know, you want
to use some kind of template.
Okay, so template So
So, now let's go back to um
So, Wolfram taste talk show, let's go to
Wolfram language for programmers.
Let's go to string, everything you
wanted to know about string.
Okay, comments print string.
Introduction, string escape
and string functions. Let's see string
functions get substring by index, get
substring by pattern
delete substring. Let's see string
functions, okay? This is how you get
how you list all functions on string.
Okay, so
and is string length, so
and what we want is some kind of
template. For example, in Python or
Emacs it's called format.
From inherited from C programming
language.
Okay, but in Wolfram language it's not
format, okay? So, there's a string
template and string join. Let's look at
string join, okay? String join, you got
this syntax and you got this shortcut.
Uh yeah, so No, so you see what we need
to do is you need to add two string. Uh
so, it's not good solution because it's
too tedious here.
So, you can you need to say two string.
Now this is kind of like JavaScript
because JavaScript you also got this
problem, two string two string.
Uh but actually JavaScript auto convert.
Okay, so
Okay, so now
Now let's remove the error, okay? Now
let's run this, let's see.
Now you see the code is not pretty.
This, okay? Now
Run it.
Fantastic and beautiful and the wrong.
X You see, they they didn't get
converted. This X and Y didn't match for
some reason.
And also the quote got Oh yeah,
you you should have
Wait.
What?
Simpson Simple Postman says Hexa
just passing by and wanted to say hello.
Hello.
Yeah, the keyboard is great.
Uh
How do I make my own internet net work
protocol?
Well, if you're going to make your own
internet protocol for yourself, it's
trivial.
Let's say here is Emacs.
Uh
Let's say
Uh let's say so, you know, so if you
have another program
let's say VS code or whatever or another
program you wrote you can make your two
programs talk in your own protocol.
So, Emacs for example, I can
make Emacs
send messages to another application
called interprocess communication.
There are many ways. So, one way is you
send it by
uh
What is it? Uh uh
you know, like
inter- interprocess communication, okay?
I've coded that long time ago.
Interprocess
socket, okay? You can So,
one program can send messages or text or
whatever, bytes, to another program via
socket.
Socket is one of the most common.
Okay, so let's see interprocess inter-
interprocess communication, okay? So,
processes operating system client
distributed microkernel nanokernel
whatever disadvantage approaches file
file, obviously. You can save a file,
then the other program can read it.
Communication file, yeah, that's uh
okay, that's that's some something
exotic. So, signal Okay, signal. Okay,
there is socket, okay? So,
you can do that. So,
how do you create a socket? You can read
the Emacs manual, I forgot.
Uh then
anyway, so one program can send
something via socket to another program
and uh
and uh this socket originally is from
Unix, but it's on uh Windows as well.
So, but what do you send?
What exactly, you know, when you when a
program receives something, how does it
know? How does it interpret it it? How
does it know if it's receiving, let's
say, Python code or JSON code or XML
code or if it's receiving Emacs Lisp
code or Wolfram code? It doesn't know.
That's when protocols come in.
So,
if you are just creating for your own,
you don't need you don't you know,
basically that's what protocol is.
You don't even need to write a spec
because you know, you know, you just
assume implicitly I'm going to send
JSON, okay? So, one
you know, one program sends JSON, the
other one
got information and it knows it's JSON
because both programs you wrote it.
So, basically you have a your own
protocol. It's you know, it's just like
uh
no protocol protocol because you it's
just JSON, okay? So, but JSON is a
protocol by itself.
So, if you want to get elaborate, you
can say some part of sometimes you want
to send JSON, sometimes you want to send
actually
uh let's say ex- HTML text, sometimes
you want to say something something
else, bytes, stream of bytes.
Then you started to have headers, you
know, in like in a header you'll say
whatever, then that's then you started
to think about protocol. So, essentially
that's what
it is. So, I I don't know what what you
mean. So, but if you want your protocol
to be used by the public,
okay? And the question The answer to
that is basically impossible.
You can create however elaborate
protocol, you know, however well
designed, but nobody is going to use it,
okay?
Uh because they are controlled by big
corporations.
Okay, that's about that. So, let's see
next
um
Fantastic and beautiful and wrong.
That's right.
So, anyway, so we got this Yeah, so it's
uh it's still incorrect, though.
Oh, I know why because
Now, remember when we use replace all,
do you guys remember? Okay, this is
See, I I can't call this
uh live because everything I do, I need
to explain 10 minutes.
So, it's not going to work
for making much progress. But anyway,
let me explain. So, when you call
replace all,
it takes two arguments, expression and
rules, okay? A list of rules. So, we got
expression, we want to replace this
expression and we got a rules. This is a
rule.
And the rules, you have the left-hand
side, which is a circle pattern, then
the right-hand side is this string join
string, right?
Now, the rules, this the this, you know,
more more than that because the rules
then
Okay, let me go to my tutorial. So, you
can see string join.
So, let me go to pattern matching, okay?
Number, Boolean, list, expression, atom,
variable, conditional, loop, iteration,
pattern matching
advanced. So, you click on that new tab.
Okay, pattern matching that
basically explain the entire thing. So,
you have to spend like 30 minutes
to understand it. So, this is symbolic
pattern matching.
More advanced than Haskell or or Camel
or F sharp.
So, in
in a way it's uh kind of like Lisp
macros, okay?
But far more elaborate. Lisp macro is
like do nothing.
So, pattern matching, so you have
left-hand side So, you have to specify
rules, left-hand side, right-hand side.
Now,
Now, when you
Now, the rules, there are two types,
rule
uh and the rule delayed, okay? So, one
type is just rule with a shorthand
syntax of that.
Okay, of a arrow, left-hand side to
right-hand side. That's rule.
So, the other rule is rule delayed, you
use this um
So, that's what I'm doing that that's
what I need to do. You use colon greater
than, okay? That That means rule
delayed. What So, what's the difference?
Rule delayed means when when you when
you find a pattern that match that,
okay? Then you give the pattern, you
know, the actual matched part to be X,
Y, and R.
You name them, right?
Then you replace by
by this expression, okay?
You see, by this expression. Now,
there's a question. Do you want to
evaluate the replacement expression
right away
or not?
You see, in our case, if you evaluate
this part right away, it doesn't work
because
at the time before you match, you don't
know what is X. You don't know what is Y
and you don't know what is R.
You only know them
when you run them, right? So, you don't
want to evaluate this part right away
because if you do,
this two string X is just X,
you know, because X has no value.
So, that's why we got that.
Now, if we do that, let's run it. You'll
fix the problem, okay?
So, run it.
Fantastic and beautiful and not totally
correct. So, but anyway, we got this 0 0
1, correct, okay? Now, the quotation is
wrong, okay? So, the quotation
uh this is
Oh, yeah, so you need uh backslash.
This escape mechanism is the worst
design possible from programming
languages.
About 2 months ago or 3, I did a live
stream talking about the design of
programming language string.
Okay, and we explained this for like an
hour.
I think there are two videos, so 2
hours.
So, this is the worst possible.
This
escape mechanism it came from the C
idiots, okay? C and Unix.
And which spread to all basically all
programming languages. You don't want
that, okay? So, watch my video about 3
months ago.
Just search for, you know, on YouTube
string syntax design.
So, this is the worst That's why,
you know, so now we have to like
worry about. So, you see, you need uh uh
wait, so you need you need that there,
then you need that there, make it
completely ugly. Uh you need that that
there.
Yeah, okay, so now do it again and see
if we fixed it.
Now, it's better, okay? X equals to 0, Y
equals to 0, R equals to 1. Style, okay,
we don't care. So, that's kind that's
correct.
Uh when Wolfram language prints a
string, it doesn't print the quote
quotation mark it outside, okay?
So, anyway, so that is
So, we kind of made some progress, okay?
So, this replace this remove that, okay?
We don't want uh
Okay, so
right now we are using string joined,
okay? Let's just leave it be. So, let's
copy that and run this in Wolfram
language so we can see
um
different rendering, okay? So, shift
enter.
There it is. Fantastic, okay? So, that
is one example of replacing a circle,
okay? So, now let's change the
expression to be something more than
just that, okay?
So, copy that, paste it here.
Uh so, put that there. That's uh put
Now, let's for the expression, let's
make it a list. So, it's just
more than one circle, okay?
So, let's say this one is circle at some
other part of some other position, okay?
Let's say that.
Run it.
So, we got two circles. Let's see.
So, let's see. So, here is the first
part, correct? This is the second part,
correct? And you got the null.
That's right, because you you you
shouldn't have that. So, that is
correct.
So, fantastic, okay?
So, this is the example of um
So, this is the example of Let's see.
Let's Let's run again.
Yeah, so here is the example of
um
You know, here this is the example of
of
turning expressions
of circle primitive to SVG circle
primitive.
Okay? Now, let's go back and let's let's
remove our um
Okay, now let's go back to our
uh problem. So, let's
make it into our function. So,
Okay, so we can just copy this part and
uh
and replace it by that, okay? So, we
define that
graphics is any graphics and this part
is just GRA, okay? Our graphics.
Okay, that works. In fact, we can
uh
copy it.
And we can actually run it, okay?
Actually.
So, for example, let's run our code. So,
cut
paste.
Okay?
So, you see we define our function there
and we
call our function here.
Yeah, that should work, okay? So, let's
uh let's um
Let's copy the whole thing. So, this
This is the example, okay?
Let Let me comment it.
Wolfram language circle syntax.
Okay?
Okay, so
for this part
and Wolfram language graphics
needs to
become
Okay, so is that clear? So, does that
helps explain? So, let's put this back
and put um
put the explanation code here.
Um
Well, yeah, so
Wait.
Okay, so
Put it there
and
uh
that's syntax correct. So, today's talk
show
we showed examples
comments and here is our code
and let's work on this code, okay?
So,
So, let's move it out yet first of all.
So, here is a sample.
Okay.
Basic
example of
replacing
circles, okay? That's hard-coded code.
Kind of works, okay? Put it back.
Now,
this is our function.
Okay?
Copy it, go to Wolfram language and
paste it
and shift enter.
Okay, wrong.
Return says a string that is SVG
representation X graphics is any, okay?
But what Oh, that's right, because
because what happens, this is correct.
But you get this error, that's because
this graphics
wherever you have graphics expression,
you know, with the head graphics that
means the inside of it should be valid
graphics primitives, okay? But what we
did is that we replaced the inside by a
bunch of string. So, they are not valid
graphics primitives. So, when you return
graphics something invalid that's what
you get this, okay? This is supposed to
be a graphics, okay? So, this is
expected. So, we can make some fix
uh by just um
by just um
Okay, so we need to fix by the graphics.
Okay, so we just change this
graphics, okay? So, this means Let me
show you guys, okay? So, this this
So, you see what whatever is inside is
supposed to be a pattern, okay? So, in
fact, this this left-hand side, the
whole thing is a pattern.
So,
this is the way we define a function.
in Wolfram language, okay? But the the
left-hand side is actually a symbolic
pattern, okay? So, you want You are
saying essentially we are saying
whenever you see something that is, you
know, X graphics to SVG string
then followed by square brackets
then followed inside is let's say uh we
can have it like anything.
Okay? Whenever you see that
then
then evaluate that part, replace it by
this part. That's what it That's
That's how this entire thing works.
It is essentially defining a function,
okay?
Now, we want to narrow it down by saying
that the the pattern should be something
graphics, okay? Then something inside.
Then
then anything. Okay, so the Whenever you
see this pattern
something something bracket then
graphics then bracket then something
inside. The
the low line means match anything.
So, when when you match this pattern,
replace it by this, okay? So, that will
work. But however, now the pattern, you
don't have a name, so you you need to
give it a name by saying GRA. That will
do it, okay?
So, when you see that
then you you do the replace all then
just pass GRA without without the
graphics.
Okay, that that will work, okay? So,
copy the whole thing. Let me show you.
Paste it there.
Shift enter.
So, you see it output. So,
this output is from
this usage in-line documentation. So, we
can like
put a semicolon at the end. That will
suppress it.
Okay, and this output is the actual
output of our function. Fantastic. So,
let's run it again.
Shift enter. So, you can see
correct and beautiful, okay?
So, let's um
for now
let's make a screenshot of these two.
So, so that we have like a record of
what we did. This is actually working.
Fantastic.
Okay, let's magnify again.
Maybe that's it for today and for for
this video, then we continue next
episode, part two.
In about 2 hours, maybe.
I think.
Should I do another one today? Uh so,
Okay, who else is watching? Who is
watching?
Report.
Two people.
Okay, fantastic. We got this um
Now
Now, let's put it back. Pull ahead.
Showing browser.
Fantastic. We got sample SVG.
Then we showed the basic Wolfram
language syntax for
circle.
Then we showed the default export,
which is what you see here.
And we explained why they are
inefficient.
When you look at the code, okay?
I mean, so this kind of bloated.
So, we then we want want to write a
program that
essentially does converts
uh circle pattern to Wolfram
language
syntax for
2D graphics shapes to the SVG version,
but in string.
Okay. Then we did a basic example that
works. Then we turned into a function
that works. Now, there's the one part
missing.
Because when you have a SVG uh
you need this header SVG tag.
So, that header would be analogous to
the Wolfram language graphics header.
So, why don't we
add this part, and let's
say that'll be that for today. So,
so somehow so it's like uh complete.
Okay, so we just need that.
Okay, so um
So, this this function only converts
circle, but there's also line and
rectangle and
and like
six or seven or maybe 10 of them. So, we
need to do more than that. This is just
for circle.
And how do you add this header? Um
Okay, so what you can do is string join.
It's going to be ugly, okay? So, let's
copy the whole thing.
Let's just make a new one here.
And let's just copy that, okay? We're
going to work here.
Um
So, here the result is a list, a list of
strings.
But you don't want a list. You want to
turn, you know, because SVG is just uh
you know, you just have a bunch of
circles. You don't have
Do you have separators? No.
So, SVG
you know, you just have a bunch of bunch
of circles.
So,
So, in other words, what we need to do
is you have
you have something like
let's say A
B
C, okay?
So, what Okay, here is here's a here's a
subproblem. Let me show you.
So, wherever you see this this Wolfram
language expression, you want to turn it
into
you want to turn it into um
Where is that header?
Okay, so you want to turn it into
You want to turn it into
that.
Okay, you want Whenever you see that
in Wolfram language, actually uh
Wait.
Whenever you see that pattern, you want
to turn this into that.
Okay, how do you do that? Yeah, that's
not
not difficult, okay?
Well, you can you can just say
string join.
Oh my god, I haven't coded
haven't seriously coded Wolfram language
for a while.
Um
Okay, let me look at
Let me look at
So, let's go to string again.
So, string join.
Substring, get substring.
Uh what What is it we want to do? We
want to turn a list of string
We want to turn the whole thing into a
string. Okay.
So,
So, basically just ignore the graphics.
Right? And inside a list
String join will work directly with a
list, okay? Let's see.
In fact,
let's run it.
There it is. It will work directly, or
you can in fact you can just use this
advanced method.
Okay.
That will work too.
Fantastic, okay? That's what you do.
So, exactly.
So, so here you want to
So, if you have a list of circles, then
that then
you just say
string join.
at
Okay, I think that's what
I think.
So, let's remove here.
Uh so
What is this?
So, here So, here is the function, and
we have a improved function.
Improved version. Wait. God, let me just
delete it. Undo, undo.
Uh please undo them back.
Yeah.
Okay, so this part
Cut.
Comment out.
Okay, and our new function
is this part, okay?
So,
So, copy that. Copy, copy, copy. Copy.
And And this time, let's give it two
two circles, okay? Instead of just one.
Okay?
Then this a different circle radius, I
mean centered at zero
two.
Okay, so copy
this.
Go back here.
Paste it.
Shift enter.
Okay, incorrect.
Improperly formatted option head. I
don't understand. So, wait.
Oh, that's right. Okay, so
Oh, yeah. So, you are missing
uh
You net needs to be there. Okay.
Copy.
Okay, let's just try it.
Delete.
What? Delete.
Paste.
Shift enter.
Uh
no.
What?
Shift enter.
Yes. Oh, yeah. You forgot.
You forgot a list.
Okay, so you need a list there. You
can't
Okay.
So, copy that.
Copy.
Call the function
to it.
Fantastic and beautiful. Well, not not
exactly. So, it's still not fixed.
Um
Yeah, so
So, this is working 0002.
But, the whole thing. Oh, yeah, because
we
we forgot we Yeah, so let's do it one
more time.
Copy.
New
notebook. Paste it.
Magnify.
Shift enter.
Fantastic and beautiful. You see, it's
just a list. It's a string. You see,
there's no comma. It's not a list
because XML, you know, you don't need
comma.
I mean, it's just, you know, elements
followed by another elements.
So, but now you just add add the header.
So, where where was that header? There.
Okay. So, now you just add
um
Here is a sample header. This we don't
need anymore.
So,
string join
Okay, so this string join
Yeah, this is ugly. Okay, ugly but
Well, okay, so let me let me just do it.
Okay, so
So, that is your string and this means
string join short syntax.
And then
put the paren.
Then
string join short syntax, then
SVG.
Okay.
There.
Okay, so
this is our function.
Do you guys understand? Anyone still
following? Do you guys understand what
I'm doing?
So, this is our new function.
So, let's see. So,
So, here's a left-hand side
and here's a right-hand side. The
right-hand side has three parts.
The first part is this SVG header. It's
a string.
Then this less than greater than, that's
a shortcut for string join.
Okay, so you can see that's just
shortcut for string join. Okay.
So, you basically join this header by
whatever the result of that
which is a bunch of circle elements.
Then you again join that. Okay.
The end of SVG tag. So, now if you copy
the whole thing, copy.
Go back here.
Select all.
Delete. Paste. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Okay, you forgot to comment
out this part.
You don't need that.
Okay, but the result is fantastic.
Okay, that's it for this one and let's
think about
the next video. We're going to continue
to do this. Okay, but so let's clean up,
summarize, and wrap up.
Okay, so so here is the code and let's
remove
this um
Do you guys understand? I guess not.
Okay, let's
uh so
Cut it. So, let's put it back here.
And then let's make a new Wolfram paste
it there.
And let's syntax color everything. Show
in browser. So, if you go all the way
down
here is our final code.
So,
what this code does is this function we
defined
which will take the graphics and return
a string that is SVG representation of
the graphics.
Okay.
And it is incomplete because right now
this this function only do circles. It
doesn't do
um
lines or rectangle or any other.
Because if you don't know, if you go to,
you know, my our previous talk show, we
did a lot Wolfram language graphics.
Look
Look at this example. So, all these are
done by Wolfram language. You know,
there's circles, lines, and lots of
other things.
And
then
um
you know, so you also need code to
convert lines and rectangles and and
dots and others.
Um
So, it only converts the circle shape.
So, but it's now we have the framework.
It's
Now, it's easier to see. Okay, so it's
not actually not so difficult. We did it
uh in in about in in like two hours.
Okay.
So, now
actually it's actually a lot more
complex because right now we haven't
dealt with colors yet.
Once you have color, thickness
and
it's going to be a lot more complex
because in Wolfram language the color
placement is very different from
the SVG.
The SVG you just attach it in at you
know, there are several ways to attach
colors
both in Wolfram language and in SVG.
You know, in SVG
you can attach color just like CSS. You
can just like HTML and CSS.
You can have them in line such as like
here.
You know, style equals to something
something.
Or you can have them
at the beginning of the file.
Uh let's say specifying style. You know,
you can so you can specify in style.
Either either using SVG element
attribute
or using inline style style equals to,
you know, the style attribute. Or you
can use
um
as a file header.
Or you can use external
CSS file. So, there are four ways to
attach
colors and thickness and transparency,
things like that to SVG element.
Now, in Wolfram language
there are also many ways, okay? But,
they are very different from SVG. So,
one way one of the simplest is like is
you just put a color in front of the
primitive. So, whatever
So, once you set a color, that color
affects
the rest of the drawing.
So, it's kind of sequential. So, that's
one way. But, another way is like you
can wrap a style
then put the put the whatever shape
inside the style. So, it's like more
logical. Style
then square bracket then whatever shape,
color, lines, or what whatever.
So, so all those inside will have that
style. You know, the style can specify
color and thickness, and so on.
So, that's another way.
Um
And, you know, so there are several ways
to specify color in Wolfram language.
So, but what you need to do is you you
want to restructure the Wolfram color
into
into the SVG color structure.
Um and how do you want to do that? You
see, first of all, you you need to
decide
which way
you want to do it in your SVG output. Do
you want them to be
per element?
Like, if you have a bunch of colors all
red
but you have to say red for each and
every element.
That's the simplest, you know, one color
attribute attached to one element.
But, you got repetition.
Um
Or, you can you know, you can you can
specify internal
CSS, you know, in the file header.
Then then you need ID for each element.
So, that kind of gets complex. Or, you
need grouping.
Um
Yeah, so the easiest way the simplest
way is simply to attach a
style to
each SVG element.
Okay, so the problem is to convert the
Wolfram structure color to the SVG,
which is not trivial, okay?
So, there's a lot to do. So,
but you know,
but we made we we begin it.
Okay, I think that's it for this one.
So, let's look at the talk show the
final form of our talk show notes.
Which is
very good. Today's
live stream is pretty good.
Uh
I think I explained everything.
So, what is next? So, next am I going to
do it today or um
Let's do it tomorrow, okay? Or, maybe
even not today. I mean
So, it's going to be three at least
three more
parts for this problem.
Okay, so this is So, we begin today and
but we got
We I mean, I have quite a few other talk
show topics that
actually what I need to do. So,
So, let's
let's not schedule another one today,
okay? Let Let it be just today is just
this, okay?
Okay, bye guys. Now, um
Yeah, so
that's it. Now, if you like my stuff, go
to my website, okay? study.info
http no s
Go to the bottom.
You can Patreon me. You can Amazon gift
card me
and PayPal me, okay?
So,
and uh then
I'll schedule our next talk show
um
tomorrow for sure. Another one tomorrow.
Maybe probably one each day.
Okay, bye guys.