Good morning, good evening everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Exon Show.
Cheers. We are going to do F programming
language coding exploration.
Okay, just random just me working on my
F tutorial exploration.
If you are here, say hi. If you are not
here, play at 1.5 speed.
You are looking at my keyboard. This is
ultimate hacking keyboard 80.
UHK80. Search on my YouTube and you'll
find it. Okay, let's go to my screen
and uh we just going to relax and do
stuff. Okay, F stuff. You don't know
what I'm doing, but I'm going to show
you. Okay, it's just me walking. Okay.
So, we did wolfam language. Fantastic
and beautiful. Okay.
And that was yesterday. So, that was
yesterday. And uh yeah, today. So, let's
go to So, I did some let's go to desktop
open in folder and uh let's go to uh JJ
uh temp files. Okay. So I did these a
bunch of screenshots
so that shift W to make them
display by window size.
So these are the things I need to do on
my F tutorial. But let's have a drink
first.
Red wine.
Okay. So, can you see my screen and you
can can you see my screen and today's
today's talk show uh and close that uh
talk show F programming language
exploration. Okay, let's just start to
do them. This is format string. So this
is about F learning nodes. You go to
string section. Then there's a section
on formatting string. Okay, that would
be there. So open it. Copy I mean the
copy the URL. Show showing browsers.
That's today's talk show. Search for
sections. Uh search for section. Section
section. Okay. Create a new section.
Okay. That's a link to the formatting
stream page. Open it. Showing browser.
And uh the screenshot says why walk
around back and forth taking a break. It
says this section needs to move up for
better clarity. That is why. Okay. Yeah.
So I I I was trying to explain spring f.
Okay. So spring f um yeah. So let's do
that.
Update today's state.
Okay. So, this one. Wait, not that one.
That one.
Uh, wait. Did Did I Did I screw up?
Remove all the syntax color so you can
better see the code. There it is. Sprint
app. Okay. So, this is a correct page.
Now, um,
okay. Syntax color everything showing
browser. So sprint sprint f turns values
into a turns the value into turns values
into a string. Okay. So comments turns
value into a string but does not print.
First argument is a string which with
placeholders. Placeholders is uh two
characters starting with
uh percentage sign. Okay.
So we begin with spring f. Um let's you
know let's um
let's add a header. Okay. Spring f. Uh
well let's say
h2. Then you got print f. Okay. Then you
got print F. This came from the C
idiots. Print F and sprint F. The habit
the convention
is you got long history you know 30
years 40 years came from C. Okay. It's
print F and sprint F. They are for
formatting purposes. So
um
so you know so alternatively if you if
you blame the C people for sprint f and
print f then what what is the better
way? Well the better way is actually I
explained in one of my live stream. Okay
the better way they needs to be separate
functions. One is about converting
values to string. Okay. And the other
one is um converting values to string.
So you have binary to string. I mean you
have integers to string, integer to
hexadimal string, integer to binary
string. Uh you have those kind of
things. And you have also string
formatting issues like
well okay so so converting uh integers
to binary to hexadimal but you also have
converting boolean data type to string
or other data types to string such as
floating numbers to scientific notation
or um engineering notation
um or truncation of the decimal how many
places. So that's you know that's two
string for numbers floating numbers and
then you also have issues like um so
anyway they should be uh different um
functions okay that is the pro that
would be the proper design but we
inherited because of convention then
because of habit we inherited from C
idiots so we got this print F and sprint
F everywhere okay That's a damage from C
now
show. So it I highly recommend uh you
watch this uh video from last year. So
2025 actually a few months ago. Search
for rock stream. Okay. So this one talk
show episode 702
the C print F crime and new syntax for
string rock string. Okay, that is one of
my best videos. This is my experience of
20 years of uh programming language
design study. Okay, that's my result. So
watch that one episode 702
talk show on C print F crime and new
syntax for string rock string I so
that's one hour long video with a video
summary by artificial intelligence and
that details lots of these things okay
anyway I'm digressing so I'm just um
shift shifted show okay so F and uh
print f and sprint f. Okay, the
functions print f and sprint fn also
takes the same placeholders. Okay. So
then you need uh so that in this new
section table so
that's so that's slightly better you
know I'm just doing minor things um
through my F tutorial which is actually
just F learning notes when it's good you
know you'll rename it tutorial but now
it's just like learning notes I want to
learn F because I actually never
actually you know all my life I've been
functional programming starting with
Wuam language in 1993.
So Wuam language is also known as
Mathematica back then. It's my first
programming language and I coded for
like 10 years like heavy deep. Uh and I
don't know anything about like the
industrial programming like what is
operating system? What does it mean?
What's the network? you know what I have
no idea so it's just mathematics woof
language functional programming so I was
like taught from you know language was
my first exposure to programming
languages
then hello uh loam manhani
loama honey you guys have weird
interesting names love your website
thank you yeah I got a problem with my
website because I cannot a sync. So it
has been up not it has not been updated
for like 20 20 days. So I need to fix
that. It'll be fixed pretty soon. Okay.
Because and also I'm thinking of
switching my website hosting. Um I think
you know I'm thinking about that. So
anyway so I'm just you know I wanted so
I've been uh I I know Wuan language for
like by now 30 years. I've been coding
it like for 10 plus 10 years and I've
been coding emac this by now for 15
years. Emac lisp is also predominantly
functional programming language
and it starting in 1998 I've been coding
uh pearl professionally
uh for like uh three years.
Okay, I need to fix this uh markup. You
see the visual this you see this L is
not um it's not I mean it it's got it
got um a new line I should fix that. So
anyway I've been I mean I've been coding
Pearl professionally for like four years
and then I started to learn Python kind
of became my main kind of my my main
language for five years or so. So and I
started to learn go but anyway what what
I'm saying is that most of my life in
the past 30 years I've been mostly a
functional programmer wuan language and
eag this actually okay I learned some
scheme and closure uh you know I learned
all this language powershell and and
some parl professionally and PHP also I
coded professionally
um
and I also learned some Java and also
get paid to do closure for a year
but overall so but I never so most of my
my life I've been coding functional
programming that's what I do I despise
the objectoriented crap okay now let me
recommend you an article if you want to
know about object
uh objectoriented programming okay so
read this one uh actually this one is
also good um creating abstractions,
objectoriented versus functional
programming. Okay, you ignore that I'm
I'm going to tell you which one is
important, the most better, the best
articles. Okay, so
you want to read this one. Okay,
objectoriented programming jarens and
complexities explained as functional
programming. Okay, I despise
objectoriented crap. I mean they I
believe deeply I deeply believe they are
just like um harmful. Okay. It's one of
the situation where you know like for
example for hundreds of years people
believe that earth is flat.
How incredible that is. You know people
actually believe something like force
for thousand for for you know quite a
lot many hundreds of years depending on
the region. Okay. So we know that you
know at least the white the western
people the Greeks knew that the earth is
not flat since like 2,000 years ago from
the Greeks.
But anyway the the idea didn't come
across you know. So people believed in
lots of places like millions of people
billions they believed earth is flat
for thousands of years for for for
thousand a thousand of years let's say
you know so it's incredible
now that's a kind of a silly example but
such example also exist people believed
in for example in USA you have like
every
I don't know every 10 years every 50
years you have some certain like
extremely fake ideas. For example, you
can think about Victorian era. Their
thought about philosophy, about ethics,
about what is right, what is wrong. And
uh you know people used to be like some
race racist um ideals, ideology. And
today you got the social justice
warriors of our our era who believe that
sex is a construct, you know.
So flat earth the flat earth phen
phenomenon you know can can you believe
that that's incredible but in the same
way this kind of believing in uh
non truth you know false stuff happens
not just in society in general but it
also happens in programming and I would
claim one of them is the objectoriented
programming paradigm for the past 20
years let's say. Okay.
Okay. Okay. So you got objectoriented
programming paradigm which is you know
which is one of the way but it's but but
what I would say is that it has been
propelled as as the solution
in a non-factual way too much basically
like Java programming language and C++
the worst the most damaging
crime.
in programming history. Okay, C++
you know you might you might say why why
are you so extreme but anyway you know
think about about flat earth it does
happen okay so that's my kind of my
if you disagree with me that's I I'm
telling you as like example of
justification
so anyway so what I'm saying is that the
objected objectoriented programming
paradigm is
um is very um is bloated. You know, it's
it's the merit of the the fitness and
the merit of objectoriented programming
paradigm is over uh overvalued
to a severe degree like severe to a to a
degree such that it became kind of like
a scam. Okay. So that that is what I'm
saying
and uh concrete example I would claim
this happened in C++ community happened
in Java community in fact Java and C++
they are like wholly dedicated language
for this objectoriented way. Okay C++
began then Java
and I would claim Python. Okay, Python
today is like one of the most popular.
In fact, C++, Python, they are all and
Java, they are the top three the most
popular programming language. Okay.
Uh the other ones are JavaScript and uh
PHP for example. Okay. Cheers.
So, is that interesting? So,
Okay, I digressed a lot.
I started to do a lot of talk then
actually doing things for for myself
because actually I need to you know work
on these things F.
Anyway, I'm telling you guys to read
this article. Okay, just search for
kali.info objectoriented programming
jarens and complexities.
Okay, search for it.
You might add my name
to in front x e to target to find my
article. So there okay objectoriented
programming jarens and complexities
explained as functional programming.
Okay, so this article has been very
popular. It went to uh hacker news for a
while like 10 years ago uh once or
twice. Anyway, so that I recommend you
guys read it. That's one of my most
popular articles. Okay, that one. And
the other one is um I would recommend
another one. So let's see.
And uh this one is kind of new history
of objectoriented programming by Casey
Murattorii.
Now Murattorii is a famous like a
programming coder celebrity. So he's
famous coder. Okay. Because he's a big
in in a gamer community game
programming. That's his profession.
That's what he does the best game
programming. Okay. So he dived he did a
deep dive into the history of objected
objectoriented programming. Okay. So
this article I just wrote few month ago.
So I highly recommend it. In fact you
should you know basically just read I
mean just watch his YouTube videos. So
he's got a v uh YouTube videos about it
like a uh it's an hour long. I think
it's an hour long. Okay, so watch this
guy's video. Fantastic. So that's the
two articles I highly recommend. So
let's copy the link here. So let's post
the link to um today's talk show so that
we have like a record what we are saying
and later on people can uh
can refer to it. Okay. So we did that.
So we did object oriented programming
jargon and complexities. Copy that.
Paste the link linkify it. Make a list.
Combine the two list showing browser. So
there you go. So fantastic HTML HTML
mode. The power of Emacs editor and
Kafly keys
undo.
So if you are wondering what am I
talking about? So I'm talking about
this. Okay. So wait undo.
I'm talking about this s flag keys. Go
to the source code. Go to it. 4,000
lines of code. Okay. Go to the top and
go to the URL here. Homepage. Open.
Wait.
Open it. Show browser. That's saf. Most
advanced key binding system for Emacs
make it makes EMAC more efficient than
VI Vim or Neo Vim. Okay. Xah Fly keys.
I have videos on it, tutorials. In fact,
I have hundreds of videos in the past
three years. Okay, there's a manual
install and also the key map, the key B,
the diagram that shows you what this
softly keys is about. So most efficient
by scientific measurement. Okay, then
Vim or Neo Vim or or whatever. Okay, so
that's what I'm using. So close that.
Close that. Close that. Showing browser
which I have a link here. Okay. So now
let's get back to the F. So did we do
this page? Uh formatting string. Yes.
Print F. Print F. And now there's one
more thing to do. Okay. So let me show
you. So we go to let's go to the page.
Go to it.
Um
section
HTML add section to H2. Do it then show
in browser. Show in browser. Now you see
now you got a section box for each H2.
So each H2 now you got like this box.
Fantastic. Okay.
Now that command I wrote it in Emacs of
course I I do a lot live stream of
writing these Emacs commands okay if you
guys want to see it. So
if you guys don't know search for Emacs
for example XH Emacs.
Okay. So then you can go to my Kasawa
Emacs tutorial. Kasa is a prominent
figure in Emacs community. Yes, of
course. So, go to uh my website, then
you can go to Emacs and Emac this video
tutorial. So, I've been doing live
stream in the past five years. So, there
are like over 100 videos about so you
can learn from the ground up about Emacs
or the most efficient and powerful
editor text editor for programmers
mostly and for writers as well.
So you can learn about that and emac
this from the ground up or Emacs
workflow efficiency. Emac this l this
from the ground up. Emacs l this the
programming language the functional
programming language. Okay. Then
[snorts] EMAC this writing a major mode.
So we wrote a major mode for Goland from
scratch
in 2021 and we wrote a major mode for
Python in 2023.
So there are three videos about it. Each
one is one hour and we uh then emac this
and lots of okay so I've done lots of
emac coding and live streamed it in the
past like four year five years. Okay. So
you just search for uh search for my
name Kasari Emacs and Emac this video
tutorial. So copy the URL and let's
paste it here. So what is this? Uh okay
go back here.
Okay so that's good. Uh well I don't
want the I don't want the absolute URL.
I want relative path. You see? Okay
browser. Fantastic there. Okay. Now,
next to F.
Okay. So, this page is about F3 thing.
Now, let's search. So, let's go to F
tutorial page. Go to a directory. You
see all these are F tutorials. Now, you
just search for three thing. Search for
any occurrence of the string three
thing. Okay. Then you can find the page.
So go there showing browser. So you can
see this page is about F dollar sign
string template. Okay. So that's a
particular syntax for in F for for for
when you want a template string. Okay.
Uh but I I got an error here. You see is
you see it says cats but it's
it is wrong. Okay. So, cats. So, pop it
out. So, run it.
So, you can see the result should be I
have three cats, but instead I got I
have three things. So, that's wrong. So,
correct it. Okay. So, I can run the
code. So, you can see all my command
calls on the pink window. Uh let's uh
let's make it bigger. So, you see cut
line or print region delete the window.
So, uh, run current file. You see that's
a command I just executed. If you search
for that, press press press. All right.
Press press press press. Wait.
Yeah. Search for that. Wait, not
Twitter. Okay. So,
look up web
run current file. You will find Wait,
not Neo. Okay. So,
Oh god.
So look up web.
Uh what? Not neo. Okay. So what why is
it this? Okay. Look up web. Do it run
file. Okay. Something is wrong. Is this
uh
what?
Why is it doing that? Because
this is incorrect. Okay. Something is
wrong with anyway. You guys don't know
what I'm doing. So, any comments? Yes,
sir. What? Yes, sir. I forgot. Love your
website. Okay. I forgot what I was
saying. Okay. So, correct that. Um, put
it back. syntax color show in browser.
So let's see what else I need to fix. Um
okay,
this says
I am currently
30% drunk.
Now what does this say in indent or wait
in doly
in incorrect
but anyway we correct it. Okay you
should should be three cats. Okay.
Uh
so what was my nodes? What was my
English includ?
Uh
I forgot what was I saying there.
Okay. So this is about some Twitter
idiocy. Okay.
you know, Twitter idiocy because this is
um
basically Twitter, you know, on
basically this is my screenshot about
the Twitter warning message. Twitter is
flagging this, you know, Twitter warned
me, posted a message to me about, you
know, it says we flagged these posts as
sensitive content. We put a warning
message on these posts because they
might have sensitive content like
nudity, sexual content, violence score,
or hateful symbols. You know, we know we
don't always get it right. So, if you
think we flagged your post by mistake,
you can appeal the warning by clicking
on each post. Keep in mind, this doesn't
guarantee you'll be removed. You see
Twitter
the the the extreme
corruption of the deep state. You see
they flag the message because you know
maybe because of a nudity or sexual
content or violence or blood. Okay. Go
is like a euphemism for blood. Okay.
When you see blood or hateful symbols.
Okay. So they flagged a post. But you
see on Twitter there are lots of porn,
okay? like poem like tits ass and cock's
penis in in vagina you lot of poem
but those they don't get flagged you
know like often time or or you know some
girl you know they doing a selfie which
like semi- nude you know they don't they
don't get flat flagged
but if you talk about the science of sex
sexuality
You know, maybe you talk about like
vagina or something, then you get
flagged. It's idiocy. The cor
corruption of the USA deep state. That's
what this that's what happens. Okay, I
can show you exactly what it is marking,
you know. But um
uh I I have to search. I forgot what is
it. I have to search for my um let's see
my uh what?
Oh, it shows Emacs. That's my old
account for long long ago. I haven't
posted to Ogo Emacs like five years.
Um anyway, so you go to my Twitter so
you can see you know what? So what is
this flag about? Anyway, it's idiotic.
Okay, Twitter. So, uh it's about this um
this picture something
maybe two weeks ago. I forgot. Okay.
Somewhere.
But you see, you see this Twitter? You
see Twitter? This one is posted by Ella
Musk. This one is shared by Ela Musk. By
the way, it's like about AI creating
girls.
You know, girls like is, you know, they
are the center of humanity. Okay. The
white men don't know it. The white men's
got problems. The United Kingdom, the
British and the German kind of people in
America, okay, in USA, they are kind of
sick.
So anyway, this this was reposted by
Ella Musk, you know, the richest person
on earth who's got like what 20 million
followers or something. The biggest, you
know, uh person with Anyway,
so going back. So, so, so this is my
screenshot. You know, I wanted to make a
record of it, but you know, there's so
many. Anyway, so this one is done.
So let's go to this one. Dollar sign
with triple quotes. Okay. So in F you
got dollar sign with triple quotes.
Okay. So
okay. So you need to go there
dollar sign uh triple quotes and what
you say what you want to say is
okay. So
just delete that. And uh
actually right now I'm like 30% drunk.
So my um IQ is not
at the highest.
[clears throat] Actually I don't like
drinking because it it dumbs you. That's
what drinking does. Drinking or the
drugs, it makes you stupid.
Uh
so what am I saying? So that should move
here. Okay. So so that should move here.
So right now I'm not thinking
not thinking I'm just following whatever
my notes says. Okay. And let's update
the date. Okay. So you can see showing
browser. So the date has been updated.
So dollar sign with triple quotes. So
you can do that and one dollar sign
means that two dollar sign means that
the number of dollar sign correspond to
the number of curly brackets need
uh needed to be interpreted as a
embedded expression.
Okay, that should be needed.
I'm pretty sure.
Okay. So,
so are you guys are like following me?
Okay. So, close that. So, what about
this one? Convert string to inflat by
the array. Okay. So, that's another
another page about converting string to
int float by the array. Okay. Copy that.
Close. Close.
Close.
And what is string format close close
and
paste linkify uh open it showing browser
go back update the date and I want to
make this into three sections that's
what I want to do okay
so let's say H2 to H3 do it do it do it
okay so undo two. So to float to to int
convert string to int to float and to by
array. Okay. So three sections and
and make it um okay so you got in
f new block. That's that's your int.
Then new block f. Yes. And you want
convert to float there and convert to by
string. Okay. Syntax color everything
show in browser. Fantastic. You see we
broke in we broke a
block of code
and one H2 heading into three separate
headings. You see convert to string to
int. That's how you do it. Okay. Now
you'll also notice you see the
background color has changed for my code
because I did some DSS code uh cascading
style sheet change. Okay. So so it
became so so this convert string to
integer type or flow type or by array
type has been split into three sections.
So I think that's helps for better
clarity. Okay.
Uh
is that correct? Is that right? Yes, I
think so. Convert string to int float by
the array.
Yeah, we can. Okay. So do that. Okay. So
we can can we run it? Yes, of course.
For example, let's do it. Run it.
Fantastic. So you see it prints
system.int32.
So by default if you know integer
um you can convert a string to integer.
Um
let's see what is that character. That
character is O capital O. Okay. So close
that. Put it back. Syntax code the whole
thing the whole page showing browser.
Okay. So [snorts] that done.
Now this okay so this is about split
string two characters. Okay. So this is
uh split string two characters. Okay. So
there are something we need to do. Uh
this part is a bit complex because a
string you see
if your string if your string contains
unic code characters such as emoji then
it can get complex for example this
string I mean so so [snorts] actually so
let me rephrase okay so if your string
contains nonasi characters such as
Chinese Russian or a teod, you know, or
or nia, you know, the those
like nia nino in Spanish
grave accents in French or acute accent,
you know, e acute e gravey used in
French, then you may got a you you you
may have a problem. Okay. So if your
string contains those characters
accented characters of western languages
or Chinese language or Japanese then or
Russian okay then you got a problem
because
because the each character may be
decomposed.
You know if you want to turn the
character sequence of string a string
into a sequence of arrays then your
arrays may become
like these half characters. Okay that's
a problem. You see this happens in if if
you convert to array or if you convert
to a sequence
uh of characters. A sequence is
basically a uh lazy eval which is a
idiotic thing.
Okay. So what am I saying here? Okay. So
yeah. So this section is about split
string two characters. Okay. So
so this you can do them this way. R2
char array
or you can do it this way. Sequence
chart. Uh how do you do this?
Okay. So, so you can actually uh assign
a text to this type sequence
a sequence of ch characters type.
But however, in both of these ways, you
the result you get is not what you want.
You see, you want basic basically you
want the list of characters, but both of
these get you incorrect. So
they are correct only if your string is
only asky characters. Okay. So that's
about that. So you need to tell um
space string to array. Okay.
So first of all
H2 to H3
um
so let's see so first of all you want to
see say split ASKI okay then then you
want to say split unic code okay I
believe
refresh okay wait
uh what
okay So,
okay. H3.
Uh, what?
Okay. So, H3
H3 is showing browser.
Okay. So, spring split string to
characters.
Uh, split ASKI string to characters.
Okay. So you actually you should change
this.
Yeah, you should change them. Uh
okay, let's try
uh some. Okay, so vanet.
Yeah. So,
so that's the output
does not work if your string contain
none.
Okay, this is important.
Um,
okay. So, that's that. And what about
this part? Same thing. Okay. Um,
okay. So,
okay, back to brows browser refresh.
Okay.
But if you want it to if your characters
[snorts]
contains unic code then any unic code
then what you can do is you can say
enumerate runs.
Okay. So how does this work? Enumerate
runs. Uh
anyway this is how this works.
Okay. And what uh what is this? I don't
understand. Okay, I think I'm tired.
So this these uh unico characters. So if
you deal with unico string to
characters.
Okay. So actually the wording is not the
best.
The best wording, the better wording is
you say split
um string to unic code characters. Okay,
that's a better wording. Split string to
un code characters. Better than split
unic code string two characters. Okay,
split string to unic code characters.
That's right. Now, what about this one?
Now, what is this code about? Hello
world
and some
some guy in space suit or something
monkey.
Uh
I don't know what is that. Yeah.
So let's go to next. Okay. So binary
octto because this one because you know
this one involves some thinking. you
have to think about what to do with
that. Uh but right now I'm not in a
position to think about things.
So next let's do some easy ones. So this
one is about default float number type
uh binary octto hexadisimal. Okay, that
one is about
numbers. Okay, basically it's about how
do you input numbers
of binary digits or input numbers of
octo digits or input number of hexad
hexadimal. Okay, so you can
edit it trick the wording to make it
more
comprehensive, better writing. Okay. So
this is about writing update the article
date. Then then you just need to go to a
binary
input. Just say input. Okay. Octo input
and has a decimal input show in browser.
Fantastic. We got the date updated. Then
you got uh number separator binary input
to input exit. Should we separate them?
Yeah, I think so. Into
uh three different sections.
Okay, let's see. Default integer number
type.
Default float number type. Number
separator. Okay. Binary input out input.
Yeah, let's say let's separate them.
Uh
okay. So binary input auto input and uh
what
hexo input. Okay. So binary input there
and this is ho input showing browser.
Fantastic. Okay. Binary input, octto
input, hexadimal input. So it's like
clear, more clear. Okay. So we done this
with this one. Yes.
Okay. I think actually uh Okay. Delete
that. Now what about this
F format string? Try CSS. Okay. So this
is about changing the CSS which I
already did you know for example let me
show you.
So you go to string and you go to format
you go to format string. You see before
every code
text that's colored red. Can you guys
see it?
Okay. Maybe you you guys cannot see it.
So shift
O so you can see better. Okay.
So every any code character was red. You
see red mean indicates it's code but now
I change them. Any code character now
now they have like background gray
color. So it's more outstanding.
You see compare you see and the code
also have gray background is you see
before it doesn't but now it does so
wait
uh format string yeah so yeah so you see
we also changed part of it so you see so
this is also done try CSS
background color you know I I wanted to
see if it's better or Not
uh so the the question here is about
styling of code. So you got two codes.
One is the code tag for example that
that and the other one is the pre-tag
which stands for a
code snippet snippet like this actual
code example. The other part stand for
like a function name you know or or
short short command name or syntax you
see. So they are used in two different
situations.
So before I just you know one of them I
just have the red color and the other
one is the actual code. But now I
change the style to this. Now I'm not
100% certain this is better but uh it's
just it's just experiment because
in fact that's what you have to do a lot
experiment okay so let's delete this
okay then there is that thing okay that
thing is about type okay
F type so do we have it f number let's
say type well
that is zero okay so open that wait open
that
so you can see
that character is actually zero I
believe no Latin capture letter O so
it's annoying so if you run this code
run it it returns that okay so O means
capture you know the print f which is a
C programmer's damage the C idiot.
Okay, so we got print F. So we got this
percent O that's capital O very
confusing. Okay, so that's another issue
about the English language. The capital
letters issue the capital letters
actually they it happens from
kind of happen stance of history. So
capital letters actually
is not very useful today. It should be
banned. Okay, it should be like we
should can completely remove it. But of
course, we cannot do that because of the
past conventions and habit.
But anyway, capital letters is usually
is not really that useful. Okay.
Um so but anyway so you so what you got
here is you see it one of the issues is
that it causes confusion.
Um
like for example capital letters some
capital letters they have the same
appearance as the small case letter but
not others. So first of all you got this
complexity
but then uh the issue here is that it
looks like you know the capital O or
lowerase O looks like zero.
Now this is not a thought of capital
letters but it's a separate issue about
about this GL um
homonym homogly something like that.
Okay. Anyway,
it's a bit cold.
Okay. So anyway, so this is how you um
get type of of some value in F. put it
back syntax color the whole page show in
browser okay so that is capital uh O
and uh what I want to do here is yeah
it's it's it's like confusing because it
looks like capital you know it looks
like zero that's one of the confus
confusing things about font which
another which is another
huge issue
Okay. So, um, so that's a that's uh
capital zero. That's part of the uh
formatting thing. Okay. So you need to
go to like uh string and you go to go
down and you go to the format string and
then here you can see the capital
O
there capital O any value formatted by
boxing the object and calling it
systemobject.2r
method.
Okay. So anyway, so that's how you um
print type. Okay. So for this one, let's
just um
uh should we say
[sighs]
is it appropriate to use percent
here is my question.
Um
because get type I believe inn net get
type already returns a string right so
you don't you know so this is something
I don't know about f
um let's ask gu okay okay let's see what
the a say that
okay we got actually we got more things
here okay so anyway
Let's ask what is it
for pre
and see how smart is squawk. Okay. Test
the AI's capabilities.
So, new you need a new question. Paste
the question here. Do it.
Okay. So, here's the answer. Yes, it's
appropriate. Interesting. Fantastic.
Artificial intelligence. Okay. Let me
get some things to drink. Okay. So,
let's see.
Uh,
how are you guys doing? Am I doing a
good like is this a good stream? Is this
what you guys looking for? Five
concurrent views. You know, it's funny
with a live stream because
like some videos I thought I was doing
really truly great theoretical stuff,
very valuable, but you only get 200
views, 300 views. On the other hand,
sometimes you do a rant which is
well rant is always dramatic but
sometimes you don't think you don't
think there's that much technical like
unique values in your live stream but
that live stream gets a thousand views.
So you know it's interesting. Okay, let
me get something to drink actually.
This is the Last shot.
Actually,
the last shot of this keto one.
Are you guys familiar with this thing?
Okay. So, this keto one, this is uh this
is like cocktail espresso martini.
I don't know what is martini but
supposedly it's like some just cocktail.
Okay,
I think that's the end of it. So,
Okay. So, let's go back to Can you see
my screen? Yeah, we got a we got a few
things to do. Okay. So, let's see.
There's a more screen.
What is this? Okay. Uh, is it
appropriate to use O? So let's see the
guac answer.
Yes, it is appropriate and in fact
percent capital O is exactly the right
choice in this particular case. Why is
that?
Uh let's see, you know, let's explore
because I thought
get type get type will return.
What does get type return? I think it's
okay. It's a special type but not
necessarily string innet
like the net object system. You know the
net is actually fairly complex. I never
get I I don't completely have a good
picture.
So anyway, when to use percent capital O
versus other specifiers? Let's see.
Generic two string or nice default
printing. Okay. H
structured debug style printing F
default only strings compile. Okay.
Whatever.
Okay, let's you know that's some details
I'm not ready to appreciate yet.
Okay, cut that. Let's uh let's go to
today's talk show and let's just paste a
question here like
um
oh guac and guac answer is here.
Okay.
And one more screenshot. Now what is
this named literal declare compile time
lit
okay so yeah so I'm talking about
named literal which is which is f
variable
um we're talking about named literal
page so let's go there
open
update state and uh basically
the problem is that
named literal you need to you know the
there's
some kind of wording problem or um
ordering problem you see in this section
I'm trying to tell the reader what is
named literal in F so you can declare
compile time literal that's what it is.
So you want to declare a variable
as a literal but at at compile time. So
there's this notion of compile time
literal. Variables can be declared as
compile time constant. Okay.
Now this is as opposed to you know
variable without mutable declared are
always constants but at runtime.
So you have two concepts runtime
constant versus compile time constant.
Now run runtime constant just means you
know whatever you declare that variable
is just a con constant.
The value never changes during the
entire program's running time. Okay. But
but now you have a new concept called
compile time literal.
It means you know this variable
like before your program even even runs
it became it got replaced by the literal
value it stand for you know so you don't
actually have a variable anymore. it
simply the program simply replace it all
the occurrence of the variable by by the
value. So at a compile time you know
before you even run the program that
that variable in your program is
actually just that value. Okay. So this
is the concept of compile time literal
which is you know my my learning notes
or my tutorial is trying to tell people.
So, but when you have this, you need to
say
right now my tutorial the way it is is
not totally clear because
uh you either need to say variables you
know you need to say variable
um
you need to say okay so there are two
ways to fix it okay so basically let me
just show you okay
okay I'm 30% % trunk. Okay. So you need
to say to
declare
a compile time
uh literal
you.
Okay. So this describe
it it gives a condition of what next
sentence is about.
So go back here. So look now refresh
refresh you see to declare a compile a
compile time literal. Okay. So you need
to say time
uh
you preede the let let line that. Okay.
Anyway, okay. I got some comments. Um,
hi Kar. What's the stream about today?
Uh, it's kind of random about F
programming language. Updating updating
my learning notes. Okay.
And a good approach. I forgot what that
is. So, how is the Emacs going? Emacs is
going great. Oh, double shot. Okay. So,
I'm done with my drunk. Uh, my drink.
I'm I'm like
30% I'm 30% drunk. Okay.
So um
which means you know when you when you
drink you cannot think you know I you
cannot think clearly
but anyway so I improved this passage.
That's what I wanted to do. Okay. So
so let's double check. Is that is that
the final version named literal declare
compile time literal variables can be
declared as as compile time constants.
Okay. Variable without mutable they
declare always constants but at runtime.
So uh one way to improve this
description is
you know don't mention mutability. Don't
mention mutable here because that's
confusing that's like a different thing.
So one way to improve this so let me
tell you what what am I thinking. Okay.
So one way to improve improve this
tutorial
the wording of it is that you say
okay you say variables can be declared
as compile time constants
and parentheses as opposed to run
constants. Okay.
So showing browser.
So one way to improve this tutorial is
you say variables can be declared as
compile time constants as opposed to
runtime constants. Okay. To declare a
compile time literal you precede the let
line by by that. Okay. So instead of
these two, so this two,
so before this list of items is replaced
by just that one.
Okay, I think this this one is better
than the these of two items. What do you
guys think?
So question from wife
Paris. What you have to do to be middle
class these days?
Uh, what kind of question is that?
[laughter]
Okay, I'm semi- drunk. So, let me answer
that question. What do you have? What do
you have to do to be middle class these
days?
Well, by definition, by definition,
let's let's narrow narrow down the
context to America, okay? Americans in
USA,
you know, because that's middle class is
kind of is kind of the concept of USA.
So by definition the term middle class
basically means average people like kind
of like kind of the almost the majority
okay by definition like what does middle
class mean by definition it's like the
majority of Americans
so what you have to do to be middle
class these days
Nothing. Nothing. Like by definition if
you are not special, if you are not
abnormal in some way, then you are
middle class in USA. Okay. So your
question waifu something Paris.
Woo in Paris. Okay. Something about
Paris. So I don't know if you are
American or Paris. Anyway, I think that
answers your question. So, let's go back
here. So, let's just delete this uh
delete that. Okay,
so named literal variables can be
declared as a compile time constants or
supposed runtime constants. Okay, so
that's what you do. Okay,
so that
okay, I think I'm done now. There is um
I think that's it for today.
So did we do this? Yes, we did some of
that. This is about
split string two characters. So this is
about
string
um
convert string
split string to characters split as key
string to characters. Uh actually that
should be split string to ask key
characters. Okay. So
open it. Search for ASI
string to AS key characters. Okay. So
refresh. That's how you do it.
Okay. So you kind of delete the todo.
Well,
well, I'll leave the to-do because the
todo signifies
it tells myself that in the future that
this is this section needs a lot more
work. Okay,
so this section is about um split string
to characters needs a lot work. Okay, so
back here my notes are deleted.
And what is this? Check rename file in
my tutorial. I think that's it for
today.
Okay. Check rename file in my tutorial.
So we did this eac this coding command
to delete Emacs backup.
I forgot what this is about. Uh
anyway,
okay. Bye guys.
We shut down in one minute. Okay. Close
it. Close it.
Set it.
Close. Okay. Refresh. F sharp type.
That's right. That's how you get the
type of of a value.
Fantastic. close it.
So F is a fascinating language I really
want to master. Okay, that's like my
to-do in for 2026.
F
uh I got still some way to go. Okay, so
uh F variables that's why I'm doing like
part of it. Oh.
Oh yeah. So, another thing I need to do
today, uh, which I how long have I been
going?
1 hour and 25 minutes already.
So, anyway, one of the thing I want to
do is to go through.
Yeah. So I have a
I have a F
find and replace code that I need to
improve which we which we wrote this
live about few months ago.
So this there needs a lot improvement.
So that will be next next time.
So that's it for today. Thank you guys
for watching.
Um I think tomorrow we either do EMAC
this tomorrow we either do EMAC this or
we going to do muam language. Okay. So
okay bye guys.
Uh
so did I answer your question? Wu
in Paris. What do you have to do to be
middle class?
By definition,
most people are middle class. Okay?
Unless you are special, for example, you
are in poverty or you are in like top
1%, you know, top 30% rich people.
Uh,
okay.
Okay, bye guys.