good morning everyone today is 2019 uh
2020 uh today is the last day of 2020
and uh welcome to another episode of K
talk show and today we are going to do
Goan we are going to write a sh script
in goand inside goand so in other words
we are going to write a sh script um sh
script
okay bash like that so this is a sh
script but we are going to put those
code inside goand so I'm writing goand
to
cell why do I do that let me explain
okay today is 2020 December
31st um and 2:00 p.m. San Francisco time
what welcome
all now let me check if I'm alive the
status of Sali alive
yes and Ender Ender
Ender uh okay am I uh checking am I
alive yes I
am uh concurrent viewers was four become
okay so let's begin okay
Goan yes indeed
um so I'm going to write the Goan script
and uh and before we do that let's talk
about let me tell you about the
background image so background image is
this one this is someone else's picture
someone else's keyboard This is do it
yourself keyboard and this one is called
K
keyboard so K keyboard looks like that
it has total of 42 keys 21 Keys each
hand very minimum and someone has this
Goan goer key capap this is goland
mascot go language okay and there's a
variation of this keyboard A variation
of the K keyboard called Jong keyboard
very strange you know they add basically
they add this one extra key at the
end I don't know what's that
about but this one but this
the author of this strong keyboard
actually wrote to me saying saying okay
so J is essentially a k keyboard with an
extra key for brackets and the
international layouts okay so this extra
keys for bracket okay strange disclaimer
like I said you can go to the Moon
without a
computer yes so you know the thing we
are talking about about is 40% keyword
which means only 40 Keys it is very hard
to type Chinese Japanese Russian with
40% keyboard yes indeed that's what I
said it's like doubling your work yeah
you can but if you need to type that two
hours a day you're GNA see a doctor
within a
month okay so there's a
quote so this is a k keyboard and joone
keyboard okay you go buy it
that's a background
image uh and so um what where am
I comments okay guys comments am I
actually talking
alive concurrent views two viewers okay
so anyway we are going to do uh Goan uh
coding right it's right time right uh
yes okay so that's a background image
and we are going to do goand uh goand we
are going to do it from scratch
okay let me gather my thoughts let's see
what I'm going to do and let's see if
I'm ready and uh and let's shall C it
let's shall uh start to code it now
actually there are two things I want to
do one is this
um you know let me let let me explain
this one so this is a sh script so what
it does is that uh this is a function
okay okay can I actually intend it okay
I can actually intend it yeah okay let's
intend
it so what this sh script does you see
so this is a function this is how I how
you WR write a function I've never done
sh script before this is actually you
can say this is the first time I'm
writing a sh script that involves a
function now I have a big story about sh
script how shall you should you should
you not use uh learn bash should you or
should you not uh long story I have a
long story about it 20 years of
experience okay uh I'm thinking about
where am I going so yeah this so look at
this article one language to rule them
all or what language to use for find and
replace so this is an article I wrote In
2011 and and by that time I already I
was I'm I'm doing Unix admin and writing
show scripts well not you know Unix
admin for like 10 years so and this
article accounts my experience about
whether you should write sh script or in
other words should bash be banned banned
from the face of this
Earth so this article I talk about that
experience um um okay you go read it
okay re go read it this is homework
let's go to talk show and on the right
window you can see all my um let's close
that on the right window on the pink
window you can see all my emx keys and
command CES and go to S Talk Show today
and the con keyboard and make a new line
magnify and uh merge these two so this
is our topic today magnify okay so uh
what language to Ru them all or what
language to use for finds and uh replace
so shall I go over it
um so I explain so the reason I'm
thinking about this because I write a
lot a
lot find and script I mean find and
replace scripts for example uh in text
you want to find some function and
rename it or you know find and replace
or sometimes SCP you know in the Unix
tradition it's called grab and set
set grab and set okay that's a
traditional Unix way grab is for find
you know grab for example you know I can
show you okay so we go to the emac Shell
let's show the window so
grab uh Jesus I haven't used oh yeah
okay okay here is what to do okay here's
a syntax I haven't used haven't used
grab for more than 10 years because I
always use it within emx or uh you know
because I have my as I said I have
written so many times in different
languages scripts that do that does
scrip in Pearl python Goan um and emac
Lis okay I have a version of all of of
grab and I also have a version for set
okay let me explain grab first okay grab
so this is a traditional uh Unix tool
for finding some text in a file let's
grab hascal okay hascal is everyone
wants to know hascal so you want to grab
the keyword hascal in all files ending
in HTML enter there it is now within
emac you can you can see this is the
advantage of coding uh grab Unix tools
within emac because so this is these are
all the occurrences you see it occurs in
this file occur in this file occur in
this file and you can just press enter
to jump to that file you see uh
here okay let's let's do it again where
is it
um okay there it
is talk show okay iMac this sit map
python syntax and design type Theory
hascal there it is so this is SCP okay
uh and uh so this is cing grap in
emac let's show you uh let me show you
let's go back to um split the window
let's go back to EA you see this is this
is the Syntax for grip now we can call
this in terminal okay let me show you
how it show looks like in terminal so go
to uh call Sar open Terminal opening
terminal this is the emac command I
wrote so there it is the terminal okay
Max magnify magnify so let's do grab
again grab
hascal all files ending in HTML so here
is the output
ugly and it's unreadable okay so that's
a in Shell so this is advantage of
coling grab in emx so you got you know
uh this uh color of colored interactive
output so grab is a traditional Unix
tool or Linux uh for finding text in
some file now another traditional Unix
tool for find and replace is suppose you
want to replace all the words hascal by
Goan okay so that's
Set uh okay so in emac let's do men set
okay so this is a set man page actually
I haven't used set for a long time I you
know I said is not good you know because
these days you code in Pearl python Ruby
even PHP and Goan or even JavaScript
with Teno you can write all these you
know in 10 minutes if you know the
language and uh you can and you can
customize it to your needs instead of
using the Unix grab and set [ __ ] they
are [ __ ] okay they are [ __ ] up [ __ ] oh
[ __ ] up [ __ ] that's what they are they
they have lots of problems I mean
typically my my readers you you are
probably a Linux
fan and you what what what is this guy
saying what crap is [ __ ] yes it is it's
so [ __ ] [ __ ] long history I'm not going
to even go you know I can tell you the
reasons from 20 years ago to today it's
no good so set so here is your uh your
set okay set it's you know it's called
stream editor stream editor editor
stream your ass and editor your
ass and look at this incomprehensible
anyway anyway let's we are
digressing gra grab and set okay uh okay
starting to have people coming in so we
actually are you guys here to look for
the goand coding because if you guys are
here to look for the Goan uh scripting
actually I should um start to write Goan
instead of instead of rambling about
grab set because I can talk about this
for 10 hours non stop so grab and set
they are the traditional Unix tools one
for find strings in files another one
for uh find and replace in fact I have a
I have a tutorial for it let's go to un
uh Linux website
okay practical Linux
tutorial so there you have it if you are
new to Unix or Linux you know there
there is a there is your grip
grip and
rejects uh and uh and uh stuff and stuff
you know unique stuff grip and grip and
grip
grip it's you know actually is quite
useful actually um yeah
still yeah but I
mean here's here's the way uh to put it
okay yeah grip is you know they are Unix
tools they are traditional and they are
they are still around and they are not
going to go away they are not going to
away they will they probably will not
going go away in 10 10 10 years okay but
however I mean because they are part of
the uni system they are not going to go
away just like VI is not going to go
away okay so
um they are useful in many re for many
reasons one is is the momentum it's a
you know backward compatibility because
every every install tools you know they
are probably call Web okay because they
because it's installed in every Unix
Linux uh you know and on the Mac so you
cannot Escape it you have to use it it's
like the is momentum it's like a the C
language the most [ __ ] up [ __ ] C and
C++ [ __ ] okay but you cannot Escape it
because it's like a black hole it's
already very big you know it's not going
to die anytime soon same way with the
Unix tools that uh GP
okay but however if your need is
actually find and replace and without
you know if you are not working a
company but I mean your goal you need to
do something find replace for your own
system or something or you starting your
own company then you don't need grab and
set okay because you can do that in
Pearl in Python in Ruby in Goan in
JavaScript okay with Teno uh you can do
it easy in five minutes and customize to
your needs because I have I have already
written uh tens of such scripts I and
I've in fact I've talked about this in
dedicated CL talk show uh once or twice
at least where I showed you my GitHub
just you
know should I start to do go land or not
you know I because I'm digressing so
much uh okay so so grab and set so I was
saying grab and set is a traditional
Unix tool and and
uh okay let's let's just go you go go go
uh let's go to Goan okay let's show you
quickly quickly what my scripts about
okay so here's goand tutorial then you
go to find string so here is a uh uh
code written in Goan that does grap okay
more powerful than grap because you can
you can you can specify which directory
you need which one you don't need or you
can specify which directory to ignore or
you can specify
multiple uh search string in grab is
just one okay you can you can specify
multiple search screen string search
string and you can also specify how much
context to show before the string
occurrence or after the string
occurrence or don't show them at all or
you can uh you can modify it you know in
fact I have a script uh you can just do
count
uh of course you can do this in Unix to
but in in sh then it becomes SCP find
and and X Arc and very complex
eventually you start to write Pearl
that's the birth of pearl because Pearl
the L world is fed up with the Unix [ __ ]
so he created Pearl that's the reason
Pearl was Bor and it became the most
popular scripting language for 10
years in the in starting around
1995 and pearl died around let's say
2010 nobody is using Pearl now because
python took over and for reasons and and
and Ruby and
PHP okay so here is a Goan script for
find for for GP okay then you have a
Goan script for set basically set is
find and replace okay Goan script very
powerful and you if you are into python
here is the python script for find and
replace I use it I used the this for 10
years you know and then the granddaddy
is the Pearl
version find and replace string in uh
string pirs in directory so you can do
multiple find replace pairs in one shot
you know and you know let me tell you
one big problem about set in Unix
because the Unix philosophy [ __ ] you
know they truncate lines you know if
your lines is long than 80 characters
they silently and automatically just cut
it off like as as if it doesn't exist so
you are trying to grab you know some
some important word let's say you are
trying to grab uh
disaster but it so happens that word is
longer than you know at longer than 80
lines it just
truncated and it doesn't tell you it
just it says disaster not found but
actually because it truncated that that
is the that is the history of Unix Unix
is like that uh in 1980s and up to and
and even up to year
2000 year 2000 okay because T was doing
that if you T something a directory and
if the directory names is more than 120
characters it just
truncated then you send it this
important file to FBI you know it's a
big secret then they unti it and and the
files are file names are trated
silently I have a article on that too is
somewhere just search for um I have too
many articles so depending on where um
what you guys are saying so and that
determines which direction I'm going to
talk okay
uh uh okay so let's see uh I don't want
to use hasc grip uh hate
gra hat hater okay year change year
changed
johani okay yeah uh
2021 amazing 2021 2021 I I am
um Jesus I'm
53 well not yet but you know I'm I'm I'm
52 now but about to be
53 you know I can code maybe five more
years then you will not here for me now
you we you know I'll just quietly
quietly disappear just like every uh
Hollywood
star okay Robin Wheels morning good
morning Anon
um anything you do is fine for me not
here for Goan okay okay uh I see your
new PC build on Twitter yes you can
stream games when you get it indeed now
I'm I joined the the game again and I'm
going to Frack this malen Jen gamer ass
this I despise them so much you know
this American Gamers you can see them on
YouTube and many of you guys too you
know let's do you know uh on the video
games 3D video 3D video games firsters
shooter games I will Frack your ass in a
3D first person shooter games okay and
not Craig okay I'm not I don't want to
play quick I want to play a game let me
show you okay I want to play a game
where there's no machine gun or real gun
or zap zap electronic you know what the
[ __ ] guns the only weapon allowed is
single shot rifle okay like one shot and
you have to reload
it so in this game I found such a game
uh on during our Discord chat with uh
friends help lunarious and many other
people help me you know we were talking
about games so once I get my new
computer and thank you guys for uh you
know I got
$4,000 over the past four years from
from patreon so I can I can buy a
computer
now so once I get a computer but I'm
getting old I'm not sure I'm going to
get into games but you know there's a
Temptation there because I'm a nerd you
know I I want to know know what's going
on in games too so but if I get into
games I want to play a a first person
shooter one on one such that the weapon
is single shot RI rifle every time you
click Mouse click M click you make a
shot you have to reload okay no machine
gun no automatic or no semi-automatic
crap okay so in that game one onone I
will kick your
ass I'm fairly confident in saying that
okay uh and that game that game
lunarious told me that that game I found
this uh you know I'm asking you guys
what uh is there such a game and there
it is there is so one of them is at
least one of them is this one
okay this one one versus one rats insta
Gip okay that that's a game and it's
only 5 I
think because in Second Life you know I
I played with these um young people you
know
the anyway this is a game okay one uh
it's the name of the game is RADS instag
Gip now instag Gip is a slan it's a
gamer SL of course they have so many
gamer SLS and you know you can I looked
up you know
it's you know instag Gip it's this
atmology for it instant
instant so actually um so I maybe I
should go back to talk about
programming uh emac and esoteric
Computing Happy New
Year's how many times can one rebuild
the wheel
um I see your new pc okay um emac and
esoteric okay what is the I patch for oh
I have a cross eye I have a little a bit
crossy since I was um te I
think IMX and Es okay so what's what is
the most important books to learn for
programmer okay that's um there's no
such thing what's okay what is the most
important books to learn for programmer
yeah there's no such
idea you you just learn programming okay
there's no magic uh
trick Sid Ali hello uh FMS hello and uh
uh R Runo says R instag G is like Quake
with only real gun weapon I played it
before yeah you know the gamers they say
real gun weapon you know so and there's
also another term I learned it's
called Uh another term I learned that
refers to the way Rail Gun Works
basically a line of sight you know
instant line of sight
death and the gamas have a ter for
it uh
anyway I I I don't I I I like to you
know play games but I'm getting go maybe
I'll get into uh let's see my how my new
when my new computer arrives so
actually so I was planning to do Goan
but you know when you do a talk
show it's actually easier for me at
least you know because I my audience and
my personality actually it's much easier
for me just to random chat about lots of
things things interesting uh
things you guys will find interesting on
the other hand I can also go you know a
tutorial on goand you know purely
technical Or emac List although that is
that is in general more difficult and
also in fact less people are interested
because people watch YouTube they just
want to you know it's
entertainment you know if you really
want to learn go you know few most
people uh especially you guys you know
hacker types you want to learn a
language it's better to you know you can
just read uh you know then instead of um
well H okay what what are we doing
so so I was talking about goand so I was
going to write a Goan
script I was you know I was this this is
my own project I mean it's this is
something I have to do so I was thinking
you know why why don't I just do a talk
show and meanwhile complete you know uh
this script because I need to do this so
essentially I'm uh doing a backup of my
you know I started to have money to buy
a dis drive so that I can back up you
know
anyway uh so I'm writing a Backup backup
script and what this
what this script does you know there are
so many ways to do a backup okay you can
use AR sync you can use one of the
backup you know uh app there are quite a
few of them uh or you can do it manually
you know I
always I have always been doing it
manually because I believed in Brute
Force you know you just just copy just
copy the whole directory to the backup
dis every month or so you know just take
one minute to drag it over then just let
let it run you know and don't worry
about nothing because dis uh you know
the disk is growing and gr faster than
we can actually use it at least for a
person you know so you just do that and
don't worry about writing a script or
sync or whatever just every month just
spend the one minute to copy the file
over that's the ideal situation but
it was never like that I always end up
spending hours and hours whenever I want
to do a backup because every time I need
to do a backup it's going to I know it's
going to be hours so it tends I tends to
not want to do it why why hours because
every time I do a backup you know in one
hand you can just trag the whole
directory you know C you know like you
know on the Mac you you can for example
just drag for example this director just
drag it over to another dis and just wa
wait just wait the machine to copy you
know maybe take two hours or whatever
let it do it Brute Force now this is the
Brute Force way the utmost Simplicity
you know you don't worry about time
machine or whatever backup or G or our
syn or you know whether which you know
whatever just manually copy it daily if
you need to be you know just take one
minute to open the folder drag it over
and let the computer do the rest of it
for an hour or two
you rely you know this is this is kind
of the Brute Force approach to Computing
to manage your Computing directories or
whatever because you don't worry about
nothing you want the simplest method
possible and you but but one thing you
rely on is the fact that the disk you
know gets faster you know the interface
usb2 USB 3 there was fire fire wire fire
wire or or many other methods ethernet
you know you rely on the interface to be
faster and faster every every year right
and also the hard dis grows and grows
more than more than you can ever use so
that's a Brute Force way but but be also
because of my personality every
time it didn't happen like that every
time I spent hours because every time I
before I drag I want to know what what's
going on with my directories which file
I really don't need which which you know
I need to run many Unix uh you know sh
script to see which file is actually
large you know for example let's
do uh actually I don't want to do it um
um because then it's going to show lot
lots of my personal files but anyway you
can you know if you use Unix you know
what I mean you know you can use du to
show the directory size so you can get a
list of all the directory size so I want
to know which you know which one is a
big file and I never use and things like
that I want to you know I spend the time
to look then I started to look at you
know sometimes there's lot movie files I
haven't looked for a long time so I
started to look at those movie files to
see do I really need this and then
there's a a matter of indecision should
I delete this one or
not so every time I do backup it ends up
you know um like that
so am I doing good so what um I'm still
wondering should I go back to uh goand
code the goand and
stuff so let me show you my goand script
okay so so here's a goand script so what
I end up doing right now this time is
that I started to um created a I started
to make every directory a g
repo you know that so this is this is a
example where I ends up spending a lot
of time because now I started I'm
thinking you know why not now git is
very popular why not make every
directory for example
documents uh documents is a common
directory uh videos pictures is all
these are common directory so every make
make them into a git repo for every
directory then that takes time because
every you know every you you start uh G
repo it takes you know 40 minutes
sometimes so I did that for my
directories
then right now I so I wrote this script
okay let me show you what the okay let
me just let's let's try let me try to do
something useful
so um so you can see something that's
actually useful instead of instead of me
just babbling okay so let's go to
get uh okay
git site
okay practical git in one
hour so let me let me tell you about
this issue so suppose you have a
separate from backup okay this is
suppose this is a new issue okay now
suppose you have a g repo of you know
let's say there in there there are
10,000 20 you know 100,000 files a few
gigabytes very big let's say
so you want to backup this uh project
right
so in the mo most simple case you just
copy the entire entire directory to your
backup Drive yeah that works but it's
inefficient because in every git
repo for example in every git repo for
example let's go to directory okay
and okay let's go to for example this is
my Kali
doino um directory that's my website
okay so we go One Directory
up you can see magnify so this is s info
so you can see this is a
git uh data base you see every time you
have a git project you have this git and
this git essentially essentially is a
copy of your entire directory okay so
whenever you have a g repo the folder
actually double in size because it had
it contains a kind of a condensed copy
of the whole directory itself so if if I
want to back up this.info
uh magnify okay go up the so if I want
to back up this.info I
can you know I can go to uh let's see if
I can you know let me show you this emac
command okay open in open in desktop
okay so you press a
key the command is this one okay showing
desktop okay you press a key and it pops
up the folder viewer and it works in
Linux and windows as well so this emx
command so you see this is directory so
if you go up one directory and copy the
whole thing to backup
drive it's inefficient because it's
actually copying the directory twice
because including the get
repository so if I want to backup this
you know I do want to backup this I can
just you know originally originally my
The Brute Force way Brute Force way is
just copy the whole thing but it's
inefficient you know because it copy
twice you know including the G repo so I
was still but I'm I'm a efficiency nerd
so I don't I don't want so so is there a
way you know if you have a g repo is
there a way to copy the whole directory
to a backup but without without the git
the dogit
directory yeah there is of course
there's a way on you you know all you
have to do is select all files and uh
click on the git doget and so this way
you don't copy the
git yeah but if you do it this way then
you have to create a new directory first
then copy the whole thing into that
directory then that you know that
directory also has to be named the same
name so it's you know it's more more
work more manual work so is there you
know I want the simplest command just C
copy the whole thing exclude the
tget yeah there are ways you know that
you can do a sh script or you can there
are some many ways okay okay let me talk
let me talk about this backup there's
actually a lot issues
okay so let's hold on a second so I
haven't finished about this topic yet
about copying a repo but but there are
digressions let me talk about that in a
git repo typically you have thousands 10
or you know typically the file size is
very
small uh let's close that close that for
example my Linux tutorial you know all
these files are the file size is just 3K
9k 10K you know very small when you have
tens of thousands of small files you
copy them to a USB or whatever it takes
tremendous time it's very slow okay it's
super slow it takes two hours even if
you have a fast
interface uh that's my experience for
the you know for my um for this uh hard
disk drive this is actually spinning
drive this is not solid state I don't
have solid state
drive but now I'm upgrading so when my
new computer comes I'll finally have
solid state drive I'm tired of the dis
spinning because every time I do for
example
um when I do online stream you know the
CPU maxed
out not now but you know the CPU max out
and the disc start to W and you know
then you wait you you wait for the disc
calling anyway so so the point is when
you copy thousands files it's slow so
one solution it's faster if you first
zip them into a archive you know zip
them all together then you copy the zip
file over so this combination of steps
is actually faster than you just drag
the whole directory over
okay so so we are talking about backup
so there's complications we were talking
about copying the git the you know git
repel over so first complication is that
you are also copying the git uh you know
the git directory you don't want to do
that then the second complication is
that you want to you know you want to
zip it first before you copy over
because that way it's actually
faster so how do you do that so there is
a solution it turns out git has uh has a
solution so here is a solution okay
archive so there is a
command called get archive so this is
basically what you do so in this in this
article I tell you uh what to do okay so
this way it will create a zip file of a
git repo but without the dogit and also
without history so this is exactly what
we want we just want copy the current
folder without dogit without history
info you know just the file so this is
what you want so you do this command it
creates a zip file for the rep
repository then you can copy the zip
file
over so now back to uh back to why am I
writing this script uh I can show you
what's going on here so practical G so
this is a script okay so back to this
script so this is what the script is
doing so for this directories you can
see let me uh so this you see this is my
git repo oh go
IMX I'm me chewing gun let me speed out
speed it out
so this is my
emac uh website this is my w English
website this is my SAR website all these
are my websites so for each directory I
want to uh basically run the make them
into a zip file without history without
dogit okay so for each one of them this
script will create a zip file it it'll
take about an hour or two
wa I run this so
then so then I have to manually copy all
these zip files to my uh backup drive so
it's still manual process you know so of
course I'm still in the process of
automation so I can write another script
that moves the all these new zip files
over but the the problem is if you know
so this takes time writing these scripts
takes time you know take it actually
takes a few
hours
then then another issue you know because
I'm writing this sh script but I'm
thinking you know because I'm into
programming languages I'm into
efficiency remember I'm into efficiency
so when I'm writing sh scripts and I
know I know Shia is the most worthless
[ __ ] of the
Unix heritance Heritage okay shell you
know the crap what [ __ ] possible so why
am I writing a shell I don't want I
don't want use anything that's a hack
okay Unix shell is a hack beginning with
boom shell then bash C CSH
tcsh uh
zsh Kell ksh you know this crap why why
are there are so many because each one
is one [ __ ] up [ __ ] that's why then
there's another new version trying to
improve it then then there's
Pearl then Pearl died you know that's
why the Unix [ __ ] so all hack the Unix
is the embodiment of the word hack
everything Unix is a hack and the this
hack attitude is condensed into a slogan
the Unix
philosophy and everyone is happy ever
since the Unix [ __ ] philosophy
so so you know I want to do backup in
the beginning I I thought just just copy
the whole thing over Brute Force this
this is the mathematicians way this is
the most elegant method for a
mathematician because mathematicians
they don't care about efficiency
mathematicians they really they only
care what is what it is you know or if
you have a goal just do it you know they
they care about can it be done or can it
not be done is it possible to do do it
that's a mathematician's philosophy when
mathematician look at things is it
possible is it I mean when mathematician
says possible or impossible it means
theoretically you know it's a the
theoretical possibility okay let's
that's the theoretical computer science
what is computable you know uh things
like that recursive you know Theory
that's all you know most T tuning
machine as you know Lambda uh Lambda
calculus
uh combinators they are all about all
these are trying to answer the question
what is possible to compute what is not
possible to compute okay so they are you
know that's a mathematician so all these
are mathematician not Computer
Engineering [ __ ] like cc++ Java
JavaScript
[ __ ] so mathematicians created the
entire they are the forerunners pioneers
of a computer theore IAL theoretical
computer science in other words
theoretical computer science which is
nothing you know okay and they are about
Lambda calculus and so on they are
actually about Foundation of mathematics
they are part of they are really part of
math and they are part of the foundation
of mathematics the reason T machine
Lambda calculus combinators are in were
invented because they are trying to
answer the question about what is
actually possible I uh for computation
to arrive at the answer what is
impossible you know that's why and we
learn turns it turns out we we learned
that actually a lot things are not
possible you know it doesn't doesn't
even if you have a machine with infinite
speed and infinite
memory there are yeah there are there
are things it's just not it's not
possible we even with
infinite uh machine infinite memory is
just not possible okay well of course
for example one example most of you guys
know the most [ __ ] idiotic example is
the holding problem [ __ ] the [ __ ] the C
programmers C++ and Unix
[ __ ] they don't know nothing but every
time they they'll say holding problem
and tuning machine they meanwhile they
don't know nothing about the context and
and and and tuning machine is the worst
[ __ ] okay Lambda calcul is better
combinators is even better and even all
these you don't know you know they they
are part of the automat okay any
anyway so digression and digression so
let let me see what's the comments okay
so let me actually go back to the backup
thing so backup thing you know I I have
said so many uh [ __ ] in this video I'm
afraid that Google is going to censor
me you know so back to the backup so
originally I I was thinking back up the
from a mathematician's perspective the
the by Brute Force I don't care you know
efficiency just you can do it and by
boot Force because the power of
computers is getting bigger and gigabyte
terabytes hard dis you know just copy it
over and don't manually don't don't
spend a manual uh time to you know mess
with it but that turned out there are
you know because I also care about
efficiency so one thing leads to another
then you know then you have the then why
don't we make a g repo okay for each
directory so that way you know why not
because that way I have I have instant
backup you know ask SCH up you know if I
uh for example if I [ __ ] up this line
save close and
whoops I spend one hour's work is gun I
can just back up okay no no do No undo
is the first level of backup but no undo
I can you know I can go
here I just made a backup here so you
see copy it close it open it select all
paste so I got my thing
back but what if if what if I delete the
whole file without uh doing a manual
backup so I can do a manual backup by
just uh pressing three keys so now you
see let me try Okay Backup backup back
backup Backup backup Backup backup now
go to the DI directory refresh you can
see I've made so many backups so this is
so undo is the first level of backup but
once you close the file you all your
undo is gun so second level of backup is
the backup of the of the file so that's
second way but if this way also fails
then you then it's time to uh get check
out third level of backup for example I
can do get checkout for example let's go
to
um computer d uh uh for example a
programming blog uh let's try
to okay so let's try to let me show you
this uh zsh prompt set up so now I have
colorful prompt in zshell okay so you
can
see you can see my colorful prompt in
z uh open a new one
magnify okay so CD okay I don't want to
list directory because I don't want to
show my personal craft so anyway you can
see colorful prompt so you have you have
the user you have the uh host
name date
timestamp and current path this is you
know time stamp is uh greatly useful
because every time you do a sh shell
command it might run for 10 minutes or
hour you don't know when you come back
you can see every prompt has a time
stamp so you can automatically see how
long it you know something took without
you
know without you uh typing a date you
know in the beginning and in the end so
you can you know run any command go for
a coffee and when it's done you can see
how long it to take so it's it's great
to have uh date and time stamp in your
prompt
so this is one of my idea but the Unix
[ __ ] you know these Unix Linux
[ __ ] gigs you know they you you can
see for the past 20 30 years you know
they they have you know they have uh
website forums talking about promp they
have many colors or color or some you
know especially Z Zell okay they have
many customizations each one is geekier
than the other but you will see none of
it shows the time stamp you know
something I find the most useful but the
Unix people always they you know they
they don't they don't leave in the same
world as I do you know they have all
these powerful ways geeking but they but
you almost never okay see them show a
Tim stamp which I find the most
useful and another thing is that I
always want let me show you I always
want the prompt you see the prompt and
whatever I type is for example uh date
okay is in a separate line that's what I
prefer because this way you have a
separation you know it's Clarity but of
all the Unix you know prompts you know
these Unix heads they create on the
website you will not see this
neither it's so strange this is so
strange so that this is why I always
despise the Unix Fanatics because their
way in every just just about in every
way they hacker these nerds you know the
their method you know that that's not
you know that when I look at their what
they say you know they they always try
to tell you what what to do you know I
look at their stuff you know that that's
no good that's no good and they are they
are telling you this is the best way if
you don't follow their way you are a
troll that's what they this uh very
common behavior of this Linux Unix phos
ophy and python you know this Cy
[ __ ] uh okay so uh sh so I was
saying so yeah get backup so for example
you I can for example uh so that's Z
shell and in the same you know you can
also set up the prompt in bash and I
have a tutorial on how to do that of
course and for example uh bash color
prompt okay now I go to uh esell
magnify CD up G status okay get
status let's see what things I've
changed what what why is it taking so
long oh oh okay I've changed quite a lot
things JavaScript yeah hold directory of
JavaScript JavaScript in depth okay guys
you need to buy my JavaScript in depth
let's magnify okay so all this file
change and JavaScript blog and CSS
HTML and more JavaScript so what did I
change I forgot so let's open that okay
let's see press a key to open it and go
to the
diet okay so you see all these backup I
made automatically by a script because
because of find and replace remember I
was talking about find and replace every
day for the past 15 years I do find
replace on like a thousand to 5,000
files every day almost every day because
I'm using a static website uh so all
these all this backup you are seeing are
actually autogenerated F replace so I
forgot what I did oh yeah I remember
because I was trying to change um the
logo my JavaScript in depth logo you see
the logo at bottom so I changed that for
the whole directory okay so anyway I was
going to do a
um I was going to do a diff I can show
you a diff okay so let me show you so
this is how I you know so you are
looking at my
workflow uh shell command diff that file
and that
file okay do it okay so you can see the
difference okay uh let me show you go to
messages
buffer uh and
magnify you see when the difference is
not many it just shows in the message
buer so you can see the difference is
just
um yeah anyways anyway I made some
change in that so okay so let's go back
to
eell so I made uh so many JavaScript
changes and also Linux yeah also I made
some Linux changes so
now get ad
okay yeah it's taking a long
time what are you guys saying okay so I
guess I rambled so much
okay so get add so now get commit
Ado there it is
okay so the third level of backup okay
once I do a g commit let's go back to sh
again okay I already Clos it okay anyway
so magnify so uh magnify so now I want
to do let me show you
okay you see all these backup
files all this red one those are the
emac backup files I want to delete them
all in all of them in my entire s
directory okay not just this directory
because in this directory I can just
press a key in emac emac ask me if I
want to delete them all yes
so it delete deleted you know uh a
thousand files you know so but however
if you go to another directory let's say
Linux you can see then you know lots
lots of backup files so but I have tens
of directory so instead of doing that I
just go to Shell I want to run the
command that basically I want to run
this command okay find this is the uni
shell uh working find name anything end
in a t Tia then for example I can do
that uh actually not in this directory
so I actually CD up
then uh unknown primary what oh yeah so
I guess that yeah so it finds you know I
want to delete them but I can run a
command called interactive Abri then
type backup then there's a you know
because I have so many Abes so this way
all Abes are listed so I can just type a
few keys and find the brief I want
delete emx backup okay Enter so it
automatically type this command for me
so I press enter Then That is done so
all these backup files are deleted in in
the info
directory so now I close now I close now
if I show this file in browser uh set
prototype. entries so this is one of the
new JavaScript function uh okay set you
have a
set like a mathematical set but anyway
so if I deleted this file by mistake
okay delete by
mistake uh now I can go
to ah okay so I okay so let's uh let's
go to uh messages buffer
magnify okay so you can see this is the
file actually I made a backup so
actually open it show in diet uh let's
show that so this is the file I just
deleted JavaScript set prototype entries
okay let's let's uh simplify okay so
this is the file I just deleted now
the no I I made a backup but if I don't
have a
backup let's say let's say okay let's
say I let's actually just delete this
file okay delete
it so
whoops I deleted I deleted a important
file refresh file not found okay so what
do I do you go to uh eell get checkout
and type the file
name roofs updated One path from index
so so that
file that file refresh buffer okay
refresh that file magically
reappears so go to browser refresh it it
came back so this is the so using git is
the third level
of of
Revival from the
dead okay the first level is undo the
second level is manual backup of the
file the third level is skit the fourth
level is from your backup drive if you
by chance deleted your entire git repo
or your remote you know repo there's a
disaster then you get them back you
revive revive it from the backup
dis okay so that's about some of the
backup issue now back to my script uh
let's see close that close that shell
color prompt close that uh zshell prompt
setup close that why are we talking
about that uh
because close that close that back to my
backup file so I was saying so I wrote
this backup file where for
each this
directories first each of them is a g
repo so this this script will create a
zip file of each one of them without the
dot git uh repository okay but then at
this stage I'm wondering why should I
why should I write the sh script because
I despise the Unix [ __ ] I don't want to
use hack you know whatever the hack
created so I rather let's
say uh Pearl Pearl python or Goan or
Ruby any one of them would be better
than writing this sh script you know sh
script you know like I was wondering I
never wrote a sh script before because I
always used a pearl
before so I'm I'm wondering you know
when you create a function are these
variables local to the function or not I
don't know I don't know what's the
answer do you know
am I still
actually am I still
running uh comments
guys let's see uh let's see how long
I've been talking oh [ __ ] I already
talked for 1
hour feels like I haven't began
um exclude in our sync yes you know the
problem with our sync okay let me let me
talk about aryn aryn is one of the let
me show you because I have aryn okay
uh you know let's show why are you again
this Unix philosophy oh I know my God
you haven't watched you haven't read or
watched my stuff because I talked about
that for 10,000 times uh but anyway our
syn you see you see this is this is the
r sync I've been using
for for for 15 years okay you see the
complexity of the [ __ ] you know our sync
you know you see you know okay so you
have all these parameters right options
but the the then you have the exclude
you know okay let me tell you guys one
of the story about Unix [ __ ] up okay
what let me tell you and and that is
part of the reason only just a part of
the reason why I despise the Unix and
Unix philosophy because Unix
philosophy anyway let me let me just
talk about what I'm talking about now I
don't want to anyway yeah so anyway so
you see ourn you have these options you
know let me tell you one of the extreme
complexity of the Unix shell tools [ __ ]
is that whenever a command that has
options to exclude or include some
directories that becomes extremely
complex nobody can [ __ ] explain it
well okay I you know I be I've been I've
been doing Unix admin on Solaris since
year 1999 Okay so I know the stuff you
know if you are new maybe you will say
oh but you don't
know actually I know a lot I can tell I
I can ask you unique questions you don't
know even if you are assisted me for 10
years so let me so right now this point
is about in Unix okay let me be precise
in Unix shell command line tools such as
AR sync and there are quite a few
there's you know there's quite a lot of
them
when these programs when when they have
a option for specifying which directory
to include or which directory to exclude
you know this is a common need okay then
those commands are extremely complex and
and also inconsistent okay because every
command every command they'll do it in
their own way their own option names
okay uh
then okay so so so you know and and why
is it complex
because when you have a include or
exclude okay
directories first of all are you going
to use uh regular expression or uh or
shell
glob
okay first of all if your need is simple
you know you can there are many
complexities let me just explain okay
first of all are you are you talking
about includ including and excluding
directories or are you talking about
including or excluding files okay
because directories and files are
obvious obviously different you know
sometimes you all you all you need is
exclude some files sometimes you
actually you want to excl exclude some
directories they are different okay so
if you have a Syntax for excluding files
that may not work for directory okay
that's one of the first problem
directory three versus files now second
problem are you going to use a you know
exact file name or are you going to use
uh some kind of pattern such as glob or
regular expression okay this is very
complex too because let's say if you are
going to use a pattern okay okay if you
use a pattern that's great great for
example this pattern okay so for example
it's this exclude so this ex exclude
means exclude all all file so directory
that's begin with 2x okay so if you are
using a pattern but if you have option
for that it may not be convenient
because sometimes all you want is a you
know you don't want regular expression
you you don't want patterns of any sort
you just want you have a list of files
you just and they don't have common
pattern you just want you want to them
to be literal okay
but if your file name contain suppose
your file name contains this as risk
then you got a problem because now you
need to escape like back back slash
Escape all these file name characters
where it contains that uh you know that
glob you know shell GL you know whatever
the pattern special character you know
it's a practical issue because you have
a bunch of you know directories or names
you have to you have to be careful
because other you know this is easy to
make mistake because you if you forgot
to escape one of the character then bam
maybe you deleted entire directory in
your server on your server okay so this
is the second
complexity that is is your option for
including or excluding files or
directories are they going to be uh
literal or are they are you going to use
a you know some kind of GRA or regular
expression or pattern okay which one you
going to do this is the second
complexity or or maybe you should have
several options you know one option is
always about excluding using literal
syntax then another option is about
using sometime some kind of pattern okay
so this is a second SE this is a second
complexity third
complexity is that uh so if you are
going to use pattern pattern is very
useful okay because sometimes you want
to exclude all directories that begin
with 2x for example in this case you
need a pattern because it will be
impossible to specify you know to
literally list all those search
directories so you want a pattern then
there's a question are you going to use
a shell glob uh
system called called Unix glob you know
for example uh asterisk means any
character okay so that's one system or
are you going to use regular
expression so this is the this is I
think the uh what the third
wait the third or fourth complexity
anyway so because it m you know on one
hand if you use the sh glob that's great
works most of the time but sometimes
doesn't work because you need something
more powerful you know your pattern is
more complex then you need regular
expression uh but but most but but but
regular expression is usually unreadable
so there are advantage and disadvantage
of using sh glob or use regular
expression you know you have to make a
choice or or you could have have another
option that specifies whether you know
your exclude is a pattern based on
regular expression or the shell gra so
so let me summarize complexities one
direct Factory versus file name two
pattern versus literal file path
three uh grab you know Unix grab file
grab or regular expression you have to
decide now four the fourth
complexity when you have exclude or
include there arises the issue of
order so does exclude has precedence
over include or does include have
precedence precedence over
exclude this is a complex issue and you
know the different tools they have
different their own uh thinking
so and it's also a practical issue
because you cannot you
know suppose you know suppose you want
to exclude all patterns you know begin
with XX but except this one directory so
if you have xx1 if a directory name
start with
xx1 then you want that to be
included so you so so you can't you know
so you cannot so how do you do that
well one way is to spe you know one way
to is to have a new Option
include
that that some somewhat take presidence
over the exclude so in other words it
comes after the exclude so anyway so
there's the older problem it's kind of
complex this it's semantically
complex so of all these four
complexities you know that's a that's
big enough and you know each Unix tool
will have different ways you know the
Apache including Apache because Apache
in Apache config files you also have
this include and exclude issue very
complex one [ __ ] up
[ __ ] and the worst thing is the
documentation because these Unix
[ __ ] they are incapable of thinking
clearly so when they you know they write
a command such s you know aryn is a
pretty good example you know let's do m
page AR
sync guess how many lines okay make take
a guess how many lines is the man page
for our
sync is it 500 or 1,000 or
2,000 okay I will
say 1,000 okay let's
see our syn Comm
page go down to the bottom
2,800 lines documentation for our
sync how long they going to take you
going to read
this nobody nobody actually read the
whole thing this a complexity [ __ ] [ __ ]
assn [ __ ] Unix [ __ ] the Unix
[ __ ] typical the last Unix
tradition tool is kit [ __ ] kit no that's
why that's why when you are doing you
know you always have question about G oh
how do you do this but you heard it's so
powerful It's the Great
tool since sliced bread but G is the
last [ __ ] up in the Unix tradition okay
get is last one basically because the
then the millennial generation took over
and they they become something else they
got their
problems but I'm talking about the
traditional the Unix scrub so uh 200 you
know
2,800 lines for the aryn documentation
and let me add and it's it's written in
the most lousy incomprehensible way
that's the Unix man page it's the
worst system of documentation of the of
the entire uh Computing industry I can
say that okay so if you have a question
so we for example which documentation of
a programming language or a tool in
Computing industry uh one would say is
the worst that would be Unix man page
okay the other runner runner up would be
or the other you know top top five would
be python documentation Apache
documentation okay Unix man page this
these three would be the top
five but but the Unix people don't know
they think the man page is the best
thing you know they think they know
complete that's a un that's a that's you
know you ask me why are you against uni
Unix philosophy the the the Jon the
Mantra the chant you know Unix
philosophy is the cause of all these
problems because you spread the gospel
oh unix's philosophy we are we love Unix
philosophy that's why there are so many
people for example they think manage is
the great greatest things since Sid
spread oh man page great documentation
in depth technical detail
in fact it's worst
worst worst technical style writing
possible in human history Unix man page
[ __ ] and the Unix are syn you know we
talked about so we we we I so why do I
hate Unix why do I hate Unix philosophy
here is you know I've talked about a few
concrete examples one is the
documentation the worst documentation
but however all the Unix people they
think it's the best is they think in in
sometimes they think it's the best
literature you know imagine that in in
English writing department they think
it's like
Shakespeare in fact there are journalism
writing about about that anyway I have
article I have I have so many articles
on that so anyway iyn okay so let me let
me uh recap you know iyn one of the
complexity of Unix tool not just in our
sync but in so many other Unix tool is
when it involves
uh when when it
involves exclude or include directories
and the complexity are whether you're
GNA talk are you talking about directory
or are you talking about files only you
know because it's a big issue or are you
going to have a you know another option
you know one option for directories one
option for files you know or or you
you're going to depend on syntax you
know if the syntax ends in a slash that
means a directory if the syntax does not
end in a slash it means a file and
there's more complexities because in
Unix directories are actually a file
because directory technically speaking
is just a file
so so too many complexities so directory
so directory versus
file pattern versus uh literate file
path okay then Unix scab versus regular
expression okay then the order of EX
exclude and include okay that's another
complexity now that's okay that's one of
my criticism of Unix now maybe one can
ask the question maybe the the problem
about excluding and including
directories is inherit inheritant
complex that is that's just the way
things are there's no I mean it's
inherent it's it's like a math problem
it's not it's not artificial complexity
you know it's not something the Unix
people created because the problem about
excluding uh
including directories or files is is
just complex therefore you know some
Unix people might say you know they they
might retort or defend Unix by saying oh
actually the problem is just complex
it's not because
Unix uh that is partially true but no
the Unix is still [ __ ] the Unix
people because when Unix people do
trying to solve this problem it's they
made it far worse far worse especially
like I talked about especially when the
documentation doesn't
clearly you know delineate you know
explain the
issue so you know so as a concrete
example if you ask you if you if in your
day job you are going to write AR sync
you know AR sync is one of the greatest
most powerful tool of the Unix lineage
if you are going to write AR sync you
know in your job for backup for example
if you are assisted me or today is soall
uh uh uh uh something
up Dev up you know today there's a new
Jon Dev up so if you need to do a AR
sync for backup you know you you will
run into this issue and then you will
read our sync man
page you know then you know you I think
if you have done this before you know
you know my you know the experience it's
not a presentant experience then you're
going to go to stack overflow stack
Overflow there's a special section for
sis admin you know or Dev apps you're
going to spend hours then you're going
to try it it doesn't work then you're
going to do you know Unix the story of
Unix
so our syn you know our sync is one way
to do backup you know but there are uh
they are quite a lot of issues okay
maybe that's that's it for
today uh I
feel that's uh another rent this is one
hour pure rent on Unix today it ends up
that way and uh I talked about for 1
hour and uh so I
talked for 1 hour and 20
minutes and uh I'm not feeling so good
about it because I was
hoping the plan was going to do the plan
is going to C Goan to reite this this sh
script in
Goan uh why do I want to do that because
essentially I want to write them in Goan
as a rapper
but but there are issues about whether I
should do that because you know the
reason I want to do that is because
first of all I think sh script sucks you
know for example in this uh sh function
are this are this variables local to the
function or not I don't know but and
even if they are there are lots of
problems for example the you know the
the if statement you know if and fi you
know this idiotic syntax I don't want
you know I don't like hacks I don't want
anything that's ugly I don't you know I
don't want anything to do with it so I
don't want I don't want sh
script so another reason for example if
I I'm writing this this is a sh script
right so I have these directories I
rather use a list you know instead
instead of calling the function on each
directory I just write a list then just
write a loop and apply a function if you
are doing functional programming you
know you just map a function to a list
of
directories but you but in Shell you
know you you you have also s of problems
you know
I uh so if I can do this in
Goan it might be simpler you know I know
for sure I know you know because I can
write the I can write the whole thing in
emag list or python or uh JavaScript or
Goan it'll be more elegant it will yeah
kind
of a bit not you know so I can write
then in that then for each thing I will
actually want to do I actually want to
call get you know make a archive I can
just call sh script
so so that's that was my thought that is
why I want to write this in goand and
also um yeah but I'm I'm wondering
whether it's worthwhile
because because there are instances
where actually a sh script just let it
be you know
uh it's if you if I write this as a
rapper in goine or python the problem is
that sometimes it will end up with a
code being more elegant and easier to
manage but not always sometimes not
sometimes it's actually just leave sh
leave sh script alone as sh script why
because I I do have a example I showed
earlier in this talk you know uh
about this article okay one language to
rule them all what language to use for
find and
replace okay I think that's it for today
thank you thank you guys for
watching uh so today is about a lot rent
on Unix I guess so let me answer some
questions so Tanner says is this
complexity a problem with uni system or
the shell language they use seems like a
more structured command language is what
is needed although I've never seen uh a
thing well I hope I give I give
explanation
towards that
already
um I was always unable to spell uh isach
uh you mean the oh yeah the case the
shell you know the [ __ ] idiotic you
know
recently so in the past few days I was
looking at Shell because I was you know
I was trying to write this sh script you
know I was wondering whether you know I
was trying trying to think about you
know on one hand I was trying to write
this script on the other hand I was also
trying to you know because Mac switched
from bash to zshell be why because the
because the free software Foundation
gpl3 you know the Mac the Apple people
they don't want nothing to do with
gpl3 so so they bash you know they The
Bash on the Mac
up to up to uh 3 years ago was bash
version you know a version that's using
gpl2 now gpr3 began like 10 years ago
like 12 years ago so so the Mac never
upgraded their bash you know they
stayed in the version like 10 years ago
up to like three years ago why because
the Mac the Apple people they don't want
gpr3 [ __ ] gpr3
[Laughter]
the politics of the open
source then uh of course lenux also by
the way I should mention in case some of
the people will say oh yeah gpr3 is
great no no [ __ ] the open source is one
[ __ ] up [ __ ] you know the Linux Linux of
course and lenux towards the the guy who
wrote Linux also you know refuse to
adapt gpr3 gpr3 is the richest storman
thing he he wants he wants control he
wants control of his Empire in in in in
a sense okay there are many different
opinions but in a sense he created gpr3
because he want control of his
commune you know his his word so lenu
Linux and many any you know many open
source project or even G project they
began a re vote you know they don't
adopt gpr3 go [ __ ] yourself go with your
you know do your gpr3 in
emx and you know that happened all in
lots of places in Debian in you know you
know War you know the the war among the
good people open source
Fanatics uh it's pretty bloody war okay
because they don't they will not agree
then we [ __ ] you go you know you do
stuff I I'm you know first of all
there's open source Camp versus free
software Foundation Camp then there's a
lot a lot camps and then then licenses
1,000 licenses MIT Apache to Artistic
license they are each one claims they
are the most uh uh most uh great great
good for
Humanity but in the end they just want
their name to be plastered over this
open source Prett ious hypocrite
[ __ ] open
source uh okay I digressed so I was
saying so yeah I was writing sh script
and I was also uh finally made my uh
Zell prompt to be color because you know
it all this takes time you know like
when you use Linux every day you spend
hours you know geeking you know finding
out you know window managers you know
try so it takes time so finally I uh
made my zshell prompt color use and
useful to
me and then so I
revisit I Revisited the shell issue you
know the the boom shell bash Zell K
shell cell tcsh now shell you know and
also the mod you know the fish fish sh
is actually I think quite good and but
it's actually uh from 2005 so fish sh is
already 15 years
old and also by the way there's also
schem shell you don't hear it much
anymore I talked about it before in one
of my episode schem shell okay schem
this you know that language schem shell
so all these shells you know the the
shell War the war of shells is old the
the wall among shells is like today's
language War you know uh back 20 years
ago Pearl versus python then python
versus Ruby of course then you have
goand versus rust then you have closure
versus common lisp you know you have
Java versus C Java versus C++ versus c c
versus D versus EF g h i j
k the Unix the war the war among the
languages but before that in the
1990s and also 1980s but I wasn't I
wasn't around in 1980s I began my
Computing career in 1990s okay so but in
1990s there's a war that's is a shell
okay that's a shell so bash Kell
seashell that's a big war every every
programers is talking about my shell is
better than your
shell this is the reason why because we
have more Nots you you don't have monads
we have
monuts sh but Shia as time goes on Shia
the life of Shia they they kind of
passed away quiet quietly just like just
like Pearl is dead sha is also kind of
dead you know nobody's because for
example we talked about today grab said
you can write those in Goan in Ruby in
Java in in Pearl uh in python in 10
minutes in 5 minutes you can write one
that's better than grab all or or set
you know the Unix tools so in and and
actually the languages are far more
powerful than all these
shells so shells the uni shells became
it it becomes the sole purpose of shell
is just is just uh interactive use you
know allows you to have a uh for example
uh allows you to have uh you
know you know interaction with your uh
operating system then there comes
Microsoft
Powershell I think Powershell is the
best okay let's go to
Powershell you should learn Powers shell
okay you should I think it's I I I don't
know for sure but I think as a
programming language power shell is a
better shell is a b more a better
designed shell than all these other
traditional bash zshell Kell cell tcsh
you know that's my
opinion um maybe not compared to scheme
shell but I think so too uh Power shell
why because in general for comp computer
languages programming languages or
almost any technology
the later ones are better than the
earlier ones if the if their age differs
by 10 years old so how old is Bash Bash
was invented in 1990s 1989 bash how old
is pow sha power sha was B in 2005
around there okay so so what's the the
what's their age difference uh about 15
years Okay so so is that more than 10
yes so therefore power shell is better
shell uh in general because when it
comes to technology later
inventions almost is almost always
better okay so I think power shell is
the actually best best shell so and and
actually today it's all cross platform
so for example I can start the power
shell now pwsh
there it is I'm in Powers
shell now let's see uh
duh dos
duh power shell okay so there it is
poers
shell so if you haven't done already
learn poers shell read my tutorial okay
and I have a section that is the most
popular po Shell versus spash where you
can learn if you came from bash you can
learn how something is done in bash is
done in Powershell you know so you have
so this is a gateway to get you started
in pow shell because based on what
things you know grab grab find you know
things you already know by muscle memory
you you Al you can also learn how it's
done in power sh okay but I don't I
don't know that much in Powell uh
never um you know it takes time to
actually you know write scripts and
learn
stuff okay finally last words for today
if you like my stuff buy my tutorials
okay so you know I have iMac this
tutorial I have uh JavaScript in depth
tutorial or just PayPal me okay and uh
thank you PayPal me and patreon
[Music]
H have you tried Elvish
now if I remember correctly Elvish is
a wait Elvish Elvish is a new shell I
guess no I don't know you know I don't
know this happy New Year by the way yeah
Happy New Year's guys 2001
2021 yeah actually I should close down
it's over it's like 90 minutes
so yeah random chat yeah I had fun thank
you guys for
watching uh bye guys Elish language okay
let's see Elish language Wait no that's
not
it
uh you are talking about shell okay so
let's see
shell Elvis shell so lvis shell is a
friendly interactive shell and an
expressive programming language it runs
on Linux vsd and M OS and windows uh
demos able blah blah blah now is there a
Wikipedia article I always like
to check Wikipedia article first uh
maybe
not okay so let's uh check Elvish
shell yeah but sh is dead okay uh I is
it true now sometimes you know when you
make a comment or when you think when
you have some opinions
you you usually want to think about
seriously
like you you ask yourself when you have
time you know is it really true when you
know when you are when you casually you
know thought about something so when I
mentioned you know I just casually
mentioned yeah sh you know Elvish is not
going to go anywhere because shell in my
opinion is kind of dead okay the only
use for Shell is interactive shell
interactive you know and you don't do
much with that be you know the real
power of shell is actually the
programming the automation part and for
that
purposes PE python Ruby goand they take
over you know even PHP JavaScript you
know so Shia is dead so so that's my
claim but is it really true you know
maybe you know so you have to think
about it you know maybe is it possible
maybe something I didn't think about
maybe in you know so maybe is it is it
possible in 10 years after 10 years
actually maybe maybe some shell
becomes so popular
that you know like today bash is still
you know most useful because bash is the
most used language to install programs
on Unix systems on Linux bash why not
because it's great technology but
because it is the tool that everyone can
r on because it's everywhere and it's
stable you know it's been you know it's
there's like see you know there's a
momentum you know so when you want to
write a installer on Unix
server the one answer is Bash okay not
not all the new shells and better
features you know you have to use
spash but uh so is it possible that bash
will be
replaced anyway anyway I gotta go okay
so I gotta go and uh
um uh yeah so talk to you guys Happy New
Year