and guys oh I'm doing so bad today I
actually forgot about this well I didn't
I
there is a I didn't forget but but I
didn't look at the time so so I was
pretty late so so let's see actually I
am not prepared yet because let's see
what what topics Emacs Lisp random
keyboard okay so why don't we begin with
Emacs Lisp and let's do a yeah let's do
this
because yesterday and the day before we
did random stuff so today let's do email
list
oh hey z tron maxim do you have to go in
a bit like i'm wondering which should i
do eMac this first or random hold on
because you see i was working on my
website and i forgot to look at the time
that I was eating
what okay so
so yeah I will be back in four minutes
okay doesn't matter okay good
okay I be back in five minutes
I'm back so so let me get ready so let's
put this I need to go through my the
live chat room Oh actually actually I
can see it here then so no problem
pop chat hug I was working on my website
you see so I was working on you should
get a drink so let's have a simultaneous
coffee sip
[Laughter]
let's have a simultaneous coffee sip I'm
drinking this is one giant orange juice
and plus it's like 60% orange juice or
70% and 30% 30% energy drink today is
this let's have a simultaneous coffee
sit mmm ok ready 1 2 3
I'm having a mega sip okay let's begin
you see when you give a talk you observe
the audience and you work out how you
talk as you go because you know if you
see your audience's so sleeping you know
get a book they get bored you know you
see them you know doing something you
know looking at their phones then you
know you gotta do something you know
your talk is boring so you change the
subject or things like that
and okay guys say hi say hi so let's see
what we have here
random keyboard okay Bassel um you okay
thank you
eMac miss okay let's do a max list
Lisbon okay and oh this is okay yeah you
may at least and this is super
interesting you know I've been doing
this in the past few days you know so
today we're gonna do random chat but
also Emacs least Cody yeah I was
thinking to do email is first but
because when people watch my videos you
know offline you know they they might
they want they they want to begin with
some topic anyway so I have been doing
you see this this my programming block
let's go to my programming blog and let
me show you okay so
that's the rent alphabet this is super
interesting
okay the Deseret half a bet now the
Deseret alphabet it is a constructed
alphabet invented around 1847 eighteen
1847 in America by moments you know the
branch of Christianity moments you know
they call themselves LSD latter-day
saints something okay guys are you guys
are they still there type something okay
type something to make it interesting
okay actually I need to go to my my
channel and get this properly so hold on
so okay so this is so bad today oh okay
hold on a second okay
tick okay I'm still here and I need to
hide my screen because I need to go to
my youtube channel stuff YouTube
channels
you do YouTube channels dashboard okay
so go to videos and go to videos click
on live and click on that and other
features other features lives live
control room okay and live dashboard you
know YouTube Google in general they
change their interface all the time they
give every every every few months and
then they have better you know not now
they have a beta version you they leave
the beta like there for years and then
there's also option for you to switch
back to classic interface however the
beta version is not complete so you have
to you actually do have to switch to the
classic interface so it's very confusing
Google and Google has been hot become so
bad so I'm back I'm back again let's see
ok I'm back again so here is my Google
so I can actually see okay so this Eric
alphabet is invented in 1918 1847 by
moments and it's constructed constructed
alphabet the purpose of the alphabet is
to sew each letter the represent form
phonemes basically meaning a unit of
pronunciation so that when you write
English you know it's supposed to be a
replacement for Latin for English I mean
it can be it's supposed to be so when
you write you know English in the
Deseret alphabet you will get a
so that the you get the alphabet
principle now this is a term in
linguistics so the alphabet principle
means the pronounciation corresponds to
the written form exactly you know
somewhat like Spanish Spanish is like
that it's called alphabet principle so
when you write when you write indirect
tesseract alphabet you you you will see
you know it's it's written as it is read
so let me show you some written passage
in the Deseret alphabet let's look at
Wikipedia and it is let's look at this
picture and there is small second very
small look they have a Wikipedia logo in
the Deseret alphabet this wait is that
right yes there is a th yes exactly for
what you know that sound
so so this is how it looks like when
it's written for example now this is not
a good example to show the pronunciation
but but our Wikipedia you know it's okay
so this is x k CD comic that features
the so let us say ever notice how we
keep with Wikipedia as a new words it
really likes what
Marla mantle is a neologism for a
portmanteau created by incorrectly
combining a malapropism with a neologism
okay it is sales of a pod not to okay
anyway so so you can see let me show you
the passage okay so funds okay here is
the pronunciation you can see this is
now by the way there there are quite a
few phonetic alphabets for English in
you know constructed you know people
amended they are like at least five five
or six if you read Wikipedia you go to
the page spelling reform then at the
bottom you will see a bunch of them
actually there's a list of constructed
language anyway so there are quite a few
you know people invented characters to
represent the sound for English and by
the way you can also do it with AP this
international phonetic alphabet this is
called API invented by French French
people but the API international
phonetic alphabet the API which is this
part you see actually so let me show you
a few things since we are talking about
this so okay I use so many saw so many
branches I'm talking so let's see sorry
English APL phonetic API not it's not
called API I got it wrong so let's let's
find it okay so okay so so hold on a
second talk which let's go to a talk
talk page of bet okay alphabet principle
that's that's when the language is
written as it sounds as it reads then
there is the International phonetic
alphabet okay let's go through my
English Wadi blog and you will find it
there
IPA yes thank you Maxim IPA
International phonetic alphabet yeah so
I'm so silly but I'm not that silly
because you know in many of the
internationalized standards it came from
France and in fact in French they
reverse the letters for example metric
system you know
for examples standard GMT Geneva Geneva
yarn
well anyway yes do you get what I mean I
guess not anyway many of the standard
abbreviations for standard things they
they are not I said they reverse the
letters anyway I should be able to think
of an example but any air so body block
language and English let's see IPA
okay so so here's the IPA characters for
English this is our this ah this is long
ah this is all for example this is talk
hot Park car hug father and this is a
short
that part hot and so on add a you know
ii ii or so those IP a international
phonetic alphabet on the other hand the
middle column is American Heritage
Dictionary the symbol they use on the on
the third column is Mariam West Webster
so you see in general American
dictionaries they just cook up their own
characters to show the pronunciation but
usually in UK United Kingdom or
elsewhere India they all use IPA to
indicate the pronunciation so anyway
that is IPA
so IPA is a phonetic alphabet so why
can't we just use IPA to represent
English Wow because IPA it's rather more
complicated because IPA is rather very
detailed they do not just capture the
phonemes of the word they can they you
know IPA is designed to represent any
language you know because they they are
designed somewhat scientifically to
represent how your your mouth your you
know teeth position your lips your turn
position so they come up with this whole
bunch of characters now for English this
is basically all you need so you have
like one two three four five ten you
know fifteen symbols to represent
English sounds phonemes but however for
but however the full IPA
you know character said they are like
this thirty forty or something and and
because they are very detailed they can
actually actually capture not just the
phonemes of a language you know how the
the basic phonetic eunuch language but
they can also capture the little bit
kind of like the how each person
pronounce something differently you know
they try to do that so I've read that
upper opera singers you know opera is
usually written in Italian or something
and you know they need to see it so
sometimes they
use IPA to indicate how you sing because
when you sing opera usually it's you
don't see the way it's written so anyway
that's IPA
so IPA is very complicated it's got
fifty or you know and also it's got it's
not you know you see it's a combination
of characters so it is rather ugly if
you write English using IPA you know
because for example this AI is actually
two characters so a lot of people have
come up with a phonetic alphabet for
English IPA so a lot of people have come
up phonetic alphabet for English so
that's right this way alphabet is just
one of them so okay okay let's let's go
back to the Deseret off of it so you
know there it is that's interesting so
another one let me show you another one
so another one is Shavian
alphabet okay shall be an alphabet I
have it here now this is this is
invented in 1960s so let's see the
Deseret so this Deseret is 1847 so
Deseret was there first by moments then
the Shavian alphabet or shown it's named
after George but Bernard Shaw show show
it's a Irish playwright have anyone seen
George pronounce shows play or something
I've never so I am not familiar with him
but anyway it's named after him because
George Bernard Shaw it looks you know
apparently he is very into English
spelling reform you know he he one day
you know
he wants the phonetic alphabet principle
you know so but when he is alive he did
not invent it but however he written in
his will and he put some money so that
when he died you know he want people to
invent a alphabet so they started a
competition and out of a hundred a few
hundred entries
this one won't out so it's called
Shavian half a bit now there's some
interesting characters about shavon
alphabet now you see the this row and
this row they are like they are just
180-degree reversal and the top row is
like you have the ascenders like person
dos is like you know when when you have
like characters like hegemony
Mattia so ascenders is like when you
have characters like d f you know Oh a I
you so this you know the vows AEIOU okay
and this character you see they come
above it it's called ascenders then you
have descenders descenders is like G J
you know so in the shabby anova bed you
you have this the top lower centers the
bottom row arti centers and also the top
row they represent sounds like voiceless
consonants like you know anyway
voiceless consonants however if you
reverse it 180 degrees with descenders
then they are voiced you know they are
voiced version of the boilers one so
that's the the constants they are like a
couple couple of exceptions though but
anyway then they are these you know
characters that represents
sure let us rock they represent
consonant consonants and also vows okay
but you see okay so many of these
characters represent represents a
combination of vow and okay anyway so
that's what I'm you forgot his headset
so sorry he can re listen to your stream
okay me Michael Mitchell amici hey is
this stuff here including your Emacs -
Tokyo - no are you kidding this part you
me on my webpage this sorry info no so
my Emacs stuff is uh no go MX dot org
website I mean if you want to buy it
then you get that then sorry info you
got bunch of things you got math
programming languages you got you know
you know code and keyboard you know lots
of things if you like it if you want to
support me I sell it $200
it's got 4,000 pages you know anyway so
so let's so we talked about this writ
alphabet then and also the shavon shavon
alphabet then there is the Deseret
alphabet
okay Shavian and okay here disarray now
this irate alphabet there's also I mean
they all have lots of interesting
characteristics but this red one one of
them about this red alphabet is that
they don't have extenders and descenders
you see they don't have characters let's
go above the line you know go below the
line okay so let me actually let me show
you a sea
says let me show you what about the font
you know font itself is there's a lot of
things about fund fund a huge history of
font you know in the beginning the
printing press they it's the metal let's
see a font family standard meaning of
fun size okay here now this is very
actually very interesting you know when
you do website today you know using CSS
and you know that you know you can
change the font right for example you
can go to for example let me go to my
CSS file this is my CSS file and let's
search for all lines that contain font
you know these so let's go over here so
for example this line you say you see I
say font family times new roman' if that
is not found then use serif okay so you
have font family now on our website if
you change the font family they actually
change the font size it becomes you know
like it's not like you can just change
the font family for a different style
because every time you change the font
family your page you know the the font
size or change it becomes super small
you know and readable too big so every
time you change font size you need also
to change the I mean when you change
font family you also need to change the
font size you know so this is illogical
you rather think you know what why is
that because and there's no standard
like like each font family their size
that they you know suppose you know what
I'm saying is that you have two font
families let's say fun a and font P
let's say they both are using size 16
pixels okay which is standard 16 pixels
but however on a page they look very you
know they are apparent size is actually
different and there is no standard that
says what font family the default size
is actually what there's not
I mean even they are all the same size
but they are they did their size very
widely why is that because of these okay
so this picture it shows what actually
your font size means so this blue box is
the actual font size you know so fonts
font size actually means a designer's
you know virtual box where we think the
Box you design a font so so each font
you know for example this is one font
family this is another font family they
look different even though they are size
you know they are font size is exactly
the same
this is font family is much smaller
that's not all because for some font
they actually go outside of the design
box you know so this is completely
idiotic it's a problem you know it's a
major problem you can't you know you
cannot change it you know a farm family
easily because each time you change you
have to also adjust the font size so
they look you know properly so this is a
problem with modern you know the CSS
font community and they apparently they
are not no one has I haven't seen anyone
you know making a complaint about these
first this is actually a real problem
you know you know all these websites
they talk about design you know design
anyway I think they are crap okay they
talk out about responsibly you know
responsive design and all those you know
over the past twenty years all the
designers come up you know they tell you
what you should do on websites is it's
all garbage in my opinion they are
partly you know the reason they are like
that is is part half the reason is
because cooperation
you know corporatism they want to make
money so they design it you know they
all their ideas opinions behaviors they
are you know what they do is they want
to make more money they don't actually
really care about the actual you know
usability or design you know and
then you know the typical program was
like the hackers you know you're the
UNIX philosophy the type that they say
oh you need to be you know that's you
know you need to be you know readable
for the blind or things like that it's
so garbage real out-of-the-box thinking
yeah so anyway so that's about font okay
and then here is the terminology about
font you know you see you see you have
the cap hate a sender hate you have
baseline you have the exhale you have
the descender hate so so those are as
ascenders and those are T senders and by
the way font design it's like that
because I can show you Wikipedia
pictures actually let's disco font
design you know they have this truly
idiotic illogical standard is because
because historically originally when you
have a font font just means a set of
metal boxes that that you you use it
kind of like a stamp you know like you
know the thing is had to press it and
found okay let's see they have a some
pictures there let me show you I just
want to show you the picture now I guess
it's not here you know it's buried in
some of the other fund embedded in
buried in some other articles let's see
if we can find a typeface weight size
weight digital typography found family
typeface okay I think maybe it's the
typeface you know also this words font
typeface for a family they kind of also
change over time you know so
yeah anyway there is a Wikipedia
somewhere let's see calligraphy
type design typesetting ok typesetting
let's hope so okay there it is okay so
fun or internally is just set a set of
these metals you know that's why it's
called typesetting you you know you take
a bunch of these pieces you place them
on a row and you know you arrange them
you place them on road so it's that's
why it's a type set you know it's like a
set of things kind of like that
historically you know type set so this
is the you know this is this is the
printing you know this is the one of the
printing technology they change every
you know hundred years so anyway that's
you know the typeset so when we have you
know out the word today capital case
lower case Y Capital y lower why don't
you say big case or small case
well it's capped away in lower case
because upper case or lower case because
these boxes you know the capital case is
placed up top you have to reach for it
you know you take those you know pieces
those are up case then low cases below
that is what you have up case and look
you know locate cap cap okay is over
lower case that's you know history so
you know that's why it looks like so
that's that's font so that's one of the
problem with the CSS font problem okay
hold on a second let me copy that and
the meaning of file size I want to show
that okay close close close pasted
actually no one pays it so actually that
that okay so we
where did I go okay so it's it's just a
meaning of fun sighs okay so we talked
about type typeface font meaning of font
size IPA international phonetic alphabet
we talked about these Deseret alphabet
oh yeah so we were talking about this
right off a bit and the testament
alphabet is used by moments you know
it's a religious group and they part of
the reason is actually you know I think
you know people debate about it
part of the reason they invented this
alphabet is so that their writing can be
secret you know can be secretive so only
moments moments they learn it they read
it so they become a Sikh secluded group
so anyway so desolate alphabet now this
rate alphabet it also have capital case
in lowercase but they look exactly the
same you know they just change the size
you know which so this way is actually
kind of logical in a sense you know
usually things like that may not work
out you know because there are so many
factors in real life
but anyway another characteristics of
the Deseret alphabet is that they don't
have ascenders and descenders you see
you look at the characters all of them
are of the same hate you know that
turned out to be a mistake you know well
you know the people they designed it
mentioned later it's a mistake because
when you don't have
ascenders and descenders every character
it becomes uniform and it is actually
harder to read so that's interesting
thing about font so I was walking on my
website with these you know that's a
Chinese characters so I was you know
written with a brush this is this is
sunny Chien which is considered
considered the father of China both in
Taiwan and you know China People's
Republic of China
you know bad by the way so let me tell
you the clarified the naming of China
so you have Chinese you know you know
you have China which is a big land then
you have Taiwan now the reason they are
different they are to two different
government because back in 1950s
there's a giant civil war that you know
there's two parties the Kuomintang Party
and the Communist Party the Communist
Party is partly supported by Russia and
the KMT Kuomintang Capades partly
supported by USA you know you give them
weapons so they fight so even eventually
the Nationalists you know the the
momentum the Nationalist Party they lost
so they fled to Taiwan in in 1950 or
1960 so somewhere around there I was
born in 1968 so anyway so that's why you
have China the Communists you know drew
with the China and you have a different
government the nationalist rules Taiwan
that's why you have did you know
different now the the official name for
the china the big China is People's
Republic of China now the official name
for Taiwan is Republic of China so you
see there's a difference when is
People's Republic of China the other one
is just Republic of China but usually
you know we most people you just go at
Taiwan and Taiwan today there's you know
this many chaos and also they want you
know some part of people some some
people some you know they want in that
independence meaning that they want to I
want to be a country by itself like the
name will be just tie one knot not
anything Chinese or China it's like what
I was you know they have a you know
that's and one you know time is now
several political parties in anyway but
however in both countries okay in China
the mainland China they are leader you
know the paramount you know the official
leader is the Mao as you know Mao Zedong
you know the MAL guy on the other hand
that
the nationalist China the Taiwan
originally that I want Nationalist Party
supported by USA they they are leader is
the junk I see ok hi good morning green
deck jankoji okay so so the the founder
of these two different China parties are
you know different but however both
Taiwan and China they recognize this guy
son Asian so here's his name sunshine he
is recognized as the father of modern
China because it is he began to
modernize China you know throw away the
dynasties the you know Emperor the yeah
the Emperor the dynasty they change to
into the modern kind of you governed by
modern law kind of so sunnysean you know
that's kind of the history of China
which is heavily influenced by the
communism you know back then because
communions communism was a thing but its
etiology you know where everyone will be
happy
you know you share you know things like
that anyway so that's a little story
about China in Taiwan so we were talking
about this different alphabet so let's I
think this let's do Emacs then so Maxime
are you still there
let's Maxine Maxine okay so let's to
Emacs there is one thing I want to do
okay let's go to let me show you okay so
you know actually there are so many
interesting things I want to talk about
because we haven't talked about these
several blog things this right alphabet
shall be an alphabet
okay anyway so let's talk about eMac
please let me show you what I want to do
so I'm going to I want to code I'm going
to do a live coding and I'm going to
show you now I'm going to explain what
do I need to do so this is my talk show
one of Mike's a talk show I put on my
website so I let's open the page so you
see view browser view in browser okay
that's that and you can see this YouTube
video here now this text block of code
that's YouTube video so now let me turn
on saw start command block mod okay so
so on the Left window
you can see all my Emacs commands okay
so this this block of code is this
YouTube now now you see so it is you see
here embedded let's go to a YouTube
video so let's let's try let me show you
some commands Emacs commands
let's see YouTube what is interesting in
YouTube
stupid dr. ko always go to Wikipedia
okay so let's pick something you know
generics I'm like of general interest
okay okay
you know the YouTube advertisements well
let's pick something generic let's see I
don't have anything generic do I the
best of classical okay let's pick this
amazing counterpoint now a counterpoint
is counterpoint is the name one second
okay
counterpoint means you know it's a
technique taken technique of composition
to compose a type of a song type of
music called fugue fugue and cannons who
are not kind of you okay which is famous
you know most famous box box fugue is
most famous famous now this is very
interesting if you are into if you are
not if you are into math programming
stuff so you might go to youtube and you
know look up what what is a fugue and
Wikipedia there's a lot all costs anyway
fugue the the primary way to compose
fugue the reason fugue the gist the
essence of view is that its counterpoint
meaning that mean meaning that you have
one melody okay one melody then you have
an another melody but somehow these two
melodies are related like they contrast
each other and basically you use the
same melody throughout your composition
but you you you two variations on the
melody then you put that two of them
both of them together like in parallel
or three of them together like you can
reverse the you know play backwards you
can prolong them you can shrink them the
length or you can move them higher pitch
lower pitch or reverse the pitch
you know when logos high it becomes high
go slow you know things like that so so
all these are taken
called counterpoint now the thing is you
cannot simply you know you cannot start
with the melody and start to just mix
them randomly like prolonging it reverse
it you know and put two of them together
that because that doesn't sound good you
come out with a sound not so good
actually I'd you know I haven't tried it
you know you guys who into synthesizers
you might try it but I think you know if
you stood apparently it doesn't sound
good because otherwise people would you
know you'll be so easy to create phew so
the art of the fugue is about you know
using these techniques however you want
to make it so that it comes you know
when it's in place it it sounds really
great fantastic so this one okay so this
this video amazing counterpoint analysis
of XI sharp minor fook from the
well-tempered clavier I don't see sharp
minor I think that's a few number four I
think let's play it a little bit let's
see
okay I guess you guys cannot hear it
much maybe a little bit this is the most
amazing few few indeed amazing
counterpoint this is this is my Fit you
you could say this is my favorite song
of all of all the songs in history pop
or whatever this piece okay let's say
top five you know this is a few I
believe it's Fugue number four exactly
okay few good number four Bach's
well-tempered clavier book one fugue
number four this is a you know
counterpoint is it's got five voices you
know people say this so-called five
voices meaning that you have okay you
have one piece one melody okay give them
a melody you do variations on the melody
like reverse speech you know upside down
you know turn your left right move it up
or down so you use these techniques to
create a few however you put you put
five of them like at some point there
are five of this is going together at
the same time so that's why you know
it's it's incredible it's difficult to
do I mean you can do it you can just
randomly pick an immunity and you know
create one but it doesn't sound good
in order to sound good now that is a
subject matter of music theory you know
so you know so what does a to knows when
does to know it sounds good
you know when when is a sequence note
sounds you know melodious ways it
doesn't sound good
you know for example one example of not
sounding good is the same sound all the
time like that you play that for five
minutes that doesn't sound good you know
so we went when does you know you have
this bunch of notes you can think of
them just like numbers you know so what
sequence of numbers make it you know
melodious to the to our years okay
that's one thing music theory then music
theory talks about
you know how many you know when does
when does a simultaneous number of known
sounds good when does not and how do you
you know make a sequence of them such
that it sounds good
so that's the part of music theory and
so when you write a fugue you want them
to sound good of course and that you
know so so Bach wrote this ones are very
interesting so anyway so for example so
I'm writing a blog you know today I woke
up I saw these oh this is fantastic
copy the URL I go to my blog I paste it
here you see that's a URL link then I
press a button okay let's see there it
is it becomes that okay let me show it
again let's put it here
okay let's show it there so the command
is our HTML any link of Phi but actually
actually that the command HTML ending
any link of I actually is a wrapper to
sever a bunch of commands in this case
it actually called youtube link effects
our youtube link of i okay that one so
enter you see so you see I have this
command I it changes this URL into this
form this form is you know this form is
is what you would need when you want to
embed a YouTube video but sometimes you
know when I'm looking at my blog you
know so I I have written this blog right
I have written it now okay so wait hold
on a second so I have written this block
now I want to tell people about this
beauty YouTube video so I need to
actually convert it I want to you know
pace to Twitter I want me I need to
convert the you are back to the original
you know boom so that's what I need to
do so let's write a command let's let's
write a command right now
oh you can get copyright strike for
classical music really not today well I
because because I see tons of them and
usually they don't get take taken off
like usually they don't take it taken
off instead YouTube will say you know
typically like if you go to any I give
you just search for Bach music let's do
it
YouTube I have this question you pick
actually I want a park well-tempered
clavier booked one okay let's see just
where temple crappier and okay for
example this one by the way this this
piece you know Bach's well-tempered
clavier there are two books you know two
books of compositions book one and book
too
each book has 24 tributon Fuchs 24 of
them each one is a pair pre dude and
fugue so a total of 48 songs in each
book so book one has 48 songs 24 of them
preview 24 of them few we usually they
are paired like number one pretty old
view number to preview for you you know
so same thing for book number two now
you know you go by records but you know
you want to buy records of these there
are many pianists you know play that or
or using you know have C code of all of
them I listened you know like tens of
them because I'm very into it in the
1990s and you know you listen to of them
okay so let's show Saudi Park Nietzsche
okay so I used to like write a list of
all you know I'm thinking I create a
list of all
psycho compositions in history and with
my own ratings and comments on it so I
started to do this in 1990s so this is
you know this is part of it I haven't
been updating it because you know any
any because since the internet began
since the internet began you know
there's lots of things on the web you
can you know Wikipedia they have far
more detail anyway so so here is the
list of all the least not all actually
least compositions and so I have one for
par let's see somewhere here ok anyway
so anyway so you see I have MIDI files
here MIDI file used to be popular but
today no browser supported out of the
box you know it just downloaded very
annoying you will be fantastic because
MIDI MIDI is a format digital format to
records the notes so it's particularly
good for instrumental music like piano
Symphony because the file size is tiny
you know for example four or five
minutes music in mp3 which is usually
five megabytes but in MIDI is just five
kilobytes
you know it's tiny because they only
they don't actually record the sound
they actually they just recorded the
note and how long it lasts things like
that and what instrument you know so you
got just a bunch of notes this so this
is very extremely arrogant does a
program you know this is truly elegant
and fantastic but however to play MIDI
you need you need a synthesizer because
it only contains notes you need a you
know digital piano to actually play the
note so back then you know in year 2000
it's very popular you have you know
browsers you have plug-in you can just
play it but somehow it just rotted away
so you know people don't know what media
is anymore except in the music music
industry that is still critical so
anyways so these are MIDI I collected
you know they had you know they are
open-source mostly I mean without
copyright it usually is hard to find out
what's a copyright but I try to collect
only ones that without copyright Oh so
back
speaking of copyright back to the you
know what we were talking about so of
all the performance of the box where
timber crappier this one is my favorite
absolutely this wonderland Oska okay
wonderland Oska she you know she say
she's a park specialist and also she
plays a very very weird instrument this
this is half C code which is a precursor
to piano but however her she is using a
particular harpsichord made just for her
actually it's it's called kravid
you know something clever hopsicle
anyway anyway you can look up Wikipedia
$1 nan desuka so so her performance is
my favorite but the recording is not so
great because back then this is 1980s
you know she died you know I think 1980s
or something the recording is not too
good because you hear you know the
background noise and so on but her in
you know the in the music community you
know pianist community is a her
interpretation you know they you know
each community they have their jargons
so instead of singing her performance or
her style you say her interpretation of
Oh somebody's you know I like this
interpretation of Chopin you know you
know at least you know those are
chuggins you know the elite you know the
you know knowing those jargons keep
you is a badge for for you being in a
community like for programmers you have
to speak of hacker hacker you're a
hacker in the you know stuff so yeah so
we were talking about copyright so there
are tons of you know hundred thousands
or millions of classical music and I
wonder about this is definitely
copyright I know this is by RCA I don't
think it's expired
anyway a lot of they I don't think this
is possibly I doubt it but anyway you
know what happens you see you see our
music on YouTube view CDs okay let me
show you you see here about few years
ago maybe five years ago YouTube started
to have this this thing so he says you
know music in this video because they
have AI you know they know with what
music it is and you know music in this
video
listen ad-free with YouTube premium and
so on and also look here license to
YouTube by then you know whatever the
company now this section is not added by
this guy I know food yeah I know for
sure 100% it's not added by whoever
uploaded the video that the guy who
uploaded video the video typically arse
canvas you know they just they copy you
know they take things they upload and
they they make money they put ads I have
ad blocker so that's why you don't see
it you know the typically I love you on
a video like these two hours you see ads
every five minutes you know these are
this typically these people are scumbags
you know that you you have like millions
of them on music on everything scumbags
well anyway YouTube itself is also a
scumbag of course they are just they are
just legalized scum so about five years
ago YouTube started to do this thing you
know license buys something something
now you wonder so I wonder what is the
karate
you know cane iPhone
okay I just rip this and put down my
website do I get sued you wonder about
that you see because anyway I suppose
this is actually legal because you know
Google probably talked to many of these
companies and so that you know so my
question is does the ad money in part go
to those companies yes here's my
question do the ad money you know so
this guy I suppose he's got ads so I
think 30% or 40% goes to the video maker
that whatever who uploaded is the other
60% go to Google now my question is does
some part of that actually goes to the
music company that is my question
because you know I I observe things I
want to know if they are Google is being
us come back here you know you know they
are powerful so green deck you can get
copyright for a second
I heard that some orchestras have
copyright for their specific recording
yeah of course you know if you do a
recording that's absolutely copyrighted
by you but but the composition is also
copyright but the four classical music
they are you know a long time you
expired if they don't have copyright law
back then Oh usually when music is
detected all ads goes to music rights
owner is it true because I'm not sure
because otherwise you wouldn't see lots
of these videos you know because these
people I know for sure maybe not him and
I haven't looked into this guy I mean
there are ten thousands you know hundred
thousands of them if if the if YouTube
actually take the money you know if
these people don't make any money I'm
pretty sure they'll start uploading they
will starve to
in that but they are not stopping you
know you still have lots of you know so
yeah so maybe I think they are still
getting money you see this is the scum
part of Google you see if we go strictly
by legality okay Google should not you
know when Google sees this Google should
immediately kick the guy off because
that's copyright you know right now
Google talking about you know weep
talking about you know government all
the nice people they talk about you know
following in the law so copyright so
Google no this is not by him Google
should kick him kick him out however
apparently Google is actually paying him
you know because ads you know he so far
we are guessing a bit a bit here so so
Google so so what here's the thing was
you know so I'm thinking so Google
actually they want this scumbag they
want these guys to upload video so that
you know so these scumbags are actually
working as a farm workers
you know they so they they upload also
the videos you know you know you know
millions of people in every corner of
the world you know from music you never
heard of you know copyrighted music okay
Google want them to to do that so once
to do that Google pay them a little bit
of course 30 percent or whatever but the
point is these millions of people the 60
percent of money goes to Google so
Google benefit forget about copyright
you know if you truly cared streets if
you stick to low then these
should not get any pay this they should
not get any money right but if they
don't get any money
nobody will start to upload any music
anymore
so Google lost these millions of you
know farm workers kind of making money
for Google so Google is the
scumbag you know one of the most if you
know if that is true you know these big
companies perform you you had back we
are almost done actually so she
we still do the list yeah so a lot of
Asians Mack Maxime deuced
likes to see it still maybe I should
complete it it will take probably 20
minutes 10 to 20 minutes
Maxime I see you there
let's see how many seven people so
actually yeah so this talk is getting
known long so let me try to do it okay
so so okay so what denied what do I need
to do so I go to my Emacs Maxime okay so
let's do this
Elise then let's see how far we can go
so I go to my Mac I go to my Emacs my
any file directory I create a new buffer
here I save it as X X YouTube Daria
okay just just a temp temp name okay and
still it today state and let's define
okay let's define different saw YouTube
get link again
okay let's just render name okay cuz I'm
back YouTube URL meaning that we want to
convert this block of text to a original
URL so what I do so we got a text here
so let's start to code it let's make it
simpler so let's say region okay meaning
that to code this command we have to do
a region first because otherwise we need
to you know find the beginning find the
end let's just do the region first if we
have time let's do something so so let
so let I want to two variables P 1 and P
2 those are beginning position and end
position region beginning and region end
so set we don't need set ok so here let
me just do so P 1 we are equals to
region beginning ok and P 2 will be
equals to reach an end position okay so
we got P 1 and P 2 and now let's do this
quickly without thinking about you know
elegance of efficiency okay so and so we
got a region so region so
now to region okay I want to narrow to
region p1 p2 so that my code will not
touch anything outside of this this
block now to region but before we do
that we need to remember what is the
region because otherwise when the
command is finished people people will
end up like just like that narrow to
region you know we want to we don't want
you know we want to end up like original
however they begin so region so I forgot
what's the command so go to Emacs
practical Emacs then go to region
practical eMac lease then eMac these
basic functions by basic functions so
let's see buffer kept up a name switch
buffer create buffer queue buffer okay
it's not there and coos above a read
write write command okay mark and region
say the excursion actually that's good
answer but that doesn't that doesn't do
this one there's another one the savoury
restriction is safe Saku supposition and
the current buffer you know in case you
switch to other buffer and other things
but it doesn't save I don't think so it
doesn't save we can try it
save restriction okay so let's so let's
do that so let's just do that okay okay
so let's eval
so now I go through this buffer I call
the command saw YouTube okay exam back
YouTube URL region oh I need to select
the region okay select the region
couette saw back YouTube symbols value
is void why is that what let symbols
value as variable is void p1
oh I got it wrong okay so so this is the
problem of paren I think that yeah yep
so you've a buffer let's try it again
eval buffer cervical region coda command
saw back YouTube URL region co-ed it
works thank you
he said really I guess oh so they say
v600 same restriction yeah okay so I got
it so yeah so safe excursion does not do
that but save restriction does save this
restriction is what I wanted but I'm
pretty sure safe excursion does not do
that but however that that got me into
this
okay so that's what we want so we save
this future restriction and then narrow
to buffer then let's look at the way is
my code okay so so basically we want so
let's copy that here so go to cha buff
buff
point minimun okay
point point minimum point me means the
returns a number that is the the least I
mean the beginning of the buffer so
typically it's one okay it's it's
usually always one actually I do not
know a case when it is not one so it's
like you can say one so we want to go to
the beginning and let's let's use my
tutorial to get a template so that's
what we want to do now is find and
replace find me face next so there is
the we have the template here let's just
copy that so go to chart template
finally place case fold case fold search
yes case for means case insensitive okay
true means case insensitive okay then
then we want to go to chop point minimum
okay then we want while such okay split
while such such that replace by that
then such that replace by empty okay so
this is actually quite tedious it's but
few more then we want to such that by
okay then that and we don't care
actually okay let's just code it so I
want to okay so hold on a second so
first of all it's on top figure I want
to remove figure right but we I don't
want to be more figure caption but I
want to remove that okay then I want to
remove remove the frame
actually
actually the best thing to do is we just
want to yeah we just want to search for
the source yeah lambie's so city
actually what oh you want want or we
need to do is such use a regular
expression search for this line and
extract this URL then then then money
then change this you are without the
embed basically that's all we have to do
so then put that on a creep report you
know on the key ring yeah that's all but
since we are doing this let's just try a
different feed it you know since you
know so we can just show some codes see
how they run yeah okay so so figure
caption so go to go to cha point me and
search for word okay
search for was figure caption okay and
that we don't need okay and split go
back we need P 3 P 4 positions okay set
P 3 equals 2 point okay so this will set
the point to the end of video caption
okay then let's do that again go to the
beginning and search for that such
forward then search
okay and set that to people okay now now
let's delete
okay let's just try that so what we have
what we doing is that we are okay so
this whole block this whole block needs
to be inside okay so what we are doing
is narrow to region and start to find we
face previous figure we face figure
replace i frame then go to the beginning
find the end position of video caption
save it to p3 then we got a beginning
find the beginning positional figure
caption save it to people then we delete
then we okay so then we buffer stream no
properties okay now we we add another
variable meet okay then we say set meet
okay then we extract from position p3
and people now that is a figure caption
text okay this is fig cap text okay
[Music]
okay so then we did we to be repeat DV
the figure caption delete the figure
caption tax then we let's say let's see
what happens now okay now let's give out
a go back here go back to my okay here
okay make a backup now select it call
the command let's see
great we are halfway done so you know
you remove so the tax except this frame
thing okay let's continue on with that
so back to our code so so far we need to
let's do that okay so now we need to
extract these so let's do that go to the
beginning go to the beginning and such
forward rejects
okay so such forward regular expression
then the regular expression we want is
this okay is this part okay so it's
going to be let me let me try to type it
first of all we don't need optional okay
their search for sr c equals true okay
then okay here is the here's when you
need lots of back slashes
to fix syndrome okay let's try it if we
can do that okay i have a bridge so we
so what we want to search we want to
search any character and here we reach
the back quote I mean the double quote
okay so that expression is okay we can
type it actually
let's capture anything , / A to Z a to Z
okay 100 mole actually let's say not
backslash not backslash that okay and so
I think that's the expression we want
let's just try it
put it here okay so so that is the
pattern to capture the URL basically but
now in when you have a regular
expression and when that regular
expression is a list you need more back
slash so from experience I know you need
that there you need that this is Emacs
let's try that okay you know extra
expression toothpicks syndrome okay so
for a regular expression so once we surf
on that we we want to get the captured
point captured you know the URL so match
string wait wait what happened okay so
match stream
SiC you you are let's say YouTube URL
let's say you are okay
then match stream first okay option we
don't need option okay then then let's
say then okay then go back to the
beginning
search for word okay search for iframe
then delete current lying okay what's
the command for delete line cure line I
guess what is a what is the command to
cure current line
I guess Kilroy
okay so Kyo lying oh my god this today I
wasted lots of time so Q lie so Q lie is
okay so Q line let's see you see what
what we do not want a command that is
designed for interactive use it it's
always better to use a command that's
not designed for interactive use in
Emacs Lisp so actually the Q line is not
yes okay I know I remembered I think
well if you want to know for example if
you go to my email is tutorial search
for line you see there's other code
that's all about money manipulating
lines you know which one is proper to
use you know you have line beginning
position you move beginning of line next
line and but anyway I know what the the
the you know if you want to kill the
current line in eMac this the best way
is this okay let me show you
delete region okay delete region okay
then use the region and give two
positions the position will be line
beginning position use that function
okay use that function not any other not
you know or the other line pick
beginning position not others okay
so DV region line beginning position
line and position that's how you kill
the convoy delete it not not putting in
a curing okay so we search for word for
iframe then we just delete that line
because we already extracted that you
are we don't need a line anymore so so
once we extracted the then we say insert
okay insert URL
okay now the URL is a new variable we
need to add it here okay let's say
YouTube URL okay YouTube you are
you know I could I usually try to use
the word that use a string that is
unique you know instead of an English
word because that way when you need to
refactor when you need to find replace
for example I want to rename this
variable I can do so easy without work
you know
without stamping on others so it's a
good thing to have unique variable names
that is why I use these names okay so
give out this buffer go back to this
with this buffer selected let's see if
it works
please meet our X star back YouTube okay
go ahead yes yes thank you
it works the guys say something okay I
think I feel lonely here we are and
we're so we are done so there's one more
thing to do because this this URL is not
proper you know it when you paste that
you are out you know that you are is
designed for embedding but if you pace
it YouTube will play it not always
okay your ear work now okay but for
example if you paste this URL in Twitter
it will not generate a icon and also I
have noticed you know last week the
Google's come they change things all the
time secretly you know I have noticed
for some URL this this URL I mean it's
for some YouTube video this you are will
not work at all meaning for example I
find some URL and I you know I use this
embed URL I go to the website I paste it
I press Enter
it says video doesn't exist okay
but however if you remove the you know
if you change to the proper URL so what
is the proper URL okay here is the
proper URL so let's let's complete it
thank you thank you
well among you so here is the proper
format for a URL so you instantly embed
you want watch question mark v equals to
okay that's what you want so anyway so I
was saying you know the embed URL does
force you know it sometimes stops
working because I think it's because for
no good reasons because YouTube some for
some political reasons they I think you
know it's my guess okay YouTube peak is
becoming you know Google becoming
unpredictable they change things I will
without telling you so anyway so you
know it's it's different ten years
before ten years before they are like
they have API you know they please use
our API they are so helpful and you know
they are you know right you you are
right but that's not the case I mean I'm
talking about I'm talking about the
video that that did not disavow in bed
you know but you are right there is you
know some video you can disable embed so
there's one more thing to do you see so
we need to change this format to the to
the other so it closed it reopened let's
go back to the Ilia II Magnus so there's
one more thing we need to do but
meanwhile I need to fix this no no no
it's good it's so first of all okay so
okay so that's that is that so
originally it looks like that yeah I
think I have a backup here it's always
useful copy-paste close so back up check
if they are identical such weight
identical okay good
so anyway so this so that's this one
more thing to do so okay so what need to
do is insert URL go to go to cha go to
the beginning of the buffer then search
for word search for word I want to
replace embed okay I want to replace the
word embed / okay copy that
okay so I want to repay as I want to
find the embed sash and then
such for then replace match okay then I
need to insert these these parts this
part this string that's it let's hope so
eval buffer go back where is it here
okay select it call the command please
yes it worked
let's try it coffee yet brave opening
brave open opening brave we don't want
to open brave yeah close close
brave wait so open a new tab paste the
link enter wait did it simply change how
long second open a link open tab paste
oh we need to delete the question mark
ie l equals to zero yeah one more thing
okay one more thing you know so it's
cumbersome wherever want you you want to
do finally facing Emacs because you need
actually three lines but I actually have
a package that simplifies it just search
for you know on my elbow you max website
anyway so we want to release equals to
zero we want to search for that okay so
Eva buffer go back well is always
somewhere how I crossed it then okay
this is wrong again
okay another command to the rescue show
copy history and now this is what we
want
copy history copy curls
paced pace it's just pace a lot so we
can work on them so okay so now cert
that call the command yes okay you
question mark is wrong okay oh you need
a question mark so this will be crashing
man give our buffer okay let's try it
again
what wait something is wrong
Yeah right anyway so what go to mean why
is the release not deleted
oh okay so yeah I actually should be
here
the eval buffer selected code the
command yay
I think you're will copy the URL open a
new tab paste good so that's that's it
for today you know it's one big rambling
and I was late so anyway so that's done
I hope you I hope you guys learned
something you need to put KU sarang last
/ what do you mean oh no no what
happened is that the you see what I was
doing is here you see I move the cursor
you know remember we moved in bed here
once we remove the embed we can insert
the watch there because it needs to be
you know right there but however if we
do this first if we do this the cursor
will be at the end of the line so then
you insert a watch you know that's the
wrong place so that is why so the this
you see this needs to be there
anyway the whole code is not you know
it's I mean I mean this is just quick
demo I mean if you want to really want
to do this there's a lot of factors to
be done you know this is this is just
quick demo I mean it's good in a way
that it shows you you know how each
thing you know you do each thing but if
you pay but on a whole I wouldn't you
know this this there are better ways
because on the whole you would actually
first use a regular expression to
extract this part then to another
regular expression to extract the
caption part then just remove the whole
thing then paste those two lines that
that that's what I would do I think that
that would be better so
some of YouTube video disabled in bed
okay so yeah yeah YouTube the YouTube
API is cancer home phone it does not
allow to listen to videos in the
background why does it not yeah yeah I
don't know but yeah you see YouTube you
know over the past 10 years they become
bad yeah I mean Google not just YouTube
Google they they change things and we oh
they do political things they don't tell
you they do you know devious needs to
make money in things like that so Bethel
muses there is an open source app called
pipe that fetches the website version of
the YouTube and allows you to listen to
videos in the background does that
extract the view to the video as well is
just audio because I mean I'm using the
YouTube get I mean there's a there's a
Linux command I mean it's also available
on the Mac and Windows it's a command
line you YouTube download YouTube
- DL okay well let me show you that you
are because they are a lot fake things
these days
so solid Linux is go to my website okay
so I have it written here you just go to
my Linux page this is a Linux
by command line tutorial it's very good
for beginners all the essential command
lines you know you can operate you know
you need on Linux you need is here so
and I explain concepts you know such as
permissions user groups top processes
things like that and so let's see if
it's it's such for YouTube okay it's not
listed here because it's not it's
somewhere else you know I
Enochs miscellaneous let's see YouTube
there it is okay Linux command to
download YouTube okay so that's how you
use it YouTube that DL so this is the
website now you have to be careful so
this I trust this website right now but
you are not sure you know tomorrow you
can you know someone can sort it out you
know they'll be sold out and then you
have you know whatever more where
especially when your update like on the
command line I can call youtube download
I actually have a brief you see youtube
download then I just paste the URL of a
YouTube but sometimes you can code
update so like there is a command update
then it automatically pulls from pull
from the github but however when you do
that you cannot be sure that the github
owner changed you know it sometimes
happens you know sometimes he maybe he
sold it out you know or maybe he he no
longer you know he went away somewhere
you know so there are all these things
you have to worry about so anyway so
that that is useful command I use but
type so what is the URL for pipe then
money money yeah thank you or like yeah
I found that
so that time you say anyone seen
screwing it smaller you Tyrion yeah
oh so you have used our engine or
YouTube I never used our engine or
YouTube
I've never actually seen it the first
time I see it is already YouTube yeah
yeah Facebook pretty bad so and so
that's it for today so thank you guys
for watching let's see minami bye have a
good day