hello guys
check i'm live good morning everyone
actually i have to i have to uh give me
five minutes okay
uh
be right back in five minutes
i'll start in five minutes okay big
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show today is
2021 201st
uh february and 22nd uh 20
20 february 20th and right now it's one
o'clock
in the afternoon san francisco time and
today we are going to do mostly emacs
and almost emacs only okay
now i have a bit closer so let me put on
this patch a piece of paper
getting old and cross-eyed my eyes going
out
you know that's what happens when you
get old so
there we have emacs today's topic and we
are going to talk about
mostly uh emacs okay
and join my discord if you haven't
already uh real name preferred okay
don't be
a internet tourist you know be
responsible
leave your name say what you think is
true
you know don't say uh fake news don't
[ __ ] post okay good morning so uh emacs
emacs we're gonna do lots of emacs so
what um
so anytime you have a question just post
the comments okay today
it's almost it's gonna going to be
mostly emacs
now maybe some keyboards if you have
some uh questions to ask me about
keyboards then we talk about keyboards
okay so emax and i'm going to do emacs
coding so first of all so let's start
xr command log
start command log so in this pink window
you can see everything i
uh type and my keystrokes so let's see
this is the first time i'm doing this on
windows
and i have a huge screen now so let's
create another
uh so this pink window let's where do i
put it here
okay so any questions so let me think
what uh we
what we're gonna do first so we're gonna
do okay so
because i got a new machine i switched
from mac to windows
uh i've been using mac for for the past
three
four years because i got a mac mini from
a professor math professor gave it to me
and that mag he gave it to me in 2007.
in fact you can see all my keyboards
uh let me show you okay all my keyboards
on my website actually so you go to my
keyboard blog then you go to
fun then you go to star keyboards
so you can have a view of basically
all my keywords in the past five years
or so
actually i well my keyboards they are
they are all free they are given to me
so i do review and sell i help
themselves
so clintus advantage you see many times
ago uh this is google
google from this guy in canada
you know do it yourself and ultimate
hacking keyboard fantastic the greatest
software uh programmable software
ultimate hacking keyword better than qmk
okay
for those of you open source phonetics
let me just put that in
this software called ultimate hacking
keyboard agent
is better is the best programmable
keyboard software out there better than
qmk or whatever the alternative versions
okay
so ultimate hacking is so if you want a
marker keyboard this is the best one to
get
uh where's my obs so you see uh wait
wait
wait you see you see the ultimate
hacking keyboard
so i have to show this every time so
hold on a second let me turn on
full screen okay hold on a second
uh hold on second i have to
ah this complex technology i need to i
want to switch to full screen so hold on
a second
so i need to first of all turn my screen
off here
check audio okay that works okay so you
can see
any camera here i don't want to show
anything private okay so you can see my
you know i i got a giant gaming much
gaming
monitor now this is what how many inches
i don't know
so this is ultimate hacking keyboard i
showed 1 000 times almost every
and this is kinesis advantage 2
with linear red switches
okay i'm back here yes make sure the
the video stays
the camera there
i need to get i need to get a new camera
this is lousy [ __ ]
architect knight 20 don't buy logitech
920 i have article for everything
you know search for exactly logitech 920
you you can see my review
anyway so so you can see these are all
my keyboards uh
and then my key bindings and you know
and stuff
and the keyboards keywords and this is
two years ago
so you can see my mac mini on the there
i got it
as a gift in 2017 but this mac mini is
actually from 2014
model so it's 66 years old
and now i have a new gaming pc okay so
you can see
my new machine here gaming pc you go buy
it okay you're
a star gaming computer just search for
that so
this so this is what i'm using now and
you can see
where's my task bar so you can see
the fantastic gpu
uh memory 16 gigabyte this one these two
uh hi-fi wi-fi and the gpu
nvidia stuff okay but
but but gaming machines are idiotic you
know this
huge giant box most of it is empty
inside
then you got these fans hauling you know
24 hours a day
it makes a noise i don't like it i want
to stop it but
i haven't looked into um then you know
on pc you got this extra
button for reset or whatever you know
complex when it comes to pc it's very
complex
okay so you can so and this is
uh this keyboard is interesting it comes
with a pc
msi so msa is a apparently a company in
taiwan
and this keyboard what's special about
it is that they have this
what they call uh
am i alive check
so what they call this uh
uh how do you like a quality rubber dome
okay
mechanical like you know that's what
they call it but actually it's
uh it's not just marketing gimmick
because
it's although it's rubber dome but it
actually has
the cherry mx compatible stem so you can
take out the keycaps actually i
should i show it to you does anyone want
to see it i can show it
okay people comments okay i'd love to
see your comments say hi or whatever say
hi
zumwalt haven't seen you for a long time
zum zumwalt from
uh i believe germany is that correct
if i remember correctly did you recently
go cross-eyed
no actually i've been cross-eyed since i
was like uh
20 i think but it's not noticeable you
know but sometimes it get worse you know
you know if you talk to me if you know
me in real life for a while
then you will notice it because i can
look at you from my right eye
or my left eye you see right left and
it's you know
and when it gets worse hold on a second
there's uh technical problems okay now
it's better
uh you know so so of course i i'm not
sure how it happened but
um but i do remember it but it was
you know i had that long ago
when when i'm tired it gets worse worse
but
uh in the past few years i i think it
also
got worse because i'm getting because
i've been abusing my eyes you know in
past five years i haven't been
so remember this when you you know we
are all nerds most of us are we code
every day so
you must okay remember must
taken uh every one hour take
three minutes at least okay every one
hour takes three
minutes to get up go outside
and look far away okay if you can if you
are you know you know
these days you can do it because you
work at home you know you can do that
but if you are at work you know you
cannot get up every hour so
every at least every two hours get up
and walk for uh five or ten minutes okay
look
look out look far away important this is
very critical because i've been
you know i've been sitting like uh like
almost
10 hours straight in in the past a few
years
uh anyway yeah so um
so i've been i've been showing my
keyboards and what else so
florida yes sorry about that zumwalt is
from florida yes
that's right uh using a real force
r2 right now oh my god that's a elite
expensive keyboard with a
topper switch no topper i don't like
topper okay
i know any of you there are huge number
of
topper fanatics but i don't like topper
at all
so actually we've been digressing okay i
wanted to uh today well mostly i was
going to talk about emacs i want to talk
about emacs
uh who who is here for emacs so you you
know you guys need to
if you are here for emacs go ask
questions okay because you guys
are the directors of my talk show
you know that when you uh for movies you
have directors
who is actually the head who leads the
entire film
for orchestra you have the conductor you
know then
in the football american football or the
rambo you know big muscle run and
ram other people american football
then the leader is the quarterback
quarterback that's very interesting
because i you know i don't like football
but
you know so you read about it so the
quarterback is actually
uh you know critical he's the leader the
leader of the whole team
so anyway so so you guys are the
directors of my talk show you say
whatever
and i talk but today i want to mostly
focus on emacs
emac lists or keyboards and we need to
actually
so if you are here for emacs you know
say something okay
so m28 do you think it's better to use
doom emacs or emacs from scratch for
someone who is new to emacs
uh community okay coming from neo vim
okay that's um there is no absolute
answer to that
it's really just up to you you know
depends on your preferences how you like
it you know or
uh you know sooner or later you're gonna
try both
probably okay so if you feel like i mean
just
just whatever happens you know just do
it so if you happen to use downloaded
doom max already just go with it
if you find that you don't like it then
you switch to
uh you know playing gnu emacs start from
scratch
so either ways you know there's no
absolute answer
so i used to uh i used to use these
streams to teach me new things
in this vmax or javascript okay i'm vi
guys so i'm here to create distractions
fantastic you create
distractions and i'll be like the
the the the
you know whack-a-mole you know every
time you say something about veeam i'll
show
how to do that in e-max and better
suggested emacs set up on a macbook
uh well emacs setup
you know emacs setup is pretty uh
independent i mean it really doesn't
depend on well
yeah it doesn't really depends on uh
operating system
on in linux windows mac your emacs
in it will almost all the same will be
the same okay
the only uh thing that will be different
is the
key binding if you know provided that
you do want to your own key binding but
otherwise it's the same
so but of course keybinding emacs is a
big issue
you know if you want to be efficient if
you code all the time or use emacs to
type all the time
you do want to change your um key
bindings okay so let's go to
uh actually so let's uh let's show that
let's go
to my emacs blog
so i have everything under heaven
everything you ever want to know about
emacs keys
on this page uh hold on a second
so so first of all i show you
um you know emacs key overview
you know this is uh let me magnify okay
so magnify
wait i don't want you see you see i have
my keyboard set up
supremely now now that i'm on windows
you know so
every time i switch operating system you
have to kind of reset all my keys so
remember last time last video also i
talked about
how in windows you have different full
screen
methods you know one is the f11 full
but then you don't get to see your tabs
that's no good
and also f11 is not supported in every
app
some app doesn't you know it doesn't
work there's no search full screen
so that's a problem then you have the
maximize window wind
up arrow you cannot toggle it you know
then you have to
win down arrow or you know
uh or uh let me show you
all alt space restore
you know idiotic but now
i use auto hard key so let me show you
okay one finger
one finger press okay am i talking
correct yeah
so look one finger press okay one key
press
full screen and that and you also see
the tab tabs
so it's not you know f11 so press again
you see so i can press anything i want
you know full screen
infinity uh go back to ex and full
screen
and i i can also do the alternative full
screen this is f11 you see
f11 or this full screen so how is that
done that's done
by auto hotkey
uh so i'm actually i started to ramble
all
over the place but anyway since i'm
talking so let me show you my keywords
and let me show you some of these um
yeah that's part of the thing i
want to talk about uh about uh key
binding how do you set up keyboard and
keybinding
kiwi map key markers on windows so first
of all the most important thing is that
you buy
you go buy a programmable keyboard okay
that's the
that's actually the most important thing
okay you got you
you go get a programmable uh fully
programmable keyboard because that
because software based uh key remap they
always have glitches
like sometimes you if you are in admin
you know on windows let's say powershell
let's start powershell
if you run as admin then
then your key marker doesn't work
anymore because because you need to
launch the key remap software in a mini
mod as well
so you have issues like that and for
example on linux
you know you need linux phonetics you
know you set up your keys you know
via x11 but if you are but they don't
work anymore in boots
full screen so uh software-based remap
always have glitches
so you want hardware you know firmware
keyboard
programmable keyboards you do want that
so go buy one of these
okay so that's the first thing then
then you want uh let's see uh yeah so i
have you know how do you program on
windows so you go to my keyboard
blog you go here let me show you where
to find it okay
so keyboard blog and you go to software
section
okay magnify uh this idiotic so then you
have the
all everything you need to know about
how to set up keys on windows or linux
or mac
so let's look at linux for example
uh
uh you know uh all these articles on
linux key setup
then you have mac uh
you know the the wait
the firefox does not remember my font
size so let's
just go to cassary info
that way firefox will remember my font
size okay
so you go to keyboard you go to
software then you have windows
okay so you have seen linux you know
lots of articles
for example set caps lock to home
oh then you had to have to turn on
javascript so you
you know then you can also set up shift
lock which is different from caps lock
because when you are in shift lock the
number key will also type symbols you
know it's actually
shift lock so that anyway that's
uh all you want need to know about linux
key setup then
everything you need to know on the mac
you know all the software's
available and app launchers
and other automation tools you know then
i haven't been on windows for 10 years
so in the past month i've been working
on windows
and i updated uh all my articles mostly
done
you know almost all updated so here
first of all is a guide
to all the software's available you know
which one
what do you first first of all what you
want to do uh
you know all these things they are
different because different tools will
uh
not be able to do them all it depends on
the you know it really
so it these are the some detail fine
details when you
get into key mapping a lot not you know
and then so i recommend first of all you
go buy a programmable keyboard okay
that's the most important you know go
spend two hundred dollars for it or
three hundred
uh because you buy it once then then you
know you use the keyboard at least for
ten years
okay then there's a microsoft power
toy tool it's this is pretty good okay
this is for simple kiwi map
and simple key marker and it's pretty
good
it's this is a new actually actually
microsoft
uh they did this uh in in the past one
year or two so this is pretty good
and then we have auto hard key auto hard
key is
a the most powerful key binding and
automation software on windows
well let's just say key binding okay
because for automation then you you also
have for example on windows you have
powershell i highly recommend you learn
powershell okay
powershell is far better than bash or
any other shell
on linux you know bash seashell tcsh
corn shell this crap you know they are
30 years old baggage
not even not just because they are old
you know even 30 years ago they are crap
they are hacks
you know bash everything is inconsistent
impossible
to read man page and all that
on powershell it different okay let me
show you this page okay this page you
will be interested
so here i compare powershell and bash
basically if you came from linux or unix
you know you know you know the things on
the left you know cat
head something unzip you know find you
know dash name you know
you are familiar with that and on the
right is the powershell equivalent
now you might say oh look at the
powershell it's so long it's hard to
type no
actually because powershell
has a systematic alias system
which you do also have in in bash okay
but you have to set up yourself
in powershell it's all set by default so
get child item
is also equivalent to dir da
or also equivalent to ls okay
so you don't even have to type you know
get child item or dir
you just type ls ls and recurs
and this option names they also have
completion
so here's another item powershell has a
systematic completion okay
you can complete names but you can also
complete option name so these full
option
names and in some cases these option
names
also have abbreviation and they are
entirely consistent
every powershell command or comlet or
you know
is consistent unlike in a unix bash word
depending on which which one you are
using
you don't know whether you are using
bash it's a commanding bash or it's
some other outside bash for example kill
so those of you linux phonetics you
don't know nothing
because i've been using unix since 1990
1998 okay i've been using quite a lot of
uh unixes mostly solaris
as my day job for four years so for
example let me ask you a question here
when you
on unix on linux when you say key or
something you know a process
pid process id where does that kill came
from is that part of
bash or is that a command name named
keo or if you type remove you know
remove the
you know you know linux idiots they like
to
joke remove dash uh
uh slash okay
so when you type when you when you call
remove you said is that part of the
rm you know is i am part of the bachelor
or is that a separate command
what is it okay that's a puzzle for you
to uh
answer okay so anyway powershell is far
more better okay so
uh you know so that you know if you are
on windows i
you must learn it okay there's no way
out if you
if you you know it's your choice you can
be on mac
you know they have advantage or
disadvantage uh each one of them
on the mac or windows uh or linux linux
is free
of course free is you know you don't
have to pay nothing and but also it's
you know open source so you have certain
uh freedoms
uh but you know it's the worst crap
you know that that's you know you you
get how much
you know you get what you pay for
basically uh but
so it's your choice which operating
system you want but if you are going to
use
windows then i uh
i would say you go learn powershell you
know do things the proper way it's
far more power it's far more powerful
than any of the uh unix linux shell bash
crap you know bash ash bash ash
tsa you know i i've been repeating that
many times you know this
and then then uh these days you also
have fish and some
other new ones but anyway powershell and
powershell is also
uh is now cross platform okay
uh cross platform okay so so you can for
example
here is a screenshot on mac
there there it is this is powershell on
the mac
and here is powershell on linux okay
so you can use powershell on linux but
you know
but basically if linux or unix is your
choice
you know of operating system for let's
say five years at least
then i would you know i recommend you
just stick with bash
because it's uh because sticking with
whatever
the environment you know the communities
it has
a lot advantages so if you are on linux
just stick with bash
but powershell but but if you are just
personal or you want to
explore you can use powershell for any
uh operating system and by the way
powershell is open source
too
you know it comes to this state we don't
know what does it mean anymore
open source you know open source in the
beginning or used to be
is some sort of moral uh superiority so
because it's
you know you help you make you know
freedom
for people and so that you are not
controlled by giant corporations
but now 20 years has passed open source
has become
the people who advocate open source the
most
are the most evil empires on earth
starting with google and then microsoft
microsoft
also owns skit
you know the the worst and they are
completely controlled by these uh
commercial corporation
empires open source it is also these
empires
who supplied economy money to
they dumped money to open source so you
are paid by them
you know then if so if you are linux
fanatics i tell you you know
uh don't be stop stop being uh open
source fanatic okay open source is a
very
harmful you know 20 years ago i was
open source phonetic in fact i was
against open source
i was a free software fanatic i was
a uh supporter of richard stollman
that was 20 years ago 1999 i have
i have photos and you know i'm not going
to go into to show it
because i talked about this before uh
but
you know you um so there are two
things that change first of all you know
you get older i got older and i learned
things you know
some opinions changed the other big part
is that after 20 years you've seen how
things work out open source is the most
evil [ __ ]
in in the planet they you know you know
you know you know oh you know you you
you agree with me that
you know you know how evil google
facebook twitter and microsoft
not so much microsoft these days but
anyway google okay so they are all open
source
you know every tool you use are created
you know they are
in the past 20 you know these uh pushed
by especially google
you know in the beginning it's like oh
my god open
uh you know google is supporting open
source my god yeah
look open is all using linux
but now it has they have become so evil
uh and you know so don't tell me you
know i i have lots of people you know
they keep telling me oh you should open
source this or linux so how come you are
not you know
linux or about crap like i
you know i feel like go [ __ ] yourself
you know open so that's
how that that's how i feel about the
open source
phoneticism okay now remember it's
phoneticism
that's no good if you are simply you
know you think you know open source is
not bad
it's you know as an opinion it's a good
alternative you know
why not you know so on one hand you have
commercial cooperation yeah that's fine
okay then you
also have open source yeah that's good
okay but when it became
a juggernaut like right out like how it
is right now
controlled by all these chinese
corporations with uh
you know with a a code of conduct you
know this
egregious you know [ __ ] controlled by
them you know
um you know it becomes a
you know it becomes you know in the
beginning it's just
uh you know a small you know open source
is the underdog
you know you have the giant corporations
up there they are
organized open source then you are open
source for small people like us you know
we are fighting you are you know you
think you are freedom fighters but but
not today today the open source is the
empire you know if you are if you dare
to say
you are you don't like open source you
you get you'll be
uh killed you know you'll be killed you
know you you'll be
cancelled you know that's the today's
word canceled and all your
friends you know like among yourself i
know many of you are open source
phonetics still but
i'm trying to pursue persuade you okay
because i'm open source then oh you're
gonna distance from me or that guy is
you know
he's saying crazy things about open
source you know i don't want to be
friend with him
you know so that's uh so i'm telling you
the situation about open source don't
don't be an open source fanatic
okay so one thing leads to another let's
go back so powershell okay so let's go
back
to so i recommend powershell if windows
happen to be your platform okay go learn
powershell okay
so copy it back to emacs so let's see
my uh oh one key operation so go to star
talk show
magnify open that magnify
so i'm going to start to post some of
the things we talked about
okay not actually so link
show in browser okay so so that's
powershell
then we talked about open source then we
talked about auto hotkey so
the hotkey back to auto hotkey so i have
updated all these pages
so you uh other heart is fantastic okay
so you should learn it
uh okay so what else let's see
uh autohotkey okay so uh
mac keyboard okay so then keyboard
shortcut tutorials
um
okay so actually i don't want the full
link here
uh you you don't know i'm what i'm doing
because i'm typing too
fast but you
see it okay
uh okay and let me read up the
screen here okay
so then i have
so wait so let me catch up okay uh so
auto hotkey is great okay
um what else i want to say
yeah so
so as i was saying you know i updated
all these pages
you go um you go to
uh windows my windows page then you see
all the tips you know hotkey and so on
okay
let's not repeat that okay so okay so
that's about that
uh that's what i want to say okay
this keyboard okay so
let's just put that here okay close that
okay so yeah so back to emacs so i was
saying so you go to
um you know my emacs tutorial so you
have everything you want to know about
about emacs right so let's see
so uh
let's see ah okay i don't want that
hold on a second so
okay xr emacs okay
questions comments posted okay i'm gonna
read the comments magnify now
magnify them once for all go to emacs
keys
and then emacs keys overview you know
as a beginning you might find it
confusing you have meta x you have
control x you have
uh you know control c you have control f
how do they relate so
this page tells you overview you know
you know
categorize what how the emacs which key
they use
you know then you have a keyboard layout
diagram
then you have emacs then you have how to
define keys
everything you want to know about how do
you set keys on emacs
and also explanation of what is the meta
key you know the most
famous thing about emacs the meta key
one of the most famous key uh issue uh
menu so anyway
so all this page tells you about uh
emacs keybinding
okay then uh let me let's see comments
38 minutes now uh emacs e-max
i love free ethics but as a linux user
it's really dreadful sometimes
free software for net phonetics
never hear any links linux people are
saying anything good about powershell
uh well of course
of course linux fuel usually they they
just hate it
because it's for microsoft and
so first of all there's a social reasons
and political reasons linux people you
will never hear
linux people say good things about
powershell because you know
they don't like microsoft that's it now
on the technical aspect
i can tell you why linux people the unix
philosophy
idiots why they don't like powershell
okay because
powershell is well designed powershell
every you know you know maybe i should
go to powershell page again
you know anyway powershell is well
designed all the name you know command
names
is fully well named okay there's no hack
there's no cat grab you know uh
uh cat grip you know head tail
fine you know all these jargons you know
uh uh
orc you know um you know these
uh kind of semi-pun you know there's
none of that
no hack no hacking okay so
every you know everything everything is
you know just clear and clean and you
understand that this i you know in earth
is
in some sense the unix people they think
they they might think oh that's no fun
you know because they want things
colorful you know the idiotic
so and so and power you know powershell
is just
ten times better technically uh
you you may not you know so so
some unix people they don't like it just
because you know
for example pearl people you know there
are more than one
way to do it those kind of people that
we are not they will not like
things that's well designed like a
systematic we are designed you know
giant church they don't like that they
want you know hacking
you know tiny you know an
incomprehensible
intertwined spaghetti and linux kernel
oh you have to trick memory you know
they like that [ __ ]
linux unix philosophy that type of
people they want to
dive into c you know oh look at the c
source code
the [ __ ] idiots
yeah change mod and chain on you know
that you know
that's you know that's linux that's uh
that's uh so there is is my linux
tutorial okay
shell basics now on this page you you
will see the
you'll learn in one hour or the most
used commonly used command in linux you
know lscdw
touch imcp make the remove the
move move is also renamed you know then
du
cad vi head tail uh and type which man a
proposed locate
anyway that's uh unix okay yeah that's a
unix
crap you know the extremely badly
bad design you know linux unix
philosophy [ __ ]
they say you know things must be each
program must
be small and do uh
just one thing well in fact no
no none of it do does one thing well and
every
every and every one of them do every
other thing
such as the grip and find you know they
you know recursive
idiotic i have articles on that okay
let's just search for
uh uh saudi unix philosophy i have 10
10 articles on the i have like 50
essays on the unix
[ __ ] more than 50 100.
unix pestilence okay this is this
this is written 10 years ago
okay unix pestilence
okay let me read this one because this
this this was
famous this this quote was popular
20 years ago but of course it's
forgotten today
this quote is very old from 1980s i
think because
i have been trying to research who
uh you know who wrote this but
so beginning in 1990s i you know you
hear this but i tried to research i
could i never found
it find it so it says i like and sharing
one's computing career
i i like and starting one's computing
career
with unix say as a undergraduate
to being born in east africa by the way
it's not
political politically correct today
you cannot say this today okay so
uh you know i like and uh
i like and starting one's computing
career with unix
say as they undergraduate to being born
in east africa
is intolerantly hot your body is covered
with
lice and flies you are more nourished
and you
suffer from numerous curable diseases
but
as far as young east africans can tell
this is simply the natural condition and
they live within
it by the time they found out
differently it's too late
they already think that the writing of
shell scripts is a natural act
exactly this is how you describe the
unix people
so why do they don't like powershell
because it's too well designed they
cannot tolerate it
[ __ ] unix
you know the i you know i would say unix
and c the c programming language is the
study of everything that's wrong in
computer
computing industry okay and so when
then then you have the sun micro systems
they are dead in around 2017
2007 i'm glad they are dead they are the
most
evil you know uh you know today you
might hate you know
20 years ago you hate microsoft because
you think they are evil empire
today you might hate google because
google is the
evil empire but but back then in 1990s i
some micro system some microsoft you
know so microsoft is the
the one of the most evil [ __ ] in my
opinion okay
more than microsoft in my opinion you
know at that time most people hate
microsoft
but micros but some micro systems is is
you know they make solids unix
and java you know they created java so
they don't you know these hackers you
know unix people
they don't uh this is a micro systems
much
but user microsystem is the worst evil
[ __ ]
so anyway i wrote this 20 years ago and
you know i have like
you know so i have 100 articles on unix
okay so
and i'm not going to uh show this so
most of this is history now
uh you know 20 years ago i'm getting old
uh okay and b
b you know b o s is another dramatic
story
um you know so anyway
okay so i guess uh oops
reaper thank you reaper for twenty
dollars
so reaper says
how's it going ripper i haven't seen you
for a while well i do see you on discord
so ripper says your complaint about unix
are similar to what some people say
about emacs
why not just use vs code with pull-down
menus
okay um
well good question let me let me think
about that okay
so yeah okay so you know i do have an
answer for that
uh you know my com you so the question
is you know my
you know my i i'm bitching about you
again is unix
and ripper says it's somewhat similar to
uh other people bitching about emacs
because those are old you know
also e-max is uh you know you could say
from the unix
background but not exactly okay
so why don't i just use vs code you know
actually
i've been thinking you know ebsco is
pretty good okay
um but let me let me tell you some of
the
some of the some of the things you may
not know
you know and many of you do not know
okay now
emacs e-max people and guru emacs and
richard stowman they are not
they're in there they are not part of
the unix
community okay in fact they are the
antithesis of the eunuchs community
the richest roman people and emax people
they are
against unix they are against the unix
philosophy
okay the emax people you know we talking
about history back
20 30 years ago the emacs people they
are
they are in another community it's
either
this community or uh the
its i think the motives community okay
that's
that's beyond my time i don't know much
about motex but anyway
but what i know is that emacs you know
you can say they are the
they are the from the least community or
these machines okay
and in fact they are very much they they
are you know they are just
they they are they are you know
explicitly against you you know there's
a war
between the least camp and the unex camp
you know unix by the way you know how
the your next name came from
unix is a pun again it's the motex
you know this operating system motifs
and came up the unix the new kids on the
blog
block you know they are going to make
fun of mo
motics so they created this hack you
know
tasteless [ __ ] eunuchs you know that's
what unix means eunuch
you know people without a penis you know
people whose penis being cut off
eunuchs so they make a pun you know out
of unix to
you know to to motives so that's how the
unix
so so you know you want you know you
like unix philosophy you know that's
unix philosophy
you know they they like the sloppy
hacking you know like
they get puns you know this tasteless
[ __ ]
you know like the pearl you know more
than one way you know taste this
unix so so so the e max
camp and you know they are from the
artificial intelligence
camp you know this artificial
intelligence very much
tied together back in 20 30 years ago
this and artificial intelligence you
probably know
uh you know even today you know because
you know this is the four
is the father of artificial intelligence
or research you know
like today you we have a lot of
artificial intelligence
you know they just don't they they just
they they are not just suddenly
over certainly invented by google they
have deep roots
20 30 40 years ago beginning
with this okay this mccarthy john
mccarthy 1960
okay this and then then you have emacs
okay
eventually you have what's called lisp
ai
winter then you know these companies
died out but back in 1980s
it's over you know in a commercial world
and government military
world ai research so that
gave us a lot of uh you know the route
for ai today for example neural networks
you know it's all popular today neural
networks that
came from uh 20 30 years ago okay
of course today's version is much more
improved we we know much better we have
better theories and so on
so anyway so as i was saying emacs was
never part of the
uh unix uh philosophy unix camp so that
you know that
right so they are separate so back in
1990s i
you know i despise unix i despise
everything the unix philosophy
you know the unix people you know crap
but i'm uh advocate for emacs i'm an
advocate for richard stowman i'm a
proponent for free software which you
know of richard's normalized idea
and again is the open source [ __ ] by the
eis
ers a scum okay eric
eric um raymond right yeah i think i got
a
name right yeah you know esr
yeah yes
esr is kind of a crack part okay but
anyway
so i was very much you know i i'm in the
lisp camp
i'm the in the emacs camp i'm also for
free software i'm very much for free
software in fact uk
you can see a quote of mine
here saying that okay so gnu
is not unix software freedom copyright
and open source
act related hacks
okay so i have a video i did a video you
know when
when it comes to these topics i can talk
non-stop i did a video
uh half a year ago
yeah actually more than one uh so
you know i was a big i was a proponent
so i i wrote this okay
in 2002 2002 i wrote this
so you can see how i feel how i failed
back then
about the war between open source and
free software okay
so i say of the open source
which is one of the most poetry idea of
humanity
of thoughts musing purpose plead
a offshoot and outright turn code
of snowman's vision and hardship
dressing itself as the mediator between
free software foundation and businessman
fiddling and hawking a pipe dream of its
own
a pot curling the kettle black thieves
and slouches
backseat and in the end it's just
another fantastic
fad pest of the world that is
lingering a circle of programmers blood
a ruse for the enterprising corpse
a desperate incongruous
slash of vaporing nothingness that we
shall see
so that's what i said you know i despise
the open source i don't like it you know
i
i'm a proponent of free software
foundation because i think it's came
from you know the moral
uh you know the inner moral uh
quality you know not just open source
you know
but i was act it turns out i was
wrong i was wrong in so many i i was
completely wrong first of all
look at the you know i i said that open
source is just
going to die okay no actually
free software foundation is dead
okay open source is become the king is
the empire
you know uh google microsoft open source
you know ruling the earth while richard
stowman
you know the free software foundation is
dead nobody give a [ __ ] a year well
you still have emacs with 10 users
counting me
me and you guys we are the emacs users
that's it
so i was wrong in in many ways so one
one thing i was wrong about open source
opens
you know open source did you know it
becomes the empire
and free software actually died the
second thing i was wrong is that
you know i you know the free software
found you know the idea is no good
actually you know and richard stoneman
he's very problematic he's the problem
he you know the reason part of the
reason
the free software foundation failed
is for because of him you know that guy
himself
uh you know and uh and also
the very idea of the free software
foundation
you know the you know like freedom you
know for people
is actually wrong um because
it is that idea that let the open source
that drive the fanaticism of open source
and
look at how evil they become but where
the open source
idea comes it was you know it borrowed
most of it from the free software
foundation
in other words the heart of it is
communism
okay you know 20 years ago you know many
people 20 years ago they don't want to
admit
you know free software foundation
including the open source they they will
say oh no
we are totally different from communism
actually it's
exactly the same idea free software
foundation freedom you know
anyway that's so so that's history so
back to the question about
emacs oh that's twenty dollars it's a
big fat juicy twenty dollars thank you
riva
so back to the question so
so i guess i gave the reason why emacs
is actually very different from the unix
camp unix philosophy okay so it's
actually very different okay
but however emacs is also pretty old not
bad
and they don't you know the technology
they don't the emac base
in you know they don't improve they
don't improve much
and the free software foundation the
organization have lots of problems you
know lots of
uh problems you know emacs is you know
dying and dying less and less people
using
and you know we need to kick
richard stoneman out of the emacs dev
okay
we need to you know maybe you guys can
do something about that
kick that guy out you know anyway anyway
the today's situation is so bad
i mean even if he's out who is gonna
lead free software foundation
first of all that's the question so
first of all richard snowman is very bad
okay
he did you know he was you know he was
you know we must thank him for what he
did
you know he is actually you know um he
did a great thing
he spread you know i mean even even if
free software foundation is not
a great idea but we still need to thank
richard stoneman because
because all the different philosophical
ideas we you know we can
never absolutely say which is bad or
which is wrong
you know at least he has a vision and he
did something
which today gave us you know open source
okay for good or bad
so we and also richard sherman is not a
bad person okay richard stroman is a
good
you know he's a he's a good person okay
so we need to
thank richard storman that's first of
all that's one thing
you know not like the social justice
[ __ ] you know cancer culture
culture
and and once you know they they cancel
you they
they erase what all the things you did
and they say
then you raped people and you know
that's what the
social justice people are doing and also
google
facebook they are all doing that you
know they become you know they are the
most powerful elite
today so anyway we we must
thank richard solman that's one thing
okay but richard snowman also he's very
old now
60 something you know he he also needs
to retire that's also
true so we and he is doing
a lot harm he's preventing uh progress
of emacs
so we need to tell him to you know get
off
he's preventing progress okay
now if richard so man is gone what we're
gonna do with uh
you know emacs we need to find another
leader okay there are some
uh people okay but will it be better
i don't even know okay because today you
know
you know with the you know social
justice people
google uh you know facebook twitter they
they they they control the technology
you know they control information they
need
basically they lead all the thoughts in
program
among programmers especially you guys
new generation
so so who
whoever becomes the next leader of emacs
may possibly very well turn it into
even worse okay i mean imagine suppose
suppose richard stowman retires tomorrow
okay
then someone else takes over okay we
have good hopes that emacs will start to
improve
we are go you know we might get lots of
new
features into emac this but then it's
very
you know we don't know for sure maybe
they will start to have a code of
conduct
you know they're gonna start they're
gonna put up a uh
oh free we are free software foundation
we started we believe you know richard
stoneman is gone
and now we are going to have code of
conduct and
you know that's that's
that's that's a you know that's very
dark now you know that's a
you know that's the end you know that's
the end that's that's far worse okay
that's the time that's the point when
when they don't like you
they just kill you okay whatever your
opinions that's
when they have that code of conduct
that's the end
uh so that's my opinion about emacs okay
that's that's that's
that's uh is that good
ripper is that good so maybe we should
that's it for today
so i was going to do several i was going
i was planning to do some technical
computation with emac this today uh
emac this coding but i guess not
uh let's see what um
so another article uh let's put it here
so close that
copy so all single key press okay now
you see
i have this page i want to switch back
to emacs
back to browser i want to copy the url
one single key press back to emacs
now i want to paste it one single key
press you see
and link okay so actually actually i
don't want to link it that way so
i need to open it because recently i did
something
to my emacs commands anyway
free software communism ideologies
and policies okay so
there it is there is your and that way
this here is the fun animation
cows it's cause it screws all the way
and then we have the open source logo
you know open source
initiate initiative by the way open
source is an organization
now they kind of fade it you know they
are led by
esr okay eric raymond
you know the hacker you know the hack
known for
quite a few things you know the known
for hacker logo
known for tartan guns known for
eva eva you know his opinion to invade
iraq known for uh hacker logo known for
cathedral
the cathedral and the uh crab whatever
the basa cathedral the bazaar and
cathedral
and known for you know anyway
esr let me show you a photo okay so let
me you know i have
1000 articles
okay uh wait uh uh shrink
i wanna go back to here magnify magnify
i want to go to
esr okay there it is
magnify so
here you can see
richard stoneman
and julian assange
he's being kind of uh you know
sad then you have richard snowman
the young rich snowman then you have uh
esr
okay so here's uh julian assange
when richard stollman here's
richard stowman and this photo
is back in um i tracked back
you know you can read it like 1980s
1970s mostly
and here is eric s raymond okay i don't
like
him but um
you know he's also getting old you know
and they are you know these
these the old generation of hackers they
are
even one generation before me uh
and they you know you know he's also you
know getting very old
so this photo is 2015.
uh okay i don't i you know
mostly i don't like this guy i think
he's uh
some sort of crackpot but not too bad
okay he's you know not there there are
far worse people in programming
community
far worse i can name a few okay
you know these uh scums typically very
rich powerful
elite scums of the social justice scan
membership there are quite a few for
example
uh i would say you know i run let's not
name
people now so you know esr and he
you know he's also by the way he's also
against
social justice you know but
you know you you probably know a few
years ago richard stoneman has been hit
by the social justice scan
also very sad he did nothing wrong
richard stoneman did nothing wrong but
anyway
okay that's it you know i have articles
about that you can also actually find
them you know i did
detail the accounts
so where's ripper ripper is my answer
satisfactory and that's it for today
today thank you guys for watching
i've been talking for one hour and nine
minutes so today
it became a giant brand uh
open source and free software and
political issues
and e-max okay at least we did talk
about emacs
and also we talked about windows
okay so let's let me read a few more
comments and that's it
punching is quite bad though no i don't
agree
i disagree i disagree
are you ever concerned about the
centralization of power in the
social political standpoint instead of
its
effect on software of course i'm
concerned
yeah but what can you do you know
not much okay listen to satoshi or more
you know so i would ask what can you do
so that's a question okay so i
recommend don't use twitter okay stop
stop using social network if you are a
programmer
or you know whatever i don't you know
most of you guys are programmers i'm a
programmer so i don't know
what to recommend if you are not a
programmer so i recommend
you know so if you're a programmer i
recommend you go study
math okay math is a thing i love or use
you know you can study programming okay
you know you don't have to hate unix as
i do you know it's a technology you know
they are good and bad bad and also when
i talk uh often it's dramatic okay so
it's just drama okay so you know unix so
you learn you know
especially if you are younger so you go
study
study math do your homework or whatever
you know do work
read read things you know read up read a
lot of things
and uh you know don't shitpost you know
i don't like
you know those memes the millennial
generation invented things
means memes meet shitposts or being
anonymous okay
say what you mean be responsible okay
doesn't matter what's your religion be
responsible online
don't [ __ ] pose and joke and you know
whatever if you are playing games with
friends yeah go you know fine that's
fine but don't
don't go to any you know
website and just post you know whatever
crap oh and don't
don't ever go post things so that you
get thumbs up okay don't you know forget
that that's
that's the that's that's the root of uh
how they turned the whole internet into
[ __ ] into clip aid then into division
in united states you know
it creates problems uh so
so that's my recommendation so you know
read a lot and be
uh don't join and don't you know don't
don't join
codes you know be uh watchful
of you know the open source or free
software software ideology
also you know um
do not fall you know i would say do not
you know
think you know think critically you know
especially today
the universities you know you know they
are like the
they are almost like 50 years ago in
germany
any opinion if you disagree you are
banned
your books are banned and you are fired
so that's the situation in universities
and they think you know they think they
are doing good but that's how
that's the root of that's how evil rises
that you know
you know what i mean so that we have
kind of we have that situation so
you want to be careful and uh you know
and also
if you are the young people you know if
you are brought up
maybe maybe if you are trans if you are
gay
if you if you oh if you you are brought
up you know you believe all these things
so then you listen to me what the [ __ ]
then you might say what the [ __ ] is this
guy we need to cancel that guy
right now okay i haven't done anything
you know
so i i would recommend if you are
watching my show i would
you know think of think think think a
bit more
okay so that's what i have to say
uh okay so yeah so i'm gonna change your
title are you gonna change the title of
the stream yes usually i do that when
i'm done with the video
uh a single key press uh thank you but
uh you still need to hear what you have
again is vs code
menu instead of mac shortcut
okay so um
so so reaper is saying why don't you say
that earlier [ __ ] you should say that
say that earlier so i can respond now
it's like now it's like too long
my video is like dragging out it's gonna
reach two hours
okay so so reaper is saying yes i have
you know let's let's show the power of
emac lists okay
that's one of the reasons you should use
part of this uh images okay
so suppose i have this page so this is
my blog okay
so now i go back to go back to emacs
and i call the command let's magnify
open vs code wait
yeah there it is because now open via vs
code
you see because i open
vs code enter then we have vs code in
the microsoft
javascript technology
so the question you know so why don't i
use vs code
you know vs code is pretty good but let
me tell you why
there are some problems okay so if you
ask me why don't
i use vs code my first of all my i can
give you my personal reasons
one i've been using emacs
for 20 years 20 22 21 or 22
and i've been coding emac lists for 15
years
right starting in 2005. so i've been
coding 15 years emac list
so i know emacs full well you know and
so if i gonna switch to vs code
that's a disadvantage because then i'm
gonna
they have to reload you know i have to
learn a new technology
on the other hand i don't you know i
already know a lot
you know that's a serious power you know
i
so it doesn't benefit me right away if i
don't
if i switch to esco that's one reason
the second reason let me tell you the
second reason okay now look
look go look at uh look at my uh
processes okay
let's see how much memory they are using
there it is vs code can we can we
magnify this window
i'm not sure you can magnify the window
okay so anyway
so you can see i
i don't know if i can magnify the font
can we
so anyway you can see the vs code is
used i just
i just started it's only opening one
file
it's using 300 megabytes of memory
now let's let's look at emacs i've been
running emacs all day with tens of uh
articles it's only using 60 megabytes
you see the difference vs code is using
300 megabytes of memory emax
and it's only on you know vbs code just
for one file it's already 300 megabytes
and emax
is only 60 megabytes and i've been using
the whole day in fact i can use it for
several days
and it's only it's going to be less than
100 megabytes yeah
like you know mostly so so you see
that is that's that is another reason i
use
emacs i'm not you know i haven't
switched yet
so let me tell you why does this kind of
thing happen you know most of you will
say oh this because
electron you know vs code is using the
electron framework
which is basically a entire browser you
know the google
uh chrome browser that's that's kind of
true
but that's not the core reason okay let
me give you a more deeper reason
vs code is not is that way
not just because it's using chrome
doesn't matter what it whatever
framework it use it will be like that it
is that way
because it's created by a corporation
huge teams you know they so there's a
big difference
between a software made by a very few 10
people you know who are so
geeky nerds you know like unix people
or linux in linux kernel when you have
software
so that so so that is one advantage of
let's say linux or or a unix you know
kind of thing
of office software software you know
they they tend to be
very extremely lean okay because
you have a fanatical nerd like me
for example i created soft like keys
it's the utmost efficient
okay it's it doesn't matter memory or
whatever
you had more sufficient because i
control every aspect of it
in the same way emacs people emac these
you know richard strowman
he doesn't code anymore but you know the
many of the
gnu dev right now i can't name them but
anyway
so that's the difference you know emacs
60 megabyte of ram
vs code is already 300 [ __ ] megabytes
and i'm not
i haven't i do not have any extension
okay i haven't
installed any extension when you do that
it's more and more you know
so that's the one that's the issue
that's one of the reason okay
and it's this issue is not going to
likely
to go away anytime soon you it's the
nature
it's going to be part of the nature of
vs code
it and i i've i've talked about why
because it is a product
of a giant corporation okay this nature
will not go away
and every and you cannot you know of
course it's open source you can forget
but but i imagine the code is so complex
it doesn't make sense for anyone to you
know fork it
and lead it because it's very big you
know
so anyway that's that's one of the
reason okay i don't use vs code
so i gave two reasons already one i've
already have you know 20 years of
expertise in emacs that's why i don't
use vs code
not yet at least two
vs code is from a giant corporation and
by the very nature of it there's a huge
difference between that
and a and a uh
you know the emacs or any nerds
tech geekers creation such as emax huge
difference
efficiency is one thing you know memory
and all that
that's the second reason um
what are the other reasons i think
that's that's the
two main reasons i haven't switched yet
okay now let me give you some positive
positive things about vs code
now vs code is very powerful okay and vs
code is written in javascript
it's written in javascript from the
ground up
well if you don't count the google
chrome
you know the chrome framework which is
you know
which is written in c you know the
google chrome browser
electron electron itself is mostly
written in javascript
uh and google chrome is c and c plus
plus you know anyway anyway so
so the the vs code is very powerful
and and in fact in many ways more
far more powerful and superior than
emacs
because emacs has the problem of you
know as i talked about
the free software community they they
got they got organization
they got lots of problems they are
stagnating
meanwhile the javascript
the language that vs code runs on is
improving
tremendously every year they have a new
version fantastic features you know
improving improving the baggage or
whatever you know
yeah and artificial intelligence
libraries from google you know
all sort of machine learning you know
millions you know
driving you know javascript is also in
space
you know they you know the console the
ui interface
the code you know the elements
spacex project sending people to mars
their console you know their ui is
written in electron
javascript same thing with you know the
same technology
that vs code is using so vs code in many
ways is
uh superior in the emacs and it's also
the future
you know we don't know what's the future
for emacs you know the richard stoneman
is kind of already
very bad and when he if he retires we
don't know what's going to be the future
of emacs
only on the other hand the vs code is
you know the javascript language
although it's kind of lousy but they
they have great tremendous
improvements every year and used by
literally
not just millions billions at least
million developers in javascript okay
so so so there's no there's no
comparison
you have like the one thousand two few
thousand people
no knows emac at least there are
few tens of millions of the top expert
javascript expert
and javascript you know in the world and
javascript as a language as a
programming language
is also by now far superior
and powerful than emac bisp okay so emac
is
it's got it's becoming very problem you
know
so the future so that's that's some of
the advantage
of vs code so i hope now
my answer is satisfactory reaper
okay yeah so okay reaper asked about uh
you know well i you know so reaper is
asking about menus
what about menus
you know i i can't you know i have to
give you my opinions and my take
you know i can't because what are you
asking so
reaper says vs code menu
uh i still need to hear what you have
against vs called menus instead of emacs
shortcuts okay so
so i guess we are talking about use so
reaper wants to know
my opinion um i guess the user aspect
the user interface aspect of
vs code versus emacs especially
i guess you're talking about menus or
keyboard shortcuts
so on that topic um
i don't have much uh opinion i mean
because i haven't dived
you know i haven't dived into vs code
now
now out of the box
both of them are pretty bad okay how do
i
let me explain out of the box
the emax key binding is worse it's worse
and it's it's the worst in all
technology
from history okay or application all
their shortcuts if you compare
all of them to see which one uh which
application in uh of
of software in human history e-max
the default is the e-max default
keybinding is the worst
by a magnitude okay even compared to all
the dos software you know
emacs people they leave they they don't
know they they are
including it probably some of you they
still think oh you might
e-max keys actually i can say no are
consistent or something no emacs
emacs keybinding is the worst of them
all okay
you use it you have rsi like many of you
do already
rsi you go see a doctor you your career
will be done for
you can no longer type anymore that's
e-max
so out of the out-of-the-box e-max key
mining is very bad
and the vs code is better okay however
now because i've been coding emacs so i
know emacs inside out so you can create
you can create entire keybinding emacs
so which i have done
with uh which is soft like keys and if
you do that
the hat key binding is supreme it's the
most efficient
in human history
[Laughter]
if i can claim that so stuff like keys
key binding is the most efficient
in terms of efficiency the number of key
presses to do
some certain things in human history
better than vi
better than veeam better than neo-vim
you can you can actually count it
you know go to go go to the vi golf
yourself if you know you know software
you know you can
you can see you you can beat the you
know all the all of them
so emacs you know if you use the default
keys is
is the worst but you but it allows you
to you can switch
to a different keybinding or you can
switch to evo you know
which is okay it's pretty good then
in the story changes then
those key bindings are better than vs
code okay
because vs code it's the traditional you
know control shift you know
you know the code keys now
but what what i don't know is that is
how
customizable and how how is the
customization system
in vs code i suppose you know i'm
guessing it's pretty good
but it's just that i haven't spent time
so if i
dive into it you know spend some several
hours a day maybe
i can see how easy it is to change keys
and there are you know there are already
extensions of plugins
that allows you to have i believe in key
bindings and also model you know
and i and i believe there's also
actually some people did
stuff like keys
for visual studio code or at least a
you know a prototype version of it yeah
i believe i've seen people do that
so that's my opinion so i you know i
don't know if that
answers your question okay that's it for
that uh today i
we need i need we need to shut down it's
like close to two hours
right one hour and
28 minutes yeah that's it for today
so reaper says i'm just saying
powershell is two unix
shells as vs code menus are
two emax shortcuts
oh so uh yeah
well i guess i did i did answer your
question right okay great answer great
thank you thank you reaper
yeah so i said so that's it thank you
guys uh bye we need to say
bye goodbye there's no ending there's
no party without an end so bye thank you
guys
buy my emacs tutorials okay you know
where to find it
bikes are emacs tutorial bye guys thank
you for watching
and stream