good morning guys welcome to another
episode of soundtalk show
merry christmas guys today is 2021
december 26th
uh so
if you have a topic for me you know pick
the one of the type it from one of the
talk show notes topic notes in the
beginning okay like right now post it
and we'll talk about that otherwise
i'm going to talk about
i'm going to code emac list merry
christmas guys
remaster
many do
row count head count tt zealand
da vinci
battle mew
hello guys and as you can see i have a
new
i'm gonna tell you about this new mouse
okay this is a button mouse we can't see
it where is it
this yeah so here you can see this is a
mouse
with uh mechanical switch keys
okay james knee send it to me so on my
discord you can see
james
james knee
uh he's from china and thanks a lot to
him
uh where is he
let's see let's see where do i find it
uh emacs unix unix so
so this guy okay fantastic thank you
james
uh so
so we're gonna um so i'm gonna tell you
several things okay so let's begin so if
you have a topic again post it now okay
not random topic louise okay you're
gonna have you have to post the topic
from this exotic actual topic notes or
you know so you know there's you know
several choices order to do or what you
can do like for those of you watching my
youtube you know maybe offline so next
time if you want me to talk about a
topic post one of the articles i have
there are about 6 000 articles on my
website so you post one of the articles
you have questions you read it then i'll
talk about it because if you just gonna
say oh uh please you know suggest me a
topic hexa do you you lack of topics i'm
gonna suggest you one that doesn't work
because people is gonna ask me random
like which keyboard is the best keyboard
which one is best emacs or beam you know
or random
topics i don't know
rational sql versus json non-sql
databases okay i don't like the
sql i don't know but i don't have
experience with it so if you ask me a
random question
i don't know the answer okay pick a
topic from one of my articles
like title of the article
okay powershot well again you have to be
specific you know
so this is about
you know because the if you are just
generic
that will go nowhere i can you know that
the result talk will not be good so what
what do you mean powershell i'm gonna
ask you then you're gonna reply what's
your question what what about powershot
i talked about powershell so many times
uh this more specific
you know so here is the guideline okay
so if you have a question that that you
really want to know my opinion with like
personal like in real life you meet you
meet a guy you want to ask him some
questions then do that forget about the
malaysian concept of oh someone youtuber
is doing a topic they're gonna need
suggestions you know let's talk about
this you know
that's not that's not good unless unless
you pay me
like your ding ching chik ching he is
ten dollars you know super chat youtube
super chat ching ching hears ten dollars
please talk about this topic sql versus
nun sql or something like that and i
will spend an hour or two dig into it
you know then i will let you know i'll
do one hour talk show on that topic for
example recently on this code
of fantastic magorical discord we have
you know recently there's a topic about
metaverse
virtual reality metaverse and web 3-0
so you know alan ripper and uh
and desi and you know several people
lunara several people talk about you
know then then i i end up spending
about four hours together four or five
hours looking into that topic you know
so i post my opinions about it and
things like that so
you want to ask me a question
consider it kind of like personal like a
question you really want to ask me not
topic suggestions i talk about this a
few times because you know when you do a
video like all the common frequently
asked questions is going to come up
again and again like
which one is the best keyboard which one
sub user do you suggest do you do you
think red switch is better than blue
switch or whatever or do you think you
know there's common questions
so i'm gonna
so start to talk about okay so let me
see quickly what else okay uh
what else here and let's begin the talk
june
uh time is so quick
so
so many of you so you guys i don't
remember i cannot remember all you guys
okay except but
i cannot remember you guys so
if you want to you know join discord and
you know then we
we chat every day then
we'll get to know each other z trunk
crazy hello
this is crazy happy
merry christmas to you guys
z trump crazy and bethlehemia
uh why should i learn fashion and cover
it
okay well i talked about that many times
okay like you you watch my pet you know
just go to my youtube then search for
powershell i talked about that many
times
like there's a full hour video about how
powershell is better than bash okay
uh
so
okay so no no no topic okay okay no
topic
what do you think of competitive
programming another
did you just listen what i said da vince
davinci
what do i think of competitive so so let
me tell you about this mouse okay so
this mouse
james sent it to me and so i think
i think a mouse with a um so i'm using
it now can you see it
uh yeah so i'm using it it's it's it's
very light
but i'm not i'm not getting used to it
yet
so um
so this is mouse i'm going to take more
photos and i'm gonna start to get used
to but right now i'm not so sure it's uh
you know i
for one thing
the spin wheel is fantastic okay for
example you have seen my spin wheel
this is a logitech so the spin wheel is
the first fantastic thing you know
without spin wheel it
you you know i have to leave with spin
wheel so
you go to
xr keyboard and let's go to keyboard
then spin wheel you can just spin it
it's fantastic you know so and you can
yeah i talked about that many times
so this mouse doesn't have a spin wheel
so that kind of and it's got a wheel on
the side but it first
i think it's not not very good okay
let me talk talk about this mouse okay
let me
go to the details so first of all it's
got a um
this camera
doesn't have autofocus so it kind of
sucks so let's see if you can so you can
see
this is the left hand side and it's got
a wheel
and that wheel is not so
so easy to use so it's got four more
four more buttons and those buttons are
extremely
requires extreme pressure to hit them so
one one of them is space one of them is
return
space return escape delete okay
space return escape
delete
uh and they are
very hard to press
then the wheel okay so the wheel
you do like that so this you see this is
a difference between a spinning wheel
and no spinning wheel when you don't
have spin wheel it sucks like you know
this is all you can do
uh and before
so if you don't have a swing wheel you
want accelera accelerated scroll that
means if you scroll fast it will go all
the way down like but
but microsoft removed that feature
about four years ago so let me go into
the details okay
so let me so several topic okay so let's
so let's
let's get them to them fast okay
so uh
spin wheel so let me talk about spin
wheel
accelerated squirrel
actually i talked about this quite a few
times
so i'm just not getting used to that
mouse so let's go to
so let's go through mouse
then you have
so that's the one
and uh i want to tell you about spin
wheel and accelerated scroll okay
so first of all so there it is
accelerated scroll and there is spin
wheel
so
spin wheel is fantastic okay
now if you don't have spin wheel what
you want is you want accelerated screw
on the mac
it's building okay you can buy any mouse
with a square wheel and you if you screw
it fast it's fantastic okay it's almost
equivalent to
spin wheel because if you have like
if you have for example
let's open that
uh let's go go to blog
so this page is about
30 screen false
so if you have spring wheel like right
right now i do again i can i can do it
one shot and you'll go all the way to
the bottom if i do it if i push it fast
but if you don't have spring wheel what
you want is you want to accelerate
accelerated scroll so the article is
here
okay accelerated scroll so that means
even for uh
even for um
you know 30 screenflow you can screen
you you can scroll all the way from the
top to the bottom by just
four or five
fast swipes but without
then then the worst
idiotic thing is the linux unix these
elide elite hackers they're gonna go by
page donkey
page up and down that's the most idiot
idiotic so you want spin wheel first if
you don't have spring wheel you want to
accelerate this scroll now accelerated
scroll is a bit complex on the mac it's
supported okay it's system white mac is
mac os is just the best
on windows
okay so you can read this article in
detail so let's copy the um
the url here
accelerated scroll so you can see
so on the mac it's
supported on windows about
it was supported
about
before windows 10 okay in windows 10
they removed it but before windows 10
if you just have a if you buy a
microsoft mouse then it's supported okay
you need to have a microsoft mouse
or logitech i believe logitech also
works okay but in windows 10
they removed that feature you know so
you don't have access accelerated scroll
at all that just sucks okay so i have a
detail here 2020 first february
microsoft removed accelerated score in
windows 10
windows 10 version 2000 to 0 004
so anyway so
and the and linux is the worst okay
linux is the idiot tho those
styling window managers these extreme
idiots they're all of them
so
so that's about the
that's about the spin wheel and
accelerated score okay
keep your comments coming and if you
have questions to me put tag me okay
attack me
do something special instead of the same
old that's that's true that's correct
okay it's a good point yeah because
other people ask me the same old
questions so let's talk let's talk about
these smarts okay so
so let me show you another article
so trackball
mouse and i want to go to um
so i thought the idea of a mouse using a
mechanical key switch
keys
us buttons is a fantastic idea but now i
actually used it i'm not sure yet i'm
not certain
so here is some of the mouse with
mechanical switches you know people made
so you know customize do it yourself
this is a kind of idea drawing and some
people you know actually quite a few
people made it so there's another one
here's another one
and here's another one this is borg
modification okay and here's a one for
trackball
uh so i think the idea is pretty good
but so far
so let's copy that and put it here
thank you louise
telling window managers
thank you
um
so hold on a second so let me get this
uh
so i'm using kusa emacs mod
so showing browser so today's topic so
let's go to
[Music]
yeah so i thought this is a good idea
but but right now i'm not i'm not too
sure
partly because this mouse you know
the side buttons is not so great and not
you know i have to you know so after
a month i'll tell you
my full opinion about this mouth
but i probably gonna go back to the
logitech because
because of the fact it's got a spin
wheel so you got night buttons so this
is the left click middle click so you
can see well you can see here left click
middle click
uh this is uh
no left key left click right click
middle click
copy paste
backspace okay
so backspace you know just go back to
previous space so scroll
so anyways
that's about that that mouse okay you
can buy in china so it's i believe is
you see the prop the pain of the
no acceleration
score so i believe i'm i'm not sure
where it is it's probably on
aliexpress or taobao
so anyway another thing i want to tell
you is that the kinesis advantage
360 keyboard came out you can order it
you can pre-order it right now
and i have a you know i'm going to
i have to talk the guy first but i'm
going to do a review of it okay maybe
maybe within this week i'm going to do a
maybe a unboxing first but let me talk
to the person the guy first
so
in my opinion
i don't doubt it that this is a great
keyboard okay like you can you know i
would yeah i don't doubt it
i have no doubt so but i'm going to
review this keyboard
uh
at least unboxing
uh in the next week
excel talk show so much for that
so thank you luis okay okay what else uh
what what make do you use for streams
okay my my microphone is a cheap mic
cheap microphone
china cheaper okay so china cheapo is
taking over the world
so you can see it miscellaneous tech
and uh
so here is my microphone i talked about
it
a few months ago when i got it forty
dollars or something cheap
okay and some uh some of these are more
expensive ones
but not
you know you know
well recommended
ones about hundred or two hundred
dollars
but mine is uh 50 and a dedicated
microphone is much better than headset
much better
because for my experience of doing
youtube
and i looked into microsoft uh i looked
into microphone technology
they are fairly complex well not complex
but
but it's not like headset headphone it's
not like a headphone the microphone
technology there are many different
technologies so there's a type of
microphone
there's a type of microphone
technologies you know dynamic microphone
condenser contact microphone fiber optic
and laser and you know so
and the way they
receive sound since polar patterns
sensitivity directional or not
you know so uh
okay so
no
i don't see a topic about um so
probably i'm going to start to code emac
display
okay vieta says chinese input method
okay okay let's do that so let me show
you chinese input method okay
first of all let's go here
copy that go here
and paste the link here
and there it is buying a microphone so
let's talk about
chinese chinese input system okay
so you go to keyboard
then you go to layout keyboard shortcuts
layout keys um
yeah then you scroll down you can see
germany
quality
as a tea
german
german layout
and german ergonomic layout there are
several of them
french layout
french ergonomic layout and the new
french layout the the french government
actually created created a new french
layout in 2015.
it's released in 2019 the french
government did it you know a new french
layout so it's an improvement but that
that
not that much okay so here's a physical
keyboard with the new french layout
so in these articles you also see
chinese input systems and japanese input
systems okay so here is a chinese
keyboard you see from the james bond
movie okay
james bound movie you know this is silly
this is kind of fake because chinese
keyboard no chinese keyboard looks like
that but however
because it's a hollywood movie you need
drama so they they they put these
chinese characters keycaps on it
in fact other keyboards in mainland
china they just look identical to the
to the us keyboard identical no special
characters on it just the quality
keyboard on mainline main land china now
in taiwan and hong kong then it looks
like this okay
uh so
so let me okay so let me talk about
chinese input system you know you know
chinese unlike french or english or
spanish you don't have you know all the
chinese characters are not on the keys
so in order to type it you need to have
a input system so
so for example i can for example i want
to type sun
let's magnify so you see
i can type sum i can type that because
i'm using a xr math input mod okay
this is emacs okay i'm using this you
know
math input mod e max
so you see these symbols or alpha beta
gamma pi
lambda you know or right arrow left
arrow up arrow you know this
or degree
you know infinity
you know you you need to use this in
math a lot integral
and delta
for example or
capitalize delta or
keyboard
command
backspace
okay so all these symbols you know
so how do you type them you there's no
character corresponding to it on the
keyboard so you have to use in essence
this is a
input system you that's a proper name
okay so you need to use an input system
to type characters that's not on your
keyboard okay
now so chinese japanese korean
and russian
well russian a little bit but mostly
chinese
japanese korean and and arabic arabic
or
um you know those languages you need the
input system so
so let me just show you an example okay
so let's see
let's open wordpad okay
let's see
okay so let's switch to chinese
okay
that means chinese okay so in order to
type the first character
and this this mouse i'm not getting used
to so in order to type that first
character you know think of it as a
as any of these summation signs so to
type the first character you have to
type
there there are several
there's
there are actually tens of chinese input
systems just like english layout you
know you have qwerty you have vorak you
have cormac and so on so for chinese
characters there are also several in
fact a lot more more than 10
input systems okay the most
common and standard one
the most common one is called pinging
okay used in most in china mainland
china okay so to type the first
character what you have to do is you
type so let's switch to chinese okay so
you have to type
z h wait
what
z-h-o-n what
what happened to my input system z-h
what
windows
c h
what
it keeps switching me back to
yeah
windows
let's open a new one okay
um
and let's make it large
z h
z h o n
okay the windows okay let's let's open
the word pad let's open notepad okay
i'm not sure what's going on with the
word pen okay
so first of all
okay yeah there it is
so first of all english tt magnify
then switch to chinese input system
z-h-o-n
so you can see you type the
you type in english how the word is
pronounced
then it pops up several choices you can
type a number to pick them so all these
words are homonyms they have the same
pronunciation so the character we want
is the first one so i type one one on
this keyboard is here
so there it is
and the second character
okay let's close this
stupid windows
okay the second character
when
okay so you want the first first choice
type it so that's how you input chinese
okay
so let's see so chinese input method so
let's go back to emacs
let's
yeah so back to english
paste the link here
and switch copy that
and
delete that
and make it
a box pasted that
and showing browser so that's the
today's topic we talked about
so now let's go to chinese input system
okay so
so we demonstrated how you type chinese
input system so all you have to do if
you are on windows
you go to
systems settings okay so then you go to
um
let's see where is it
uh
personalization
time and language you click on time in
language
and you click on language
then you click on keyboard
here okay so you can you can you can you
can click on add a language so right now
i have english and chinese you click on
add a language
then you can see verac here you can see
arabic here you can see chinese here you
just click just add it okay
you know you you can you figure it
figure it out so then once you have it
then you can just go to any wordpad
then press window space and you can
switch to that chinese
ping
okay so let's type something
okay
me
say okay that means who are you okay now
you see the
inconsistencies of the font
allen has been talking about it you see
this is this is a
to the series serif font
okay and these two are analogous to the
sans serif
now the you see so the font is
inconsistent very ugly
if you read chinese you can tell very
ugly
so this is a problem of windows it
doesn't happen on the mac
so this happens for several reasons okay
but basically if you pick a language or
if you pick a font then you'll work
because
this happens because right now it's
thinking maybe you are using check using
japanese or something
okay so
uh random topic so let me talk about so
okay before we finish that let's go to
another one okay let me show you
chinese font okay so if you are web dev
there's a lot of issues about chinese
font okay so let's go to
box model
box model box decoration layout css
layout
layers
transformation line wrap so there is a
form section
decoration font font family
common web fonts meaning font size in
chinese font okay so
on this page i document
all the things you need to know about
chinese fund
because if you are not careful
then
on your website you're gonna have a
situation like that very ugly you know
this is you don't want to do that so
this article tells you all about chinese
font and what are the chinese fonts
names that comes on
comes with microsoft windows and what
are the chinese font names that comes on
the mac and the sample for example this
is the image so you can see it
doesn't matter what os you are using and
here is a mac d4 chinese fonts available
on the mac
oh those are windows so this this is
what you actually see
so let's magnify so you can see the full
glory
so here are the microsoft chinese fonts
okay
then let's go down
then here are the fonts chinese fonts on
the mac
okay bld
let's go down
so you see some of them are cursive so
this is cursive so this is analogous
to serif sense serif and cursive for
example
well you already have i
i already showed the example so
and so this is the mac what about let's
go down go down
chinese found on linux
you know that sucks donkey s you see
on the mac it's the best okay on windows
you know they have so many they have
like over 10 chinese fonts variations
it's it's you know it's okay
on the mac it's most beautiful
and you won't have the inconsistency
problem like that okay
but when it comes to linux it's sucks
donkey ass it's a fantastic
on linux
linux people don't know the window tiny
manages you know these rice or whatever
they don't know and unix people
on linux you only have one
because open source you know open source
when you cut off money when you demand
everything is free
then the result is you don't get nothing
why don't you write one for you you know
write one you know create one
for us
you know you want you linux phonetics
so so that's about found on chinese okay
now let's go back to chinese font okay
so we were talking about so
so in this article i have a full detail
and tutorial about
about chinese input methods
okay and i demonstrated
one of them
and
i want to
talk about why
there are
so many different chinese input methods
okay there are quite a few uh we already
did a demo for example on google if you
go to google google chrome browser or
google email
gmail
they also support several chinese input
systems of their own google's own
chinese input systems so you see all of
these one two
three
four five six seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve thirteen there are 13
by default chinese input systems
similarly on microsoft on microsoft you
have maybe five or six
same for for the max
so
but google created their own
regardless which operating system you
are on so you can on any computer you
can go to gmail and and type chinese
using google's chinese input system
you know why they're doing that because
china is a big big big market you know
usa has 300 million people china has 1
billion over 1 billion about 4 times
more people than usa
so
for everything you sell on usa you can
sell four times small in china
so that's google and and here's the mac
you know chinese input systems on the
mac you can you know add one
add them and on emacs by the way yeah so
let me tell you on e-max e-max supports
chinese input system by
itself okay so let's let me show you
demonstrate emacs okay so let's magnify
then let's type something here okay so
let's type something here
so magnify so i'm going to
set input system set input method okay
then
then type
china chinese
p
y okay so emacs also support you know
more than five input chinese input
system so i'm going to select chinese py
okay
okay now
let's type the same thing
here
okay so let's see
there it is you can see in the mini
buffer it
pops up several choices so that's the
one i want yes
and the second one there it is
chinese input system in emacs okay
okay now i'm done with that now let's
um
toggle
input method back to english okay
now back to english okay
so there it is emacs chinese input
system in emacs
and i have a tutorial on that
for you emacs users okay just read this
page
and you'll know how to turn it on how to
do it
okay so now let's put a link here
close reopen
reopen
uh
put links here linkify and merge the
ui url list
so here's today's talk show topics
now back to
back to the chinese input method so why
why there are so many so because chinese
is based on logogram meaning kind kind
of like a picture for each word
so
it's fairly complex and it's not
systematic okay the chinese writing
system the chinese characters
it's not systematic
essentially you have to
memorize each and every character
so for a typical chinese you grew up you
know
in in grade school in middle school in
high school you spend five six years to
learn writing chinese okay
so chinese characters so how do you
so here is a question for you nuts how
do you design a system you know units
you know oh
cormac
quality you know
borax layout you know you obsess about
later arrangement you know about the
design so
if you if your writing system is chinese
you know there are there are literally
over ten thousand chinese characters but
basically you need to know about three
thousand chinese characters
to be
to be able to read newspapers 3000 is
minimum
essentially
same with english okay you need to know
about 3 000 english words in order to
uh to begin to barely understand
newspapers okay journalism kind of
writing 3 000 words same thing in
chinese same thing in japanese that's
about the same thing in i suppose every
language okay 3000 words so in chinese
you need to know you need to memorize
characters okay
so you have this you know
over 10 000 characters how do you design
a input system
to to to enter these characters that's a
big question so
that's a big question that's a big
design issue that's uh you know so
that's why so over the past 100 years
china and taiwan
they have created many you know each
person study you know it's quite a lot
to study you have to know
you have to essentially you become a
scholar in chinese language you know you
have to find a way
to somewhat somehow systematically
create a input system that is
somewhat efficient as sufficient as
possible
so actually i i looked into them so
so let me give you an outline okay why
so what are the types so first of all
there are two categories of input in
chinese two primary methods
one is based on the character shape
okay so you
so you classify the each chinese
characters into
it's it's very hard okay this is almost
impossible because it's not systematic
okay in general the chinese character
each one is basically you each one is
just just ad hoc it's this is not like
english
letters phonetics you know you have at
least something to base on the phonet
how it's pronounced but in chinese
you don't really have that so
essentially each character is just
a doodle by itself so you
so
so one of the major way
major category of chinese input method
is based on the characters so you design
a system to kind of
codify
the gen general shape of each character
then
then you create a system you know to
to type that okay so anyway it's a shape
based you can simply call it shape based
okay now the other category of input
system is
pronunciation based so if you know
how a character is pronounced
then you just type the english
pronunciation for it
that is what we have demonstrated for
example these two characters pronounce
zhongwen okay zhongwen so you you
type that
you know that's pronunciation song and
there it is then you type that w-e-n you
know that's the pronunciation for
example this
knee
say okay so you type ni okay
say okay so that's pronunciation based
now pronunciation based systems chinese
input systems is
more intuitive intuitive to vast
majority of chinese speakers
because you know you know you learn in
school how each characters is pronounced
so you just type the pronunciation
but
the phonetic based i mean the shape
based system is in general more accurate
you know one one of the problem with
phonetic based system is that once you
type something let's say zone okay there
are
there are so many
characters that has the same
pronunciation so you have to make a
choice
so that slows down you significantly
so if you are a beginner for example i
don't type chinese much essentially for
every character
i have to make a choice like one which
one is it you know you type of character
then which one is it pick one you know
that is inefficient
but for a character based shape based
input system
in general it's much faster but however
it's much more difficult to learn
because you have to spend a lot of time
to memorize
the system okay
that's about it so any more comments
maybe i'm getting boring
so let me read some of the comments okay
if you have a question for me address me
okay
so how do you input cjk with gui wasn't
a thing yet
uh
well that question doesn't you know
so the question is how do you how do you
input chinese when graphical user
interface is not there yet
basically it doesn't exist okay
it doesn't exist basically so remember
the computer history began mostly in usa
so it's western you know it's mostly
english based
then
and china during that time is pretty
poor you know not until recent decade
china becomes very powerful and
economically
uh doing well
so
you know people try to create chinese
you know you you you can't begin to
create chinese input system before you
actually have a good operating system
you know mostly china they use
windows you know so
so basically that question just doesn't
come up because china doesn't have a
computer you know first of all you need
to have computers everywhere
then you can start to think about
so before gui was invented basically
china
they are not using computers china and
taiwan okay
so there is a defender of glue linux you
can you know it says you know
just
are you chinese you says you can install
every font you can on windows because it
supports the same font formats yeah you
can but it's not free you have to steal
you open source linux buckets fanaticism
you have to steal from microsoft you
know steal their fund in order to do
that in general okay
that's what linux people do often you
know these
phonetics okay so i think that's it for
today so
finally let me let me demonstrate
writing chinese okay this would be fun
so let's start photoshop
uh okay so let's open a picture so let's
see what
opening
okay so here is
so i want to uh close actually
try her
it's
i'm not too familiar with uh
undo undo
so
pain so i want to deselect
deselect is what
unselect
what
there used to be a unselect or where did
it go
this not even select
oh they they put the select into a
menu by itself
so i'm not selecting anything so let's
try
okay
i want red
try ah stupid
red
okay
try what is it why is it not red
ah this is stupid okay so open a new
window
okay
okay there is writing chinese
takes years to learn okay
no kidding
so uh
so
what to write okay
okay
so let me type that
[Music]
okay and
okay that's this part
was the
i am sardi okay and
these two characters means america okay
united states of america
okay
okay so that's
uh
america
and china
have your chinese degraded over the
years since you left taiwan absolutely
you know if you don't use it you degrade
i haven't you know i haven't been
writing chinese for long for
20 30 years you know i write talk speak
english just about every day
but i haven't
i haven't
handwrite chinese for
not even once a year you know once in
five years you know during some period
maybe i write an hour you know so i
haven't many characters i don't remember
so i have to look up
and uh you know what so related to one
of the question above about how do you
create chinese input system without gui
you see
when i was in taiwan i never used the
computer before so not until 2002
in america
i started to
learn
about
how to input chinese
on a computer okay so that is something
i learned
when i was like 30 years old
so i never did it before you know why do
i learn it
in actually
not because i need it mostly because i'm
into you know typing and study of the
linguistics and the input systems
so that's that's it for today
hey reaper thank you
[Music]
so reaper's question what do you think a
realistic solution to censorship by
internet platform is okay that's
that's uh
that's a good question okay but okay so
what do you think a realistic solution
to censorship by internet so what do you
mean so
so the question
so there is so one of the question is
how do you do censorship
from a technological point of view okay
so reaper you know while i answer your
question you know
like i you know let's refine you know
ask me more you know if i didn't address
your question
refine it so
one of the
one of the question is how do you what's
the best technology
to sense the internet okay that's one
one interpretation of the question
i don't i don't really know because well
i don't really know because
because that involves understanding you
know tcpip in detail you have to know a
detail you know one of the ways simply
firewall like china great firewall you
know in china
you cannot access
facebook you cannot access twitter
by default you know you cannot access to
youtube i don't
um
yeah i think so i i think you cannot you
know so china has the what's called
great firewall
that prevents any traffic from certain
sites you know entering china
how they do that
well firework firewall is the most
simple technology
to do censorship in a nationwide sense
okay firewall of course
china's great firewall is not just
firewall it's it it actually involves
quite
as
as heavy as technical advance as
possible just like whatever fbi and cia
is doing you know
you know they can you know then they so
in order to and you know that
question about this question you have to
know
tcp very well in depth so i have a i
have a
actually i have an article on that so
let's go to um
so how long have been talking almost one
hour okay so let's go to
okay so let's go to
so you have to know tcp okay so you go
to one of my tutorial
and here is a beginner's tutorial on tcp
ip and http you know the whole internet
suite of protocols this is how
internet is possible okay so
if you don't know what tcpip is if you
don't know how email works
begin here okay so you you know you have
these
hardware devices you need them you have
the ethernet ports you have the wireless
protocols and so on so tcp so you have
to you know fold us so any any of you in
programming industry you have to
know the basics of tcp okay read my
tutorial so that's one way to
you know the question interpretation of
the question now you know so
there are several others okay so for in
usa
the culture of usa
does not allow
nationwide
firewall okay but as you know
google twitter they are doing censorship
all the time
you know especially in the past few
years getting severe
um so what is the
so yeah so twitter and google you know
they
they do censorship they do
you
they do censorship in so many different
ways you know they you know usa you
cannot just have a
point-blank
firewall and since you know that's not
that's against the culture
you know but
then but you do lots of other things for
example youtube you know usa is
different from china china is run by one
single government or the western would
call dictatorship or as i recently
learned
social democracy okay
china social democracy you know actually
there's a wikipedia you know social
democracy
socialism democracy something like that
but anyway so in usa
since censorship takes many forms okay
so for example on youtube just about
you know you so usa is not
is not one government usa is like
is is corporation based essentially
google twitter facebook amazon they
new york times basically this run usa
okay more
more or less
all your all your corporations weapon
industry they run usa so you don't have
one blanket you know like censorship but
rather you have you know for example all
the
computers we use microsoft you know
microsoft apple all the computer they
have
so when you want to post a video so so
this they have rules you know
uh user agreement terms of service
you know that that is
part of censorship because you have to
agree for example i want to for example
right now i'm doing youtube i cannot
just say whatever i cannot say
women and men are different
i'm gonna get killed
but but but this is the in the past five
years it happened but there are many
other things i cannot say for example i
cannot for example i if i saw an
accident someone you know and i record
it i cannot upload it to youtube
because it's a violation of user
agreement you cannot have a you know
uh accident blood okay but you can do
that in china you can do that in russia
i saw it i saw
so many of them people you know get shot
or run over or lots of other things i'd
rather not you know
in one one i also saw
lots of things you know blood and gold
which in usa you cannot do it you cannot
you will not in no way or you can see it
you cannot post on twitter although
twitter kind of slack
these sensors only certain things you
know but basically essentially you
cannot do it anywhere but you want to
for example middle east you know in the
past 10 or 20 years there's lots
beheadings
where do you see that video okay
you cannot see it but
most of you will know where to look for
it you know there's like like like
like um
how they say uh dark internet you know
you can there's a certain website hosted
hosted outside of usa then you can see
those pic those uh kind of video so
that's one
category of things you cannot see in usa
even though
there's no censorship but it's
effectively censored
one
huge category involving go
i mean i'm not talking about like
like
like intentionally dramatized skull
but blood is a natural happening
everywhere
especially car accidents
you know
but you don't see it all or suicide
suicide happens every day in usa but you
cannot you will not see it you know the
mentality of the people is that oh
that's
that actually encourages or that bad for
society i don't think so i don't agree
i think
when you actually see
i mean i'm not talking about like some
troll in tennis intentionally i'm
talking about natural
accident and natural goal okay it just
happened happened to
it you know everyone dies okay and if
even you die of old age okay but you
will not see
those on youtube or anywhere in usa
because it's not allowed it's a use of
violation of user agreement no
censorship but violation of user
agreement that's the thing
that's just one category there's quite a
lot so but
so so reaper is saying okay i'm more
asking about has a collective internet
in the u.s not come up with a legit
alternative social platform that has
less censorship
okay why is that okay what are your
thoughts okay so
so why so okay so i'm talking about some
other things so reaper is asking why
essentially why is that
in usa
google and twitter facebook these giants
you know so-called
tech giants
they
they essentially rule the information
they don't yeah well basically i think
the answer is because they don't allow
other
you know smaller players to come up to
to compete
you know when they become big or notable
they kill it
using many excuses
for example
you know in a political area we know
there's a gap there's quite a few okay
uh well
and it's getting worse in the past five
years so
so why does that happen i mean why is
why is the you know
well i i just you know
i think the most obvious reason is that
these
big money corporations google facebook
twitter
youtube for example they don't want
competition
you know because what
part of that part of that is that
because then when there's any other
they do okay they use all sort of
excuses to kill them
uh and
that's part of the reason and also
google youtube you know these giant
corporations they are kind of the
establishment because they
once you are big you are part of the
establishment so you tend to follow
whatever the big league
uh
consortium kind of you know twitter
facebook you know they all agree this is
what we allow or not allow you know any
any other new we're gonna you know they
use lots of excuses to kill it
for example one one of the thing i would
like to say is https
okay my website does not have https
google pushed that and google basically
brainwashed all the open source unix
linux phonetics to support it to help
them
push for https so beginning in the past
few months my website sometimes you'll
see
when people click
you'll see error because my website does
not support https okay you started to
see it in the in the in the past half a
year okay
so let me show you okay so
for example this guy is asking me okay
so you click on that
wait no wait not that
uh
you see
you
you know you you just type saudi.info on
twitter and twitter will generate you
know this nasty they will generate a
tracking link so this link is actually
not linked to sally.info it's actually
for example you can copy it let's see if
we can
copy link address okay
paste you see
this is what twitter generates
it's twitter's own website
so you click on that saudi.info you
actually go to twitter's own website the
database of which
of database of websites and who clicked
it he knows you know i click it he or
not twitter we don't know so
redirect should you know this is short
url
so twitter generates this tracking link
then this tracking link twitter
automatically assumes that this is
solid.info is https
you know they shouldn't assume it
because anyone would know any any any
person with a brand
who works for twitter any programmer
know that some links are not https okay
but however twitter doesn't care they
decided they decided to assume all links
are https
why because they are part they you know
they are part of the giant league they
want to push for https which is a which
is a control of the entire
internet okay https because you need a
cert where do you get a cert
certification authority
so
that is my opinion about why google
pushing http https so anyway beginning
past few months this started to happen
it didn't happen before the past
past year
half a year only only begin recently
so you click on my website you get you
get you know
the site can provide secure connection
because they are using https
twitter twitter did it
so if you remove the s you know my
website works so back to the censorship
so i i think that question is very
simple because the google facebook
twitter they are
giant
establishments so they
they tend to do all sorts of things to
remove
potential
rising
competitors
i think that's that's my answer
so related to censorship how would you
contextualize or analyze the concept of
shadow binding in historical
philosophical non-context okay
shadow banning is the most
skunk
behavior that begin with the millennial
generation shadow band you should never
do that okay in my opinion you don't you
don't shadow bad
if you
you know suppose i start i start a
social network you know a website or
whatever or even on my discord okay on
my discord we have also the people and
sometimes people are
crazy you know
all of us are crazy but sometimes they
make a they make they make trouble you
know we had a few
so what do you do
so these millennial generation idiots
they they thought of hey let's wait why
don't we do shadow ban
so that they don't actually know they
are banned you know that's no good
that's don't do that okay that's not
that's not a man that's that's
that's
that's uh how do you say that's not a
proper you know you shouldn't do that if
you want to ban them
let them know
what they did is not acceptable okay
on either my my server or your server
whatever you are you know irc you
control whatever a reddit
a reddit
subreddit a reddit room
that you created or
major platforms social networks such as
twitter youtube or whatever facebook
okay if you want to ban them you know we
should what the proper thing to do let
them know
what they are doing is not good
make a list of rules you know
and say okay you did it wrong they don't
do that again please they do it again
you ban them okay
you are banned and say who banned it
okay important
show your id okay you
admin on irc already the faces
at me they love to ban because that's a
human nature you know
exercise power
so if you want to ban them
you tell them the reason put your name
there i banned someone i xani ban xyz
because
he did this this this
and that should be a public record okay
that's what bad means then the other
person
who who got banned
um if he agree okay he see the reason
you know he can agree or not agree if he
doesn't agree
you know
you know there's always bad guys in
society murderers and thieves you know
if you agree maybe he oh he didn't
realize okay now maybe he
you know wait for a month you know you
and you shouldn't ban people permanently
you know give them a you know give give
people a break bend them by a week a
month something like that okay let them
know if they did something wrong let
them know no
this you shouldn't do that or you are
not welcome then people will leave okay
that's a natural human real life
interaction you know let them know you
are not welcome okay you do you keep
doing that okay eventually maybe we
didn't agree
on things
then
you run your life i run my life okay
don't come to my home
that's what bad means okay that's what
it should be
you don't do shadow band that's a
scum the millennial generation
invented that and now it becomes so
common it's like
that's my opinion on the shadow band
yeah interesting so america you cannot
see real life people dying but you can
see in the movies
america that's another thing about
america okay
in america if you
show a tits you know a woman a girl
you know even by accident that's like oh
my god the big thing
censorship fine you know the
but then american movies they have they
have they have torture upon
and it's a box office you know big time
block
buster
you know like like the movie is like so
or you have massive killings you know
whoa you know the
the
movies make money so
okay that's it for today thank you guys
so any any um
aspect you
uh about the censorship that
that you think i didn't address or
something reaper
that's it for today so i'm shutting down
okay that yeah that's it for today
we talked about shadow band
google
facebook
twitter act
sensor
ship in
america
about shadow ben
bye guys
thank you ripper
fantastic
close that close that
kinesis great keyboard i'm gonna review
i'm gonna do a unboxing or something
uh probably
in the coming
in in
before new year
so watch out for that
because that tcpip tutorial tcpip
tutorial go learn it
tcpip
every self-respecting programmer
must know even you are devops okay you
should know how it works basics tcp
tutorial
chinese font
do i have this article uh
put in my link okay there it is chinese
font
okay
bye guys
merry christmas
you need to switch your youtube chat to
live chat okay
bye