good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of c talk show today we are
going to code emac lisp and Powers shell
drunk
coding partially slightly drunk okay
this is red
wine okay let's begin emac this coding
so my keyboard is kesis 360 wired
there's a wired version and Prov version
my version is wired which offers better
programmability of the keys and on the
Fly key programming so you can press a
few keys and remap keys so uh create a
key marro and this is Ultimate hacking
keyboard the best marro
keypad okay I have reviews on my website
now okay let's do
let's start to code Powers shell okay
we're going to code Powershell and emac
this now if you are here say hi
okay suu
Su
suu XD High okay so we begin
coding poell and emac
LP uh the first thing we going to write
a command to change file name involving
a nonbreaking space to low line why do
we need that
because let me show you on the
Mac uh let maybe I can find some example
let's see not that not that not that not
that not that not that uh okay I don't
have a example open open this is emac
diet so this is my emac I'm using emac
and I using soft FL keys and I'm using a
Vora keyboard okay so you search for
kadi keyboard blog you can find my best
keyboard recommendations gl8 kesis
360 these two I recommend today not the
kesis advantage two so gra 0 conis
360 and uh Expos night or if you prefer
60% keyboard I can recommend happy
hacking keyboard okay and uh I'm using a
v keyboard of course layout ergonomic
keyboard layout this is quy heat map and
this is vak that's what I'm using
hardwired into the programmed into the
keyboard
firmware and I'm using S Keys which is a
emac key binding system like Vim model
and more sufficient so for example let's
go to the source
code 4,000 lines of code and here is the
website Sly
Keys uh there's a videos you can watch
you know the introduction and the pink
window shows all all my command Calles
and the key strokes as I type them okay
so that's a introduction so now let's be
so why do we need to uh okay so let's
copy that show this in browser close
that copy that close close close you see
I'm pressing this
key to close the buffer okay reopen it
and that's a feature of soft keys you
can see the command is not open last
closed so now I'm using I paste that
here make a link make a list Kar
keyboard blog showing browser and uh you
see I'm using Kar HTML mod and you can
buy my Kar emac system just search for
Kar emac you'll find
it so we have that close that intro to
soft keys copy back here paste link make
a list combined the list combined the
list sh browser so that's all power ofar
flly Keys andar HTML mod for emac okay
so close that s like Keys we already
copy that link heat map go switch back
paste the link make a list combine the
list there it is okay now Powers shell
so why do you need to change file name
that has a nonbreaking space who the
[ __ ] creates that Apple okay in apple
when you do do a screenshot it creates a
file name with you know with something
something am AM and PM and before the
word Am Pm they put a nonbreaking space
so let me show you what that
is
nonbreaking space okay so they they they
create a file name let's magnify so you
can see they create a file name so in
emac when you have a Unbreaking space it
shows like a a little underline thin
underline with red color so that's a
Unbreaking space how do I know you do
describe
CH okay so you can see the command
describe chart there can you see it yes
so you can see then it pops up the
window that tells you the name is no
break space so this is a invisible I
mean well space is already invisible but
this this space character is different
from the normal space character it
tells uh nonbreaking space it tells the
application whoever display it to not
you know this space is cannot be break
so that's so this is part of unic code
and apple whenever on Apple on the Mac
on Mac OS you do a screenshot it creates
that file name it's is no good okay why
is it no good because then all your
scripts moving files uh
uh for example the for example let me
show you let me tell you why is it not
good let me create a file with
nonbreaking space okay you see here is a
screenshot uh let's see let's magnify
okay so here's a screenshot it's a
picture let's show another one okay it's
my commentary uh register machine this
is computer science about regist machine
so I can open this file in
you know so I'm calling the
command open in external app and on
Windows I'm using Windows I'm I'm I'm
using this iPhone
view image viewer this is the Classic
this is the best one back from the 1990s
but today is kind of lousy
because because time changed and all the
commands you know all the features they
are back in the 90 1990s and early 2000s
way of thinking so you don't have so
they even support things like select
scan train Source you know train is like
back then 20 years ago is that is is is
when you want to you know back then you
have
scanners like uh some device you can buy
to scan books or Pages then I I guess it
creates some some format then you can
inut code from those you know TR called
TWA a TW w a i n so this is history so
let me let me just show you okay so
Random talk show I'm going to show
you TR okay tww tww I N that's one of
the old uh stuff
so search for
it so Mark TR no not not Mark TR uh
something about scanner so these days
you
can so you have to search train
scanner so there it is Wikipedia let's
see I think that is it so magnify train
train direct application programming
interface and communication protocols
that regulate communication between
software and digital imaging devices
such as image
scanners and digital digal cameras
that's a thing so train is very popular
back when the scanning so like 20 years
ago so or in the 1990s so you can see
this is almost like obsolet technology
oh stable
release in 2021 they have a stable
release but anyway these days you don't
hear people don't hear anymore so so you
see this Earth and view is a classic
best uh uh image viewers on
Windows and in particular is it's the
first application image viewer that
allows you to view gif animated gif and
and other things so anyway this is a
best but today it's pretty much outdated
but it's still very good for the fastest
fastest for dis displaying JPEG and it
also can do slideshow so that's what it
was known for so anyway I'm using TW I
set up my windows to open PNG file so
JPEG files in Oran view this is
application name so uh okay so let's go
to Windows let me show you so you just
search for Microsoft Windows TP tips
ons.info then you have a page great
software for
Windows so you can see image view for
Windows Earth view so you can see a
Wikipedia article about that Earth view
what a idiotic name but this but this is
interesting because this is written by a
single guy by this Earthen oh his name
is Anan Anan
skan so back in
1996 so he still maintains it and is
alive but this
days not many people use it I I
suppose so window Microsoft Windows tips
today we going to program Powershell and
here is my Powershell tutorial the kind
of best introduction you'll get you have
two sections you have how to section
that is how to navigate directory how to
exit how to [ __ ] how to you know
show help files such as like the Linux
main page how to navigate directory uh
how to list files list files by while
card by literal path by subdirectories
if you want recurse what are the option
names and things like that all the
Practical how to you know the things you
want to do daily so howto section show F
uh show file full path filter file by
name and you know and all how do you fig
filter out file names by regular
expression and list directories list
directories as a tree and creating new
directory in Unix that's meor and how do
you create a new file in Unix that's
touch how do you do that with Powershell
and so on so this is all practical and
and how do you zip unzip files or unzip
t files on Windows without installing
you know the Unix
andar or unzip so how do you do it
natively with power shell and zip andar
gunzip you know extract seven Z files
extract lzip files LZ files and how do
you create them zip tar 7z you know a
bunch of
practical how to sections on power shell
then you have also indepth section that
is about how how power shell works you
know the power shell is a programming
language it's a sh programming language
in uh in the typical in kind of the same
sense like bash or zshell on the
Mac so you know because power shell is
very different from uni shell because
uni shell they process text they
basically just passing around text in
power shell they pass around object
everything is object so you have objects
and methods so this is
detailed kind of introduction to poell
in depth that makes you understand po
shell so you know search for go for Mya
Powell
tutorial and yeah so we were talking
about uh so we have great software for
Windows that's kind of a little bit a
bit
outdated uh so let show close that close
that so we were talking about
lots of things uh okay close that close
that close that close that and close
that reopen so that they are not so big
we were talking about nonbreaking space
Mac creates that no good okay uh
now delete that great software for
Windows and uh pow sh tutorial that's
it's already here so so let's start to
code shall we uh of view so we talked
about Earth and view
so the train yeah idiotic train
stuff okay how are you
guys one of the few on emac these
days how are you I'm good so how do you
manage your page files in
backup uh how do I manage I manage them
in emac of course so I have a lot of
script for example these are backup so
talk show let's in emx show uh show the
pink window I press a button you see all
the backup files are listed and that key
is uh where is
it you see diod flag backup files and
that key is the apostrophy one single
key then if I want to delete them I say
I press X
and it says are you sure you want to
delete this yes you see and uh right now
I'm I'm I'm on this file let's say on
this one and this one I can mark them if
I want backup this specific files I
press some key you see I got a backup
and that command isamic backup and save
if you search the web chances are you'll
find them okay let's search the
web
uh okay
uh so there's one of my
article autosave no that's not what we
want this is brave search let's try
Google search press press press some
key uh there it is Google is actually
better search engine but Google got so
much censorship so there it is the code
you can download you can just copy it
put your your emx in it you'll have the
same feature as I
do so and how do I search how do I look
up Google for
example that's this command look up
Google uh and let's go to the source
code you see this is emac L I read I
wrote go to the top and uh go to this
page that's the homepage look up web
look up web look up Google look up
Yandex
Google is filled with censorship these
days you cannot find anything sensitive
you want if you search for programming
stuff Google is still good but if you
search for any Pol politician names or
any celebrity or any girls pretty girls
you know let's say you are Russ
searching for Russian girls or whatever
Google is going to come up with come up
with bad results so that's when you need
Yandex
Yandex uh search engine from Russia so
you can have these commands emac command
I just press a few Keys uh and you you
know you go to the web and search it and
you can also search you know definition
for word English word uh you have
atmology and you have V victionary you
have Wikipedia search you have internet
archive search oh internet archive so
let's try that okay so copy that new
buffer paste that that's a file path
make it into the S URL fully qualified
URL and let's search for look up
internet archive so I I don't remember
what key is that well I can find out but
let's just type the key uh archive okay
oh chhr okay
so
internet archive way back machine
requires your browser to support
JavaScript they want to know where you
are and who are you okay turn on
JavaScript then there it is you can see
the internet archive of one of my
pages so click on that January
2023 last year okay so you can see my
the the archive page of of this C looka
package for emac this and you have to
pay okay because I now you have to pay
me to get it because for about 10 or 15
years I have my entire emac tutorial
free and commands free on a website no
nobody give a [ __ ] you know but instead
they just they just have drama oh is
crazy this you know nobody pays you open
source story of Open Source so how do I
manage my files so emac of course and uh
I typically do not use one of those
backup
uh software I just write scripts sh
scripts power shell or bash or python or
even that just manually copy files or G
you know uh do
that what tools is that showing the
commands on the purple okay that is a
command log so for example you go to my
Kar emac package so here is Kar emac
okay you pay $100 you get the entirety
all of all my packages I use let's
delete those backup delete yes okay so
but one of them includes log okay
actually it's not here so log the
the pink window you see that is done by
a package called command log emac Comm
command log something okay and I can
show you uh a b go to the directory so
this is the one command
log. so it's written by Nick faer then
Modified by
leean and uh then uh original author is
uh Michael Weber I gu guess so beginning
in 2000 you know there several
modifications so I modified a bit so
anyway this pink window you see is from
this package it's on GitHub okay command
log mod okay now we digressed so much
let's go back to
uh look up the web okay so copy the file
path close close close and paste it here
so we talked about that that delete that
paste it here merge the list showing
browser there it is so you see I'm using
my ultimate hacking keyboard for one
single key press of manipulation of
Windows and so so on so if I want to
close this tab press that key if I want
to go previous tab okay close that Tab
and previous tab next tab previous tab
next tab or one single key press so you
don't have to control all [ __ ] you know
that [ __ ] up that gives you repetitive
strain
injury ah cheers now we haven't got to
code yet shall we yeah so we want to
code so let's uh okay so copy let's why
don't we just paste all the links
here that things we talked about close
close Okay keyboard uh yeah let's show
let's paste ke keyboard here as
well okay close now what is this uh dual
function keys home roll mods that's one
of my article uh for keyboard
Fanatics okay so back to our original
problem we want to write a power script
that change all file names in a
directory so that the file name does not
contain the nonbreaking
space we want to replace that character
by a normal space okay how do you do
that
easy so let's let's show you let's let's
start to write it okay so let's begin
writing it so
let's start a Powershell so I'm
using I'm using HTML mod part of my Exar
emx package so I can press a key type a
language I want Powers shell so showing
browser you can see I got a poers shell
block then I can press the key then it
pops up into a poers shell mod by the
way this is alsoa poers shell
mod uh so we can show you the source
code uh let's see um describe
key and describe
key that okay so you can see Power shell
mod go to the source file so here's a
source file about 1100 lines of code go
to the top then go to here open that
link showing browser Kar poell mod so
you see this is Kar system so if you
want
it pay me to get it okay so now back to
code Powell how do you do it okay uh
well actually I already like I talked
about I have my poell tutorial and uh
how so right now the problem
is we want to write the poell command
that change your file names in a
directory to replace any character of
nonbreaking space to a normal space so
there are two things you need to do one
is is this directories okay the other
which is very simple the you know the or
LS so let's show Powers shell okay so
here is the powers Shell let's magnify
so this is s directory okay actually we
don't want that close
that so in fact we want to let me show
you another emac command I want to open
this directory in power shell how do you
do that uh not this directory let's open
this directory in pow shell okay so in
IMX this directory is you know web info
talk show I want to open this directory
in pow sh how do you do that well
there's a emac S emac command you press
the
key boom boom boom there it is you can
see po shell magnify in that directory
and that command is open in terminal and
this command command is free so now
let's do look up Google on
that uh uh wait so wait where is the
command so
here there open in terminal so you grab
this code emac this put in your emac
initial you will have the same
functionality free okay so copy that
close back to emx CL CL so what is this
page talk show okay so close back open
that and paste it here okay linky now
let's go back to poell how do you code
it yeah so you see we are in pow shell
and uh we want to write a command so in
fact it's already here so po shell so
two things you need to do one is a list
of directories or list of files the
other thing is how do you do find the
replace of a string so you can
see search text okay so there is
actually you want to uh replace so you
in that case you go to poell in
depth uh and uh string so there's a
section on string how do you quote
string string operations regular
expression operations string
Methods there it is string Methods list
string Methods so I show you how do you
actually list all string Methods in
poers Shell by that okay we can show it
so that command do it you you see you
got the list of string Methods in
Powershell this is Powershell coding
Powershell is very practical you know
it's a native shell for Microsoft
Windows and it's been that way for 10
years you know it began like 15 years
ago but it started to be bundled with
every Windows bundled with every Windows
since since about I think almost 10
years ago and so when you work in a
operating system it's always best to use
the native shell or native whatever
because otherwise you have like in you
have kind of like lots of frictions so
if you work in window
you want to know Powershell okay
Powershell today is is entirely open
source with net entirely op source so
you could use it on on Linux or Mac as
well I have it installed on my Linux on
my Mac
machine but in General on Linux you
better stick with bash okay so you know
always it's best to stick with the
native uh system uh because you avoid a
lot of fr s and compatibility issues
like conversion and stuff so anyway
Powers shell so this kind of
introduction to pow sh so string replace
so here's an example how do you replace
a string for example let's copy
that case sensitive replace okay so run
that command we want to replace do by
cat so this is how you do it dog replace
become cat
so anyway let's go back so to do what I
want to change the non breaking space to
space of all files of a directory I have
already written it so let's go to my
bookmark
paral paral
profile. PS1 open it this is my file uh
it's 600 lines now drop into diet
directory so you see Power Shell by
default stores your own init
directories you know and the in this
directory documents Pell and by default
the file name is microsoft. power.
profile. PS1 that's your poell in it
okay by default open it so 600 lines of
code and one of them is
replace uh nonbreaking space so let me
just
search search for break there it
is so this is part of another command I
have so but so I basically already
written it so let's
just copy it and uh let's make it a
independent command Okay so close it
close
it paste it here so we're going to write
a inde independent command how do you do
that I forgot
I don't code power I don't code pow
shell every day so I forgot how do you
create a function in Pell so power shell
in depth uh
function there it is function so this is
how you do
functions simple function template allow
allowed characters in function names uh
semi colon optional if new line okay so
named parameters so the this is how you
do that blah blah
blah uh okay
so then you have switch parameters
positional
parameters then you have accept pipeline
okay so to write this command so let's
common first
Common write a Powers
shell
command
to
change all file names in a by
replacing any
nonbreaking space to normal space okay
that's a
task okay so how do you write a function
let's see do I have a shortcut function
okay
oh the power ofar power sh mod expansion
so let's do it again
F expand to function press space again
you got this nice
template all you need is here so we're
going to go with that now the name of
the function is going to
Bea
replace
n breaking space long name okay now
power sh has its own Convention of
naming of
commands they by their convention they
go by two words so the first word is
um verb and noun I think it's verb and
noun so yeah so for example the uh for
example you know if you type
du that's actually the full name for the
command du is get child item so you have
verb and noun that's how that's a
Convention of how sh name it I don't
really like it though but let's screw
that okay so let's you know this is my
function s replacement breaking space so
before you write this function there is
a design
issue that is how do you want this
function how how do you design the
interface of this function for
example you know you could say in the
current directory you know you say you
can say replace non breaking space okay
then that will just replace
all file names in this directory in the
current
directory you know do that
or you can design your function so that
you can pipe any directory name or file
name to this so you can say the you know
du will list the current directory right
you can say du then then pipe it
TOA uh replace nonbreaking space
okay so there's a design issue you want
this command just just um change all the
files in the current directory or you
want it to do that and plus you want it
to be able to take a
pipe
okay now I'm a bit tipsy so I'm not
going
to think about which way it should be so
for now let's
just make it take the pipe because take
the pipe is usually is probably correct
because when you take the pipe because
Powers shell just like Unix Bash
has a pipe concept so you can have one
command that specialize in doing
something then another command
specialize in doing some other thing so
in the case of you know deleting all
file names you know change your file
names replacing the nonbreaking
space so that's one thing but as far as
listing directories or listing files you
want you probably want to rely
uh on on other commands you know because
other commands can filter by file names
and and all other things so you don't
have to do those in your command so you
just pipe a list of names to this
command so that's probably better way so
let's do
that so okay so now I need to explain
how do you write a Powershell command
that take a pipe basically this is what
you want well it's explained in my
tutorial accept pipeline okay now let's
read the
comments one of the comment by plasma
Scythe says you should use common lisp
instead of wolam
language
that's the most laughable idea it's so
laughable I'm tired of it for like 10
for for 20 years it's the most idiotic
extreme idiotic
idea common this compared to wolam
language this no comparison wolam
language is like how many times more
powerful and more easy to use and more
pain ass in pain in the ass free is Ru
language then poish then then common
this 10 or is it
100 you know the common list idiots I
despise common list
okay now but there's a
exception now if you want to you know if
you know there's a exception wolam
language is not b o and n o right none
of the essentially none there's no one
single language you can say that's best
in
everything in every task any in in in
writing a operating system in writing a
real time system in the most easy to
understand you know the syntax in the
most easy to the most powerful
expressible expressibility you know and
the most
correct provably correct like hascal or
ACTA or Co you know there's no language
no single language general purpose that
that is best for
everything
however now those of you interested in
programming languages however there is a
general concept a valid concept of best
language somewhat roughly valid that
means this this language is general
purpose and on average it compares
favorably to all the others
comparatively
speaking okay so you can compare by
speed you can compare by ease of
learning the language how easy it is to
learn the language you can compare it by
for example a social aspect popularity
of the language how popular is it that's
an important element most nerds will
ignore it's an important element because
that's what usually uh where you get
money to code for in that language for
example C CS C C++ even C Goan
JavaScript python these are popular and
even Ruby this languages get you a job
you know wfam language no you can Master
Wan language you don't get a job okay
you know so you can compare a language
by speed by by how easy is is it to
learn by how good is its documentation
you know that's also important for
example PHP got the best documentation
PHP Java wam language these are all the
best documentations you can easily find
what you need when you are you know have
lots of coding problems you can easily
find exactly which function you need for
example PHP
um wam language and Java okay these are
good example bad example of
documentation is python JavaScript
JavaScript don't have document you know
and you know and and uh and uh even C
don't really have a documentation you
know so anyway so there's many criteria
to judge a language many aspects so I'm
not going to digress I've made video
videos in the past about which
programming to learn uh so if you are
interested in
that uh let's see ex which programming
language to learn because that's one of
the popular topic people ask me and one
of the popular topic I talk about okay
so uh it's not here
but
uh it's one of the video with a kind of
a
chopstick
pop keyboard to it h good God so who
else is watching now I'm semi drun and
we haven't got to
um okay now I got
hiccups we haven't got to the coding p p
sh yet a lot digression
so so you want to find yeah one of my
problem one of the problem of my videos
is that I've made of I made 500 videos
in the past three years okay uh but
usually it's not so easy to find you
know a specific topic that people are
interested for example right now we want
to find which programming language
what's class opinion on programming
languages which one you should you want
to learn so so although I repeat it so
many times um but it's not how do you
find it so let's try
exage talk languages okay uh l n Gua
okay so there are 35 there it is s talk
show
2019 January 10 which programming
language to learn python or Ruby or
hascal open that
okay that's one of them but that's not
the one I have in mind
uh so talk show another one programing
language is L homo
homo
homeo conicity that's one of the least
phonetics
idiocy uh then concurrent languages you
know uh then eag this you know so I made
so many langu so many videos 500 of them
it becoming hard to find uh what what
which one I want okay
so yeah lisp and lisp so many of them on
lisp
so what I can recommend is that if you
go to k the.info
code so if you want to watch some of my
best videos usually I invent them on my
website so for example
uh my.
homeinfo homepage I embed three kind of
best videos that are of different nature
so one is about the keyboard glove 0
which is a great keyboard and one is
about uh the most efficient emac work
workflow so it's about emac one of the
my main topic the other one is about
wolam Language tutorial for programmers
from the ground up so you should watch
that one okay then you go to for example
I have a lot of articles on language
design comp land ping okay I think it's
there comp land ping open that there it
is that is a video that is the one I'm I
was thinking of s talk show 2021
February 6th characteristics of hascal
Pearl Ruby python closure Java
JavaScript Lis wam lab okay so in this
video it's over it's 1 hour I give you a
characteristics of these different
languages anyway so let's go back so
um what do you think about guix ni I I
don't know you know so many random
questions you you you know this you know
you guys question you know that's I
think that's typical for a YouTuber
typically you'll get lots of questions
that's been asked a million times and
you have answered a million times so I
can answer the question today but by by
next month you will have the same
question because the vast majority of
you know the lamb Zoomers you know they
idiots they they don't they don't they
don't
they don't study they don't care about
nothing they don't really care about
anything so they just ran into some
YouTuber like me so you just came to my
show maybe for the first time and you
have a question one of the question
that's answered a million times like
which one is is better n ninja ninja
sword or the
Western long
sword you know so you get this
frequently asked questions every day you
answer them a million times they pop up
again again and again because vast
majority the the most you know the
bottom line you know they they don't
care they just watch it and by tomorrow
they forgot they don't really like they
don't have like they don't they are not
truly concerned about some
question you know anyway that's just the
common situation you know so anyway so
uh yeah let's let's go back to the let's
go back to coding the pow Shell let's
okay let's code it so we want to write a
function a command a power shell command
that change or file name of nonbreaking
space to uh normal space and uh and this
part is uh Powershell documentation we
ignore for now actually description link
let's say uh let's put the
description here okay so this is the Pow
shell convention for documentation be
when you follow this convention then
then you can actually in pow shell you
can type help for example help the you
know then okay enter enter enter enter
enter you know then you see the
entire this is like Unix man page so it
can give you examples it can give you
external links it can give you
description then it can tell you options
you know you know so you have to follow
this uh this convention okay by this
comment okay so let's say description
is
uh
file let's just let's just be sloppy
okay change your file
names piped to it by
replacing n
breaking space to
normal space okay that's probably that's
not the best documentation but let's
just go by that okay so
param uh we don't care about par so
let's let's let me just do it okay so
you want this process block that means
other commands can pipe to it then
you'll run this process block okay so in
this process process block what do you
do uh wait so let's C delete that copy
the file path wait com BL ping so copy
the file path close it go back to the
talk page and uh paste the link here so
we have a record of what we talked
about comp land perving that's
about comp perving that's about nering
about all the syntax and semantics and
design of computer languages okay so
let's merge this links too many uh so
I'm using SAR HTML mod you know much all
these things so anyway we are back to
Power
sh so open that so process so wait what
is the how do you do it
uh okay uh well this okay so how do you
do
that so power shell mod okay that's not
what we want we want yeah here so here
is the Pow shell how do you write the
function in po shell so you want to
accept
pipelines so you want to yeah so
that so grab this part put this so
basically in this process Block in this
block of code anything when there's a
dollar sign underscore that represents
one of the input piped into your command
okay so you want to do something with
the dollar sign under score okay so in
this case let's say so right host is is
just print print it okay so right host
uh let's say let's just say that
okay uh rename file then breaking space
to low line okay so let's just state
that just print to the screen okay right
host is
um help Echo let's
see no that's different from right
output anyway that's a bit technical
detail so if you all you want to do is
to print the to a screen then you want
to say right host okay so then get child
item
um no not get chart item
so yeah so we don't want even this
part to the recurse file filter
so
so for each object
wait okay so there's a issue do you want
[Music]
to uh get the to so let's remove to the
current current you don't need you know
by default it's a recurse file filter so
it only change files not directory and
you filter by that okay
so oh God so this is this is
taking elements from a pipe okay
so maybe that's not the best thing
because if you take elements from a pipe
that means you must first of all run
this command because because this this
command will actually show a list of
files that contains the nonbreaking
space so if you do it this way that
means every time people call your
command they have to type this whole
thing because they have to get the list
of you know nonbreaking
space kind of you know we do this
because we want to we don't want to go
over files that does not contain
Unbreaking space for efficiency
reasons because if you have a medium
file and only one of them contains a
nonbreaking space and if you don't do
this filter first then you just like
you're just going to try to go through
all file names of the medium files and
do the replacement even though nothing
happens but you know uh yeah
so okay how many how long have I been
talking
almost an hour so we are about to done
so let's see how many people are
watching and I need a break now 15
minutes huh when I when I'm chaty
usually there's more people watching
there's no more
why uh okay let's just finish this okay
whatever uh whatever sloppy way let's
just finish this so we have something to
show
so let's comment it out okay let's just
say for each object so
for wait so wait we don't you don't need
you don't even want for each object okay
so let's just
that okay
so so F new name equals to name replace
okay you replace by oh here it replace
by a hyphen actually let's replace by a
underscore okay so you replace by
underscore oh this does more than uh
more than just um nonbreaking space
because this also replace comma
by remove comma
and it also
replace okay so it replace those then
let's
see semicolon is a command separator
usually you don't need it if you are at
the end of line then you don't need it
okay so we don't need it
actually so we replace them then right
host then we we print
out the original name and with a new
name so we can see what has been changed
then we rename it then we actually
rename the file yeah
okay so I think that's it so that is the
command so let's shrink it so let's
remove this redundant you know uh
documentation link okay
example
okay let's just say that so here is a
command this is a complete code
okay so I think that's it now we want to
format pretty format this code you see
usually you need some kind of
indentation so to make them nice you
know so how do you do that well I have a
in power shell mod I can press a key to
do that okay
watch tap
F there it is beautiful so that command
Isa power shell format code if you
search the web you'll find it yeah let's
search the web
okay look up Google so command to for
format Powershell code there it is click
it you copy this and you'll get it so
this is emac
disp
well actually that's pow shell uh wait
let's go back so you need two things so
you need this emac this format
Powershell code put this in your init
but however you also need a poell script
this
one so the Eis code we call the pow Shar
code which is this
one and this code will actually call A M
Microsoft Powershell package
to actually do the formatting because
reformatting is a very nontrivial
task okay it seems simple you know
reformat the code it seems simple but
actually it's very very non-trivial
because you need to understand the
grammar of the language and so on and
not just grammar any anyway so anyway so
you see now it's pretty formatted now
press a key press a key back to the talk
show showing
browser there it is the code we wrote
today now inar HTML mod press a key to
syntax color it showing browser so we
got syntax color fantastic now the we
need to test the code that's a real test
okay now you need to copy that code copy
it close
that bookmark jump to my Powers shell in
it file and let's say put it at the
bottom so paste it here so we can see we
have this you
know code you
see so now we want to launch
Powershell not here because in over here
it doesn't know the new command yet so
close that now we want to call imex
command to launch a pow
shell and make it in this directory so
this directory is you know the pow shell
in file document pow shell so press a
key that's a emac command there it
is that command is open terminal is also
free okay so now magnify magnify magnify
so you can magnify we we need to
magnification because we are getting
old oh God I need a break my back
hoods am I doing good okay now you guys
if you like myself pay me okay because
all the saying doesn't do a thing it's
just uh pay that actually makes money
makes the world go around you know all
the you know some if you wonder
why why some politicians is you know all
the bad things happen because money okay
and if you are wondering if you are the
positive guy wondering why the good
things happen money okay don't you know
you might think oh that's because they
are good hearted
people yeah to some degree true but
mostly money money is making things
work so anyway here's a poh terminal so
now we can actually call the command so
let's so we can copy the command name we
can actually call the command we need to
pipe something to it so we need to pipe
the then pipe to it now right now it
won't work
because we don't have any file name
that's involves a nonbreaking space
let's create one okay make a backup
let's make another backup
then magnify the window let's just
change the name let's say XX then insert
a insert a nonbreaking space so what I
did what I just did is I called a one of
the command in SAR fly keys that allows
you to insert unic code for example I
can
insert hug okay let me show you
so the pink window you can see let me
show you you see insert unic code that's
a command that's part of Sly Keys okay
so let's insert let's do it
again press then let's say insert
star there it is a star now you see the
first character is a Unbreaking
space describe
Char you see it's
a no break space there it is okay that's
this character now okay
so are you done yet okay so press contrl
CC that's rename so the command we just
call to rename file is part of uh
emac
so this
so it's called W diet okay so anyway
it's somewhere here
there it's so you know if you just
search for Sardi emac tutorial you'll
find it rename file okay so anyway so we
have a file name here so you can press
another
key show in desktop you know it launches
the Microsoft native file directory
viewer which is called file explorer
okay magnify so you can see we have one
of this file with the weird characters
okay now ultimate hacking keyboard press
a key to remove this window do it okay
we back here so now we go to p pow
shell escape to remove that the list
directory so now you can see a
hug and there's a invisible you know
nonbreaking space there you know kind of
a tricky
now
the this directories then pivate
to um what is the file name so I mean
what is the command we just wrote Close
That replace
okay r
e tab there it is rename file space to
no line low line no that's not what we
want tab again rename file to Hash no
that's not we want tab again there it is
so I'll replace them breaking space okay
do
it did we did it work I think it did you
see see you see this
line but it shouldn't print other you
know it shouldn't print file names that
doesn't contain replacement so we need
to like make it better change that so
now let's du again
du you see the same file is there but
now let's see if there's a Unbreaking
space drop to the
diet so now you in diet you press G to
refresh right now there's an Unbreaking
space but you need to refresh the
directory so press
G [ __ ] doesn't
work describe Char there is still no
breaking space didn't work what the
[ __ ] okay it didn't
work
why uh so name so we renamed it so it
even
says you see this output rename file and
breaking
space so why it didn't
work
oh God
[ __ ] it did not
work this is a nonbreaking space
so we change it
why it didn't work I don't
understand so let's restart another
shell okay magnify a bit
magnify let's run
directory so there is supposed to be a
nonbreaking space here and let's repeat
the
command okay we pipe it
to right we pipe
it
then okay we also need to
fix Oh there's
uh there's there's some eror source and
destination path must be
different so actually if the file name
does not contain a Unbreaking space we
don't want to do anything with it okay
so we need to do a if
statement yeah okay so more
work so that means we need to go back to
Powershell
tutorial we need to
check if a string contains some
character how do you do
that okay so back to
stream stream operations string Methods
okay let's see string
operations
join join string string
length
split that's not what we want string
match by W cards that's not what we want
string regular expressions
n that's not what we want string
Methods uh string replace okay so these
are net methods string split string to
array check
substring what is check subst string
contains
okay okay so here's the
example let's see
so
so if
that
contains
that okay
[Music]
so so that's a method so that's what we
want in the statement so if that
contains then put these things
there
okay
now yeah
[ __ ] I'm trying to pedify the code now
it
failed why is it
failed unexpected
token pass
error contains in expression or
statement unexpected token
contains why why is
this uh you need to two string I guess
so the dollar signore do name that is
actually an object I'm pretty sure so
you need
to change that you need to convert it to
string
God this is the pen in power shell I
mean the yeah so yeah it is a pain in
power sh because everything is object
so the file name you need to turn it
into a
object is that right
yeah
oh so we have the replace operation so
we can maybe you we just use powers
shell
operators so you have join you have
split you have
string Methods string while cards
regular expression
operators okay let's check that regular
expression okay let's use this so if so
match so we can just so instead of
contains match
then take a regular expression
so so if string match okay
now prey the code
fantastic
now now close
this
open this directory in a new power sh
terminal
magnify okay opening
terminal now
du okay we want to do that one okay
now up Arrow to run previous command
okay now let's make sure the window is
wi now do
it
how it works now actually this this part
needs to be moved here within
okay so now it seems to work now let's
be sure it's back to emac go to diet
now press G to
refresh ah didn't
work
the file still has
that you know nonbreaking space
character close white the
[ __ ] if the name match name
replace now is that a nonbreaking
space yes oh wait
okay that's why it doesn't work because
in
the because we are
replacing a character that's called
narrow no break space this character is
what Macos creates when it does a
screenshot okay so you need to do that
but also
a nonbreaking space so let me add
so this the first one is the first one
is let's put the name
here uh describe
CH so this character
is
replace narrow and breaking space okay
then we
want replace no break space let's make
sure sure the name is correct yeah no
break
space okay now predy the
code s power shop format code okay
that's why that's why we got it wrong
and then replace comma then we can just
say replace
comma okay so this actually
does several things this command we
should rename it uh
replace you know replace Bad characters
in file
name something okay but let's stick with
that
now C the close this power
window open this directory in
power
magnify
magnify this directory first
okay let's do it again list directory
yeah this directory okay just you know
[ __ ]
clear clear
screen this directory now that looks
nice
now let's see do it so now it's looks
looks
nice it says renamed
okay uh and the message should
be renamed files okay it just say should
be renamed files okay so now it's nice
now let's double check drop to the
directory
refresh what it's still here
what the
[ __ ] no break space
wait describe chart so this character
is C 160
okay
refresh C Point 160 close close now what
is
this co. 82 39 okay now go
down co.
160 oh yeah that's right so yeah so we
need to
actually you know because it's kind of
recursive so oh
God so what is this replace can you take
a regular expression so we can just like
combine
them okay so let's look at the operator
replace does it takes a regular
expression
argument there it is replace replace
string matching a rejects pattern okay
so here we are just going to do like
that and uh put this in here and uh also
add a comma so all of them is going to
be just Dash
Okay and uh place that and uh put that
there and uh don't need that don't need
that okay now actually
better start a PO shell
terminal magnify a few
times the
okay now do this now back to emac go to
directory there it is fantastic we done
our
job
fantastic do you rate power shell over
Linux bash scripting they both
suck yes they both s okay that's it for
today is sure we did this job okay let's
finish okay let me answer that question
and that will be it for today okay so we
successful fantastic okay so here's a
code uh we copy let's copy so let's rame
it
replace bad charts let's just say
replace bad charts in file
name okay
so so let's copy
that uh wait where is it yeah okay so
copy that
copy make a backup close that close
that today's talk
show pop this out okay select all paste
it this is the today's
code pop it back syntax text CL it show
the pink window show in
browser so this is a code that does a
job now we need to rename some of the
things you know we need to actually fix
a documentation so replace by charts so
change your file names by piping to it
replacing so replacing the breaking
space and uh
okay what exactly are you
replacing replacing bad
charts in file
name bad CHS include
narrow no break space no break space
comma okay usually we don't want that so
you replace these characters
okay
uh to hyphen okay replace them all by
just
hyphen okay so here's the better
documentation and we don't need this
part
anymore
put it back in
emex color coded showing browser there
it is
fantastic now let me address that
question do you think power shell is
better or bash is better or
what okay I can tell you power shell is
much better okay Power sh is much much
better okay just search for s. search
poers
shell then love you'll see why I love
pow shell so I give you my
opinions in detail why do I think power
shell is great okay so here's article so
let's put the link here so you you know
people can read
okay why I love power shell however
power shell is not the best thing it's
not the best thing since sliced bread
power shell is very complex as I learned
you know I've been kind of studying
power shell for the past two or three
years so you'll
see an article po shell complexity okay
and then an article Powers Shell versus
spash that's like that's the article you
guys want to know what which one is
better you know power sh versus fash
okay open it so you can
see here's the article power shell
complexity I tell you power shell is
fairly complex fairly comp more complex
than bash okay now bash is complex
because
idiocy because bash came from like 40
years ago you know and from this Unix
idiots they don't properly design the
syntax the way bash and The Bash came
from Sha came from Boon sha okay
the way they designed syntax their
syntax is like the way C syntax came to
be it's like it just works it works it
works now look it works that's how the
syntax bash and C is okay which you know
which spread to C++ C
and pearl python you know basically so
anyway
bash is complex because it's kind of
brainless design it came from Unix
people boom Shia boom Shia you know came
from Unix people you know so brainless
design you have complex incomprehensible
syntax
nonextensible sometimes
incorrect
cryptic you know and you know that's
that's a that's a that's a story of Unix
okay bash is like that syntax very
complex and not very powerful okay
that's
spash however power sh fixed all that so
you have one consistent system
consistent system designed from the
ground up every El every element every
aspect is that way because of thinking
because of intentional conscious design
as opposed to C syntax most of the C
stuff the syntax the semantic it it's
not from conscious design okay it just
it works it works now it works look and
and short and convenient that's the
story of c and
Unix poell is designed in 2000
200000 three around there okay from one
guy
so doesn't matter you like it or you
don't like it but at least everything in
power shell the syntax the semantics
came from conscious
intentional design okay so and it's very
consistent okay but however there's
complex complexity why because in pow
shell it's not like the bash where
everything is just text when everything
is text things are much simpler but in
Powershell it's everything it's object
and also it's based on based on the net
object so it's the entire net system
that net is very ambiguous system where
you have you know it's a it's a base
core of where you can have different
programming languages on top it on top
of it for example FSH CSH and others you
know even
closure has
a net version uh back then but anyway so
net is a very complex
managed system okay that allows you to
have programming language is on top of
it so poell is based on that it's it's
it's one of the net so inet everything
is object it's a objectoriented system
so you have object you have methods you
have string string has methods okay
every file every file every directory is
a particular type okay so let me show
you so the powers shell complexity okay
uh so compared to bash it's better
design but it's you know it's fairly
complex to really understand so let me
show
you uh so you want to know pipe commment
value types string then variable how do
you define variable Pine type
conditional data structure Loop
iteration function profile and uh where
is
it uh
uh oh value types there okay so object
type properties methods so everything in
po shell you have it's a object it has a
type and it has properties and it has
methods and it's more even more
elaborate that than that so for example
in power shell when you do a duh you
know a no branner a list of directories
file names right but actually a file a
file is a type
system.io
file info okay that's a type of a
file when it's a directory it's a
system.io do directory info okay so on
the surface you see them as just strings
but actually it's object when this
object is displayed on the on the
terminal on on a display then it goes to
object to string transformation so
there's actually two string method
applied behind the scenes okay so this
so that's why so you see so this is the
nature of powers shell you know on the
surface you you see it oh it's like bash
you know Str but it's not strings so it
get complex for
example and then a string itself is a
object okay string itself is object type
so you can get member so you can see all
the you see methods for
string so these methods for string they
came from net but actually in pow shell
they have a higher level of command and
commet and system and functions that
deal with and operators that deal with
strings and in fact we just run into one
of them you know do contains versus Dash
replace so power shell is in that in
that way is is fairly
complex
um so which I which one I
prefer po okay uh I wouldn't say it's 10
times better but it's better okay it's
more consistent it's unified you know
consistent design from the ground up and
uh it's based on objects I don't really
like object it's fairly complex
anyway so power shell is not just a
shell you know in fact I believe Powers
shell you can use it to create any
programming you know like goand like C
like cop you can actually use poers shop
to do that but you have to you know go
over some Loops but anyway so it's very
powerful and so you know among the
Articles let me show you one more
article
so
so there's article y bash Su okay you
open that go to
it po shell so here's the article
Powershell versus bash oh that's that's
just a tutorial that's actually just a
tutorial you know it shows you if you
know how to do something in bash this is
how you do it in Powershell okay then
here's article y bash Su which I give
you a concrete list of reasons why bash
truly sucks okay thank you for watching
that's it for today bye
guys so yeah so I'm tired I need to get
up and
walk
bye donate if you like my stuff and this
is like an hour this is now 90 minutes
video so if you watch it put some time
stamps in the comments help me you know
put time stamps
and uh and tell your friends to watch
the video things like that or specific
section of the video things like that so
that helps me you
know you know like the YouTube marketing
you know like please thumb up please you
know the
[ __ ] but anyway but that's you need that
some some
somewhat because otherwise your video
get buried okay thank you guys bye