hello
welcome to another episode of talk show
today is 2021
uh july uh july 6th
so we are going to do emac this coding
for maybe 30 minutes
and uh if we have time i'm going to
answer your questions
so post your comments and questions in
the comment
box in the chat box okay
so uh i'm going to just do quickly uh
we talked about this command because i
reformat lines and you are by the way
you are looking at my kinesis keyboard
okay just search for it
sorry conditions advantage you'll see my
reviews
and video reviews and ultimate hacking
keyboard
and also these fantastic mouse
okay so i'm gonna start coding emac this
we talked about in last video two about
cassatri format lines okay so let's go
to talk show
uh i'm just going to code okay so
code and show in browser this is today's
uh talk show page because i reform matte
lines we're gonna modify it open the new
window
too big
okay open a new window we're gonna
modify this uh let's go to the source
code okay
uh source code we're gonna modify this
command
and so emac this coding so describe key
that's a key go to the source code here
is a source code
and uh split the buffer go here
and search for format okay so we make a
backup here
we copy it
and uh put this in in this file okay and
we're gonna work on
here okay so we're gonna work on this uh
file this code let's see so
what is it i'm going to modify okay so
uh let's see
uh reformat modify the command so if
cursor is the beginning of
uh is at is so if cursor is
if it cursor is on the left parenthesis
or bracket
just do a bracket text okay so for
example i'm gonna
i'm gonna you know watch my video the
two days ago i i discussed
i discussed why do we need this command
and why the emax version the field
paragraph doesn't work well so you can
also go to this url
i have full detail on the source code
and also
the reason why this command exists
as opposed to when uh the emacs
building field region and the related
command
problems okay so
so that's the reason why this uh we why
we have this command but
but okay hold on a second let me paste
the link here but
but uh what is it i want to modify yeah
so for example let me show you so
so what let me show you this what this
command does okay i press a key
so it basically make everything into one
line
okay undo so you can see so let's copy
that
new buffer paste it here so you you see
uh let's go to
emac this mod okay i press a key
anywhere it becomes one single line
i press it again it becomes uh 70
characters per line
show ruler uh so something like that
toggle toggle toggle toggle okay
so so if you have a list code like that
actually this this
code will run you know this is the
significance of the syntax in
programming languages
that is the white space okay yeah yeah
should
should i continue about uh coding this
or should i digress
about the white space issue okay let me
quickly show you the white space issue
in programming languages
because it's a very interesting topic so
you just go to
saudi website and turn on javascript
in modern society we we need javascript
so people
so the corporations can snoop on you and
it's required otherwise the website
doesn't work
no javascript no candy so you go to
you go to sally.info and you go to
uh syntax soup all you wanted to know
about computer language syntaxing
tactical issues
and and somewhere here there's a issue a
discussion about white space
uh so here is the article so let's open
it
so the article is about what does it
mean
when a programming language claims white
space is insignificant
now there is a lot misunderstanding
about this issue
because most hacker types you know those
c or c
plus plus they think they know but they
don't know
uh so what does it mean actually what
does it actually mean when white space
is
insignificant okay so anyway so my point
here is that
in the lisp syntax in except a few
exceptions okay
in mathematica it works well but anyway
in lisp
the white space is basically
insignificant
except comment okay this is
uh this comment okay this is a comment
in lisp okay so two exceptions
white space is not significant
in lisp except
the common syntax such as this one
because it relies on the end you know it
relies on the line the end of line so
that's our problem
uh and uh and
except the comment yeah basically that's
uh
yes mostly basically that's it okay so
in general the list language syntax is
fantastic because
because you can just compact it this
will work you know in fact sometimes i
prefer this but
anyway the long story okay this is
actually unreadable but it can
be readable if this adopt
um certain synthetic issues
i explained in detail that is about
mathematica
meta expression okay watch my video
about a month or two two months ago
on mathematical syntax versus
language syntax versus this lips syntax
the this syntax about the
syntactical um equivalence okay in any
way so that's a
meta syntax anyway so white space
so when a programming language where the
white space is
actually truly insignificant first of
all you have to define what does it mean
so you read this article i'll give you
detail what exactly
uh does white space mean and what does
it mean
exactly when you say white space is
insignificant in general white space is
basically tab space and all that okay
depending on the language different
languages define them differently so
so in some languages such as javascript
so let's look at javascript white space
blah blah blah this is not my website i
want to go to xaudi website
[ __ ] okay so just type my name is uh
so you get the so there it is white
space characters so for example in
javascript they consider several unicode
also as a white space
so this matters because when if you have
a command that trim
string you know remove the white space
at the beginning or end of the charact
of a string this matters you know
which which character is actually
removed so
in perl in you know in different
languages they have different ideas of
what
constitute a white space so first of all
you define
what is the what what set of characters
is a white space
then you define what does it mean when
white space is insignificant for example
if you add
a white space to a programming language
does it change the meaning of the
language
uh in general it doesn't in lisp okay
except
like i mentioned before except when in
common for example
so for example this code still run but
if i add a comment and i remove the
white space
it [ __ ] it [ __ ] it up okay so this in
general this is uh
you want a programming language syntax
to be white space
insignificant in a specific meaning okay
me
so what does it mean for example can you
add or remove a white space
or can you add or remove remove a
sequence of white space
so basically the one of the good
definition of
white space insignificance uh in my
context
is that first of all you define a set of
characters
uh that's why space okay then you
you you define white space is
insignificant to mean that whenever you
have one or more
white spaces you know or in other words
a sequence of white spaces then it does
not matter
what sequence it is okay but however
you can never remove or
a white space sequence for example okay
for example
for you for example okay let me show you
okay between the py and p2 there's a
white space
sequence okay uh white space sequence
now i can add
a white space you know uh a line returns
the white space
so does it change the meaning or no it
doesn't
well actually i didn't add a white space
because i'm i'm just uh
you know because i we you know again we
have a sequence of white space
and we just add a white space still it's
one sequence of white space
so we did not add or remove a white
space sequence
but on the other hand if we do actually
remove
a right white white space sequence like
that
then the the the semantics of the code
changes
so if basically [ __ ] up the code
so that's so that's what i mean
you know what what you know so depending
on the language what does it mean what
space is uh insignificant or significant
and in particular i you know
we can define a meaning of white space
to to mean uh insignificance to me that
doesn't matter what kind of white space
sequence they are or
interchangeable so what if you define
that then
it satisfies this
this good property we i want okay which
is
uh which is then then for example let's
remove the comma
which means then this code this code or
uh or you know uh anyways or
all this way uh all works the same
and so then okay so that's one thing
then
there's another question then you might
want to ask
why does anyone want to do this you know
why do you need to do it you need to do
it
there are quite a lot of reasons okay um
not quite a lot of reasons well one of
the reason is um so what what is
good about this you know one long line
when do you want it why is it good what
do you want the language to have this
property
where the white space sequence doesn't
can be interchangeable well the reason
is that
by the way also except string okay that
is
in general because uh that's another
interesting topic about computer
language syntax
that is whether you should have a syntax
that allows
literal things
which in general screw up your language
such as a string
because inside the string then you can
have for example
for example we have a string right then
inside the string you can have
basically you can have your entire
language in the string
more or less when you escape the quotes
but
anyway that's another topic that's a
complex topic about language design
whether you allow the string syntax
and if you do not allow the string
syntax what
possibly can you do if you want a
literal kind of a
string so that is in another article
here
design a string syntax okay here
so let's open that let's open that so we
talked about this
then we have this article computer
language design
string syntax so this is venturing into
the exploration
of the question about
you know uh different string syntax and
that's that's another
very interesting topic because then you
have here dot you have different type of
quotes for example python uses three
quotes
to to to let you have kind of literal
string
then then there's a question whether you
have interpret interp
in inter um interpolation that's what
pearl
causing interpolation or meaning
or in other languages you know whether
variables or
expressions can be evaluated inside the
string so
that's what this article is about okay
i mean that i mean more than that
there's many many many interesting
things about
uh string syntax in computer language
design for example then you
for example when you have regular
expression you are familiar with
uh toothpick syndrome especially bad in
immaculate
and in this in general this all
essentially all languages all these
languages have this
severe toothpick syndrome when they have
a regular expression
because lisp got a problem okay
so many interesting aspect about
the string syntax design programming
languages
but however most languages anyway so
then you know the escape is a big issue
the big issue then
then for example in html you have
entities which becomes
very complex because when you have
entities or escape code you know
such as backslash then you have the
problem
of determining whether a given piece of
string
is it already encoded or is it not
encoded
because when for example you want to
decode some string
but you cannot tell whether it's already
encoded or d
or is in the state of already been
encoded or it's uh decoded
you know so you have the double you know
triple or
quadruple backslash problem you cannot
tell basically
so you know if you code uh bash you know
for example if you code emacs you need
to
call bash you know a shower command you
need to pass to shell
usually you'll run into this problem
file path
file path or url path or on windows then
they use forward slash it becomes more
complex
for example a practical example if you
want to
use a regular expression to search your
python code
to search for a particular regular
expression your python code
so you want to you know you want to
search it you want to use the regular
expression to search a
regular expression in your python source
code you can
essentially you cannot do in any
language because
because the backslash escape you know
the so-called escape or entity so
that's you know they become impossible
to
decrypt to decode okay so that's a many
interesting issues about white space
syntax design in programming languages
i mean the about the string string
syntax
then of course you have um
uh you know then then
okay so one of the way you know one of
the solutions
is to do not allow a string syntax
embedded in a programming language
you know at all so you know i explore
some of that question
that uh those questions that's this
article okay
so white space is one thing significance
of white space and string syntax is
another very interesting thing
and they are related because when you
have a string then obviously you can
have white spaces in a string right but
then
there's a question you know
let me put it this way once you have a
string
like a double quote string then it [ __ ]
up the white space in significance
because obviously in a string
you cannot just arbitrarily replace any
white space
by another white space you know that's a
that's an issue
and by the way all these talk the best
language that has this
uh white space in significance is wufam
language okay i showed that many times
in my video so watch that
so anyway so this is the digression
about white space let's go to
excel talk show let's uh so today's talk
show
so we we mean to code emac this but we
digressed
okay digression digression digestion
okay javascript why space characters
okay
wait uh wait so we talked about uh
computer language syntax design
computer language syntax design and
when does uh what does white space
insignificance mean
okay so those are the things we talked
about as a log
okay now i guess i already talked
uh random for uh 20 minutes
hey code bamboo so i talked
so let's i guess let's now go uh start
to code
okay let's start to code this um
yeah i guess uh let's see okay
so um eight people watching
okay say hi and the questions okay
so uh okay we already started to
uh talk about
you know uh syntax related issues
and now it uh let's go to uh isha so
is it here okay so
okay so let's i guess we start to code
okay
should you die let me think about it
okay um
we're gonna code this so the first thing
i want to change
is that let's go to talk show the first
thing i want to change
is that so there are two things okay
there are two things uh i want to change
okay
so basically i want to do this one first
okay so show in browser
magnify magnify so if cursor is on a
parenthesis on left parenthesis or
bracket then just um
you know like this okay so for example
if i
call the command it becomes like that
like that doesn't work
in e max because because of the comment
okay because this
this part so or if in a string
uh same thing similar happens uh okay so
anyway
so so what i want is sometimes i want to
for example sometimes i for example this
line okay
i want to make it one line so if i just
call the command it doesn't you know it
does the whole thing i want to i need to
select it
then do it okay so now this
is fantastic okay
let me explain why this is fun you know
yeah we forgot to explain why do you
want
this feature what why do you want to win
like when like
people are normal average industrial
coders those cc plus
plus even ascot people or these people
they don't know
they are brainless so i mean the
question is why
when do you want for example when do you
want a code like that
there are um there are some advantages
okay there are great advantages
to have code like in sync where the
white space
significance is not significant
by the way you will hear this in java in
perl
in many languages many many languages
except
python okay you'll hear this in c
c plus first java uh or
or or javascript or lisp
sometimes they'll say in their you know
in their uh
introduction to the language they'll say
oh our language is white space
insignificant
that's they don't know what they're
talking about because they haven't d
you know they are not you cannot do what
i'm doing here
in those languages yeah almost all of
them first of all first of all if they
have this
line based comment you cannot do that
okay so anyway back to the question so
why do you want
uh why do you want you know source code
looks like that
there are quite a few advantages you
know most industrial programmers they
have no idea they haven't thought of
they've never
seen uh i can show you um
you know mathematica is the best example
okay but i i'm not prepared to
do mathematica i can show you some
articles but let's forget about that
so anyway let me just explain okay so
why why
um so so when you have this
white space in significance
insignificance aside defined
then you can okay here's a gist
you can essentially have a automated
way of code formatting to any style you
like for example to this style or to
this style
or two for example some people prefer
you know
code formatting is a big talk you know
every every you know
it's a bike shade bike shade what color
should
should how should your car be you know
it's the one of those things every
programmer has
the idiotic opinion
okay let me let me not let me get to the
gist of things
so so so so so yeah
formatting okay so so one of the great
property about white space
insignificance as i defined in my
article
is that you know as i explained before
is that
when you actually have a well-defined
white space insignificance in your
language that means your language can
have
automated formatting okay for example
this line
okay i press a button i cannot do it now
because i cannot do this in images
because in general
has this uh comment you can it's not
white space insignificant
but in in wolfram language for example
i can press the button and it becomes
like that
like that okay and i can adjust in my
editor whatever
preferences i want in any format so when
you have this
automated formatting that eliminates
the entire babbling about
code formatting style guide like every
language online you
you'll see that on ruby by this by by
anyway ruby javascript python
not python okay python is white space
significant
by design okay so you can so
python does not um is not relevant here
anyway well i'm saying that
code formatting even in python they will
you know you'll see your article or
frequent ads
frequently asked questions for example
google
google javascript style guide
let's say javascript style guide let's
not type google
google has one okay so google has one
then
uh then the stupid uh idiotic w3 schools
then you know then you have you know you
have view
js style guide then you have um airbnb
style guide
you have quite redux cell guide you know
uh
those are big popular ones then then you
have the javascript standard
there's one you know the millennial
generation idiots
here javascript standard style go [ __ ]
yourself you call
yourself a standard you know this
[ __ ] this this young guy okay i know
who
i mean i kind of uh
i don't know the guy but i i know who
you know i looked into you know
so style guide you know if you're a
programmer you know there's a huge
amount of style guide and arguments in
almost in just about every every
language that's a waste of time
what you should really have is automated
style
automate automation okay
and today after 30 years today you
gradually start to have that for example
go land okay go
land okay so let me show you a go
go you know so here's my goal line code
for example
you start you begin to have these for
example okay so for example
golan okay we are not going to i don't
think we are going to end up doing email
this
coding because i started to talk about
this it's gonna be
uh i don't have time now uh so for
example go
land okay i can i can make this into one
line
okay now but this golan actually support
automated
i mean they they do have a tool go
format that auto
automatically reformat your code entire
source code
not just one line you know that's what
typically programmers do
you know line by line oh i i want this
you know i i want this space
three space oh i prefer five space i
prefer
five space plus a tab you know idiocy
the
especially the e-max ring people they
you know they
they dribble about this all the time but
you should have you automated you know
i just you just write whatever you want
then when i'm ready
uh kogo format okay so i have a nice
system set up you see this key
delete uh c is the go format and delete
key is right here okay
so on my kinesis keyboard right on the
thumb so so watch this okay
ddc it will reformat the entire line
okay so it it [ __ ] up here uh it
didn't work there because like i said
the problem is go golan is not a white
space
insignificant language it's not exactly
it's not
100 that's why i have to that's why i
talked about why you need to define it
um you you need to have it well defined
like defined by a by uh mathematically
or by your
algorithm but anyway let me demonstrate
the go format okay so for example let's
say i have that
okay so now i press ddc easy
it reformat for me uh let's say i have
that okay
that's not that okay ddc you see
you can um and in fact i can
if i do add a semicolon
now you probably don't know land i mean
you you may know but i take some time to
explain about the row of semicolon in
gold line for example i
added some semicolon here and here then
i compact the line you cannot do
you know you have to skip the comment
because common is the problem commons
common is always so anyway i made some
lines into one single line now let me
try the
go format again okay do it
ah okay so if i found return so actually
i need
where do i need um
yeah okay so i need actually i need to
add more
uh i believe here
let's just do this okay what
expected that fund return what okay
so okay kogo format okay
that works okay you see let me let me
let's uh let's uh let's do this again
let me explain okay
so you see i have a code like that and
there is a semicolon here
that's required well actually not
depends
you know that's a problem it becomes
complex because
golan is not a
white space insignificant
white space sequence it's not a white
space in
insignificant uh programming language
although if you ask gold and you ask you
know ask yourself ask most programmers
they will say oh golden is actually
white space instead
insignificant you're idiot ass
okay go white space is significant in
golan however they have
complexities to to to to try to
remedy the problem so that so that for
example the semicolon
is not required most of the time
when you if when you have a new line
then it's not required
it's complex okay so so let me show you
okay so for example this line
so let me let me remove let's remove the
that okay
so this line nope no semicolon okay
let's make a backup okay no semi-colon
right
now okay remove that one right
this is valid code no semicolon okay now
but i
make it into one line and now i try to
run go format go for a man says hiccup
you know
it choked it says expected uh
semicolon but found return it choked
okay
but now if i add a semicolon here
and here and and here
okay now i make it one single line you
can see or see the semicolon
you see you you can see you can still
see the semicolon
now i make one single line but now i do
go format
do it it worked you see it worked it and
it also removed the semicolon you see
so um so what i'm saying so so back to
my previous what i was saying that
beginning about
like five ten years ago the industrial
programmers begin to understand
the power of automated um
automated formatting tool so golan
you have go format okay fantastic in
javascript you also have uh
you also have you know deno
javascript.js
okay you also have that okay you begin
beginning of
starting with go line go line is the
first one go format the
first one to have that eliminate the
idiotic talk about
formatting style guide guide their
[ __ ] ass
most programmers they they did with
each and every line and and in e-max you
have you know complexities like
normally when you press return it calls
it calls
you know just insert a new line but in
some mods it will also insert then
indent you know dealing on each line
this program idiots the industrial
programmer idiots
you want autumn automated formatting
okay
so so i was saying beginning in the past
10 years starting with golan
we start to have that and also you have
javascript i can demo but you'll take
some time javascript
deno.js okay one of my video i talked
about that denote.js
just search for it okay denote.js
actually i can
uh okay uh deno js okay it's it's just
called deno okay
yeah i don't want completion okay so
they know
uh the marketing talk is securing time
for javascript anyway i
don't know it's a great thing i
recommend highly recommend deno
instead of the not js crap or the mpm
[ __ ] the npm leader is a [ __ ] face
so denno is by by the ryan something guy
that he's a great guy and
very uh a great programmer and a good
person okay denno he's this is his new
project okay dinner
and so denno has automatic formatting i
you know i can demonstrate but um
okay let's let me just to demonstrate
since i'm talking about these so
let's go to some uh some some code okay
so i do have a code
let's see unicode
uh unicode search okay unicode
emulticons okay
so search for uh let's let's um
let's actually go to unicode index okay
so here is a page
let's say interactive dynamic
unicode search okay so i type water uh
i type try so all these unicode contains
word try
the name their names okay so interactive
search
let's try gram okay
so so how is that done that's of course
javascript so search for
javascript uh there it is so you can see
here is my code and it also supports um
you know here's the code so let's go to
javascript so search
open it so now we have a big javascript
code
okay uh this is actually typescript
which is a superset of javascript but
let me try this okay
so i don't want to [ __ ] up that code so
let's
create a new page dot ts
so here's a code you know uh
33 000 lines that's because mostly
because
of the javascript i mean the unicode
data that's 33 000 lines okay
anyway what i'm trying to uh tell you is
about for example here is a code
you know i make it into one line
then i call the deno format okay what's
the command let's see
uh there it is okay
so ddc excel type script compile uh
wait ddg javascript format code
if you go to the source code
uh you will see that it is calling
the demo format here you see the damn
you know it's calling the show demo
part of the demo come with demo so so
let me demo
demonstrate that okay so i made it into
one line
then i'm going to call uh ddg
there it is you see it
it actually so it reformat the entire
source code
you see let me undo okay now watch the
window let's undo
okay so undo
you see so we actually need
um let's add a marker okay so xxx so we
are no we know where we are so
so not right now the code looks like
that now pay attention
let's say to the this this block okay
i'm gonna call deno and we will actually
reformat the entire thing okay deno
format
so watch it okay okay do it
uh wait did it uh wait undo
what uh
what let's let's make this
let's try it again oh wait uh
what oh i i called compile and say okay
let's
watch you again okay so watch this this
this
this uh these few lines okay
dd g reformat you know there it is
okay now let's scroll up now remember
our mark
our mark xx here so you see one two
three so it
it looks different now that's narrow to
region okay
uh uh what what's the command to narrow
to region
let's try again okay so so watch this
delete okay let's now to region now
okay okay so we focus on this
so ddg reformat the entire buffer so it
looks like that
and also okay you expanded the region
anyway you so i guess
i hope you see the change you see it
reformatted the entire source code
you know 4 000 you know almost 3
30 000 30 000 lines
although most of it in the beginning is
just like that
so so that back to my point i was saying
beginning about 10 years ago
the industrial coders begin to have the
concept
have to to catch up the to realize the
idea
where automated formatting tool is
great thing okay before that the c c
plus plus
idea they don't they don't understand
you like i talk i argue with them they
don't understand it they say oh you are
a troll you know
so beginning with go from go land go
format and
even to this day you know when you when
you have you know we
you know when you tell the coders they
say oh each line must be 80 characters
you you are doing that you know the
idiots
this this is a hum that's why i say this
is harmful unix and c
c began this kind of tradition 80 70
characters per line
okay so beginning 10 years ago you know
industrial coders begin to realize the
importance the you know critical the
advantage of the formatting tool now
however back to my again previous
point is that this formatting tool is
great but however
it's it would be even better it will be
much more better
much more powerful if the programming
language languages
syntax support it
that is that is we go back to the
significance of the of the white space
significance you know you need a
well-defined meaning of white
white space significance okay so
that is why i'm saying that you know
this this is
uh significant and there's a lot
misunderstanding you know
for you know gold land is gold golan for
example
is not white space insignificant
so so even though it has the great
powerful go format
tool okay so even it has a go format
tool it's great but it doesn't
work all the time because you because
then you have the complexities of the
comma
i mean the semi-colon okay
okay so and again let me repeat so for
lisp
it's good most of the time except the
comment
you know if we just if we can just
eliminate
you know which what so instead of the
comment
syntax what should it be it should be
like that okay let me show you okay uh
it should be like this okay something
like this
for example common okay
this should be the least common
syntax but but today's this was they
don't you know since 1990s
they don't they don't they they don't
understand they don't understand this
idea
you tell them they say you are a troll
they're [ __ ] idiots
and they say you know even to this day
you know uh people where for example you
look at this one okay so people say this
is this
casa you are a troll you are [ __ ] an
idiot you you should not have these
lines like that you should not show
other people
don't do you know don't don't read
kazaa's tutorial because he's not
following convention blah blah blah
because they are idiots
you know when they see these they they
say these people they say you should be
this way
this is the you know commission idiots
and
this touch on another point that is a
semantic
unit so this all these problems came
from unix and c okay
so why why you want a single line
because
code you know we are looking at the
source code source code should be
category should be organized according
to semantic
units okay not syntactical unit
the [ __ ] you know these industrial
programming idiots okay
so this is not a semantic unit
okay this is more of a semantic unit
okay and similar for for for other
construct
but in general this this because of the
nested parenthesis syntax
in general it's one you know it's uh
the syntax in general
in lisp this syntax in general
uh corresponds to semantic units
that is there that is you can tell by
syntax alone
the semantic unit of the program you you
see
what i'm talking about this can do that
but this property
is not true for uh c based syntax for
example in
in go no you know
you know sometimes it's line you know
for example this one line is
kind of a semantic unit but not really
you know
you know you know in this basically
every
parenthesis is one semantic unit but
it's very problematic for uh c based
syntax
uh goldland or javascript
okay so i rambled for full hour about
the meaning about the syntax design in
programming languages
in symantec unit uh and uh
okay so we got several comments and uh
i'm not going to code in code this now
because we
we i already talked for 50 minutes uh 40
minutes something like that
about the issues you know the syntax
syntax issues
you know why why am i so like passionate
or fervent about this topic because
these
syntactical issues or programming
languages you could say
is my lifelong it's my lifelong study
you know for 20 for like yeah about 20
20 years
you know uh and uh
you know it's one of the most uh thing i
study um anyway so that's about that
so let me read the comment and maybe
that's it for today okay so we
um yeah so let's see hello bot
uh yeah today's
uh live stream is impromptu
i just decided you know 10 10 minutes in
advance
because i thought nobody's gonna watch
but i have
tons of things i need to code you know
so i thought you know why don't i code
and you know just do a live stream
so i was planning to you know nobody's
here i'm pretty sure you know one one
two
per person i'm just gonna you know do my
own coding you know to to to
modify the this uh code
and decided to do a live stream
impromptu but then
i started to explain why i started to
explain why do i need this command
then one thing leads to another
explaining the whole thing
about the significance of white space
you know what what does it mean and also
the you know the string syntax one thing
leads to another string
syntax in programming languages and
different languages their meaning of
white space characters
and uh um anything
and and you know the the in the
giant rant okay so that's it for today
okay so i didn't i'm not going to code
this anymore now i
i guess i mean not in this live stream
so
uh what else uh
so i have finally decided to buy
advantage
2 keyboard fantastic okay
so if you like my stuff again you know
sponsor me right sponsor me paypal me
paypal oh yeah there is a convenient
link a patreon
amazon gift card fantastic
it's from you guys amazon gift card
thank you guys
that i i that i recently bought
100 of uh of
you know of this mouse and this pen
so um yeah so thank you guys for that
you know sponsor me and you know buy
keyboard uh you know for my website
the kinesis
this this thing fantastic okay
okay let's see what you know so
something you know i've been working on
a lot in the past a month or two on
emacs you know on my emac
my emac website you know sadly
uh i worked a lot on them one month or
two in the past a month or two
a lot of stuff so for you emacs fans
and uh you know uh and and i worked a
ton
on in the past week or two several weeks
on the keyboards lots of interesting
things
for example this is from a video game a
russian
keyboard th this
keyboard actually simulates you know
it's a it's a game called
breath age breath age
breath edge uh you know a survival game
in space in outer space
so this is like a keyboard used in space
shuttles you know things like that space
station
in other space then you know there's
something similar for example let me
show you
so i uh so there are
several there are several fictional
keyboards for example here's one
uh in anime but i'm not sure this might
actually be a real keyboard
i don't know i don't know for sure but
you know because
um because from a friend who told me
the city hunter anime they usually have
very realistic
you know tanks and you know airplanes
helicopters
so this might actually be a real uh
keyboard
so they these are you know then then
there is the
uh keyboard from the alien
you know so you know the
movie alien 1979 classic
and of course this is the most popular
uh
ghost in the shell by the way this is a
new you know anime ghost in the shell
there's an old version like 20 years ago
similar but
they redid it
and here is some pretty pictures about
ghosts in the shower
uh so that's about it for today
by the way i haven't watched this one
uh i hear that it's not so good ghost
initial there it is
japanese uh naked girls of course
we love it uh so
ghost in the xiao japanese
and by the way they have a sex scene
of ghost in the shell from 1990s but
it's censored in american version
so anyway so because you know
um speaking of ghosts in the shell there
is something interesting
uh in ghost in the shell there is this
robotic ai uh bot
kind of a comical character so here's a
japanese steward yourself headaches
keyboard
uh ghost in a shower is from japan of
course then in ghost
in the shell there's this uh bot a.i bot
so it's called tacky coma okay you can
go to wikipedia this is
about alcohol on that so but so i was
wondering you know what kind of
part is this looking at that it looks
like city
you know it looks like a toilet so it
turns out it's kind of a
you know comical character in in the in
a ghost in a shine
animation but anyway so there's you know
there's this
model you can buy japanese are crazy
about it
so let's see what else common hi
everyone hi
art mob style must go svg xml to css i
guess
style must go style must be
svg xml to css what do you mean
so what uh so mario says just have
a really really nice automating
formatting tool fmt okay yeah
so yeah but you know like i said
beginning in
10 years ago the industry programmers
begin to have that but i need to show
you mathematica okay so actually
wufang language you'll be like what a
magnitude beyond
you know like 10 years ago the industry
of programmers
you know the cc plus plus or javascript
they begin to understand they begin to
have that
but matt wufang language okay wufang
language they have that
uh they have that like starting in 1997
and it's not just you know it's not just
automate
automatic formatting of the source code
by
changing the you know the new line space
it's not just that
it's it does that as you type you know
just
just like buffer as you
uh let me type something long okay as
you type
something long and once
upon let's copy that okay copy that so
uh time you can see you know what i'm
trying to get it is that
you can see that it is automatic you see
it there's automatic a wrap you know it
that happens in word processors
since 1990 1990 you know 1990
okay you want that automated oh
you know automatic but the stupid the
c programmers the hacker types they say
oh you cannot do that
you need to you know the [ __ ] then
then you have the code formatting style
guide [ __ ] idiots [ __ ]
[ __ ] damage this is the damage
directly this is damage directly
inherited from unix
and c okay for 20 years now
so we begin to fix that begin you know
with the new generation of coders skolan
deno and and rust and i hear from
you know the sea the you know the the
that compiler what's what's the name the
popular
compiler they they start to have that
only in the five in the past five or ten
years ago
okay you have to wait for the previous
generation to die that's how things
change
because habit habit is the most habit
is the pain of progress habit
okay so formatting code formatting okay
so yeah you begin to have that
in lots of programming languages uh
what's the difference between
tactile and morph uh more forum okay
uh well that tower nemo forum they
basically
they are different keyboards okay what's
the difference between tactile and more
forum okay let me let me let me
let me show you okay okay i gotta go
so let me explain that then that'll be
done so tactile
tactile and more and more manual form
there are two different designs by two
different people
okay so you have tactile which is
kind of copying the kinesis okay kinesis
is the granddaddy
kinesis beginning in 19 okay let me show
you some history canes is beginning 1990
i think 1992 or something like that
okay kinesis beginning 19 big uh i
i i might have some histories here on my
page
somewhere i don't remember for sure but
it began night i believe i think it's
1991 or 1990
1989 or something okay and kinesis
is copied from motron
keyboard this is the earliest okay this
is
uh from what year 1977
okay but i believe
i've read someone says anyway
i believe this is the first the first
curved
ergonomic you know curved surface
ergonomic keyboard
motron keyboard okay on the web
on the hacker you know one of the hacker
keyboard side what's the name you know
what what's a what's the name i
sometimes i forgot
geek hack okay gig hack website i
i remember this article saying that ibm
was actually the first one but i don't
think so because
uh anyway that's you can go look
for the history okay so motron is the
first okay
let's let's write down what we talked
about okay i i gotta go so
uh so that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
donate okay donate don't forget that's
that's
that's that's why i exist that's what i
am doing
uh that's why i'm doing my stuff
okay that's my alarm turn it off so
more tron is first then kinesis then
then let me show you then
uh then
so motron 19 1977
then kinesis around 1990
1989 something like that then
then ergodox okay
basically these are the major basically
the major lineage of the
evolution of the i mean the these are
the major ones so organics
organics 2000 um
what they 2013 yeah 2013
began oh docs which is a copy of kinesis
but flat okay then then
the next i guess the major one is
tactile tactile uh
2016 you know
uh this guy this this guy is also a
great guy
i actually met him face to face
he's also a mathematica
he's a wufam language expert
okay he is actually a
expert of wolfram language one one of
the great expert
of wufang language he happened to be
but he's you know i i i should mention
also
since i've you know since me being me
he's also very
social justice uh kind of person so
you know political opinions which is
very different from
me so we have kind of frictions anyway i
i met him you know so he's a great guy
he designed
so he could create a doctor okay so he
created doctor so let's turn on
javascript
uh wait why is it not available
uh okay so you have to watch it on
youtube
uh so anyway doctor okay so then
so so that tile is uh 19 i mean 2016.
then someone has created a manual form
okay
not tactile manual form doctor manual
form is a
tactile and manual from a hybrid okay
but there's a manual form i don't i
don't have it on my website but
you we can just uh maybe maybe we can
find it
so manual form is not very popular so
right now if you search it
all you see is dactyl manual form but
manual form
is kind of a weird uh one created by
by someone just manual form okay
so maybe this
no oh wait are we
hey i don't think it's this one okay
but are they what are they talking about
and they i think they are talking about
something else menu from keyboard okay
let's
search for
this day so you see stackdown manual
form okay they're here
manual form keyboard okay now do they
have a picture
uh they don't have these people you know
you
always put a picture you know these
people you know the idiots these
hacker types you know what you doing you
create a website talking about
keyboard no picture what the [ __ ] you
doing
you know this notes type you know they
don't know
you want it to be popular put the
picture you know you need it it's
necessary because you're talking about
keyboard you know
anyways you can find i'm pretty sure you
can find
a picture somewhere okay so that so they
so there's a manual form you can find
what it what you then then
someone combined you know combine
combine the tactile and manual form and
created the doctor
manufacture so that that's basically
that's a story
uh why did my browser change keeps
changing color
i have a big story to tell okay that
because
basically because windows ui is so
idiotic because there's no way
because it's it's hard to it's
impossible to see
which window is actually in front you
know
you know so i have to so i change color
so now so i just have different color
for each
different application because otherwise
because if this is also blue
sometimes it's hard to tell if this is
one window or is it
different app inside you know stupid
windows that's what it
is the the [ __ ] in windows
[ __ ] and in you know and they are
talking about you know they have pretty
boys on stage
telling you oh we designed the metro how
great it is the most idiotic
[ __ ] however apple computer apple you
can
you can general trust you know when
apple doing some design things although
they are kind of
very pretentious and elite but however
apple they do actually know when they
design
you know whatever interface they they do
a good job
the window is just idiotic
okay so let's not talk about that too
much okay so
just you know so anyway so you know
because he you know we
you know like so what i'm saying is that
you know we
society you know the world has seven
billions of people
and uh there are many different type of
opinions typically the white people you
know they
avoid talking about it so they keep
things nice they don't talk about poem
you know even though they probably watch
it every day they don't talk about it
you know they they need nice polite you
know
talk only politely don't talk anything
that's you know
they do that but it's not good
if you kind of keep doing that
censorship you know
society gets worse and worse
but on the other hand but anyway but
what i'm saying is that is that you know
there are different people different
opinions from different uh
countries so sometimes um
for example i i was born in taiwan but
i don't actually like the taiwan
politics it becomes
you know so bad but that creates a
friction
because i know for for a fact that many
people in taiwan who would actually
follow
me and recommend me but but they have
seen you know
sometimes you know i have a bad mouth
about taiwan stuff a little bit
they see my political opinions then then
then they distance themselves from me
that's the issue same thing this happens
to you every one of you i'm pretty sure
even if you don't talk about politics
you know sometimes it'll come out
so people begin to distance from each
other
because you believe me in red i believe
in blue or something
you know oh you know that's no good okay
that's not good so yeah we do have
differences but you know
you usually you can try to talk it out
you know you know
instead of becoming you know separatist
you know
becoming very you know like usa is today
though
because of the twitter scumbags twitter
and google
their boss in apple you know these
scumbags they created
the divide as a side effect because they
want to make more
money so they created that situation
uh okay that's it bye guys