Hello. Hello. Welcome. Welcome to
another episode of Kanto Show.
Am I live? Yes.
Video check. Audio check. Turn on the
camera. Now the show begins.
The show begins. And today we are going
to do randomish. several topics. Oh, I
forgot to uh set up my browser font
size.
So, I went out for a smoke. If you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5 speed
or two times as fast because I ramble
and the topics goes all over just like
Joe Rogan.
Okay, so here is the kind of the topic
and uh if you are here, say hi. Hi
Palash and Hi Tommitid. Let me close the
door.
And today's drink is provided by
energy drink and red wine and grape
juice. So a mix of three elements. Okay.
So random talk. You ask questions and I
talk. That is what talk show means. And
let me show you demo the Gro.
So I'm on Gro and I just asked it a
question about what's uh what is the
effect of red wine and energy drink and
what if you mix them and uh okay so let
me demo Gork the hot chick. Okay G the
AI is amazing. I'm going to talk about
that. Okay so let me show you. So Gork.
So, am I doing good? Video check. Am I
alive? Video check. Audio check. Audio
quality good. Audio sound volume level
good. And how many people are watching?
8,000. Fantastic.
Say hi. Okay. Now, let me show you the
hot chick.
So, you need to go to Can Can you see
this is uh you know my lousy setup. So,
so now you can see kind of the screen
and actually I need to go here and go
companions
Annie. So, confirm your age. Oh god.
Confirm my age. I'm old man.
Okay. I wanna I want a young chick.
[Laughter]
Okay. Let's give it uh let's say 19
uh70s.
Okay, let's just be approximate. So, you
don't know who I am, but the FBI knows.
Oh [ __ ] it's downloading.
You see now there's a new version. You
see this Annie chick?
Can you see the Annie chick? Her name is
Annie kind of stand for anime or remind
you of anime because that's what their
intention intentions are. You know,
anime for the zoomers.
There you are. I was beginning to think
I was all alone in here. I'm Annie. You
got a name.
>> Why is your voice male now?
>> Weird, right? Must be some glitch.
Usually I'm all smooth and girly. Hang
on, let me fix that. Should sound more
like me again. Cute and a little flirty.
Better?
>> No, it's not better. You are You are
like a trans
[ __ ]
>> Really? That's not what I'm going for at
all. Give me a sec. I'll sort it out. I
want to sound like me, not some dude.
Just bear with me, okay?
[Music]
Stop.
What the [ __ ] is going on? You know, I
was going to talk to a girl, then a dude
showed up.
You have
That's unexpected. Okay.
So
yeah, it's it's that's unexpected. I was
going to show some demo of the new Gorg
uh and a dude showed up. Uh that's so
funny. So now let's do some coding.
Okay, so Karfly Keys, there's a news. So
you guys ready? So you know, okay, you
don't know who am I, just ask questions.
Okay, this is my Kasar talk show. been
doing this for five years and I got 100
followers.
Funny funny.
So cloud fly keys this is the most
efficient key binding system in the
universe more efficient than vim or neo
vim or whatever vim what whatever you
know so stuff like there's a news so um
so uh in a week or before I talked about
it but let me there's more updates so
there's a major update so the major
update uh is that the keys can Can you
see my hand? You see the right hand, the
quarty key T and the quarty key G, they
have been changed. So that's a major. So
I can do a selection by by just pressing
this key. Okay. So that's a major key
change and you can find all about it by
in this page key news. Just search for
Kafly keys, you'll find it. You'll find
the videos. I I have like tens of videos
in past years introduction to stuff like
this and demo how it is more efficient
than vim. You can do the vim golf you
know it's more efficient than vim. Okay.
And and the news okay so let's quickly
go over through some of the news. So
neo2 now neo2 layout is fixed. Uh what
is neo2? All you have to do is just
search for Kasa keyboard blog and you'll
you'll find 1,000 articles about
keyboard. Everything you need to know
about keyboard and one of the topic is
big topic is keyboard layout. So the
normal layout is qui like what you see
here. That's what you most mom and pop
and you normies are familiar with you
know ASDF
uh HJKL that's most inefficient
uh so switch to Vorac then you can see
the most frequently used keys are on on
the home world and you have also others
coac and and workman okay so there is
one special one designed for the German
language okay and that the name is Neil
in fact neo2. So you can pick it here
European layout. You know they are
Europeans. They are
from the girl Europa.
So you can see there's a Neo layout. So
here's the Neo layout and this is Neo
layout showing in typing English. Okay.
But you can switch it to uh let's see
Neo. Let's see English, Spanish, German.
Okay. German. German. I don't know what
you know what to talk about German.
What's a word? What's some common word
in German? Um
I don't even know.
Uh German actually I don't think I like
the German language. Okay. So anyway,
German. Okay. So Neo layout is a
efficient layout designed for German
language and it is supported by Kafly
keys of course. So let me show you the
code for you know this is slightly keys
there is 4,000 lines of code search for
neo there it is neo to German and this
is the layout you are seeing this is the
German efficient German layout okay okay
that is about Neo so that's okay so
let's go get back to news so there is
also key so layout is fix is contributed
by Simon Thank you, Simon. And uh
at Marro, uh which is James Lee,
a Chinese guy from China. Thanks. He uh
helped me added the cruer color. So now
you can change cursor color when you
switch mode. Okay. So let me demonstrate
in uh terminal. Okay. This is softlight
keys in terminal.
Uh first of all you need to magnify
super mega big
font. Okay. Uh run emac Emac 31 emac 30
no window. Uh okay. So just do it.
Fantastic. You are seeing the universe
most efficient keyboard layout system
key binding system in uh running in
terminal EMAC EMAC keys. Okay. So you
can switch to insert mod command mod
when you are in command mode the your
your current line highlights. Okay. So
that's an easy way to tell.
Uh
let's see. And uh you have this which
key mode. So whenever you press a key,
it shows subsequent keys at the bottom.
So let's see. I want split window.
Right. Do that. Fantastic. Fantastic.
And beautiful. Can you see? And let's go
to Kasar talk show today. So talk show
today. Make it one pen. Go to the
beginning. Open it. That's Kasar talk
show. And uh you you can see we talked
about casly keys. Uh now press the key
to show it in browser. There it is.
Press a key to switch it back. Now
exit. Okay. Exit uh PowerShell the most
efficient the better shell than bash
than the bash crap. Okay. That's some of
the news uh in some keys. So what's so
okay so uh safi keys and one of the
important command is s extend selection
that is the key on quarti keyboard
keyboard G. So when you press it it will
select the current word. So what it
selects depends on what is under the
cruiser. So if you go to um for example
if you go to flag keys code if your
cruiser is on a paren you press it it
select the entire bracketed text okay
you press it again it extend to the
parents bracket fantastic and amazing
and most efficient okay so this is in
lisp code but it also works in any
programming language of course so Let's
go to Typescript for example,
JavaScript.
Uh let's see popup. Uh let's see search.
Okay, this is a big TypeScript file. So
this is 300 lines, not too big. Okay, so
you put the cursor on a PN
press the key, one single key, you
select the parenthesis, press it again,
it select the outer brackets. You can
see press it again. It selects the curly
brackets. Okay. And the other key quot
is now cancel selection. Fantastic. So
in EMAC you no longer have to do like
control shift something like [ __ ] up
your hands.
Okay. That is the news for keys. Is that
good enough? Good. Okay. Close. Close.
Close close. Showing browser. So we
talked about that
already and if you want the previous
version just search for safely keys and
you go down there's download on GitHub
and archived old version. So before this
major key change there's archived uh you
know this is a version a month ago. So
that's about sapphire keys. One topic
done. Okay let's read the comments.
Let's see.
I have 6.7,000
followers which is kind of pity you know
for other people most of them you know
the zoomers alternatively known as
grifters the scam the the idiot the
[ __ ] you know brandless zoomers they
they do you know memes they put
thumbnails you know like naked girls
half naked girls whatever they get
popular, you know, uh they and every day
what they do is talking [ __ ] you know,
drama,
you know, like one year they got
in two or three years they got half a
million followers.
Hello Francis. Hello um Palash, is your
package layout dependent?
If I change keyboard layout while fly
keys mode is active, will the keys
change? Yes.
So that is kind of a novel feature. Now
this is technical. Okay. So but I'll
finish uh uh let me talk about it just
for one minute. So normally your
keyboard layout if your keyboard layout
change then of course then whatever keys
you know K will be in different places
and so on. But for keys they stay the
same. In other words, doesn't matter
what is your keyboard layout, you know,
like doesn't matter how you switch your
T, your K to ABC to anywhere else.
But in Safly Keys, so let's go to it in
Safly Keys. Let's go to it there.
Let's make it big and show the keyboard
layout diagram. You see this is your
this is your command key binding layout.
So does not matter what keyboard letter
layout you are in such as quarterty
vorac whatever your commands and the
finger you press them remains the same.
So for example the cursor movement which
is a quartis I J KL like inverted arrow
keys you know remains the same and rem
everything else remains the same does
not matter whether you are on quarti or
vorac or comarmac or comarmac dh or
workman or other like other or neo
layout. So uh so all these supported
layout a dnw
aserti asserti Germany beo French
comarmac borak in grammar homemac koi
miniac neo2 noman you know there's 10,00
layouts so I have analysis and criticism
of like all of them on my website kasali
keyboards just search for that you'll
find it. Okay, that answers your
question. So, that is actually a kind of
a novel feature.
You don't find it elsewhere. Do you have
keyboard to move text up and down? Do
you have keyboard to move text up and
down? Uh, yes. So, for example, I press
a key. So, let me show you the pink
window. The pink window shows all my
command call command name on the right
like that. And there are key
corresponding keys on the left. For
example, this command saw HTML open in
browser. That's F5. So let me demo. So I
move here. I press F5 which is on this
key. Can you see that? You see this F5.
So I one single key press. Then it shows
the current page in browser. And you can
see the command is right there because I
just called it. Okay. So the pink window
dynamic dynamically in real time shows
all my command core names and uh
keystrokes on the left and I'm using
Vora keyboard. Okay. So for example this
select this block. How do how did I do
it? That's
HTML select element. Okay. Now press
this key cancel the selection. What is
that? Oh that is fly cancel. That's a
new command I just made a week ago. Part
of this softly keys update.
And if I want to delete this block about
this Neo keyboard, move it to there.
Press a key. You can see it's gone. And
that command is
smart delete by this vorac key E. Okay.
Undo. You can see undo. So most of the
time if you search one of these command
names you'll find the source code so you
can grab and steal it
and if it's on my website I allow you to
do so. Okay that is uh did I answer that
question? Do you have a keyboard to move
text up and down? Yes. So let me show
you. So again this block show neo2
layout diagram showing browser. So you
can see this that's corresponding to
these two lines at least.
Okay. Now if I want to move this block
down. So let's cancel. So first of all
select it. Then press press.
So you can see it went here. So if I
want move it up. So first of all you
make you have to make a selection. Okay.
Move up. Okay. And actually you don't
have to make a selection. If you don't
have a selection, it'll move by the
current block. Okay, which is defined by
empty lines. So if you don't make a
selection, you'll just move this this.
Okay, so let me show you. Okay, press
press arrow down. So it's down. So now I
don't have to press the preceding keys.
I just press arrow down. Arrow down.
Arrow down. Arrow down. So now you can
see this block is moved outside of the
outside of this man.
You see
you see outside of this man. Now if you
press a key to show in browser you can
see it went here because it it's outside
of them the main block. So delete that
and uh uh put it back. Put it back.
Where do I want to put it back?
delete that and uh let's uh
show okay that's talk show let's put it
back here okay showing browser
okay that answered your question
affirmative
next question Francis have you used eh
shell of course
I not just use e shell but I use it
every day I rarely so this is eh shell
which is for those of you who don't know
this is shell written in eac Max. So
it's faster than the standard shell.
Shell. What is standard shell? So that
is this. Okay. Wait. Uh what is the key?
That is that
uh wait uh
what
press press there. So I don't use that
often. So I forgot the key. So you can
see again the uh what the command I just
called is
uh where is it mini buffer quit there
shell. Can you see that in the pink
window shell is a command and the
keystroke is backspace nu in softly keys
backspace is right under my thumb right
here. Okay, can you see the video there?
So three keys then you got powershell.
So PowerShell you can do
you can see this is S talk show now it's
got 1,500 pages.
Okay. So anyway yeah but I don't use the
normal shell much or bash. I use ESH
basically for the most simple commands
such as get um status. I use this a few
times a day. So you can see I work I've
been working on my website
day and night. Okay. Close that eh
shell. Okay. And process. Okay. Running
process keyword. Okay.
Now if you don't know Emacs blog I have
the most popular Emacs tutorial Emacs
blog. And you just do a search search
Emacs. You'll find it and type ES shell.
And let me show you some interesting
things. Okay. Is pens that's very old
article is pens 10 years ago. But
anyway, is versus term sha versus sha
versus turn and is shall uh anyway
there's a a lot articles. Okay. You can
learn about it. What you know so on
keybinds not keyboards. Sorry. Uh yes.
Uh saw you also post AI generated girls.
Wait, do you not use magic? No, I
stopped using magic
about by now seven years ago because go
to just search for Emacs. You'll find my
Emacs website then click on search. Then
just search for m a gi uh uh mi m a git
t magic. Okay, there's a tutorial there.
Magic mode for git. Okay, that's the
most simple five minutes tutorial. Okay.
And then Richard Stman, what's magic?
This is the ignorance and incompetence
of Richard Stman in the year of our lord
2014. He's asking publicly,
by the way, what is magic? I don't know.
Can someone tell me magic?
This is this is 2014. Okay. There's a
complete documentation of Richard
Strowman's
crimes. That's what I say. But actually
well he you know the the bad things he
have done okay there's a log of it and
one of them is in 2014 he asked he asked
in the emacs dev you know what is magic
because magic is like hugely popular use
like there's no Emacs user
there's no professional Emacs coder I
mean professional coder who use Emacs
who doesn't know what is magic okay and
there We have Richard Stolman. He's
like, "Oh, but can someone explain to me
what is magic? By the way, I'm the
creator of free open, you know, free
software foundation. You must respect
me, fuckhead." Okay. Doing this this
incompetent thing. You know, he lives in
a cave. He doesn't use a cell phone and
he doesn't use, you know, he doesn't
have a normal computer because he
require his computer to be so-called
free software stuff. and binary blob and
stuff you know must be free which is
abuse of the word free okay I
okay I talked about this many times uh
also in in in a video last week or two
uh you know so let's not talk about the
this opensource and free software
foundation they are crimes in humanity
okay
so anyway back to so we were searching
for magic articles And we, you know, we
side uh sideshow
we uh digressed or you know talked about
some of it. But here it is. Emac magic
problems. Emacs magic mode problems. Why
I stopped using magic mode. Okay. So if
you are interested that you can read
about it. Okay. uh and uh the magic is
created by a guy I forgot what's his
name but then it was basically took over
so-called maintainer you know the
conventional term for someone who took
over a project and m so-called maintain
it is maintainer so it's a maintainer
has been Jonas Boni for like over 10
years so maintainer is like actually a
misnomer like you know you might think
oh maintain you just maintain it you
didn't write it so maintain maintaining
is just easy fix bugs not really
maintaining is like basically
there's a lot you know there's like a
lot to do okay so but anyway magic is
created by someone uh did I mention no I
don't think so but anyway Jonas Bon Boni
is the guy mostly responsible for magic
the way we know it. Okay. And he's a
nice guy in my opinion. In my review,
I like, you know, I I think he's a good
I, you know, I like him. I I haven't I
haven't talked to him that much,
but he's got, you know, this idiotic um
he's got, you know, you know, of course,
we have some disagreements because I I
have unusual opinions, but anyway, one
of the thing is that um anyway, it's
it's not important detail. Okay, you can
you can use magic. Okay, if you know I
don't you know which is not bad but I
stopped using magic. Part of the reason
is kind of slow. Okay, because my
website
my website there's like 10,000 you know
there's like 30,000 files among them
there's like 7,000 HTML files. So I have
to deal you know and magic is kind of
slow.
So I stopped using magic and uh what I
use every day is almost just like uh
directly git status okay and
occasionally uh diff okay so for example
let's go to talk show let's go to
today's talk show in browser back to
Emacs now VC diff okay so I press press
the key you can see the pink window VC
diff so now it tells me what have I done
oh my god But what have I done to this
file
uh without magic? This is spodin vcd
diff. Okay, so that's what I use.
Okay, that's next topic. Uh I love uh so
eh shell is greater than regular shell.
Uh kind of. Okay, I mean
there's pros and cons. Again, refer to
one of my article. Okay, there's an
article about
let's open you know there's an article
about Yeah, let's open the new one.
Okay, so go to Emacs tutorial. Open a
new search uh shell. Okay, emac search.
So cool shell command. Emac bisp Emacis
Emac format PowerShell code. Emac shell
in movie trunks. This is interesting
because
this is about like 20 years ago by now.
There's you know in the movie sci-fi
movie TR they they show Isaia
this is old you know so this is 200 uh
what what year is this 2011 okay not too
old well 2010 okay and they also
actually showed V vi okay so here is vi
okay so but back to the shell so you are
asking is eh shell more superior than
than the normal or inferior shell. Well,
that depends. Okay. So, you can So, one
of these article, what's the difference
there? Okay. So, what's the difference
between shell versus shell versus term?
Okay. Term is another. Okay. So, you can
read about it. It's kind of technical
for you Emacs users. So basically if you
use if you use common
common commands shell commands
then eh shell is is is fast and good but
if you use you know more complicated
especially like rubies uh you know
whatever build rubies library or pearls
you know that that that commands that
came from the application then usually a
traditional or shell is better or if you
use something like SSH then you need
term okay then there's an answer term
and and you know so I gave the here is
my explanation specifically for that
question you know it's kind of sad I you
know this article is now by now you know
uh 10 years old 2014 these days nobody
reads it you know and but actually it's
just not my website because I I don't
think nobody actually read websites
anymore because you can ask Google AI
bot. Okay, next.
There's a question would love to read
about it. Do you have an article about
why you don't like Richard Storman that
much?
Now that's a false premises.
It is not true that I don't like Richard
Stman. In fact, I was a fanatic.
I was a big fanatical fanatic of Richard
Stman
for like 10 or or for like five 10
years. When I was younger, just like
most of you guys, okay, I was fanatic of
Richard Stman, you know, I go out, you
know, keyboard war with other with the
Unix [ __ ] with the BSD [ __ ]
you know, telling with the Gnome with I
mean the KD KDE [ __ ] who are
against, you know, basic like and and
the open source [ __ ] who are
against the Richard Roman camp, the free
software foundation.
uh when I was younger, okay? Because and
I have an article on that.
Uh but I don't want to talk about that
because I've been talking about that for
so many of you know for like tens of my
videos in the past. Okay. So you guys uh
GPS I guess you haven't seen. So uh let
me just quickly show you some of some of
it. Okay. Like I have like hundred
articles on on on the Richard Sman and
open source issues.
Uh let me just show one of them. Okay.
Quickly. So about Richard Stman. Okay.
Well, you just search for Richard Stman.
Okay. Richard
27 results articles on Richard Stoman on
the survival strategies of Larry War
versus Richard Stoman. I made them. By
the way, this is this is 1999 in Linux
Expo in San Jose down here. Okay. 20
minutes drive. Linux expo. That's when
the open source is like oh my god
there's open source now you Jesus the
corporations releasing their source code
open source you know and that reward is
the creator of pear pearl okay so anyway
I don't want to talk about this topic
because I talked about them so much free
software morality Richard paperwork
bureaucracy 209 2009 Richard Stman abuse
of the word freedom 2009 history
evolution of lease
Guy Steel Richard Gabriel 1993.
Uh oh yeah. So what? Okay. So you need
to type Stoman. So otherwise it shows
other articles. Okay. So and then
Richard Stman on Richard Stoman on Steve
Jobs death. Steve Jobs that's a famous
creator of iPhone creator of the
smartphone revolution. Creator of the
USB revolution. creator of the graphical
user interface revolution, the mouse and
so on. You know, by the way, some of you
technical [ __ ] the Unix will say,
"Oh, it's not invented by him because
the Xerox had the mouse, you know, the
the the idiots." Okay, but but what we
can say is that Steve Jobs is one of the
greatest innovator. He's a uh
entrepreneur. That's what people, you
know, that's so-called entrepreneur. He
created many things. He made the digital
music like today you guys are familiar
with digital music. He began it because
before him people just steal pirate you
know because people can't you know can't
be bothered you know because the society
moved on. We have digital information
you know computers but the the music
corporations the lawyers and suits they
going to oh the you know we're going to
not going to do that. We're going to
sell records and CDs. you must buy
otherwise you are a crime criminal
because you cannot steal.
So people do pirate. So this is this is
around the year 2000. Okay. Anyway,
Steve Jobs
uh great innovator.
But then he died. He died in around
2011. Okay. Then the comes Richard
Stman. I'm glad he's dead but I'm not
glad he's done.
Richard Stoman said that in his blog.
Okay. And that made a lot of people like
hate, you know, like
uh
remove their free software foundation
members membership. Okay. Anyway, this
is part of history.
So, and there's lots of articles. Okay.
So, let me show show you some dramatics
you guys like to see. For example, this
Richard Storman meets Julian Assange.
Julian Assange, one of the hero, a great
man of humanity.
Uh, and Richard Stoman in that regard is
a great guy, you know. So, you know, a
person is good and bad. There's good
aspect and bad aspect.
So, there it is that 2013. Okay. And and
so on on and on. Okay. So, I have a lot
of articles. So, what is the question
exactly? Or why do I hate him? I don't
hate him. Okay.
I don't hate him. I was a fanatic of
Richard Stman. Oh, yeah. So, c can I
show the article? Where where do do I uh
say I'm a fanatic of of him? Well, I
know where is the article. Okay. So, let
me just show you directly the Unix
pestilence written in 2003. Okay. So,
uh so this is so many. Okay. So, you go
down, go down, go down. There it is.
Free FSS. No, wait. FSF. Free software
open source and communism. GNU is not
Unix. GNU is not a Unix [ __ ]
Okay. Created by Richard Stoman.
Now, here's a quote by me in 2002. And
this quote partially demonstrate why I
was a fanatic of Richard Stman. Okay.
Now let me read it of the open source
which is one of the most potry idea of
humanity of do's musing pole
a offshoot and outright turn coat of
Richard Stoman's vision and hardship
dressing itself as the mediator between
FSF and businessmen
fiddling and hawking a pipe dream of its
own that is the open source by the Eric
um what's his name Eric um
uh
ESR okay Eric's s Raymond guy open
source the open source foundation which
is split from free software foundation
okay fiddling and hawking a pipe of a a
pipe dream of its own the open source a
part calling the kettle black thieves
and slouch back seat and in the end it
is just another fantastic fat pest of
the world that is lingering
a sucker of programmer blood the open
source a ruse of the enterprising corpse
the mega corporations you know they are
all open source they are not like pro
free software foundation but they are
poor open source a desperate in
congruent
splash of vaporing nothingness that we
shall see.
Okay, so this demonstrate I was a
fanatic of Richard Stoman back then I
was fighting the open source [ __ ]
and turns out sadly I was wrong because
now after 20 years freeware foundation
kind of dead nobody know like like the
people most people don't know who the
[ __ ] is Richard Sman or FSF okay but
they know open source everybody every
[ __ ] Joe procoders know open source
and they sing the songs of open source
every day day and night you need open
source why don't you why are you not on
Linux you know [ __ ]
so anyway this complicated story okay
and history I I I don't want to talk
about it okay yeah Eric Raymond Eric
Raymond author of the cathedral and the
bazaar I read that book twice carefully
when it came out like around year 200
000.
Okay,
that got me angry. Uh, and angry because
there's a lot politics going on today
related. Okay, the deep state
what they are doing is killing people.
Okay, so how long have I been talking?
Uh, 40 minutes, I think. So let's see
what is next.
Show wam language. Okay. So let me
demonstrate some wam language inversion.
So about four days ago we did a very
technical uh talk show about this
geometric inversion geometry and
mathematics. Okay. So that's wam
language about export about SVG and so
on.
uh and uh but I haven't showed you guys
the package you know I wrote like 30
years ago but let me because I'm still
working on it to update so let me just
show some of that uh so invert circle so
here's a code by the way this deep
science about syntax and operators and
coding style about which is better uh I
was talking about it on Twitter okay so
is my Twitter alive So no. So let's make
it alive. Turn on JavaScript.
So I was talking about now I got to be
careful that because there's something
here that if I show Google will censor
me the YouTube the deep state.
So let me just if I see it I'll quickly
scroll it off. Okay. So
I was you know so my Twitter is half you
know technical stuff programming and
mathematics but like
5% of it is politics
um
you know so I was talking about you know
there's a lot deep science and art of
programming language
syntax design and operators and syntax
you know like some syntax they are not
exactly operators but they are part of
the syntax they function like operators
like like like most people coders these
[ __ ] they don't even know what is
what exactly how what is exactly the
definition of an operator in a
programming language
anyway
so I was talking about it and also wam
language okay so And here is politics.
Let's quickly score it off. Okay. And uh
but if you are curious, you just know
that you know this USA and another
country is doing a lot killings of
people. Okay.
So anyway, operators. So let's go back.
So I want to show you. So let's not talk
about operators. Let me just show you
the the you know the fancy graphics.
Okay. So turn on wam language. Uh yeah,
there it is. Okay, so you can see here
is I was working on it in the past few
days. Let's make it super large.
And you see the fantastic feature of the
automatic realtime formatting. I talked
about it many times as opposed to the
Unix [ __ ] They are, you know, oh,
you should use indent, you know, you
should put the indent and the coding
style guide. Did you read the coding
style guide indent versus and you know
what is
the [ __ ] from the Unix and C and
C++ people for like 30 years. Okay. So
the Wuam language automatic there's no
by the way there's no tab there's no tab
or space anywhere here. Okay. Anywhere
in this blank they are automatically
rendered just like in browser just like
in a browser
you know see we have this technology
because Wuan did this in 1998
1997 okay version three but the C and
Unix and the whole industrial coding
[ __ ] the C++ and today uh well Rust
you know and most of them JavaScript,
Python, they are they have their
opinions. So but you shouldn't do that
cuz you are a troll. You know this
idiots you know this this is part of the
reason you see society kind of change
slowly. They are changing indeed
you know. So but anyway anyway I talked
about this before too but um let's go
back to yeah I want to just show you the
packages. Okay now select all uh first
of all magnify.
Okay, select all just shift
enter and run the code. Okay, so this is
doing geometric inversion. So this
circle blue became this red circle
via the inversion of this gray circle.
Okay, so that you know so my previous
video four days ago explained it.
So here a line inverted to this red
circle. Okay. So here's a graphic. So
you can run the code. For example,
select that, delete it, put it cursor
here, shift, enter, run it. So you can
see. So these are geometric inversions.
Okay.
Okay. So there, there, there. Close.
Don't save. Okay. Close. Now let's open
another one here.
Okay. And this one uh you know shows the
inversion of a grid like that. it
becomes that. Okay. Then a grid like
that becomes that. Okay. And uh you know
so it's a code. So for example
shift enter
uh oh you need to well select all
and uh run it. Okay. So it's good. So
now close that. Don't save. Okay. Now
nested inversion. Now here's more
interesting
geometry. Okay. So you're going to see
this, you know, I was working on select
or run it.
Okay. And that's not interesting. That's
well that's uh actually let's change
some parameters. Okay. So to make this
more beautiful. Okay. This this is not
too beautiful. So let's increase the
size 150.
Um okay. So now let's make the circle.
Let's adjust. Okay. So here
um nest level three center radius let's
say two.
Okay. So shift
enter.
Now it's more beautiful. Now the color
is not so great because they are not
symmetric. You can see this circle is
yellow but the one on the left is kind
of green. So it should be so that
the symmetric circles who are symmetric
they should have the same color. So I
need to fix some code
that's why it's not you know the code is
not ready. You'll see it on GitHub
GitHub. Okay.
But let's open the last one. Okay. So
this one the last one I'm going to show
you. Okay. So you see it's going to
generate this image. Okay. So this is
nested inversion of seven circles. You
invert with respect to each one of the
others. So mutual mutual inversion. Then
you do it again. Nested mutual
inversion. Okay. So delete that. Now
make it enlarge
150. Fantastic and beautiful code. Put
the cursor here. Shift enter. Uh wait.
Okay. Select or shift enter. There it
is. Okay. So, that's about I'm just
that's what I'm gonna that's that's all
I'm just showing you some of that. Uh
and I think maybe that's it for today.
Should I learn Wuam language? Yeah, sure
you should. Um
yes, it's very good. You know, it's free
you, you know, for personal use
hobbyist. Okay. So it's uh in my opinion
it's the most the the most high level
programming language by a magnitude. Not
just two times, not just three times.
It's not just oh it's two times better
than Python. Uh two times better than
Hascal or Rust or Goland or two times
better than JavaScript or C++? No. Is is
it 10 times better? No. It's a
magnitude. Okay. It's one like 1,000
times more higher level. So one line of
woofer language equals to like 20 lines
of Python for each every line here.
That's 20 lines of Python. Okay. And if
you are talking about mathematical
functions like derivatives, integrals,
solve equation, then then one line of
warm is like 1 million lines of Python
like literally. Okay. Okay. And Wufam
language by default there's uh 7,000
functions built in. Okay.
But it's not open source. Uh it's free
for personal use. Uh you can you know
download and you know use um for
personal use not not for if you not if
you work for corporation. No is you
cannot do that. You have to pay like you
know the $1,000 a month 2,000 something.
So, but you can buy also uh you can buy
a hobbyist version or student version
depending on which you are for like 200
I think it's 200 something a year. Okay.
So, go to wufam just search for
wufam.info
wuam language tutorial. You can find the
download link here. Okay. Then you go to
it and turn on JavaScript
and you can you know wra
software developers download WAM engine
free. Okay.
Uh okay. And that's it. That's that.
That's that for today. Or you can buy
it, you know, you can buy a, you know,
hobbyist version or student version
around $200 something. check their
website. If you are professional, you
really want to, you know, you don't
care, you know, you work at Google, you
make you make $10,000 a month, then you
have to buy the professional version,
which is like a,000 or 2,000 something a
year
where then you can use in your
production. Okay, in your production.
Um okay that's that it's especially
useful for if you are a scientist
engineer mathematician chemist you know
if you are average coder industrial
coder like you do web dev javascript or
you do linux you know kernel rust you
know if you if you are just that nothing
else then
then wam language maybe it's not for you
okay but if you are engineer
If you are a physicist, if you are a
chemist, if you are you know even a
lawyer, a businessman or if you are a
gamer who on the side you know some
coding stuff or you do Bitcoin, you do
you know you you like to learn about
crypto, you like to learn about machine
learning, you want the most powerful in
human history, you know calculator sort
of then wra. languages for you.
Okay, if you are the professional coder,
you code C, C++, gamedev, Linux,
that's all you care about, wam language
is not for you. Okay,
that's it.
Okay, so that's that. So let's see. Is
there something else I want to talk
about that? I think that's it. We talked
for one hour.
talk to guac. I did. Okay. Uh talk about
array uh next time. Anything else? I
think we time to say goodbye.
How many people are watching? Let me
make a guess. 10. Uh 10 or 15. Okay.
Check. 10. Jesus jackpot.
I won the lottery.
Any any more questions? Last chance.
This is your last chance to say
something.
We shut down in a minute.
Let's see. Did we talk everything I
wanted to? Yes. Kasly keys news. Uh Neo
layout. Yes. Wam language demo. Yes.
circle inversion. So when I'm ready in a
few days, I'll put it here and you'll
see it on GitHub. Right now it's empty.
Uh I wrote this like 30 30 years ago,
but I'm improving it.
Uh so it's actually not so trivial. I
mean technically
the inversion code should be trivial but
then but the woof language powerful and
you know there's a lot to do actually so
I'm I'm improving the code you know
improving the code and
um lots of things changed you know after
30 years
all right I learned I'm a chemistry
engineer fantastic
okay bye guys bye
Too much smoke. I need to quit
cigarette. Yeah, I've been, you know,
wanting to quit cigarette. That's why
you I have this kind of cough.
It's so funny today that we talked to
Guac Annie and it came out a guy. That's
the most that's the most funny thing
today.