welcome to another startup show today is
June 24th 2019 and in fact I'm going to
start five minutes later so let me
update that start in five minutes be
right back
310 so let's say 310 and saw talk show
on let's see what what is today's topic
today's topic is a sundry things is
about keyboard today on keyboard web dev
JavaScript and act etc okay copy that
and back to Chrome here is my chrome and
let's put that there so people know and
we're gonna get my windows
this needs to be at the bottom you see
this is a efficient technique you move
your mouse always just move your mouse
to the bottom and you'll get to Firefox
or Emacs you know no click so anyway I
will be back in five minutes actually
give me ten minutes so yeah my drink
[Music]
good morning
good morning Sean I'm back welcome to
the South Hawk show and so Sean says
give us something to listen to while you
prepare your beverage
never mind I'll just you in your anyone
cares I'm I mean 16 tons by Tennessee
Ernie Ford so what song is that I did I
don't know what that song is Polk post a
youtube link so I'm back and let's begin
and Shawn's a self topic but when you
come back so I'm wondering what kind of
music you are into okay that's a good
question I'm into two type of music one
is classical and the other one is part
of course well
classical and non-classical okay so
classical of the classical music
basically the only music of classical
type I listen to is piano piano some
occasionally organ organ music or half C
code so I love piano music so of the
classical music almost the only type a
listen to his piano and among the piano
music my favorites are ba and the least
now Park is the what do you call classic
Baroque era classical music and least is
a Romantic era classical music so among
classical I own basically almost only
listen to piano music but I don't listen
to for example I don't like symphonies
at all
I don't like symphonies well there are a
few pieces you know
Chopin's fantasy of something you know
basically I don't listen to any
symphonies okay occasionally I listen to
string quartet string quartet or piano
and
violent together what's that code you
know or concerto you know okay yeah so
basically I don't like symphonies but
sometimes I listen to concertos but
mostly like 95% is piano now among the
piano music my favorite favorite Abba
and least okay now a man park my
favorite are these if I can only pick
one piece that would be well-tempered
clavier book one okay book one previewed
and fugues
so that's my favorite of Bach's music
now my favorite of lists of lists is the
these transcendental attitudes in
particular number twelve
okay so and embark in Bach's
well-tempered clavier my favorite are
two pieces fook number four in book one
and Fugue number eight in book one oh my
god these are these are you know they
say it's mathematical perfection but
it's not just that it's just you know
it's a it's steady beat every note is
perfect to such a degree your brain
cannot take it after you decent for a
while like you play in the background
okay for example I playing in the
background I mean I'm you know coding or
doing whatever and and you just keep
playing in a background and suddenly
when it reaches some passage passages it
you know it swab your brain so Sean says
I love everything late romantic in
Russian so what is late romantic like
what were the example late romantic like
you know you know what what what are
some examples of late romantic and
Remini no yes I love that - so lemony
North would be my Sikh second favorite
to least with respect to you know peope
that piano composes so I've laid out you
know or the you know so there are two
parts classical and non-classical among
classical I almost listen only to piano
among piano music - favorite composers
spa and least and among box
my favorite album is well-tempered
clavier book one and two there are two
of them but when - but my you know
they're baccarat so many like and so as
well at least and other people so but
you if you only can pick one that will
be back Bach's well-tempered clavier and
fugue number four and number eight in
book what they are mathematical
perfection they drive you insane
but now least transcendental idiots you
know something you can also be said you
know Bach's music you know those are
Fuchs and his music box you know it's a
perfection but it's cold and austere you
know there's there's no emotion there's
no like I give you a pat in the back
there's no hey cheer up like the [ __ ]
you know sloppy jazz okay jazz jazz and
whatever whatever you know you know it's
zones so box music is just pure code
austere that's that's how I roll okay by
the way you know you like rock n roll
you know some people you like rock n
roll you're fine you're gonna go like
rock n roll go like jazz look alike
whatever go like rap you know black
people's rap and violence and what today
is social justice can would call
misogyny but they don't go but they
don't you know they denied you know
because it's facts and you know that
that's another story of the social
justice era of today but then
so what what am I saying yeah so yes you
know the you know how you roll you know
you like rock n roll you like you know
country music or whatever but so you
know the so what I'm saying it's not
just me I mean I'm talking I'm pointing
out the code you know code nice and
austerity of box music that like there's
no emotion there's no nothing like that
is simply pure music and but and on the
other hand least now the least and Bach
are entirely different because you know
least is romantic park is the what would
you call the Baroque era okay but so
least is entirely different however you
know as music goes you know they say
music touches your soul and well it's
not the same for everyone though because
the music I like it touches my so it
doesn't it may not touch yours you know
you you you played you know classical
music most people they don't they don't
feel a thing you know you don't care but
then they care about their stuff you
know some whatever music or heavy metal
you know what the [ __ ] you know that
touch is there so whatever so you know
so that's why it's different now I was
comparing this and Bach now list is also
touches your soul touches my soul okay
but it's entirely different these days
it's emotional okay
these music is highly because it's
romantic it's you know classified as
romantic romantic music emotion is the
main thing
but however least music is also code
there's no you know like Chopin Chopin
is like the modeling you know the soap
opera you know oh oh sad Oh sad so sad
also soothing you know this is nothing
like that
[ __ ] that you know that nothing like
that the in list music okay let's trans
transcendental attitudes you know and as
in my favorite
and these transcendental attitudes they
are twelve of them is the number 12
number 12 is the name you know you know
it's given a name as plowing snow storm
sometimes so you know it's inescapable
darkness and groom each node is a
knifing on your heart it repeats over
and over with greater strength intensity
and sternness forces of nature in
execution sense mercy and in Chinese
Chalfont Pao whoo - info Lu tau tau tau
crushing fetching vania Lang cool zone
so that's that's a little Chinese what
did the verse Chinese was I wrote to
describe the song and which is similar
to the English description here that is
that is this is transcendental attitudes
number 12
okay let me post it here so maybe you
can listen to for you know my my dear
readers my dear you know followers and
subscribers oh I have five people
watching great good morning so so he
says I love everything so here's a link
to late romantic from song so let's see
who they are so I digressed you know
today I had other topics but you know
today is you know we're gonna talk about
random so Romantic era 1815 to 1910 yeah
after that is modern modern whatever
[ __ ] and now they have postmodern era
[Laughter]
[ __ ] [ __ ]
if [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] it you know oh
yeah so I I forgot to say so you know
the part I like about cry you know so
that's what I like about
psycho music but non-classical I also
listen to like you know maybe 40% of the
time of the of the non classical music
let's just call it pop okay you know so
over the pop music I usually listen to
you know well pop you know like a mum
pop music there's a special genre which
is just called pop you know that's
basically the songs you listen yeah the
radio plays you know Madonna Prince
that's old you know 20 years ago today
you have whatever Swift whatever Swift
in whatever you know these today's so
Britney spheres for example that's she's
also you know 20 years ago 1990s 2000s
so anyway so of the pop music I listen
to
well some of the part and but mostly a
few things I like I won't say about that
is that I like the dance music
electronic dance music like frenzied
brainless dance music you know this for
example let me show you some examples
dance me music so this is my music block
actually so so here's some of the songs
I dance frenzy songs now like many of
them for example this blue army like
usually they are not for example this
song is played in the dance dance
revelution you know like just beats you
know the egg brain has no meaning no
meaning just beats and for example there
are several electro house okay okay this
one is good listen to this one okay let
me show you oh yeah this Miami
hotline Miami OST is fantastic
now the music I'm showing now here is
some of the
you know Brenda Stan's music oh they
removed it you know the YouTube Google's
come back you know since about two years
ago they stopped giving you reasons why
a video is removed usually I just show
show blank like no reason but used to
give reason but in this case however
they do give you a reason so it says
this video has been removed by the user
okay so anyway electro house music and
by the way you like you know I noticed
because I've been you know listening on
YouTube you thanks thanks for what
so the you the electro house music yes I
go to youtube you know when when you see
oh you know you to search for dance
music 2090 not with that you know or you
know popular dance musical popular gamey
music you know you type it and all the
icons are these chicks like that you
know hot chicks so so that means
actually so this dance music are
actually very sexual you know they I
guess yeah I suppose you know they they
are typically some kind of you know they
drive your your nerves to you know like
you know like you go to youtube you see
all the Oh hot girls those icons they
they this was this dance music they yeah
they suddenly have some a la six right
sexual drive anyway so so check out this
one okay hotline Miami Miami hotline
Miami OST I think that's a game or
something I don't remember but you know
this this is the example where I you
know I I like you know the brainless
speeds then there is this - okay let me
show you the ones I recommend this this
one electro dance music
mpi a three I think that's also from a
video game or something I don't remember
but anyway so listen check out this one
the first one the MPI a3 or the Miami
hotline they are like openness kind of
brainless
brainless frenzy that's what I call did
and and they have I guess yeah this is
from this music is from a video game I
guess hotline Miami so they have this
artwork this artwork is fantastic this
artwork I you know and so I don't know
who who is the artist I should actually
I should find out it surprised I
surprise surprise you know I never I
didn't look for it before and distance
music so they yeah so the you got this
picture this picture represents the the
relations of male and female of human
animals okay you know all the guys wants
to get a girl and of course pretty young
girl that's the key thing here always
must be younger the guys age doesn't
matter much the girl is more you know
it's anyway so that's that's a big
digression and let's get back to oh yeah
so list of Romantic era composers so
late romantic let's see who are the late
romantics late classical era early
Romantic okay Beethoven I don't like and
tendon under
Dhin Dhin Dhin Dhin Dhin Dhin Dhin Dhin
Dhin Dhin so who else late so those
ah Jesus this oh god this page is like
hundred pages you know this this is some
funny thing what's going on here you
know there's the funny thing this taste
wait do I have the you know these days
these browsers these [ __ ] companies
in I guess I'm surprised that Wikipedia
is doing it these days you know they
control I mean they they log of your
scroll like when you scroll to a page
they know they measure it like they know
which part of the page you stopped
especially on Twitter Facebook you know
other social networks web sites so they
measure you know they want to know where
you stopped so that they can they can
get more info about you like what you
like what you don't like and you know
one way you can tell is that when you
scroll a page it does not scroll
naturally like right now I'm pressing
the spacebar
I mean I'm page you know the thumb down
it does not behave like this right now
okay so when this happens you know
usually there is a JavaScript going on
there's this this [ __ ] yeah and in
fact the programmers you know why this
happens because these programmers elite
you know unix/linux loving open-source
loving facts they got us this you know
into this is e this is in firefox okay
in Firefox
I have JavaScript turned off you know
don't know JavaScript now I press at
page down key you see how this page this
is how it normally behaves but when you
have a website that uses JavaScript to
to to to monitor you know where you
stopped you know at what part of the
page for how long you get this you get
this behavior
is this nice [ __ ] you know companies
and and and indirectly due to the
[ __ ] programmers and among
programmers you know part of it is due
to this open source elite UNIX loving
[ __ ]
you know I I say that because it's you
can you know it's kind of is
exaggeration but not really you know
because you know you look at the society
you it's not it's not their fault you
know it's not like oh this you need
people UNIX lovers you know Linux
open-source lovers they caused this it's
not like that but rather they are part
of the reason to blame though I mean
they have also responsibility everyone
you know basically you know this is this
is you know this is a web page this this
is made by programmers programmers are
us you know and among us you know there
are many different you know philosophies
and people in personalities but you know
big part of them is open source people
so what I'm saying is that it's always
some ansible responsible okay for this
kind of trend you know what society goes
into you know how today's you know
tracking and ads everywhere why are they
every ads everywhere because the open
source [ __ ] because every time they
see you know they they they run the ad
blockers or whatever you know oh they
every time every day they whenever
there's opportunity they flame you know
the ad you know the you know
corporations but that's that's that's a
problem you know so they think oh that's
not a said oh that's not me you know cuz
I you are [ __ ] it no because you know
you see what they do easy society is not
like what you what what will happen is
not it does not depend solely on what
you do it depends on complex reasons for
example if you are you know if you have
an ideology and you ignore reality you
ignore you know let's say you say Emacs
is the best editor om access no problem
at all no problem zero Emacs is in fact
the
you know ultimate editor you know you
you deny all the problems you know
people points points about Emacs or
whatever okay that's that's when you are
you know ignoring you know you are not
seeing reality you are living in
ideology and so whatever you do even
though you think it's it you know it
helps Emacs because you know you say all
the good things about you max you denied
problems so you think you are like the
big help to Emacs community no but
actually you are doing damage to Emacs
you know when you can when you for
example one one one cause is that you
you are strong believer of certain
ideology and ignore reality that's one
example there are others of course of
course one obvious you know is some
people you know just always flame Emacs
for whatever reason for no reason at all
but anyway so what I'm saying is that so
why do I blame a lot to the open source
people because they they are in ideology
and you know the you know they just you
know programmers are just like every
non-programmers you know like I used to
think yeah at this you know maybe
subconsciously that programmers are
different somehow or nerds are different
somehow from know more people because
you know so we see the truth or whatever
that's not true so I you know
programmers are just like average common
people they believe in first of all for
example they've they follow fashions in
fad
just like you know the bunch of girls
following you know the King Kedah seein
you know who made the sex tape and
become a media 100 you know a thousand
media you know the news you have a
gaggle millions of girls following
Kardashian whatever she wears today all
the girls you know gonna you know what
they want to buy whatever you know she's
wearing same thing happens in
programmers community you just said you
usually don't think you don't know then
you know programmers like for example
the best example is that you go to
hacker news you
see you know the vermin say they talk
about idioms what the latest programming
languages that's that's the same thing
ignorant you know they never studied
actually know about the thing so well
that's a little R and about that you
know about this you know this is this
browser behavior this you know
JavaScript [ __ ] [ __ ] so if I you know
but I'm surprised actually Wikipedia is
doing it I don't think I have noticed
Wikipedia but you know I've we have
tried in Firefox you can see in Firefox
it doesn't have that behavior hold on a
second magnify so in Firefox you see
this is how it that's how it behaves
but in chrome it's not like that I think
it's due to JavaScript so one way to be
sure to find out is to turn on
JavaScript off but we are now going to
do that okay so that's that's another
topic I try to link with but I what I do
oh yeah the you know the posting links
in in YouTube yeah they have automatic
some kind of you know like theater like
whenever you post the link some links
not all links those some yeah I don't
know you know because this stays Google
you know doing a lot censorship in you
know I and you know that sort of thing
okay twenties we've we've been talking
for 36 minutes actually I have been
talking only for 20 minutes because
first ten minutes is yeah I was away so
let's talk about today's topic then yeah
shown so yeah so we we talked about
music so
so we I think we're gonna do another 30
minutes so we're gonna talk about some
keyboards some web dev JavaScript some
goodies I'm gonna show you some goodies
okay so keyboard JavaScript and yeah
possibly I'll do a live coding of
JavaScript if there's interest
are you interested showing to you
program are you a programmer if so do
you program JavaScript what like what do
you do and and where are you from by the
way what country or what what state so
we might do some live coding of
JavaScript and oh you are learning
JavaScript okay so I guess we will do
some JavaScript today then you'd like to
see yeah so let's do let's begin so
first of all let's go to my keyboard
block okay keyboard check check okay I'm
still good so keyboard block
okay so a friend showed me these
synthesizers he said he bought it this
this thing is like 800 800 dollars you
know when I was a teenager around
twenties I prayed a lot with
synthesizers so this is around 1990 not
too well even in year 2000 I had so yeah
up to year 2000 so it's like 20 years
ago I played I played a lot with synth
so I learned you know the fundamentals
you know how they you know how they
control how do you control a sound what
kind of technology are there you know
there's addictive synth there's a
subtractive synth there's sampling
sampling synth you know so anyway so I'm
interested but you know I haven't been
doing any for 20 years and today I don't
have money to to any of
these so anyway this looks like a good
one
he bought it so it's you know if you
like it buy it for my you know if you
buy for my website I would get you know
2% 4% of you know whatever okay and
that's a sink sink and there's some
keyboard questions on reddit people are
asking me you know private message by
the way so I would prefer public
messages whenever you have you know
questions for me
doesn't matter programming keyboard or
whatever so you know one thing you can
do so that's a new Moog I see I didn't
know it's move movies was a popular you
know the classic brand for synthesizers
they I think they are famous for making
analog synth you know not digital they
they were famous for making analog synth
so anyway so yeah don't scripting okay
great so about keyboard yeah so I got
two questions about keyboard and so by
the way you know I would prefer to post
questions publicly because you know I I
spent like one hour or two hours just
answering questions for the past like
you know 10 20 50 15 years as well
especially in the past five years
everyday to you know two hours well
actually more than that you know
especially when I was doing yoga max
project so you know I get and especially
private messages are no good you know I
also got emails this place is I barely
read emails private messages because I
have to answer you know every day you
know just almost the you know similar
questions I ask answer every day people
usually you know I have written a lot
you know they are like a few thousand
articles you know you like Emacs
question so keyboard questions mostly
you can you know I you know I I almost
always right
I try to you know whatever you know
opinion so after I studied some subject
so anyway try try post to youtube
comments or let me mention this old I
have a reddit so you go to reddit reddit
saw ok I have like a public likes a fan
curve okay this one solvated this is
this is let's let's give you the name
Chris our fan club okay
post here you know it's a sad thing I
used to have comments on my website like
every page you know like so I answer
questions on my comments on my website
all day every page he is you can post
comment but then then the discuss you
know forum they started to charge you
know those yeah again you you know
discuss started like ten years ago
it was more than ten years ago it was a
way to have comments on your website no
you know there's a history to that too
because before in year 2000 a web page
is just a web page there's no comment
you know there's no common thing then it
got invented you know then then almost
every page got comments you know this is
a you can post your comments then after
5 or 10 years ago that kind of you know
went away I mean well didn't people
started to hide the comments like only
when you click like you know view
comments then the comment shows so
there's a last story about website
comments you know oh wait you know
originally they are not all crap but
these days it's like oh crap oh like Oh
nonsense like no real content like every
you know and again I would plant I blame
the [ __ ] open-source programmers ok
that's kind of exaggeration but I blame
the people that you know the like
there's this group of people you should
you know it's called hackers typically
and they have opinions of course they
have opinions about everything
you typically see their opinions on
Hacker News and before that on select
Ashdod okay so their opinion whenever
comes come you know they have opinions
about how you should post how you should
you know before these new scoops how you
should you know this or that you know
typically nerds you know and and my
followers I suppose you know a lot of
you hunt like that they just wrong they
are just bad so anyway I mean you know
let's not go into that because we're
gonna that's another ten or twenty
minutes talk well anyway my point what I
want to say is that they are P so today
we have the situation where you go to
read it or any any place YouTube reddit
or on Twitter or Facebook you look at
the comments like ninety five percent
you know vast you know much majority of
the common ninety-five like ninety five
percent more than 95 percent you know
it's all content less crap and by you
know Superman Batman
you know Jesus but you know butit's not
supposed to be like that you know you
you don't like we we get used to it
today you don't even feel it today you
just look you know every day you wake up
you know go to your social network or
whatever comments you know you know is
someone y'all read it you know you think
that's no more that's not normal
that's you know it's supposed to be
comment your thoughts you know you don't
take post [ __ ] post or you know a limb
you know oh thank you we know the crap
it's not supposed to be like that this
is related to today's society you know
politics censorship it's all related you
know and you know the [ __ ] the
open-source [ __ ] the hackers the you
know for UNIX philosophy type of people
they want you know they want oh my god
their opinions are just so bad on
everything you know that so so to me
okay to me you know I think they have
you know they are the problem they are
part of the problem as at least among
programmers you know I'm a programmer so
that's a
is I you know my community you know
that's how you know me you know and you
know so so that's I that's people I
criticize I you know I you know so I
don't know about lawyers or what other
people do you know so but uh
non-programmers is this hacker types lee
their opinions is just bad so and this
is all related this is important because
because all the website google facebook
aku who made it to them we made it we
made these sites yeah but you may say oh
my but my boss told me no or the
marketing told me not not exactly true
you have a big influence you know how
the tech grows so anyway so so yeah so
the the point is about you see you look
at the comments you know like you know
you go to Emacs even Emacs rated E max
you know something technical all the
comments using a 90% is crap is content
to this that's a key thing I mean even
though even if there's no swearing words
that's fine you know today the social
justice can [ __ ] heads you know they'd
been swearing anyway you know remember
swimming we libros fault
for it it was conservatives
conservatives back in 90s who censor you
know you know you cannot say [ __ ] you
cannot disorder I say this you know they
censor it now it it's 180 degree turn
with we found for it you know because
back then if you look at the English
dictionary sometimes you cannot find a
word such as [ __ ] oh you know
fornication oh it is true you know in
some you know that was back then in
eighteen nineteen eighty so it all 90s
some dictionaries do not print those
words anyway so back to the you know the
website comments you look at them I mean
so
swimming okay there's no swearing words
but you know it's like content list
that's the key thing I mean even this
even even if there's no [ __ ] poet
posting but every post is like no
content and posted by you know
random Superman Jesus you know this
anonymous Fox but you know loved by
these eunuchs [ __ ] privacy Oh
privacy or open source or Richard
Stallman Oh [ __ ] free software
foundation Oh ethics ethics these facts
they are [ __ ] because they they are not
you know they are ignoring reality
that's what it is they are so remotely
you know out of touch they are not you
know seeing reality they you know they
are you know and you know that's called
cause problem and this applies to your
personal life too you know if you have
something you cannot ignore it you know
you you have to you know you cannot
believe you know so I believe I believe
I'm the smartest guy on earth I VD I'm
the greatest Emacs coded if you believe
that you know you kid
yeah well if that if that is true then
then maybe that's you know then thanks
good but if it's a little bit and true
then it's still good you know I'm still
pretty good but if I'm you know I'm if
I'm not a good Emacs coder and Oh at all
but but I believe you know my belief and
reality is you know there's if there's a
huge gap it's gonna create a problem for
me you know so this applies to personal
you know things as well as well as you
know general society you know you don't
want to anyway so so what what are we
saying talking about so I was saying so
many things one thing these to another
so I was saying you know so there is
this reddit a stash saw that's you can
post comments here it's kind of like
Microsoft fan club and Reddit and on on
YouTube so you can post comments on my
youtube I'd love to see that and I hope
to get back come to you know put back
comments on my websites
discuss forum oh yeah I was saying you
know they they began as free like 15
years ago
then about two years ago they started to
charge I mean they started to about
three years ago they started to have ads
but however you can turn off image ads
but then but the text ads textual ads
are forced you have no choice I mean
either you pay them like ten dollars a
month or they're gonna display text ads
image ads you can turn off okay but not
but after after a while you have to have
a year or so they they even stopped that
they know it they force image ads on
your website if you don't pay you know
otherwise you have to pay them to use
their service the you know the comment
service and they're in their ads is like
you know loose fat or these this weird
trick to lose fat in ten day you know
those kind of ads you know and skinny
you know go in bikini or some kind of
you know do it you know dramatic you
know pictures plastered over your page
all of my webpage if you use them so
that's anyway that's how things are you
know that why is it like that because
open source facts you know because they
need money
you know they it's not you know they
need money to run you cannot blame them
to force ads they need money but where
they get money you think you donate like
every time when ads come up this
[ __ ] open-source [ __ ]
they go over reddit or you know
everywhere they all say oh no don't put
ads we all be happy to donate you know
what you know whatever ten dollars they
all say that reality that nothing like
that happens I know because I mentioned
this before because I when I don't have
donate and when I had no ads donate
button I get like oh five ten dollars a
month now if I have ads I get you know a
few hundred dollars a month is
big difference even even most of my
readers of course you know these tech
geeks we you know my community they
already have you know ad blockers on so
you have to stick with reality you know
so these Keeks you know so they anyway
so the discuss yeah so they you know
they don't have money they have to you
know keep you know they have to stay
alive so they've they are forcing ads
cannot really blame them you know it's
just how things are but you know because
they you know they have and by the way
they are not open source they are not
exactly in their source code I don't
think it's open source anyway so let's
go to so yeah so keyboard questions
actually I mean I want to answer the
quick key locations actually so I I got
this question
McVoy voiture
so Bob Moog started with the Moog for
sure that that's a Moog synthesiser I
guess okay so so someone asked me the
question about he says okay your blog
about your keyboard so he says I should
he should learn touch type or maybe not
and so it's kind of a long question it's
kind of it's not a specific question
it's a bunch of things so let me talk
about should you learn touch type do you
do touch type show so the question is
should shoot you learn touch type and
also he talked about some keyboard
layout
okay let me talk about a little bit
about typing so if you want to know
everything about typing or repetitive
strain injury read my blog okay you know
just such sorry keyboard you'll find it
on this page there are like they are
more than 20 articles about that
so should you not touch type that okay
so there's no absolute answer okay I'm
saying this because you know otherwise I
would tell you yeah you should because
I've been touch typing since since
nineteen eighty eighty seven on a
typewriter and since since 1990s on
computers and in 1994 on Vora keyboard
so I would love to tell you yeah you
should but actually so the truth is it
actually depends on you then the major
question is how much you actually type
so if you type a lot
you should learn touch type okay if you
type if you don't touch type that much
really there's no need it doesn't
there's no need actually you are you are
you are fine you know without if you are
a programmer again programmer is not
enough to get two programmers to not
type that much okay what you actually
should do is to use a key logger okay
let me show you here
software okay you go to the software
section and you will see the key log
security section then there's this page
lists of keylogging software you know
pick one of them key logger is important
because then you actually know
scientifically how much you actually
type you know like most people program
especially programmers you know they
think oh I type all day therefore you
should press ctrl you know with cap
locks or whatever could crap know a
bunch of [ __ ] nonsense Emacs Emacs
[ __ ] you know they tell you to use
Emacs devotees know first of all you
want to measure
to tell me exactly how many keystrokes
you type a day okay so so get a keylock
software okay so that's that's on this
page then then then check out this
article how many keystrokes program a
type of day so once you have a keylogger
you measure it for a month then you know
how many how many keystroke then you can
read this article and compare so you get
idea oh how much I actually type am on
you know average you know whatever you
know like if like most programmers
whatever they type a day on average over
a year you know of their working days
okay it can be can be typed for ten
minutes like basically they only type
for ten minutes ten minutes a day that's
it you know if they type continuously
you know that's maybe that's surprising
okay you know if you don't believe me
believe me measure you know get a
keylock measure your keystrokes come
then you have a scientific basis about
how much you actually type then you can
decide you know whether you should learn
touch type or not the thing about touch
type typed touch typing is extreme is
efficiency you know it's like when you
practice let's say when you play
football you know American football you
know Rambo yoo-hoo
let's see who is bigger you know you
learn and lime other people American
football you know you that's a
professional sport
okay well suppose you are doing kung fu
you know you you must have watched
confuse you know they talk about you
know all the techniques training every
day and thinking about how to fight you
know or even ma MMA you know mixed
martial art today they if if they're if
you are professional you think about all
day you dream about it you know the
techniques or whatever same thing with
the mathematicians or programmers you
sleep you drink dream about math
problems and for program is simply so
they also so what I'm saying is that
yeah so
so why are you mentioning this
professional sports or whatever so what
I'm saying is that if you want to be a
professional okay you have to follow the
professional techniques you know if you
know for example football they are
training whatever the proper ways to run
for example if you are a professional
pianist there is a proper posture you
know if you are a competitive
competitive pianist you know when you
grew up you want to be a pianist you
know you have to practice just like
tennis you know practice hours you know
three hours a day then you know music
theory whatever and when you practice
it's not just random you you there's you
know lots of developed techniques you
have to sit in a certain way your
fingers you know must type in a certain
way okay same thing with the
professional football you know whatever
professional athlete running you know
you have to there's some or marathon you
know there's a you know practice or a
weight training weightlifting you know
there are ways you developed you know to
increase your power of performance truly
you know not just you know if you just
you know like if you just think oh I'm
gonna be a pro football player without
going to professional training you know
not you know I'm not going to be okay
well you know past maybe but not today
today you there's a lot of scientific
you know oh maybe you have to read books
so you have to so they are developed
techniques same thing applies to typing
so so once you so if you really want to
type you know given you know a certain
amount of typing tasks you have to date
to every day if that is a good quantity
okay now if you touch type you'll be
fine you do touch type you know if it's
not too big you touch type you can do it
for a year no problem if you do not
you're gonna have a problem because if
you don't follow the techniques you but
you have to do this amount of fixed
amount of a walk
you're gonna take you know two three
times longer
and you gonna have to get tired and
you're gonna you know have problems so
so anyway anyway I went on a long kind
of digressed a lot but my point is that
whether you should learn touch-type it's
actually it's not truly important it's
not like oh you have to
it's like depends on you how much you
type you know so if you want to learn it
that's great if you don't you know if
you are a programmer you know you you
don't have you know you don't write
documentation
you don't write blogs you don't have to
learn touch-type that's the thing yeah
that's the thing about touch-type in
fact you know another okay let me talk
about another thing about touch-type is
that in fact most people do not because
because touch type including programmers
I think most people most programmers do
not touch type because touch typing is
actually a kind of a learned skill you
have to actually spend an hour for a
month to actually get you know start to
touch type you know 50 words per minute
so it's kind of a quiet skill and and
yeah so most people don't and and it's
okay because you know you don't really
need if you don't touch you know if you
don't you're not a writer and and also
let me mention another thing about touch
typing okay let me mention another thing
about touch typing it's this go to type
in section then let's go to oh yeah most
people programmers in fact you know in
particular they don't touch type but
they say oh I touch type you know like
when you talk about these things people
you know like took not not able to touch
type is like a stigma okay it's like you
don't want to go out you know as a
programmer you don't say oh I don't I
don't know how to touch type you know so
people don't say it but rather they say
oh I touch type but in my own way like
you know everyone is this their own way
of touch typing like
they think so let me tell you you know
don't don't living a fantasy okay let me
tell you how to do you did how do you
determine whether you actually touch
tight like this girl cover you no takers
power you know a blanket blanket oh okay
cover your hand on top of your can put a
towel on your keyboard and try to walk a
lot what works like that for ten minutes
if you can you touch you do touch type
if you cannot no you don't touch type
you don't touch to type in your [ __ ]
own way you don't touch type period okay
that's how you judge how whether you
touch type or not you know gun don't
don't kid yourself you know we are by us
you know so that's about touch typing
okay so and by the way it's not you know
necessary like that you have to learn it
it just depends on how much you type so
okay that's about touch typing and
there's some other questions about okay
I've been talking a lot today so you do
so you so Sean says you do touch type
corty on a go
ergonomic keyboard and what's a go P so
so what I'm you say so what I'm saying
let's go back to the how many program
how many type you type a day and key dog
right get a key dog and yeah let's talk
about layout something about layout so
they are you know different software
layout keyboard layout okay so so these
I have like 30 articles or about layout
and I want to show you this have you
seen this song like to show you my web
pages so this is interactive let's let
me show you this there is this
interactive oops tablet all in
to active cha frequency counter so you
know it's fun to use I did I wrote this
JavaScript app to you know to compute
you know the key letter frequency so I
have the letter frequency in English and
also computer languages character
frequency and on this page you can
measure JavaScript : + C C++ Java you
know you can see what characters
punctuation characters are most
frequently used for that language and
also include has cow I think I added
Haskell recently so Haskell so you know
you just copy your code let's go through
my code okay good let's go to code
somewhere and let's go through okay so
let's go to code let's see okay so we
got here is a big you know 500 lines of
JavaScript code so you go to click this
page select or paste and magnify and you
can see the character count so coma is
the most used most frequent in
JavaScript after that it's parentheses
then period okay so that's about that so
what I want to talk about yeah the
keyboard layout so they are keyboard
layout so where is it
keyboards layout so they are different
layouts I kind of spent a long time
talking about this today I wonder if I
should good morning Danielle so Sean
says oh girl Docs okay Oh Google Docs
okay Docs is great so okay I don't tell
up Amy have a break let me drink so I
got five people watching now great
this is energy drink by the way so this
is this is this is Spain this is like
red poor but cheap brana's name when
nameless brand cheap version then as
usual the grape juice 100% juice grape
juice of grape flavor did you know that
today the veggies and fruits we eat are
very different from let's say 400 years
ago you know so today we have you know
orange you know orange grapes big red
waves of green grapes seedless grapes
and watermelon and whatever melons you
know few hundred years ago they are like
ten times smaller five times smaller
maybe also it's or engineering D and you
know also engineered all the you know
fruits and veggies are engineered by us
oh my god I talked a lot and then stop
talking so so back to so we got actually
we got a lot of things to talk about we
haven't we gotta talk about keyboard I
gotta answer the question here but
basically the other thing he's kind of
asking is about he's talking about lay
keyboard layouts
okay so keyboard layouts let's go to
keyboard layouts so this I have this
article that's a survey of keyboard
layouts so you have Corti keyboard
layout means you know the lead letter
arrangements on your keyboard so you
have quarry Barak you have programmers
for AK and I give analysis of their
efficiency for example in particular
programmers will rag I detail there's a
issue about a efficient layout for
numbers you know number row
you know promise layer programmers
warrick layout and also french layout
they invert the number in symbols for
the number row so when you type the
number key it actually types another
symbol instead you know like normally
when we type a numbered row on top it's
a number but the paramus will rack they
swap it so you know that in order to
type numbers you actually do you have to
press the shift key and this is done
also for French keyboard layouts so I
also have a articles about French
keyboard layout and the German keyboard
layout efficient German keyboard layout
and efficient French keyboard layout you
know and French trader frequency and
German data frequency and also Chinese
input method and Japanese input layouts
in phonetic you know I teach I teach you
you know like I study you know these
things and about efficiency so here this
article you can learn about how to type
Japanese even if you don't know [ __ ]
Japanese
you know like right now you can just go
to your operating system or you go to
Google Gmail they have a choice that
lets you choose Japanese input system or
Chinese input system so you can learn
you can actually type [ __ ] Japanese you
know by reading this article and also I
show you the Japanese layout they they
have also great varieties of input
systems now input systems is getting
more complex you know yeah I got a lot
to talk about so here is a Chinese input
methods you can also learn to type it in
fact you can do it in Emacs
I have article but anyway just so just
such such food kasaa Emacs Chinese input
you will see the article and with step
by step instruction of how to insert
Chinese yeah I'm not going to do it even
though it just take two minutes but
anyway so I want to show you so input
method so first of all we have layouts
okay so first of all we have the layout
let me talk about the layout layout
keyboard layout so first of all we have
the different layouts for English
language
now most of them excuse me most Muslim
are designed for efficiency of input so
you know so this program is for racks so
I was saying I have article that discuss
whether if you swap the number row with
symbols is that actually more efficient
so I have article they are here a vision
layout phone numbers this is a
scientific study
okay don't believe you know whenever you
want to say something about this
keyboard thing most people vast
majorities he people's opinions you know
you see that they talk about oh I like
this way I like that way your caps-lock
or whatever it's all based on habit you
want to based on scientific as much as
past
scientific methods so anyway excuse me
oh that's so bad excuse me enemy coffee
okay I'm back so what I'm saying is that
so I studied here you know efficiency
lay out for numbers you know I studied
oh actually this is another thing this
is about arrangement of letters of the
numbers Howie
which way is most efficient but there's
another issue about about keyboard
layout is inverted number row better so
I also made the study of that it is not
is it it's not better okay in any
absolute since it's better
only if you for certain kind of typing
tasks so programmers for Ag if you are a
C programmer well maybe it's better okay
but if you are you know if you are a
science scientific programmer or math
mathematician it's you know you swap the
numbers it's not good you think you know
it's very inefficient
so this programmers ball rack is not
necessarily good event depends on what
programming language you use most of the
time and also depends on what kind of
type of programming you are you know
doing your job
so anyway this our code discussed lots
of these layouts then there are also
some efficient they are designed for
German you know German language of
French or Portuguese so anyway this guy
has a question about layers okay let me
talk about these so let's see what do I
have any comments comments comments guys
so let's stop so the so I'm saying
layout okay
yeah so this given so-so layout is the
first step to type well first of all you
need a keyboard hardware okay then then
the other issue is the layout the
arrangement of letters but but after
that but how do you type for example
this math symbols for example it's
magnified let me show you how do you
type that how do you type that Delta how
do you type for example the math symbol
Delta for example how do you type a
right arrow you know how do you type a
cat face cat cat face yeah cat face
emoji you know so you cannot type this
let me show you how to type Chinese then
so set input method okay
Chinese pinging okay let's type the word
love okay
this dramatic let's say love okay you
see that is the character for love in
simplified Chinese that is okay let's
say my dear lover okay you know you add
honey okay so you say you you you say
like this
okay so that's like my dear my beloved
you know that's how you type Chinese ok
so let's switch back
[Applause]
oops where my god my software cheese and
vorak and everything is good now I need
to exit the input method in Emacs
so that's command X no way meta X meta X
what God save before entitled wait this
is good
yeah let's let's forget that oh yeah so
basically I want to code the switch
input method to switch back to english
so what are we saying so Chinese so yeah
so you see all these characters you see
easy all these characters they are not
on your keyboard your keyboard is like
you know 30 keys four letters so in
order to type all these you need what's
called a input method now for example
I'm typing an arrow like are a four
arrow that's a brief or Sun I need to
get out of the Chinese input method
let's see
I forgot what's a command so let's open
saw Emacs input method so Daniel says
I've mentioned that I'm practicing vorak
this has been going on for weeks form
four months I think and maybe thirty
word per minutes
yeah only thirty which is kind of worse
then I can do with Corti I'm more
comfortable with quality I need to
switch yeah but you are also yeah you
are doing Daniel so you are trying to
learn for AK meanwhile trying to retain
your quality skill that's not good you
you know you're gonna take you one year
to learn more AK you have to do if you
really want to do it do it code turkey
you know take a month like summer
vacation or whatever
pick one month then you know don't don't
ever touch type Cody again don't you
know you know if you want to learn more
I just focus on ball rack one hour a day
after one month you will be sixty what
four minutes for sure sixty is you know
more than most people can you know like
it's kind of like what people average
people can do yeah yeah so yeah you know
because if you try to learn more rack
you know but meanwhile try also try to
retain quality you know that that's
gonna you are not going to learn more AK
mud you know that's my advice because I
know you know anyway okay there it is
Chinese Emacs Chinese input so this page
shows you how to toggle input method
yeah that's the command I want to call
toggle input method okay finally I'm
back in English okay so what I'm saying
is that if you want to type math symbols
if you write math or if you want to type
Chinese or Japanese or Indian or Russian
you know The Critic Cyrillic
after that you know or you know a rabbit
you know you need to type things on not
on your keyboard that's when you need
what so called input method including
you know this abbreviation right arrow
left arrow up arrow you know this is
also a method to input so that that's
also usually you don't call this input
method but it is actually technically
it's also an input method
so anyway input method is about when you
need to type something that's not on
your keyboard you know you don't have a
key you know a lot of situations you
have that situation you know it's it's
it's so input method in your senses and
use are necessary useful so so yeah I
was talking about keyboard layout then
you have input method now there is
another thing related okay that is
shortcut layout most people don't know
this you know you have you know hacker
keyboard hackers already mechanical
keyboard you know forum they don't know
about this including all the Emacs
idiots elite you know the people let me
tell you so what what is the exceeding
on a second
oh my god that that way now so anyway
what is the the shortcut key board
shortcut layout so you have the letter
layout you have input methods the other
thing you have is a shortcut layer most
people don't think of these short Caleta
layout is for example copies control-c
paces ctrl V and so on and Emacs you
have a bunch and V in V are you ever you
know lots of others you know a lot a lot
of them too and also in Photoshop and
also the shortcut later layout is also
it's also there's a lot of fishin C
involved in fact the shortcut layout is
if you are Emacs user or vim or
Photoshop user shortcut layout is
actually more important than the the
keyboard later layout because if you
measure I have measured you know if you
go to some Emacs key statistics I have
measured because for us for programmers
for programmers the the keystrokes you
type majority of them at least half of
them depending on actually dive into
many on the person but on average most
most of the keys you type are actually
not typing you know not not not you know
not typing something straight like that
but rather editing like opening a file
switch you know go to tired you know
close the buffer or move to forward work
backward you know new paragraph new new
file and so on things like that copy and
paste and so on
copy paste switch window you know so the
majority of your keystrokes are actually
shortcuts not just you know input so
therefore if you are concerned about
hand health
the shortcut layout is more important
than the letter layout you know that
like partying and Borak like if you are
thinking or whether should I'd learn
more AK you know so so remember that if
you are you know a programmer and you do
a lot programming then shortcut layout
is actually more important this advice
to Photoshop you know users or any 3d
software users as well so anyway I
talked about a lot of things today so
back to the question so so he says yeah
so and also yeah he was singing about
talking about when you have a layout
some of the layout has layers what so
called layers which means when you you
hold down some modifier in the letters
change for example shift key is layer
shift you know it's one layer basically
my opinion about layers is that don't
use it you know it's the best that you
don't have any data at all one just one
single layer if you need to type any of
these any other characters not on your
keyboard use a key you know there's a
lot of techniques for it for example a
brief is the most efficient in Emacs or
Microsoft Word okay it's also available
and available in the other editor setup
brief and also what was I going to say
so
oh yeah he's talking about layers so
layers for example what are layers let
me show you layers let's go to software
and go to Mac you see you see these
characters symbols those are on Mac now
how do you type that if you press the
option key down then let me show you
so show show keyboard okay come on
where is it oh oh here it's already
shown here you see if I hold down the
shift key you can see that you see how
they change now if I hold down the
option key you see they're changing to
change into Unicode some some of these
Unicode symbols this this these symbols
has been with Matt since 1990 at least
you know yeah Mac had this you know when
Windows don't have that so anyway so
this is what layers layer is about you
know they let you type alternatives you
know symbols or somewhat rarely used
symbols so what I'm saying is that don't
use it don't use layers don't you know
that it's you know because they are very
engli efficient and also holding down
any model modifier key the concept of
modifier key is the worst for repetitive
strain injury don't have you know if you
can don't you know remove all such
shortcuts instead instead of use key
sequence instead for example for example
in soft like this it's all key sequence
for example I want to open a new file
look at now look at the left panel look
at the key I press ok I'm going to open
a new file so you see I'm pressing space
C dot then Emacs asked me to open a file
you know that's all okie sequences you
know don't I you know don't hold ctrl
hold down control meta whatever that's
no good banned them I also have article
here it's under key bindings that's
about this so the
sections is is all about shortcut
layouts the study of efficiency of short
curly outs okay so that's that's that's
that's that let's go back to
Oh God today I talk I talked a lot
there's one more question so this the
other guy's question is about so he says
I use oh yeah so he's his question is
about Kinesis keyboard versus model
Canisius advantage versus versus
keyboard IO so this is Kinesis
this is Kinesis that's what I use I
showed you many I showed I showed my
Kinesis many times that's a that's my
Canisius keyboard on top is the on top
is a it's a number pad I programmed it
as function keys so so it's all function
keys so so I'm using Kinesis you know
for like four years now for since when
since 2000 2000 16 august very good I
recommend it ok if you want to buy it
buy for my website I have video reviews
here as well and there's another great
keyboard actually all of this here are
great but this keyboard IO it's also
great but I never actually used it I
only tried it for like you know two
minutes so I I don't I cannot give you a
good opinion about it but from the
design point of view I think it's very
good it's excellent so but his question
is like is kind of like for small hand
which is better is Kinesis better or
keyboard IO I'm afraid I cannot say you
know even I mean because you know this
can you know because mostly because I
haven't used keyboard IO I don't have it
you know I only tried it for 2 minutes
but the the what I'm what I want to say
is that about keyboard is kind of
details you you really you can you
you cannot get the answer from people
you really have to try it yourself
because you know this your hands your
hand how you type it's all intricate you
know words cannot explain it really so
you cannot just you know like a lot of
people of course a lot of people who are
also fans of keyboard then you know they
read about all these keyboard like I'd
you know like I do you know then they
cannot decide or whether this is better
or that is better but I like this
feature but that one doesn't have that
feature but that one however has the
other feature I like so you know geeks
you know make lot kind of decisions you
know thinking about these kind of things
a lot as opposed to some other type of
people they just buy it you know you
don't they don't they don't spend not
much time you know worrying about these
little details
anyways so between you know I cannot say
you just have to try it yourself I
cannot really say which one is you know
better they are about the same price by
the way the keyboard I oversees the
Kinesis
so yeah you you have to like have you
know you know not you have to like used
it both of them for you know for a week
actually to actually really say for
certainty your opinions about them okay
that answers that question
but I think that's it for today because
I talked about quite a lot things today
so I talked about 18 minutes yeah so a
lot comments I think let me read the
comments
so let me see the comments arrow try
again let's see cold turkey yeah
Danielle's cocky five layers okay yeah
oh go ducks yeah almost all those they
like layers I don't think it's a good
idea yeah but you know my opinion is
usually unusual but here's why I say you
know you know I saw I look the issue you
know really I believe you want to stir
you want to look at scientific way okay
now first of all it really depends on
how you how much you type just like I
said about touch typing okay measure it
you know so once you know how much you
actually type you know maybe you don't
type that much when you don't type that
much layer is a good thing it's actually
a good thing because layer is a standard
way to type you know Alton you know
Unicode symbols it's a standard everyone
knows you know there's lots of tutorials
on the web you know it's a common it's a
normal thing you don't have to spend
extra time to learn how to set up a
brief how to set in Emacs how to set up
you know type you know what's a code
point for some math symbols you don't
have to you follow you know most what
people do you know it's not like Linux
you spent one hour every day trying to
configure it you know all right I need
to config the font to this you know so
so yeah if you don't have hand problems
you don't take you know by statistics
you don't type that much yeah cool you
know go for layers that's you know you
can you know there's nothing wrong with
that but what I'm saying you know my
this here's what I think okay I think if
you really type a lot you know so what
do you mean type a lot give us a
concrete example example in competition
let's say there's a marathon you know
there's a marathon for runners you know
they really run you know two hours
faster then you know the speed a run is
fast
then you can do for 10 minutes running
anyway you know so marathon is a
competition you know widely popular
fears in the same way there is no
marathon foe
you know typing but but they are you
know that's what a lot of people do you
know jobs you know there used to be
data entry crooks so you know imagine
there's a you know usually the typing
competitions they last only for one
minute that's not realistic okay like
online there's lots of typing websites
you know you could you know typeracer
you compete you know like how fast you
can type o 120 words per minute you know
but those are not realistic realistic is
you know you continuously you know you
if you have a competition type
continuously for one hour that's kind of
more realistic a little bit more
realistic the more realistic is that you
type you know you don't continuously
type but however you keep typing like if
you are a writer you keep typing the
whole day but but you know which breaks
a lot breaks you know you think about
things you know but you have to type a
lot you know several hours anyway so
what I'm saying is that so if you
actually type a lot okay oh if you have
a hint pen you know you you are you know
you maybe you visit some doctors for
your hand then you will understand I
think then what I'm saying is I didn't
you will see that the layers approach
let's say you are a mathematician your
job is to type math formulas every day
you know hours typing math formulas so
what I'm saying is that then then you
are know when you really actually do
this lots of quantity of work you are
know then you know layers is no good
modifiers you know oh press you know mod
one - you know four layer what mod - 4
layer - that's not good that's
inefficient one slower and it hurts your
hands it it you know for the same amount
of typing
you know using layers using the modifier
key do more harm to your hand
oh yes oh okay so so showing is saying
yeah so it's showing saying is there's a
layers you know they have special layers
that is designed to do some markers your
markers are good so for example instead
of pressing ctrl alt shift s you can
just press you know a specific modifier
like modifier s yeah that's good so that
is like a macro feature I mean so that's
good
but what I'm saying okay is shown
possibly you might try what I am saying
is that even better is to read up your
layers like you have our go Docs you
have several thumb keys right try to try
to remove over them so instead you know
whatever mark was you do make the
beginning a key sequence as the as the
assume as instead of layers so for
example let's say you have three
modifier keys smart one month to month 3
on your oviducts for example so remove
all the layers instead make make this
this week is not one not two monthly
into a leader key now you know leader
keys right leader key is basically the
first key of a key sequence make them
into a special you know leader key then
follow whatever so modifier s will be
you know modifier you know release the
key then press s instead of holding
modifier so I think that is more
efficient okay so last one the imager
oh so this is your setup great looks
great
so you have you have a number-pad by the
way is this programmable keypad is it a
programmable is it just a number pad or
is it the programmable keypad now if
it's just a number pad
did you actually remap the keys so they
actually search workers function keys oh
it's just ducky okay
yeah so they yeah so it works like a
number pad key but same thing with my
you know I have here it's also just a
number pad it's not a programmable
keypad but however a Mac or Linux or
Windows you can program them so they you
know they they function as key markers
which is what I do okay so yeah number
pad yeah okay so I think that's it for
today thank you guys for coming
yeah so that's let's see let's see we
talked a lot topic actually let me take
one minute to summarize we talked what
we talked about we talked about music
classical music romantic music park and
least and then we talked about let's see
yeah at least how least music is oh is
merciless and groom then we talk about
dance music dance frenzy Brenna's dance
music electro house and cute chicks and
you actual dance music this I recommend
mpi a three then we talk about Miami
hotlines hotline Miami hotline Miami OST
this is great dance music then we talk
about let's see
vedat so cuz I read it it's my like sod
you know you can
sorry fanclub you can
hey Daniel so you can post comments
there and so keep your layout Chinese
input Chinese input in Emacs Emacs
command statistics war akibo Kinesis
keyboard efficient layout yeah okay so
thank you guys bye