Hello guys. Hello guys. Good morning.
Welcome to another episode of talk show.
We are going to code waman language. I'm
going to give you a groundup tutorial on
how to program graphics in wuam language
such as this one you are seeing this.
This is called pedal curve. So yeah. So,
graphics for beginners wam language.
Okay. Uh if you are here, say hi. Love
to see your comments. Keep them coming.
If you are watching this offline, play
at 1.5 speed and skip around because I
ramble. Okay, let's start wam
language. Video check. Audio check.
Good.
Um so say hi for people
watching. So we started Wuang language.
Um so let's let me prepare a little bit.
Let's put this here and uh yeah the size
is good. So we're going to code negative
negative pedal. Okay. Uh let let me
explain. So go to today's talk show in
browser uh talk show
today. Okay. So we going to code this.
So let me show you first of all I have
the code already but I'm going to do it
from scratch. Okay. So let me show you
um the
code. So let's copy
it. Copy.
Go here. Showing browser. Okay, that's
today. And uh let's start a wolf
language. Paste the code here. Pop it
out. Uh pop it out. So that's a woofam
language code. And uh if you don't know
already, look at my wuam language
tutorial. Just search for kasaw wam
language tutorial. You'll find
comprehensive tutorial on graphics and
everything. And also where to download
it's free since about three or four
years ago. Uh you can
download and if and uh uh and you need
to install uh Jupiter so that you get
graphics for the free download otherwise
you just buy uh Wuang language. Okay.
Then you get the
notebook. So yeah. So you got the
tutorial and then you got uh my wolf
language t- t t t t t t t t t t t t t t
t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t
t t t t t tutorial, my packages for Wam
language for plank curves that's very
relevant for what we are doing today. Uh
so this is written like 30 years ago and
I updated uh this year last year. So I
did the live stream updating it uh you
know and so it can draw all these. So
what we are going to do today is to show
you how do you actually program this. So
for example this is uh parabola optical
properties
um and you can so all you have to say is
the formula and the say a length and say
the light source position and it can
draw these rays. So that's the uh you
know so you can draw many things uh
kissing osculating circle uh evolute
imolute
uh all sort of things. So we're going to
show you how to do that how to program
this. Okay. And in particular there's
one uh pedo curve. So this is what we
are doing related today.
Pedo. Um yeah. So then there is um so go
back. Then there is woof mod which is
allows me to code wam language in
emacs. So I'm using kafly keys and I'm
using vora keyboard. Okay. So let's
begin. So unit v. Um so we actually
updated the code few days ago. Let's
see. the Excel talk show
uh wolf
language f emac
lisp ped curve so this is uh March 23rd
we did this and we got the code updated
here so let's begin from this okay copy
select or
paste so let me just show you first of
all what the what what does this thing
do. Okay.
Copy and then Okay. So, let's see. So, I
I don't want that.
Close. New wrame
notebook. Paste it
there. Okay. And
magnify. Let's say 125.
Okay. Then here is the
code. Control shift D to split them into
two different cells. Okay. So evaluate
this code. Shift enter. That's done.
Then you can just type this and it'll
plot it. So first of all control shift N
to make it type set. You can see
beautiful type setting. So then shift
enter.
Fantastic. So that's what we going to
do. I'm going to explain the code. Okay.
So you can see now we can change the
point change the point um here. So let's
say uh one and
one. So at the x = 1 y = 1. Shift enter.
Then you got a different graphics skewed
and you can do a animation. So let's say
for example yeah for for you know for
fun let's do a animation
uh let's
see okay manipulate then this
expression and uh Then
uh let's see what is how do you type the
uh
correct? Yeah. So uh manipulate from
let's say
t from
uh zero to one. Okay. Now I don't
remember that's the so manipulate take
two arguments. First one is the
expression. The second one is a variable
a range and a
range. Uh and uh so now let's change it
to so x is one. Let's move y from zero
to one. So this would be t.
Now I don't know if this is correct
syntax but let's try it first.
Fantastic. You can see. So now you got
the
[Music]
slider. You got the SL. Okay, let's
magnify more. You got the slider and you
can move it. Fantastic. Can you see
that? So this is the point moving up.
You see that blue dot over
there? You see? So this this this curve
I mean these lines forms a curve. So the
red dots is a parabola. Okay. Um
basically y = x² and uh
then the black lines they they form a
curve. This is called the envelope of
the lines. So this new curve is called
the negative pedal of the parabola with
respect to this blue point blue point.
Okay. So
that okay so that is kind the demo of
this code. So the code is just this part
uh this this part. Okay. Above that is
the documentation the in inline
documentation for that. Okay, let's
begin with let's so we're gonna write
this
code. Let's see where do we begin. Let
me Okay, let let me just begin to tell
you how how do you do
graphics? Blue hour. Hi. Always love
mathematics
uh mathemat math contents. Fascinating.
Yeah. So, we're going to show you how to
generate graphics. Okay. So, let me show
let me just uh begin to show you. Okay.
So let's put it back. Let's create a new
uh woof language. Pop it out. Pop it up.
Okay.
Uh so wam language when you want to draw
a line or a circle they are represented
by what's called p uh graphics
primitives. So for example uh let's type
it here. So because emac is um so circle
at 0.0 and radius one. Okay. So if you
evaluate
that shift enter that's that represent a
circle at this center and that radius.
Okay. And to represent the line all you
have to do is just say line and uh then
a list of points. Let's say 0 0 to uh
01. Okay. So if you evaluate it it
returns itself. you know
when it doesn't do anything special but
it just represent the the line or
circle.
Okay. Now if you want to so so these are
called graphics primitives. So you have
circle, you have line, you have points,
you have uh rectangle uh and also there
are 3D ones such as tube
uh a polygon and things like that. Also
polygon um can represent a 2D graphics.
Let's say polygon. Let's let's just do
some. Okay, so polygon and we want
polygon is a list of points. Let's say
uh 0 0 1 and let's say uh two and three.
Okay, just some random numbers. Okay,
so shift enter. So you know it tells you
you know this is a number of points
three embedding dimension two. So this
is a polygon in two dimension. This is
this output is kind of makes it easier
to see because usually when you have a
polygon you have thousands of line uh
thousands of
points you know. Yeah. Yeah. Especially
in 3D. In 3D then you uh
uh anyway so let me continue. Okay. So
these are called graphics
primitives. Okay.
So now you can also you know check out
my wuan language tutorial and then you
go down there's a section on graphics
which will cover uh all the things we
talked talked about graphics programming
okay so there are many topics so first
of all is how to plot this is simple you
know you don't have to program anything
you can plot services pie
chart and so on okay and then uh or uh
parametric 3D
surfaces. Then then here is about
related to programming. So you got
graphics primitives. You got points, you
got line, you got polygon we uh covered.
Then you got text, disk, circle,
rectangle. Then you have 3D uh
threedimensional graphics primitives,
points, line, polygon, sphere, cuboid,
tube. Okay. So by itself they by
themselves they don't do anything. But
if you want to show it as a graphics
what you do is you say
uh not not
graphics graphics 2D. Okay.
So GH
uh what
GH graphics. Okay. So if you want um to
actually show them then you say
graphics. So for example graphics circle
one. You see now you got a graphics. Now
if you want to show axis then you have
to say options
uh let's say
axis true shift enter. So you see so so
this is great. So if you want to show
all these for example then you put them
in a list. Okay. So give a list all that
uh and remove uh remove
that.
Copy paste run. Uh I got error. So yeah.
Okay. You forgot the comma. Comma to
separate
them. Copy.
Paste. Run. You see we got a circle, we
got the line. Um, let's show
axis. Axis true. Shift enter. So you see
now this polygon the uh the line and
polygon they overlap. So let's change
the line to uh let's say 21. Okay. Copy.
paste run. So you see you got a circle,
you got a line, and you got the kind of
a
triangle. Uh let's say axis true.
Okay. So that's the fundamentals. So
this is very powerful. So this is
basically almost all you need to know
about programming graphics in Wuam
language. Okay. So all you have to do
um all you have to do where is my talk
show page? Hold on a
second. Show talk
show. You see all you have to do to draw
any of these fancy graphics. You see
there are just lines and points is to
create you know just create this circle
and you know the position and and that's
it. That's all you have to do the very
fundamental just remember that. Now if
you want color let's do it again. So if
you want to have color uh let me explain
to show
the graphics
primitives
use this graphics function.
Okay.
Um, let's
say put them inside the graphics. Okay,
that's how you show. Okay, next. What
about
color?
Color thickness.
are
called
graphics directives. Okay. So all we
have to do is very simple. All you have
to do is let's say you want the circle
to be red. So you put inside the list
again and let's just say
red. Okay. So now you'll get a red
circle. Shift enter.
Fantastic. And if you want the line line
to be blue, so you have to say put
inside the
list, then in the beginning just say
blue. Okay. Uh so but so you got a few
just like CSS some colors are named. So
you can say blue, but you can also say
uh for example blue. Let's just show it.
Okay, you got a blue line and you can
type them by itself. Let's say red run
it. It re it returns a square
representing red. You see? So, uh blue
is just blue. You see you got the you
got like 10 names also. Blue, red,
white, c, you know. Uh but you want a
general mechanism. You say hue. Okay,
hue.
uh hue
is like the rainbow
uh modeling of the color. So hue zero is
red. Then hue is
uh hue
uh brightness and saturation something
like that. Okay, let's say uh one what
one. Okay, that's red. Now let's say uh
five. So you got kind of brownish. So
and you can see the documentation for
hue. It'll show you a
table. So hue represents a color in HSB.
So that's hue, saturation, brightness.
That model color model has many
different ones. You also have you can
also use RGB color if you want. Okay. In
wam language. So this shows the model of
the using the
HS hue, saturation, brightness. Okay,
that's about color.
So So you got Yeah. So we got the color
and similarly. Okay. So not this one. So
let's show the other
one.
Um Okay. So let's move this here and
let's put that one here.
Okay, we got a color and similarly for
thickness. So let's say the polygon you
want to be
um
um you know if you don't want them to be
closed then you just use line instead.
So, but for now, let's say I want them
to be
uh okay, let's say
thickness. Okay, thickness 0
uh one. Okay, so that is a percentage
with respect to the graphics. Okay, so
let's show it.
You see now you got the thick thick line
line. Okay. So that's a basic that's
that's almost like like this is the
fundamentals of a graphics. You got
graphics
primitives to represent the the thing.
Then you put them inside graphics that
will show it. And if you want to control
color thickness and so on, you use these
uh so-called graphics directives. Okay.
So now that's one thing that's the
basics of wam language graphics here.
Okay. So next so so now we going to
start to get fancy. We want to draw this
thing. So what do you have to do is that
you want to draw you see the black lines
is the is what we want to draw. So how
do you get the black lines? You have to
find basically you need to find the
position of each line. So line remember
a line is represented by just this you
know just this line two points or a list
of points you know they they they'll
draw it. So to draw this all you have to
do is you you have to generate a list of
lines and you have to know their uh you
know like a vector two positions. Okay.
Now that part is mathematics. So to draw
this one you need to know this is called
negative pedal. So you need to know what
is uh you know like like where are the
points? How do you draw them? So so
that's defined
uh negative pedal is kind is this is the
definition mathematics mathematically.
Okay. So given a curve and a fixed point
uh
O draw a line from O to any point P on
the curve. So given a curve the red
curve and and the fixed point O such as
the blue
dot then draw a line from O to any point
P on the curve. So let's pick a point P.
So let's say this
one. Then draw a line perpendicular to
line OP and passing P. So you want to
draw a line passing P and perpendicular
to the O2P. So that's going to be this
line. Can you see it?
Uh okay. And then you just repeat this
for every point on the curve. So for
every dot on the parabola this red dot
for every dot you have you draw a line
the black line okay then you got these
black lines okay so that is that is the
mathematical definition of negative
pedal the I mean the construction okay
the the actual negative pedal means the
curve that is formed by the envelope of
these lines so you got this kind of
shape shape, teardrop shape. So
mathematically that the the formed curve
is called negative pedal. But the
construction is by you know drawing all
these black lines.
Okay. So that's what this code is
doing you know. So all we have to do is
you know just say uh you know the the
pedo point and then um you'll draw it.
So the code is here. The
code to do
that is here.
Okay. So now we're going to explain that
one. Uh so that one. So far so
good. So far so good guys. Say
something. So how long have I been? 30
minutes. Half an hour. So now it now
this is a harder part. So let me see how
do I go about
it. Yeah. So let's do this from scratch
because it's easier to do uh from
scratch. But and then we want to
um yeah let's do it from scratch. Let's
write this function from scratch.
Okay. Okay. So show uh show in browser.
Okay, this is existing code. Now let's
do it from
scratch. Okay, so let's put a new
um wam language paste. This is
description of pedo. Okay. So,
uh
program graphics program the negative
pedo. Okay.
So this part this a comment this is what
pedo means. So we going to stop simple.
So given a
curve
parabola by the
formula x x² let's just say that
okay for each point on the
curve and okay so another thing given a
point
Let's say
uh let's
say 01.
Okay. So x at zero uh let's say y uh
let's say one one.
Okay. This is called the pedo point.
Okay.
Now we want to
draw a
line passing a point
P on
parabola and uh we want to draw a
line L passing point P on the parabola.
uh given point O.
Okay, we want to draw a line passing
point P on the parabola and
is
per perpendicular
I don't have that shortcut. So, let's
create a shortcut. Let's digress and
create a shortcut. Perpendicular. So, uh
abbreviation
perpendicular. Okay. I don't have that.
So now I do evaluate the buffer.
Evaluate. Close it. So perpendicular.
Fantastic hand pen
saver. So we want to draw a line out L
passing the point P on parabola and is
perpendicular to the line
OP. Okay, that's what we want to do. And
we want to do this
for and we want to do this for many
points
P on the curve.
Okay. So let's remove that. That's the
thing we want to do. So first of
all, so list of points. So first of all,
we we going to draw the red dots, a list
of points for parabola. Okay. So what we
do is we want the point
primitive. We want to
map. Okay. We want to map points to a a
bunch of least uh parabola. Okay. So,
let me just do it. So,
um so what we want to do
uh
parabola.
Yeah. Parabola points.
equals
to equal equal equals to
um
table x and x² and x from let's say uh
-1 to
one in steps of let's say
uh
0.1 Okay. Something. Okay. Let's try
it. Fantastic. These are the points on
the parabola.
Okay. Now, this table function is very
powerful. It's similar to for example
Python's
um Python's
um comprehension list comprehension
idiotic term. Okay. So it's similar to
list comprehension. It's it's it's a way
to generate a list of or nested list.
Okay. So uh hold on a second before
anything. Let's do a
wait, let's do a screenshot of this. So,
we have a
record.
Fantastic.
And and let's put it
here. Showing browser today's talk show.
Go down. That's what we did. Fantastic.
Now back to this programming programming
this thing.
Okay. So now parabola points we got that
the a list of points. Now all you have
to do is you want each point to be a not
just a pair of numbers. You want to be a
with a
point graphics primitive. Oh I don't
have it here. So but but it's this one.
Okay. So
map map that to the par parabola list of
points. That's it. That's it. So run it.
Show it. You see you just add the point
in front. Each one represents a graphics
points. Okay. Then then what you do? Um
so actually so
um graphics points something like that.
Okay.
Um but let's just say dots dots equals
to that.
Okay. Okay. Then you got a bunch of
dots. Then what you do? So let's let's
uh evaluate it. That's that's what you
have
dots.
Okay. Then what's the next thing? Okay.
So we can show graphics now. So
graphics
dot
axis.
True. Fantastic. Beautiful. Is that
beautiful? Fantastic. We got a
parabola. Uh now we want to make it red.
So again just say
red.
Okay. Paste. Fantastic. And
beautiful. Now, for each one of these
point, you want the
line, you know, you want the pedo
um you you want the line that is
perpendicular to another line. Okay. So,
how do you do that? That's uh so that
would
[Music]
be linear algebra. We don't actually you
don't need need linear algebra. You just
need basic concept of vectors. This is
what you learn in kind of pre-calculus.
You don't even need calculus. You just
you need to know the vectors. You know
vectors move them around. How do you
make it perpendicular to another vector?
Things like that. Okay.
And I have not done you know I've done
this like 30 years ago. So I don't
actually
remember. So but but we got a code
remember. So let's see. We got a code
somewhere here we can grab. So looking
at it then I'll remember. So I'll show
you. Okay. We'll go this step by
step. Okay. So next next you want to
draw yeah so this is what we want to
draw. So, so first of all draw points on
parabola. That's what this do. Then next
uh next we want to
draw a
line that
is
perpendicular to line OP. Okay. and O
remember remember O is a given point in
our case it's one one
okay so let's say uh okay so given a
point given a point let's
say pedo points
uh how do you name it uh given point O
um
Yeah. Yeah. This is called pedo point.
Okay. So, so let's define the point.
Okay. So, one
one it's uh we need this
point pedal
points point equals to that. Okay. Uh
draw a line that is perpendicular to
line OP.
So uh so draw a
line let's say
this point okay so given a point let's
say this point is some point on parabola
uh that would be you know that would be
one of these points let's say
uh is a nice one 0 0 okay 0 is 0 0 is a
point on the parabola So let's deal with
this point first. Okay, we got a point
there. Then we also got the pedo point
which is you know which is the blue
one. Okay, so we got two points. That's
all we need. So next we need to draw a
line that is let's name this curved
point.
Okay. So we need to draw a
line such that it passes the curve
points and is perpendicular
to to pedo point to curve point. Okay.
So this is line
op. So let's do this line op.
Okay. Yeah. Line
op. Uh line op is very simple. It's
just list of two
points. Okay. One one is curve points
uh pedo points. The other one is curve
points. Okay. Very
simple. So this is line op.
Then now here is a line passing
P and
perpendicular to
OP. Okay, how do you do
that? Okay, so this is when you need
basic
vector. So you got a line. So this is a
vector. You want to find another line
which is two points. You want to find
another vector that is perpendicular to
that. Okay.
So, so let's look at the co uh code. I
forgot.
Okay. This this is ve basic vector uh
geometry. Hi man. Hi man. Hi Pio.
Uh
so well the the you know the so given
the vector you want to find another
vector that is rotated 90 degrees. So
all you have to do is you can kind of uh
multiply by s cosine. Okay if I recall
correctly. Let's see what I did
here. Oh yeah. So yeah. Okay. So I'm
using a faster trick. All you have to
do, okay, here's a trick. Given a vector
AB, you know, given a vector with
components X= to A, Y = to B. So AB,
right? So like this to find the
perpendicular vector, a vector
perpendicular to it is you reverse it.
So first you first of all you make them
negative both component negative then
you
just reverse one of the sign
okay we can try it okay so let's try
okay
so okay so given so let's
say let's say.1 one okay so suppose you
have a vector one one you want to find
the perpendicular vector rotated 90°. So
that would be you see that would be uh
-1. Okay. So how do you do that for
general in general
um example
um how do you so so so what you do is
you make them negative.
You make both of let's look at the code.
Okay. You make both of them negative.
Then you just
um reverse the second the sign of the
second part. Okay. So let's see if that
works. So make both of them
negative then reverse the sign of the
second part. So you got exactly that
works. So here's what to do. Okay. So a
line passing P and perpendicular to line
OP.
So to find a vector that
is
per perpendicular
to AB to vector
[Music]
AB is
uh
is
Okay. Uh what? Uh
wait. Oh, you just flipped you just
actually all you have to do is just
flipped the x component. Is that right?
Uh,
wait. Uh, what is what are we doing? Oh,
and we have to reverse. Oh, yeah.
There's one part you forgot. You have to
reverse.
So, so the new one is actually
BA no I don't
feel that's lousy question uh anyway so
I believe this is uh this is it okay so
let's say
uh to find the vector that is
perpendicular to vector AB. The result
is negative B A. Okay, this is kind of a
trick. You can work it out if you go,
you know, you you you go look up
Wikipedia on um on vectors. Okay, but
this is like a shortcut so we can test
it. Okay, uh graphics. Let's just
quickly test it. Uh let me show
you, you know, wam graphics. Okay. So,
graphics
line. So, for example,
um
clear let's say a a bb. We clear two
variables. Okay. Then a a equals to um
let's say uh
uh two. Okay. Then bb equals to let's
say three. Okay. So we have then vector
x vector equals to a
a bb. So we define we got a vector. Now
the per
ve would be equals
to negative bb aa. Okay. Uh wait
uh that
okay I believe. Okay so we can test this
by just drawing the graphics you know to
see if we got it right. So line. So
first of all you draw two lines. Okay
you draw two lines. That's one of them.
And uh make it a list. So one of the
first line is
uh 0 0 to
uh wait you need a list.
Okay.
02 x vector. So let's uh rename it ve
one ve two ve 2 is perpendicular to ve
one suppose. Okay. So so ve one is
uh uh ve one.
Okay zero to ve one. Okay. And make it
color red. Okay. and and the the second
one would be ve
two and make it blue. Okay, so we got
the code. Beautiful. So this code will
uh verify if our theory this
perpendicular vector is
correct. So we can go here, paste it,
run
it.
Fantastic. Can you see that? Beautiful.
So now if you change some variable,
would it still work? You see you, this
is the beauty. So you can change this to
uh let's say uh
2.5. Would that still
work? Uh now remember we want to show
axis because with
axis that
um make it easier to see x is true.
Okay. Okay. 2 3 becomes 3 -2 that's
perpendicular. Yes. Now let's say the
vector the let's change let's say
2.5. Shift enter. Would it still work?
Yeah. Seems so. Now let's say
um let's say nine. Make it big. Oh, it
still works. Now let's
say
nine.
Fantastic. We got orthogonal things.
So our theory is correct to find a
vector that is perpendicular to vector
AB just swap them and make one component
negative. Okay. Uh so it actually should
be
that. Okay. So along the way we learned
some vector geometry tricks. So now back
to our the thing we need to do. We got
the curve points, we got pedal points.
We need to draw a line passing the curve
points and perpendicular to these two.
Okay, so let's do
it. Um, so this is a new
section a line passing P and
perpendicular to line OP. Okay. So, we
just need to create a P line
uh
neck
P
line equals
to. So, we got these two point uh two
things we swap
them. Yeah. So, this would be a line.
[Music]
Uh this these are the two
coordinates, right? So okay. So you got
you have to now you need to do no more
vectors
because you need to translate them and
normalize them and stuff. Okay.
So yeah. Okay. So
you so the curve point actually we let's
use a different curve point because 0 0
is kind of
special. Um yeah so let's use a more
generic curve points something something
not um two and four let's say so you see
parabola points you know let's say uh
let's say two
two in steps of
0.5 okay so these are some points on the
parabola and one of them is you can see
two
four okay so Uh so let's change this to
24. It's a point on a curve.
Okay.
So so now we draw the negative line. So
what would it be? So it would be let me
show you. Okay.
So this is a vector geometry bas you
know very basic. So you
got curve points to to Peter points to
curve points. Okay. So
um so let's uh
let's so we talking. Okay. So so which
one is the vector? Yeah. So the vector
is from the pedo point two curve points.
Okay. Pedo
points
ped to a point on the curve. Okay. So
the vector would
be pedo vector equals
to curve points
minus pedo point. Okay, that is a
vector. Okay, then you want to so that
you know that line you know that line
segment you want to normalize it. So you
want to make it
um you want to make it with length one.
So what you do is you just say
normalize not
normal. Okay. So you just normalize
this make make them length one. Okay,
still in the same direction but length
one. Okay, so you got that. Then you
just
then so now that's a pedo vector. Now
you just want to turn it 90 degrees so
that it's perpendicular. So the new
vector
um
p line
uh this this actually let's name this
vector
op. Okay.
uh
op vector OP. Okay. Now the P
line vector P line would
be
you swap them.
swap them. So you say
reverse. Okay, you swap the x and y.
Then you make the last one negative. So
you have to do is
time
one. Okay,
so equals to that. So that this line
would
be perpendicular to this. Okay. Now
umh am I doing
good? Okay.
So okay so that you know so we can
actually try
it. Uh yeah so okay we can try it. So
now
graphics we want to draw vector op
um
I a
list
from 0 0 to vector P.
Wait, we need to draw several things.
Okay, so hold on a
second. So first of all, let's draw the
curve point.
Okay.
So there is a curve points
uh which is a
point.
Okay. Now let's see. Hold on a second.
Let's
see. Yeah. A point. So let's say
blue. So we got a curve points
then I mean this is a pedo point uh wait
this what uh curve points. So first
important thing is the pedo point. Okay.
So let's copy that again.
So the p
point is colored blue. Okay. Now the
curve point is colored red. The point on
the
curve. Okay. Got it? Right.
Then okay so you need a comma
then so you got we got the blue points
that and we got a red point that then we
want to draw a line from the blue point
to the red point. Okay. So a line from
uh p point to curve points.
Okay, let's say
pink. Do we actually have that color?
Yes. Show in browser. I mean, look up
the documentation. Wolf language
documentation. Pink. There's a word to
represent that color.
Fantastic. Okay. So
[Music]
then next we want want one more thing.
We want this perpendicular to to to
to this. Okay. But we can actually just
show it first. So that reduce the
mystery. Okay. So let me let me show it
first. Okay. Copy that. Copy. Go here
and let's paste
it. Oh, we got error. So we got extra
comma there.
Um, that's what what we want to
do.
Paste. Do
it.
Fantastic. We got a blue dot there. We
got the red dot supposedly a point on a
curve. Then we got a pink line. That
seems correct. Now remember to show
axis.
Okay. So let's go. Let's show axis.
Okay. So that we can actually
[Music]
see. And let's change I want the point
size.
Okay. Point size. And kind of make it
bigger.
05.
Okay.
Paste. Uh point size syntax is
incorrect. It should be
dot shift
enter.
Beautiful. Okay. Now let's now you see
it automatic automatically
um draw only the portion of the graph.
So you see so this point is the pedal
point but we are not seeing the 0 0. So
let's in let's put a plot
range plot range negative 1 2 1
um x axis y axis let's say uh
three so x is -3 to 3 y is -3 to3
Okay, do it
again. Okay, we got some issue. We don't
there is no option called plot range.
Okay, uh we need something else I think.
So what we have to this option is not
available. Okay, but it's available I
believe in
show. Okay, show takes two arguments.
The first argument is a graphics. The
second argument is whatever uh options.
So let's move that
to here. Okay. So the first uh
so x
graphics equals
to equals. So this is a graphics then
show
that copy
it paste. Do it. So we got one graphics
and the second one
uh list is not uh yeah so there's no
such option. I forgot what is the option
to limit the graphics to certain area.
Um you can say it by
options
at let's see what is the option
for aspect ratio axis access label axis
origin color output uh display function
format type frame
label image size label style plot range
clipping ing plot range
or yes there is a plot
range. So plot range is an option of
graphics. So why is
that why is my use of plot range not
um so what why is my use of plot range
not
Yeah, there's a power range right
one to one 3 time three. So why is my
power range not? Let's try
it. List is not a type of graphics. Why
is that?
list is not a type of
graphics. So that's graphics is
true. Uh what's going on with the plot
range? Let's see documentation.
Power range is an option for graphics
function that specifies what range of
coordinates to include in the plot.
Okay. So,
um plot range
automatic.
Yeah. Let's see. Plot region.
So plot
region background
sphere graphics
uh plot
region. Yeah. I let let me I want to get
um I want to find out what's wrong here.
This is a minor
issue. We shouldn't worry about it. But
I do want to show you
know specify the range and uh because
that way we can
see where our points are with respect to
the zero coordinate.
So we already this is already one hour I
think. Okay almost we almost done.
Um so why is the plot range plot range
list is not a type of graphics.
What I believe so plot range
or so that's part of the option of plot
range.
So graphics. Yeah. So that you see why
is that not working? So, let's try
again. Uh,
here. Close that.
Here. Paste. Let's see what does this.
Oh, we got the syntax
wrong. Why is
this? Did I spell it wrong?
plot range. Yes, we spelled
correctly. This is not a type of
graphics. Oh, right. The plot range is
not a function. It should be the arrow.
That's so silly. Silly me. Okay, my
mistake. Should be like that. An arrow.
Okay. So now we got it. So now let's do
it
again. Let's do the whole
thing. Wasted five minutes. There it is.
So you can
see you know we can see the with respect
to the you know the whole graphs. Now
let's increase this to
five pl increase power range shift
enter. You can see the blue is the pedal
point, the red is a point on a curve and
we draw a line. Now we want to draw a
line
perpendicular to this line and passing
the red point. Okay. Uh we almost done
one more step. Okay. So now one extra
line. So that line would
be let's say what color? uh let's
say
black. Okay. So that line would be a
line passing. Okay. So that line would
be ve vector
line. Okay. Uh so that line would be ve
vector pedo line plus we are doing
vector
arithmetics vector pedal line times
let's say 10
uh wait not not yet so vector pedal line
you want to translate to the p okay so
translate to
uh to p So P is curve
point. Okay. Then you want to increase
the length. Okay. Then you
just So wait. So
that
times nine. Okay. Increase that. I think
that's it.
do it. Okay. So, some some something is
wrong. Oh, we forgot the comma. Forgot
the
comma.
Uh,
no. Wait. Did
we Oh, lie. So
you line two points right? So yeah, so
this needs to be um we got uh so vector
pedal
line which is a vector then plus curve
points you move
it then you
magnify then you need the curve
points.
Um, wait. So, don't magnify that yet.
So, vector P
line plus curve
points. So, it would be curve
points. Yeah. So
uh wait so this line would
be starting with the curve
points
to two what's the other
point to
that times 9.
Okay. Okay. Let's try it. I hope this
will do
it. Okay. We missing. It's not showing
up. So, plot range. Let's increase the
plot range. Okay. So, yeah. God, we need
to
this increase the plot range.
Okay, let's make it easier now. Let's
see. There it is. But it's
incorrect. Our black line is
incorrect. Wait. So did we reverse the
um yeah we didn't reverse wait we
did so vector pedo line oh yeah so
wait so vector so that should
work vector pedo
line and it's
Uh there it is. We multiply wrong. So if
you want to multiply I mean so
anyway that is we kind of we you know
this is one step to draw all these black
lines. We kind of did it. Now we just
need to increase the length of the black
line. So let's do that and that'll be
it.
So we need to increase the length of
black line.
So, so
[Music]
um let's this line let's make so there
is another um primitive graphics
primitive in wam language that represent
lines infinite you know not just a
segment but
uh you know going in both directions. So
let's look at the entire list of
graphics primitives. So you got disk,
circle, rectangle,
raster. Um you
got okay line
polygon. Now the how uh let's magnify
magnify. Okay, you got line polygon. You
got let's click line. No, not that.
Let's see.
2D graphics object. There it is. So, you
got points, point size, line, half line,
infinite line. That's what we want. So,
just change this
to infinite line. Okay. So,
copy back to language.
Paste.
Beautiful. Okay. That's it for today.
Thank you guys for
watching. Now we reduced to
four people. Okay,
so hello
Cyu. Thanks for setting my slot up.
What? Please set skater three gator.
What? Okay, that's it. Thank you guys.
So, here is a code. Fantastic.
Um, we finished.
Um, let's see. Let's put it back. Color
it. Show in browser. So, we did this.
Fantastic. Thank you. If you like my
stuff, pay me.
Okay.info. Go
to.info all the way to the bottom.
Patreon or Amazon gift card or PayPal.
Okay. Pay me
$100 if you have a job and like my
stuff. Okay. Thank you. That's it. Any
other
questions? Now, Syu, this Syu guy don't
know what you're doing. He's a troll.