good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of our talk
show today's 2019
November 10th Sunday 3 o clock p.m. San
Francisco time and we need to talk we
have a lot to talk and today's main
topic is live coding plus tutorial of
Emacs Lisp so let's start brave and
let's see what's going on in saudi
discord Saudi fan club you know so I
want to thank to Emily and a lot of
people there who you know who helped
making the discord channel thrive and so
there's there's a lot interesting stuff
there's a lot photos of keyboards and
keyboards and real life pictures of
different cities and stuff so if you are
not there join up so discord you can
find the URL at let's go to my exit out
page show and you know sound Hawk show
page and you can see the discord channel
where is it okay here so join up it's
fun you know so good morning Matic so
technically it's like a fan club
you know how I asked you would you call
it but but you know you guys you know we
are we have certain interest you know
that converge together so you guys can
talk about that people can talk about
that you know whenever I have I you know
I've been thinking of starting something
like channels like that
in the past years there's always the
question you know how much how involved
should I be you know because if I'm too
involved then it just becomes a place
where everyone just go there and ask me
questions I think you know I cannot do
that because then is all the questions
just gonna ask me questions about Emax
you know things like that so and the
other thing is you know I you know it's
I thought you know it's always with me I
didn't want to like intrude too much so
on the on the other hand on the opposite
extreme the idea is that people just get
there and talk about you know well my
life string and my stuff that is that is
I don't think that is reasonable as well
so anyway so you know when you have a
question like that in your life you have
a lot of questions you know
so I usually look up so what do other
people do you know apparently there are
a lot many famous youtubers they all
program programmers celebrities and they
you know they they are far more popular
than me you know hundred thousand
followers or something and they so what
do they do so you know some youtubers
program youtubers they also have like
reddit channel dedicated to their stuff
and what they do well they they just
they are kind of they they they just be
normal okay I guess you know this is my
channel so you guys can talk about it
and go there you know that that's how
they do I guess so anyway so today's our
talk show we cannot talk about we gonna
do this
Emacs least the Wonderland of Lisp and
Emacs so let's start magnify and go over
here start saw start command log mod and
you can see all my Emacs commands
on the left window here if you guys have
questions comments comments and
questions okay so Emily says maybe it
always is after you wake up
the crazy cannot work where it's always
morning yes good morning hello beautiful
people
hello to Jack Zack Republic and hello to
London and Germany and London where he
is but we missing part bodies getting
pissed about my random schedule yeah my
random schedule is a problem so cuz our
talk show so let's let's start saw snot
hawk show today's state is a new page
link it as a list footage here remove
that open it show in browser okay and
we're gonna talk about we gonna talk
about fantastic stuff and here is a
wonderful song you can check it out well
yeah in the link is in discord Alice in
Wonderland looking through the and
through the looking-glass this this was
my favorite book I read it several times
over over different years I would say it
was my favorite book of all times was
not today because because after all this
is just kind of like a nonsense I mean
so anyways our talk show so this is what
we're gonna do we are going to write a
command we're gonna do live coding of
emag based write a command to open a
buffer in browser for example this page
right now I can press a button let me
show you that
okay so press a button it shows in
browser and I can hold
Sokol command you see some opened in
brave okay enter it shows the page in
brave browser okay
and then I have another command let's
see this command is open link in brave
it will open the current the the URL
under the cruiser so let's call it open
link in brave okay so it opens that
linking browser so there are two
different commands one is open the
current buffer in browser the other one
is open the link under cruiser in the
browser and today we're gonna we are
going to try to merge these two commands
into one okay so this is this kind of
our topic zone to talk about actually so
related to these two topics so let's go
back to where - here and so you see I
have two commands to open open buffering
brave and open linking brave you see
they are browser specific that is you
don't just open the default browser you
I want to specifically open you know
this buffer or link in gray browser now
they are there are variations of that
command you can see let me show you here
variations of the command so you can see
open in google chrome so we have open in
Google Chrome browser
the current buffer or open link in
chrome so that's Google Chrome then you
also have Firefox versions you also have
great browsers versions then you also
have Safari versions wait and missing
ones open link in Safari
but anyways for each browser you have
two versions of open the background
buffer or open the link under crew
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
write this command from scratch you know
the code is already here you can just go
there and copy it and use it if you like
but since we are doing live code into
Tokyo I'm gonna teach something about
each email beast so you can learn from
but Emma Emily is a massive Emacs Lisp
good morning but you are late so hello
beautiful people hello beautiful people
says Zachary public is pronounced Czech
Republic yes that's right Czech Czech
Republic good morning George George from
Australia and currently in Taiwan so ok
comments or questions on today today's
topics so let's do it
so I'm going to so let's let us write it
down you know when you are confused you
write it down so I write it down I'm
confused
ok so we are we okay here so magnify and
showing browsers show this command
window so so we're gonna code a ellipse
elyse command to open current buffer in
in what browser in chrome let's say
Chrome ok then we're gonna modify it
coda release command to open current
link and cruiser in quo in chrome okay
so that's two commands then we are going
to merge these two commands let me show
you so so again you can see here so code
let's see okay open in Chrome so you
this one command to open buffer one
command to open link now
ideally it's not necessarily ideally but
but you could have these two commands in
one so you sir have to do not have to
worry about think about which one to
call because you can call the command so
that if the current if the cursor is
under a link such as you know over here
under this link then it opens that link
otherwise you if if the cursor under
cuza is not a link you just open the
buffer so we're gonna merge these two
commands and that code has not been done
yet that's what we're gonna do let's see
how much time I've been talking cuz this
will be okay we talked about for you
ever minutes but sparked so join this
course you know lots of things going on
there you know join this course we miss
you yeah because you know and your you
know your project you know you can you
can create another project you know
that's you know this project is probably
gonna be dead because since now I
started to have this code and it's busy
so you can probably do something you
know that's also useful so it okay so
let's get to the Emacs shall we Oh shall
we digress more okay so we're gonna do
we're gonna write the command from
scratch then we're gonna try to open a
link okay so let's do that then okay let
me also mention you know in Emacs so you
see I have so many commands to open
different you know to open in specific
different browsers there's also command
to open the current browser you know for
example I press a button right now for
example you see if I press a button it
will just launch the
in whatever is a default browser you
know according to the operating system
the preference is for the what whatever
you said so for example I press a button
it opens in Firefox and that command is
called you see I just caught that
command this one excite tml browse URL
of buffer now if I go to soft Mac OS and
change the default browser and C go to
general and change the default browser
let's say to brave okay then I call the
same command I press okey then you see
it opens in brave
it just opens in whatever default
browser so there are quite a few
variations of these commands so that
command is called HTML browse URL of
buffer so why so many browsers I mean
usually you don't need to but if you are
web developers then you might need that
so that's that's the reason I needed you
know for my own purposes I need
different browsers for different
purposes but if you are web dev that
that might be useful so let's start
coding yeah so let's just okay so before
we do that let me mention though Emacs
itself has speeding all these commands
Emacs has been building so let's call
you let me show you
so which caused a proposed command okay
then you type browse PR o w s okay enter
so you can see in this window Emacs has
tons of these commands you see browser
URL chrome that is similar to that that
basically means open up current buffer
in Chrome browser
okay then browser URL chromium okay
chromium is the open source version of
Google Chrome the engine the browser URL
conqueror + URL D for Mac OS browser
browser URL window browser browser you
are
a link I don't know what that is buzz
URL Emax this sense to Emax browser okay
it's stupid you know so so you know it's
let me finish and then we talked about
that the stupidity of all the
open-source Emacs things so brass URL
epiphany you know epiphany you know then
you have passed your five out scallion
generic no mods browser AG no mas but
URL KDE then browse through our mosaic
browser via Bosnia Mozilla and browse
your Netscape crap you know bunch of you
know what so when when I need a command
like that I look at him acts oh it's all
building until you try them nothing
works none of them works and most of
these are long time dead like Epiphany
so you are looking at the history of the
internet over the trend over the past 20
years that's what you are looking at
this scallion you this KDE
this you know Guardian browser anyone
know still the anyone still using that
Guardian like who knows what Guardian
browser is anyone
good morning turn your landlords so
Guardian you see so and epiphany you
know these are kind of I think these are
like in the in mm you know they have on
Linux is you have these browsers they
come and go then then you have browse
URL Netscape it's kept it stayed for 20
years and it's still in Emacs browse URL
Netscape and for example they have brass
URL Firefox let me show you the idiocy
let me demonstrate the fact I mean let
me prove it to you how the the idiocy of
the Emacs you know the fanaticism okay
so you have you have we have here browse
URL Firefox okay let's try it I love it
oh you will say me days of coding my own
commands and and save me from the Emacs
phonetics who doesn't like me who walks
Isis TRO he doesn't know nothing it's
opium but he spent time to create his
own versions this this phonetics
I'm sorry
it's avoid this avoid you know going
crazy so browse URL Firefox okay let's I
want to do that yeah lovely so let's try
it meta X browse URL Firefox okay you
asked me to type a URL what the vac okay
you asked me to type a URL let's say
sorry that info enter whoops
searching for program no such file or
directory
Firefox idiocy infuriating let's try
this brass UI out Chrome ok same thing
you know a browser Chrome
nothing no such file or directory so so
what so what does that mean so if you
are Emacs phonetics that means oh oh you
you start you know you need to look at
documentation okay let's look at the
documentation brass URL Firefox okay
what does it say let's see ok magnify so
browser on Firefox and this this and as
Firefox www browser you see that
terminology is he the history of
Internet you don't call a www anymore
that's 1990s so so as the Firefox www to
load URL default URL around OB for point
ok passes the string to the variable
browser URL Firefox arguments to Firefox
okay so interactively Brava Brava you
know loads of document in Firefox window
matter of fact they saying you know you
have to like you have to you know you
you have to now think what's going what
is the ye
technique jargons is talking about that
you have to like you have to spend two
hours just to understand what what he
see it's saying okay interactively if
the variable brows you are our new
window flag is n'l loads the
documentation in a new Firefox window by
bah-bah-bah
you know this is the the complexity of
the general generality of Emacs Emacs
supposed to be o you can configure
everything yeah but it doesn't walk so
you pass on your 5 bucks a new window is
tab isn't a neo then whenever a document
would be otherwise be loaded in window
windows it is loaded in you in a world
use the optional second argue a new
window instead of okay
nothing nothing about setting a file
path a max fanatism you did this doesn't
say nothing you know right now so I
tried I just tried to command doesn't
work he says I need a path then okay I
read the doc this is no doc this is
nothing about it what are you supposed
to do yeah so you if you are a Linux fan
you're gonna spend hours digging it and
you know and you say oh ye max is
fantastic in anyway so so I'm so that
that is about that so Emacs has these
you know hundreds of these pass you are
and most of them are outdated you know
they don't work in fact I tried this
like 10 years ago exactly like 2002 2008
you know I tried it on it was only on
Windows I don't remember if I tried it
on Linux maybe it's you know some of
them working you know some of them for
sure because scallion and Mozilla you
know many of them you know they just
beat rot and so anyway so let's start
right out okay so let's begin that Emacs
Lisp okay we create a window so you Mak
this so let's do fun we already start
coding
let's say open in let's just say five
bucks okay this the the browser you can
change yourself like like brave five
bucks Chrome Safari you can change it
the the name you see okay so we are
starting to write this function now
there are two main issues about writing
a function the to two main difficulties
difficulties one is Emacs Lisp okay like
if you are beginner then you don't know
what to do right so so that's one of the
difficulty now the second difficulty is
about about actually finding out how to
launch a browser in different operating
systems for example on the Mac on
Windows Linux they all have different
mechanisms to open a browser to launch
your browser I mean you have to do this
program programmatically
so that is kind of kind of nasty because
that's because the email is party is in
a sense simple because you just study
eMac B's everything is where document it
where document did it and you know it's
a language you learn and I you know so I
know you Mac base you know where also I
have no problem writing these commands
but the difficult part is the how do you
actually you know from eMac list you
have to talk to the operating system to
tell it to launch your browser and also
feed it arguments like what URL things I
got or whether to open a new tab or
default code or the current window or
you you wanted to launch your new
instance or just use the existing
instance if it's already there so that
so this part you know about talking to
us that is actually I will say that the
the nasty the more nasty part because
these kind of things they change over
the years and it's gets really complex
different operating systems they have
different ways and especially on Linux
you know on Linux so let's just start to
code it and let's show let's see what's
what happens okay so 24 minutes I'm
doing okay so today it's probably gonna
be 90 minutes hello beautiful people
thank you so much for the for the father
for the super chat good morning sink 2
sin 2 is from China I think are you from
China good morning George Jones
so Guardian is a genome desktop it's a
gecko base is is its new around or is it
like long dead epiphany is standard
browser in elementary OS I think so
elementary is a windowing system right
down on the Linux you know back then
this is 2005 or so you know Linux is
like oh god all these things thriving
and they are showing you know fancy
windowing systems with you know shiny
fires and transparency and but actually
technically it's crap it's a it's the
worst crap but if you don't use Linux
like like during mm I don't use Linux
well I have I've looked you know I
observed they they have a website of
calories all of the screenshots you know
of this KDE with whatever window
management system there's a new one
looked like back then where they show
composition you know transparency and
you know and and 3d visual effects like
when you switch window for example I
switch between my Emacs and crump then
they show a 3d box like usual 2008 and
there was you use it Scrappy's worst
crap in Linux
truly infuriating idiocy good morning
Miranda Miranda waiver okay let's get
back to e Magna spend your money works
if you have fire files in share path
that's yes that and that's you know
that's true you know because I've you
know I've tried to use it I've done that
but you see ultimately you know so so
like I have to choice you know so I
if I want a command to open a specific
browser I have two choices one just
write your own like like what I've done
you know Reggio to use the Emacs you
know those fielding ones but try to you
know find a proper way to fix it you
know I find out what you need to do like
say the path and so and use that you
know I so you know many maybe many many
of them will choose that choice because
that is more kind of you know more
conventional I mean more more you know
approved by the Emacs community because
see that's what you want to do but you
know to me actually writing your own is
actually simpler and works better you
yeah in my opinion because you know why
because if you well if you don't know
least maybe not but if you already know
least writing your own is keys but it's
probably better because you have control
because right now you know for example I
have all these commands it just works it
works in Windows
it works in Mac it works in Linux okay
and it's pretty simple it just works it
you know you don't have to install you
you don't have dependencies you don't
have to install you don't have to trick
you know you don't have to have another
code that sets a path you know you make
things simple that's the thing but if
you follow you know if you've tried the
Emacs standard way like we showed before
you know like
let's say describe function describe
function okay you know for example we
showed this browse URL Firefox you know
you read the doc you and you have all
these options options flags people wants
to control it you know with a new tab or
not new tab you know think things like
that and just make it anyway let's start
coding let's start coding with it so we
yeah this it's let's just start coding
let's try to do this fast because let's
yeah because I already spend 30 minutes
flaming so so what we so this is this is
kind of a default template opening fire
Firefox okay not fire Firefox okay open
your Firefox so we want to open the
current buffer open but let me try to do
this quickly if I can open perfect in
Firefox so what we want to do we want to
first of all get the buffer path file
path okay and okay let me do let me do
this in the simplest kind of way so
don't worry about the proper style I
mean if you are you know you make this
coda you're criticized so this is no you
should do it that way but let's just let
me just do this you know let me just
show you know the basics of emag B's so
people knew about Emacs Lisp you can
learn how to do it so set path file path
so you want to find a current buffers
path and and how you do that is that
command is buffer name buffer file name
okay I think that's it let's see so
describe function to look at what it
does
okay buffer found returned the name of
returned name of file buffer is visiting
right okay so that sure it should be it
for example I can evaluate this and
the answer is indeed you see in the mini
buffer it says you know the current path
of the fire so buff a file name will
return the current path of the of the
fire location associated with this
buffer now if this buffer is not a file
they returns nil okay so so we said the
file path and now we just call shell
command okay shell command shell command
okay shell command we want to okay here
is a tricky tricky part you know
remember I said there are two parts to
ready in the command one is knowing eMac
this the other one is about knowing how
to call how to how to talk to a marine
system to launch launch a browser or any
app so this part is operate operating
system specific so right now I am on a
Mac I know what to do just by experience
so let me just do that then we will talk
about how do how to do on Windows and
stuff and you you also have to determine
find out like whether you are on the Mac
or Windows zone or Linux but let's just
do this get it to work so shell command
so what you do is you do you call open
so what is open open is a building Mac
OS command so for example okay so let's
open a new buffer I mean new new
terminal here so you can see magnify
okay so let's see if I can magnify
so open-open is a bo d mac commands okay
let's say open firefox okay so actually
you have to say - a means application
and we want to open using firefox and
let's say open a URL so let's say sorry
dot info okay oh sorry that info does
not exist I guess okay so let's say
let's say the current directory yeah
let's just say con directory dot okay
there you have it you know you open the
Condor tree in dot now if you want to
open URL or something you have to this
here's what we do so man open we look at
the open documentation you know so then
you can read about how to pass the
argument to the application you know so
there it is so this is actually one way
to do it another way is is you call
Firefox directory so let's see which
Firefox okay so let's try it again
which Firefox capital F okay so which
Firefox start app okay so let's try it
again Firefox app come on not found
let's try it again
capital F Firefox app not found this is
easy this is what I mean by the tricky
part of operating system this is all OS
specific now actually I know how to call
that command I think the full name it
would be this okay so let's try it let's
just try it blindly so you know this
this is trial and error methodology it
works universally so sash application
slash Firefox start apps sash contents
sash Mac OS let's just try it
then fire fox okay there we have it
there you go so so you see there are
many you know this is kind of many ways
to do it you can Co fire fox directly or
you can call the Mac OS open command I
think the open command is better it's
more you know it's designed to open apps
so we can just do this email Emacs
Firefox okay open Firefox then then then
then fire fire path okay so show command
so we have we need fire path here
optional we don't care okay but this
doesn't work because the fire path needs
to be evaluated so what you do is you
can contact so here is what you do okay
so contact
not contact oh yeah contact kongou looks
fine so open firefox
filepath let's let's try it let's
evaluate this code yeah that works so
contact that's what we want put it here
and remove that and make it pretty
so that should be it let's double-check
shell command we will Emacs show command
command will call will basically cause
shell you know use the shell to code so
open Firefox the in fact file path so
evaluate this buffer done let's go back
to some HTML and now let's call open
buffer in Firefox okay let's call open
buffer in Firefox
let's see please make it work please
symbols value as variable is invalid
file path okay
symbols value is invalid why is he
invited oh because we are doing it
outside of the let you see it must be
inside the length okay eval buffer okay
now go back to some HTML page then call
open buffer in Firefox the fire barber
bra top show Firefox does not exist okay
so let me show you the message buffer so
you can see the error message buffer
magnify make it one window so what is it
saying so it is saying
so the user talk show Firefox does the
the file the file does not exist okay
what do you mean the file does not exist
so let file path set queue file path
equals to buffer file path name
then let's go show command so what do
you mean why is the fire path does not
exist
okay let's try to find out print okay
with you know this is the the best way
to debug print statement avow it go back
to the on HTML file and let's look let's
watch the messages buffer and now let's
call the command call it so it is
actually passing this I mean so our file
path value is actually this which is
different from the error message it's
trying to say some talk show so it's
dropping the okay so there is something
strange we okay I think I think oh okay
because
okay so here's what we need to do so
let's add a new command so this is
command string so this is we are showing
debugging skills we want to set SEC you
command string and so we can you know
see what our commands is and let's there
we have it so we are going to print out
command string let's see what we have
and comment that out avow the buffer go
back to HTML code a command let's see so
the command we are calling is open fire
oh we missing the - a what an idiocy
open open - a yeah well the idea c eval
the buffer go back try it open buffer in
vivax and indeed it's going to call this
command seems correct now let's let's
actually make it a shell command and you
know run it here we're actually called a
shell command so now let's try it again
yay yay fantastic success ok successful
so we need to oh thank you seen to
should've should have checked my
comments that would be enlightenment
desktop environment best room is clean
tidy room there's a message attached
this room is a green tidy room now I
need to clean my you
okay okay I'll give it I give it a shot
how clean I'll swing there our doing
that today so its own destroy best on
Ubuntu it's visually reminds me of voice
OS X okay so we are talking about
enlightenment I don't think it was a
distro back then maybe you know maybe
you are right it was okay so okay so
Emily complains why are you putting the
sake you hear and as opposed as as
opposed to let's see
so like that that's a good that's a good
question well only because you know I'm
trying to do it fast
you know because you see we when you put
it here then you have more complex
issues like right now if we let's try
that so we you know so let so you can
you know if you want to set the value to
a variable you can directly put a let if
you already know the value like this
symbol so you can do that but then we
need also to put a command here you can
you know so we can also do it put a
value here and in that case the value
will be this you know contact but then
then there's complexities because now
the file path depends on this value
before then you cannot use let then you
have to use let star so the difference
between let star and let is that let's
start we are you know the the Oder you
know the latter variable values can
depend a value that you know that said
before like that so you know so this me
some details you know how so I was
thinking too
you know not talk about that but yeah
but this you know so by Emax convention
typically you want to do it this way but
again you know as my typical and you can
use your opinion I I don't think that's
necessarily good because why because if
you just stick with this format you know
where let is just a bunch of variables
then you have a bunch of set you know
this way this format will be universal
because if you do things this way you
wouldn't have variations like let then
sometimes let's star let me try to do
that
Oh sometimes like even if you use it
this way even if you do this way then
you see some variables you don't know
the value until you run some complicated
code you see so so some of it some
variables you will have a value directly
like that but some others then you
either have a big chunk of code but uh
but sometimes you just cannot you have
to do it you know you have to use set
cue in the body of the code so what I'm
saying is that if you try to use this
form this form of let you know where you
set of value to variables then you have
kind of various formations like you know
you and it's necessarily so you know you
know you cannot just enforce one format
it's like sometimes you have let then
you have let's star then you have you
know let with with some has values some
doesn't that happens in the body so you
know you see what I'm saying so that is
my complaints about about the idea where
you know some some Emacs the issue of
style you know some acts conventional
issue of style so what what do you think
about that
so what do you think about that my
retort yeah so what you know my so my
opinion about how using a simple let of
these formalities has has advantages you
know let's say you know you know the
other thing is when you you know when
you use this LED format where you have
variables value together you see the
thing about Emacs is that emag Lisp is
not a typed language not strongly typed
and there is no concept concept of
constant in images so even if you do
that you can still change the value of
the variable in your body so it kind of
so-so
so this way of this style does not carry
the same semantic advantage of declaring
constants so rather it's kind of just
the advantage of it if any is just kind
of visual you know it helps you maybe
organized you know it makes the code
easier to understand so it's not really
significant so that you know so so
that's my video details about coding
style in eMac list of the various forms
of let you know so a little bit history
like personal history like in the
beginning you know three or four years
of my MX based coding I always stick
with this format like always I'll never
I'll never do this I never do this and
never never let start neither you know I
always just stick with that because for
the reason I just kept you know I don't
think those others are better you know I
don't think there are better that's the
first for like five years of my you
Magnus coding
but today if you look at my code I do
use a lot of these and when I do this
it's usually because the variable I
consider it constant like if you see in
my code if you see this form that means
I never change we'll never change the
value of this fire path in the body of
code so I started to do that and that's
not ideal either because like like I
said Emacs does not have constant
concept so it's this is merely kind of a
convention so so I've been thinking
actually going back to this so you know
I've emphasized about this you know I
think about this a lot I worry about it
every day like whether you should use
camel case or you should use snake case
or vision or whatever or - case you know
I worried about every day obsess about
it
and going back and forth okay so that's
about that so so Emily says I can send
messages and that's the one message that
posed through oh okay yeah so so YouTube
yeah YouTube they start to they have a
mechanism that hold on okay so let me do
this let me copy that okay I think we
been talking a lot and not doing it much
in my list but I mean let me do this
because they also actually allowed to do
a lot to continue with that eMac this
actually so
so that's a comment for today I'm I'm
saving it right now because I'm about to
switch to live chat when you do that
often it cuts off some of the talk so is
that that's what you mean right you
cannot post messages anyway opposed to
this code then I'm programming
okay so Emily says I see use of set cue
like use of go-to okay yeah but it's not
going to right so like it breaks the
nice functional aspect
hmm okay so okay I see what you're
saying but still it's it's kind of it's
it's really it's rather all about just
visual style I mean it has nothing to do
with semantics you know right so but you
you use each walk well yeah so okay so
let's listen it's just to let's continue
with our commands
okay so so we did this okay it's now it
works now what what's the next problem
so next problem we need to get this
command to work on Windows and Linux and
how do you do that so you have to so
there's a variable called I don't
remember okay so let's go to you know
let's just go to my code so we can save
time so there's a variable called where
is that
so let's magnify opening vs code system
type okay so here is a variable system
type okay
system system type now system type is a
building variable that tells you what
what operating system
you are in so we want to check you know
which operating system we are in because
we need this command to work on Windows
and Linux so we need a condition so
condition if so this is the form for
condition so if string equal why don't I
have string equal okay oh there it is
string Co so if string equal system type
if the string is Darwin now Darwin is
new Emacs name for Mac OS okay that's
idiotic
okay for political reasons so anyway
because story is the kind of the open
source core of Mac OS okay so anyway so
if it's if we are on a Mac then we do
something okay then if we are on Windows
now Windows is windows name is Windows
NT then we do something else
if we are on
Linux you know then Cunha wants to
correct new Linux politics okay then we
do something okay this is how you do it
then otherwise we can say otherwise
arrow okay
now Eric the arrow command is just like
messages you know it's it it prints on
arrow and stops the program so otherwise
arrow use good logic problem
you got a logic problem okay well
actually it's not a logic problem
because it's possible is someone else is
on Solaris or some of the you know weird
green system your OS is crap isn't it is
not pop there for not supported okay
something like that okay so we write a
condition let's make it pretty and so if
we are on the Mac so let's now let's
clean the whole thing here we actually
need to
okay let's just clean them up clean them
up she'll come and clean clean then so
if it's on the Mac then you say that so
if he's on Windows then you have to do
something something then if it's on
Linux you have to do something something
now since I'm on a Mac I cannot test on
Windows so let's just copy the code we
have here so this code is open in
Firefox so we have where I don't have I
don't have the version in Firefox so
let's just let's look at my source code
okay so let's paste the whole thing here
now this is a code for opening Chrome
and but you can see it's just copy the
condition part okay so you can see the
condition part so if it's on the Mac
then it does something more complex
because it's trying to because that
command we are open several files in
tired you know if you are in tired you
can do that for example let me show you
so I want to open okay this is too big a
window so I want to open this file and
this file and this file in Chrome
browser I can do that so Chrome okay so
let's try again open Chrome so kesaji
TMA are opening Chrome browser do it you
see you open all three pages okay so you
see that's kind of useful sometimes
so that is why you see this map thing
but bit but basically what well what we
need is to find how to you call on
Windows how do you call how do you
launch your command so we can see the
windows code here this is what how we do
it there there are many ways to do it
okay like I said before but you know
this is the way I happen to do it so
actually we don't need the map you know
so so this is how we do it we call start
process then we call PowerShell then we
say pop start process again that's part
of PowerShell commands start process
then you say Chrome
in this case since we are doing Firefox
so that should be Firefox I think a walk
so this is how you how you know if it's
Windows this is how you do it now if
it's Linux it's more complex okay so so
if it's Linux let's see okay so string
equals to Linux okay so here is how you
do it that's let's just okay so
so you share command then Firefox yeah
that should be it that's how you do it
okay so so we we spend a lot time to
write this simple function but basic
okay so it it does illustrate what we
want to do so the file path this is
wrong
that should work okay evaluated
I cannot test it you know window so
Firefox but okay yeah so my keyboards
Canisius advantage I showed that in many
of my videos like almost many many of
them and you just search for Saudi
Kinesis you'll find my website with a
video full review of it okay I think I
you know we we did this but we there's
actually a lot to talk about
okay we did this function the next
problem is to open the link under
cruiser in a specific browser now how to
open you know a specific browser is over
here already we cover that so the
problem is about how do you get the URL
under the cruiser so that's the next
command we can do and also after that
then we can you know we can merge these
two command okay so I don't know maybe
this is you know maybe this is good
enough for today so let's look at the
comments so you guys have comments
questions should I should I continue to
the next one about writing a command
that opens the URL and a coozer
in a browser should we do that or or
maybe that should be it today or maybe
we talked about some other things so let
me know okay so
comments let me know let me get a drink
okay tea so do I look okay yeah I look
okay because it's quite dark here
actually let me turn on the light and
the Kooza is interesting okay let's do
that let me turn on the right
okay yeah Emily Emily is a lisp expert
Emory has coded you know lots of Lisp
code so did you try the stunt WP or WN
sub stump WM that's Linux window manager
written tiling window manager written in
Common Lisp have you tried it
okay so let's do the okay so so let's
open so let's just do this okay so let's
copy that base our code on previous code
copy paste is the most powerful
methodology in programming truly in
practice right so yeah so let's do open
buffer in open link in Firefox okay so
it says open link and open the URL or
file path and who's in Firefox okay
that's our dark string and here you
always you need doc string okay open
buffer okay so doc string open URL file
path and the kusa in firefox that's
great Doc's string is great but it
doesn't do nothing you have to write
code okay so you need to write code so
so file path we need that just like
before then open the URL okay so now the
problem is how do you grab the path and
the kusa okay that's the you can do that
by there are so many ways okay so let's
let's try to let's let's go with the
easiest conventional Emacs default way
so there is a thing there's this piolin
package called thing at point so let's
use let's use that thing at point okay
so you can look at the documentation
basically basically what it will do is
that you'll get for example let's for
example let me show you it's easier than
okay so that means we remove all that
okay remove all that so thing at point
URL what that means is that it will grab
the text around the cursor
that's a URL and so for example let's
let's do this path okay
so set path to that okay so we're gonna
set path so that's what it does it
returns the URL under the kusa so this
is actually the is easiest way but it's
got problems we we might talk about it
today but it you know you can search for
saudi king at point Robin then you'll
find my article you know it's a bit
technical but but this so one of the
problem is that you see for this command
sometimes the thing is a URL for example
google.com or some you know some website
you want to that's under the cruiser you
want to open but some other times you
have a link that's not a you know that's
a local file path you also want that you
know so you want to be able to use this
command doesn't matter if the let me
show you okay so you want to be able to
use the command that whether the URL is
a you know maybe it's a URL or it's just
a local file path you want to be able to
call the command I know you know need
either one of them but if you do use the
if you to if you use the thing appoint
URL then if but if your cruiser is under
file path you'll be screwed you won't
walk so that's kind of the problem what
what I'm talking about thing at point of
course there are solutions but let's
just go with this
let's just go with this okay so so so
path is seeing at the end point and okay
so we already done no actually cheese
this is so simple so let's say yeah this
this should be it let's let's try it
okay so give out the buffer copy the
command name go back to a UI our page I
mean the HTML page
let's move kusa into a URL somewhere
like here okay so we move it okay there
then code a command paste the name open
link in Firefox yeah that's right so do
it there it is
open firing external app this is you see
this you see this URL that's that's this
uija that's what we want so it worked so
it's so simple oh it's my god this is
simpler than I thought because I thought
I was going to do something and but but
this won't work let me just show you it
won't work if you have a fire path so
let's try it so now my cursor is under
fire path so I'm just going to call the
command again open link in Firefox enter
wait
close that let's try it again I don't
know what's going on so open link in
Firefox you see it doesn't work it
doesn't work because you can see it
doesn't say you know it doesn't it
doesn't even give you give you error
messages it doesn't work because you see
that thing at point let me show you that
thing at point this thing at point
command if you give their URL it will
try to consider you know whatever is
under kusa is a URL and so it's kind of
unpredictable what it actually returns
it does not return you know because I've
noticed sometimes the wheel add htdp in
front of it it's very annoying so for
example it's you know let's see what's
going on so let's go here messages fire
path let's just print it okay
eval buffer go back to this buffer and
try it again
Kodaka man do it okay now let's go back
to Emacs
open the messages buffer and see what is
says go to the bottom we just print it
it where is it I don't know what let's
try it again
message is xxx this one okay
ivar buffer go here
try it open okay
now go back to Emacs you see it says
Neil so when the you apparently when
when the thing under cosa is not you IR
it returns Neil about seven years ago I
have noticed it actually sometimes it
adds HTTP like it it couldn't
concatenate a string HGTV's you know
colon slash slash in front I hate so I
blog I wrote a rant about it I don't
know
you know maybe they they fixed it or
they changed behavior something like
that anyway we see this problem here you
know we have this problem so
alternatively for example there is you
can also do this by our past I think I
think path or something let's see the
thing at point ok so you can another
file name yeah so you can do file name
but if you do file name then the dua or
if you are you under you are that then
that doesn't work so that's a problem so
the way I solve this problem let yeah
let's do that
and maybe that there'll be it for today
yes we can complete this yeah we will
try out tomorrow being a busy ok so
isn't using Ultima hacking keyboard now
this why I'm using both ok so anyway so
so how do you solve this problem so the
way I do is you just manually code your
own that graphs for example let's just
do it okay so so comment this out
comment this out so we want to grab kind
of the you are under cruiser so one way
we can do it let me just begin this is
this is not the final solution but let
me show you you can see my my own
solution the final solution in my you
know
this page is already already there but
now I'm trying to like teach you know
you know some emag based stuff so let's
do it
so open fire yeah so you want to grab
the stream okay so one first solution is
we want to we want to move the cursor to
the beginning of the double coil then we
know the beginning location of the file
path or URL then we move it to the end
of the double quote then we know the end
position then we grab that so that's one
solution to begin with okay so let's do
that so say excursion okay so they do
not search for such backward okay
such backward search backward for a for
a double quote
okay that will move closer to it okay so
okay let's do that then set point p1
that's a beginning position okay then
you search forward for a quote okay we
don't need the rest of it then you set
set p2 that's the end position so we
have two new variables P 1 P 2 okay then
then both then okay so okay so then set
file path to perfe substring no
properties okay P 1 P 2 so the buffers
substring no properties will take two
positions then you'll return the string
between those positions then we set that
value to fire path that's how we do it
now there's a little detail we need to
fix because when you search backward it
will move couse
- before the before the stream but the
actual position is after the stream so
so what we want to do is for watch ah
okay for a child what then we set a
point beginning position okay it so that
bring the template information what
template template information like what
you mean the message is buffer Oh
what do you mean Emily so we so we set
point okay for a child then we set point
and there is another thing we want to do
because when if if you're Emacs Lisp
code move the cursor you better restore
it when your command is done because
otherwise when user cause your command
then the cruiser ends up you know
somewhere erratic you know user don't
want that so you want to restore users
cursor position so there is a convenient
command
that's called save excursion okay so
what do you do is you call save
excursion and do whatever you do so by
the end of save when you know by the end
of save excursion it will restore the
users who's the position so that's what
you want to do okay so actually so that
is that is done that is that is I think
that's that is it let's double check so
that's our first approach to solve these
problems of the finger-point problem p1
p2 so fire path buffer so I think that
should be it so Eva buffer go to some
HTML page put cursor on a fire path okay
then it's call open linking Firefox it
should open the hawk
a text file do it Oh God wrong so it
says let binding can only have one value
oh ok so I got some syntax error here so
here's a message and it's just some
basic syntax here oh yeah so so this is
wrong
yeah let's avow it again back here
try it again do it okay unexpected end
of firewire looking for matching ok yeah
so so here's the arrows
it says unexpected and a fire arrow why
are looking for the double quote so
basically what that means is that I know
what it means
but you don't you may not know what it
means because I know it because I spent
10 years so this is kind of you you know
you get experience from the error
messages so that error messages came
from such forward basically it cannot
find a string well the reason is that
sees such backward then then forward cha
then set a point there in such forward
then you need to move backward okay so
for watch ah negative 1 then P 2 P 2 P 1
P 2 then then we set the path that's
correct okay
eval buffer and go back here let's see
okay so that's I think that's okay let's
try it now I'm not sure what is arrow
but anyway let's try it again try our an
arrow so Kodaka man do it
there it is fantastic it works
so we now let's try the URL so let's go
to some URL this one go to command do it
yay so now it's you know it's great it's
close it close it fantastic it works so
that is about how you know kind of
custom solution now this is our first
step but it's not optimal why because
for example if you are in a text file
for something you have a google.com so
for example HTTP you know you have a you
you know let's say someone said go to
this to fine info okay so you know you
have a fire out there so you want to
move the kusa here you want to call a
command and visit that URL so in this
case our command won't work because it's
trying to search for the double quotes
so in this case you can add you know
such backward double quote or space you
know basically the problem the issue is
we want to find what we want to know
what are the delimiter you know that
brackets the URL so Emily what what do
you mean templates templates but you
YouTube kept deleting my messages stupid
YouTube what did you use to put the
template information of a function in
your buffer oh that's that's just my own
eMac list mod so let me show you okay so
it's that's Chris quickly to answer so
so if you look so is this is my only Mac
this mod when I press tab it calls this
command if the cursor is afterward then
you do completion if the cursor is
before a word then it will do
indentation now when it does come
it will complete the emag list function
name and if you press again it will
expand it to a template you know and and
and and that part is done by a brief so
you can see here is our Omega brief so
you can see this defining a brief table
so that's all Maya brief so if I type
for example you know
so that's Oh Maya brief then you see the
templates for example if I type append
then space it expand to append you know
with a bracket that that's how I do it
so it's kind of manual yeah you know you
can just grab this if you want you know
if you want to do that if you like that
you know you know it's a manually
created it covers basically the most
frequently used Emacs these functions
because I actually did a statistical
analysis I grabbed all the source code
so so if you search focus on sorry Emacs
okay so Elise it's on github and it's
also a OPA
yeah so it's on github and also on my
Appa you can just get it you you know
you know feel free to you know get the
you know the briefs then you can have
that okay so so we covered you know so
we are so our current problem is what if
the URL is not bracketed by double quote
or what if what if it's bracketed by a
single quote and then let me show you
okay so what so what if it's like that
or what if it's like that because some
sometimes you people a lot of people use
this one so the solution basically you
can you know
already coded it you can see stop that
let's magnify so showing desktop open in
terminal opening Google Chrome so open
in Google Chrome then here is open HT
open link in Google Chrome so you can
see the code here so you know I'm giving
it several pairs of delimiters they can
be spaced tab return new line or any of
these brackets or double quote or curly
quote you know so you use them as the
delimiter you know you you know then
then the rest of the code is similar so
that's how I solve that problem so I
think that's it for today yeah so thank
you guys for coming by any any other
questions any questions thank you hello
beautiful people for the folder donation
okay so that's that's it for Emacs Lee's
now maybe we can talk about random
things for for a minute or two so
discord discord and against akhira he's
flexible yeah so what what is the oh
yeah let's let's look at how many one
hour in 25 minutes we are right on time
oh there's one more thing when what one
more thing guys you know as the Steve
Jobs says you know before you remember
we had a problem of you know it's right
now we have two commands you know open
buffer and versus open dink so so it's
inconvenient like like what like every
time you have to think whether you want
to open the buffer or open the link it
happens to me because you know sometimes
I call command but but it's open
improved the buffer instead of the link
so you'll be nice if you know if the
cursor is under a link or file path then
you open the link otherwise just open
the buffer so how do you do that so we
so that's how you know we want to merge
these two commands you know these two
commands are basically the same you know
the the poke of it is the same so
so how do you solve that okay so the way
you solve that is that now you actually
you have you know have to think about
that so the problem is you know what we
are trying to use the delimiters you
know we have a bunch of diameters to
grab a URL so but if the Cuza is not
under the URL the possibility the result
is that it might be a huge chunk of text
you know from arbitrary point maybe from
here to you know to here you know so
that's one possibility
arbitrary chunk of big text the other
possibility yeah that's yeah I think
that that is a result do you typically
be arbitrary chunk of big text so so how
do you yeah so the problem is how do you
know if your Cuza is under file path or
URL so I think we can go by some
heuristics I think that's what you have
to do there is no one simple absolute
precise solution so by heuristic it
means that we first of all we check
maybe the string length for example if
the string length is 1,000 then
obviously it's not a file path it's not
a URL so the string length is if it's
less than 300 then okay then then we
also check well if the strings start
with HTTP or you know FTP or you know
some other URL schema then we know okay
it's a URL or file you know file colon
slash slash and and also if the whole
string does not contain any space
then it's likely to be a URL or fire
path yeah that that that is actually a
strong heuristic that's probably
something we want to check first yeah so
the stream needs to be short the string
should not contain any space and the
string typically we are either have to
slash slash we are either have like
colon slash slash or a bunch of sashes
oh okay yeah well there's also a
possibility of no sash at all yeah so
okay so you know so that's how I go
about solving that you know a bunch of
heuristics okay so that's it for today
so thank you guys for type so how much
how fast do I type I don't type very
fast so let's go to let's do that and
that's it you know finish the typing
test and that will be it for today
that's two a type speed demo sorry
typing tutorial okay so you go to my
tutorial your thought about this code
compared to IRC I don't think IRC IRC is
too old basically 30 30 years old
obviously this code is modern and you
got video you got voice chat we had fun
with Emily and guys and I had overview
for people chatting voice chat on this
code yesterday IRC you know our IRC is a
nerds thing you know and it's it's kind
of its time it's 30 years old in its
time it's replaced by slack and you know
and also the newer generation you know
the Millennials and post Millennials X Z
generation you know they they wouldn't
use it it you know older people died and
died out so I a see is going away
so typing games so here we have a bunch
of cell my typing speed 91 for me okay
if if without practice if with practice
maybe maybe more
you see when they talk about typing
speaked
speed it's very specific to the website
because it's it can vary from 10 to 20
word per minute depending on website but
depending on the word they use for
example this website they use the most
simple words no capitalization you know
most you know common English words no
period even nope no coma no punctuation
you know so if you dude have that then
it's gonna be fast on the other hand
like when I was you know I was at a data
entry clerk I was a secretary in 1991 so
I have to go to a temp agency you know
wait they hire people you have to do
standard typing test okay I think
electric either you like Trinko
mechanical typewriter so I did that but
but so back then you have a letter you
know D or something something you know
that's 1991 style of writing businessman
you know salesman people you know tea or
something something we something
something you know it's kind of foam so
you know that's back then the style back
then so you given that you have to type
that and that is obviously very
different from just a bunch of most
frequently used words which is a case
with this let's go there typing speed
test so which side is this one time in
speed test nu dot-eu okay that other
that's that one okay so that one you go
there and let's turn on JavaScript
so the world matters okay so I mean that
it depends on a website look at this one
you know much dog found true or Beauty
wood is the most very simple words most
frequently used words but on the other
hand if you are gonna type you know we
are formulated that's that would be a
difference between I would say ten words
per minute I would say so it really
heavily depends on you know your score
really depends on the websites
specifically also well let's just do
this and then we will say goodbye I
really like ten fast fingers for the
simple testing for that simple testing
okay let's go to ten fast fingers okay
ten fast fingers let's try and also our
my Canisius keyboard you'll be slower
you know so you'll be faster on the
laptop keyboard and another thing
interesting about speed typing speed is
that there's a difference between you
know one minute test and two minute head
test and thirty minute test you know
it's like granny it's a different you
know when you do if you are a champion
of sprint you will not absolutely be the
champion of marathon in fact if you you
know champion about sprint you know
hundred meters you will be the last one
to finish in a marathon and likewise so
you know same thing with swimming the
distance you know the deviation matters
these different techniques that you know
so so what I want to say is that
typically this typing speed website you
know they focus on like one minute which
is impractical I mean that's not real
life yeah they focus on why made it
because that's fun you know that's short
and people can say oh my God look at
this one this guy 204 let's let me just
do it okay I'm not going to be I I would
say maybe seventy okay let's do it
and we all shut down
found should him later
move a hand
not okay so it's 81 yay bye guys
now Ducati now if I do worry it's gonna
be it's gonna be 20 words per minute
actually you're less
[Laughter]