but and we are live
let's then go to youtube and hello guys
welcome to another episode of talk show
and today we have a guest with me he's
Israel dove laughs now that right Lord
of with her why yes well okay it's kind
of you like why are you usual so that's
a Hebrew name what about a dove pot oh
yeah that bearing reminds me there's ice
cream ice cream you know you notice I
seen USA where you have a white there
I scream mascot yeah yeah okay yeah I
see I was wondering you first
intentional but okay with a like I see
oh I was so so DeYoung Dion says we got
some reverb that's that's the error on
my part because I always got that right
on the audio well I guess we'll just I
have to go
fat hey so so it's talking about help
you actually yeah so what's she talking
about Jewish Jewish culture or her brew
the language something like that man
okay so I are you able are you watching
the video as well are you able to see it
okay okay okay yeah I should have the as
you've done the screen so you can see my
screen so yeah okay okay okay
so I was watching some of your videos
you had the last view is about her brew
in emacs yeah you know so her brew is
from right to left
[Music]
yes yes I know that yeah because I'm I'm
trying to you know I haven't tried with
her brew but I've tried you know the
Arabian alphabet yeah because I was
trying to put there a big title for
Arabian Nights you know that 100 in
1,001 nights and so yes you know the
direction goes you know like on the
wings on the part of English you know
it's that's right but then he suddenly
jumped through the other end so that was
very confusing so so yes I see I see so
so this kind of this thing I mean does
this happening other word processors
[Music]
maxi
right yeah yeah so let's go to the
actress just go to typing go to youtube
Emacs is great so you know so people can
see she is good in X is great so when
did you start to do when did you start
to the video
[Music]
my whole idea is that people people
should get the t ho yeah exactly that's
needed yes yes yes yeah exactly because
usually I mean usually there are videos
that's prepared and condensed and so
it's everything is perfect they just
come and everything so you know yeah
yeah I hear people are ready asking for
you know you know real Emacs expert they
want to see you know Emacs experts using
Emacs not just you know demos of
something so
yeah
so I'm looking at this video this is
Max's great episode 40 part 2 and
yesterday I was watching had and in the
end so you know you guys can you know
watch this the URLs here and the end I
saw these so you wrote these two
functions in Emacs that first of all you
disabled
let's see defend you disable the bite
duration I actually as you do that I see
oh I see especially if you don't use a
keyboard Arabic okay okay there is okay
so the variable name is speedy display
reordering setter to force me all right
okay actually let me do that let me just
type in here quickly PD okay this white
variable so I get a variable name type
for me p display recording yes
that's okay so I'm gonna have that and
okay no no second neighbor set set B D
display really Neal so set his said
[Music]
all's I want to say to what okay okay
okay I got it
okay so it's to that set defaults okay
Oh city for be this way you're doing
you're going to kneel then I got an
arrow is safe sitting constant wait
Oh city for is it wait
alright okay yeah okay so um I think I
think I think it it's just yeah yeah I
think that and the peaceful place like
yeah well because like we you can use
that to set indexing a array like you
know you know so it's the Emacs code
face you know like any basically when
you said you know like when you said cue
some variable you know that variable E
max you know all these people think of
it as a place and so that's said he can
also be used to set you on the way you
as
[Music]
right so so that he is pedicle I think
like yeah like you know they came from I
think he from logic it's like you know
predicate meaning like true or false
okay so I have these that's so I okay so
this is a good tip everyone so this set
cubed is very order Neil and I said
security for yes okay so let me see is
is it in a video description right but I
don't see the link to your kids it Y is
a I think be holy okay found it
okay
anytime JavaScript
hey idea huh sighing let's see how many
of you are watching for people okay I
need food Judah that's not gonna help
you know I need four thousand years so
anyway so I met jokey lab so Emacs T but
anyway so so here's a link guys you can
check out his code here but go let's go
back to YouTube and code is right there
you have the different BDD spray be
ordering and I think you have a toggle
yeah
Beauty Direction toggle so this would be
useful if you are yeah yeah so let me
just paste it here actually great and
your Bertha
so yeah boo boo okay
hope through that's interesting let me
save it here so um okay so that's one
thing about her brew right to left left
right so okay okay let me ask you so do
people okay maybe this question how many
I mean to what
what's popular languages over there I
mean would it be similar to USA that's
interesting question too but I was
learning about foreign languages well I
mean like no not official but I mean
which one is popular incumbent companies
over there
I see I see some kids what I see okay
PHP yeah yeah so so PHP and obviously
they use yeah oh yeah so so will you
guys Conan let's say PHP PHP do you
actually I mean are there people who use
her proof for function names and
variable names they're people do okay
Ozzie what about comments to people like
you submarine winging comments
[Music]
oh hey great
make the loop going to see you so yeah
we got a guest and he is this guy my
YouTube screen use use real dough and we
are talking about her her booze surf and
coding coding so I got some reverb yeah
I think that's too bad you know
something I have to find out how to do
that how to get rid of the reverb in yes
so but I don't think I can you know I
don't think I should try to change that
that would break things down you know so
I'm still running and the user is you
know first time join me join me and we
have audio together so let me figure out
you know how to do that and actually
actually use useful you might know yes
anyway he showed me a program that riot
can't can you talk about that program I
think that's great program that you know
that
[Music]
yeah oh yeah
so yesterday was asking me for key but I
kind of just you know
[Music]
okay you are right thoughts come okay oh
yeah so I've been chatting with you
yesterday
right and it looks great so so they're
actually using the the matrix is a new
[Music]
how do they call it like matrix portico
okay
you know I'm looking up you know maybe
I'm trying to search it you know see
what it is matrix okay so we found this
page and Wikipedia actually they talked
about it matrix start oak okay great so
I'm gonna read about this so
I see and you you mentioned they also
have like some forum right like right by
it like a goof chat for I see yeah
that's very cool thank you
[Music]
yeah yeah so I'm gonna frame or with it
I'm gonna you know so we got this matrix
thing right actually yesterday I didn't
even read any of the documentation I
just I just click the link you gave me
so so I registered so yeah so let's see
so I'm looking wait let's go back okay
what's next topic let's pick some next
topic look at your YouTube videos should
we go there or should we talk about
different culture one yeah so about the
Jewish culture you know the Jewish
people actually I never I never you know
stand you know to me they are like so I
never got the seems to be a big
political thing
USA so you know I say most my don't like
I say so often you're here about Jewish
or something you know sorry good
[Music]
okay so actually so the Judea that then
region so we get so we got seventy were
watching now so hi guys okay I guess a
something hi guys
type something here and you know just
let us know you are here and hey break
the loop house so a he says hi to you hi
so he's break the loop that's his hand
up yes so so so so you know guys type
just typed in the chat box okay you have
opinions or any questions or you know
whatever thoughts you come up so you
know like we can you know I can see you
and we can know where we are going that
what the sense of yeah yeah yeah I
prefer that way as well you know I don't
think you know you know I think you know
I don't know for sure but my impression
said you know us well this this is worth
a lot more today but he used to be I
mean before to know before let's say
that past ten years before is it's
mostly ruled by conservatives and this
also census [ __ ] but I mean even what
you mean like today
yeah yeah yeah that's different so you
got two questions yes
so break the loop ask you what
programming languages do you use most
often it walk there's one question the
other question is also are there any
technologies or software that you are
excited about learning in the future
okay that's two for now and the third
question is do you like better about
github or gillip
[Music]
well yeah okay so many challenges what
what if Microsoft portkey lab tomorrow
[Music]
right
but what happens if you know but yeah I
know what you mean but but open source
you can't make much money I mean the
company cannot survive I mean like you
said you can focus right so you know
there's no worry about Microsoft but in
the same way you know if be successful
you know they make some money they can
survive I you know or some big
corporation you just just focus and
create better marketing you know they
have money they put marketing and you
know they just take your code and they
copy because then then the key lab you
know will you know shrink and die so
what what do you say to that
yeah but now it's run yeah I know yeah
but now it's it's run by this Evo big
giant corporation they just take over
your I mean because they just take the
code but they have you know money
so they were marketing and they become
like centralized you know you know so
it's like you know your versus you know
the the married you know kind of like
they took it you know they because it's
open so they get what did whatever they
want and they make money yeah but yeah
but but the thing is they are making
money this evil you know cooperation
while the people who wrote the code you
know you know all contributed they you
know don't make money make money is this
evil empire you know okay okay yeah okay
I get that
so what about which language which what
programming language is most often a
walk that's key
[Music]
fifteen years I actually don't think PHP
is you know bad that Dad well you know
you hackers people think PHP sucks you
know it's one of the most read eager
[Music]
right so you know Facebook created this
hack land basically it's a kind of their
version of PHP with us I see
so he said popular at all hacklin right
okay so the other question yeah yeah so
the other question is are there any
technology so software that you are
excited about learning
[Music]
okay so here is a video to me
I watched yesterday it's funny so it
shows this pair head talking
10 second here okay
okay so yeah yeah that's a good point
you know I you know I I watch my own
videos you know every time I do one I
watch it and I notice I you know it's
yeah I know it's good to have this it
looks like a feedback you know you can't
like see yourself and you guys you know
you can sometimes see that yeah so okay
we got this okay so this pair I want to
I want to ask you and also how do you do
how do you did you do the pair but let
me just read the other question here so
big loop asks Israel do you have any
problems with pain while taking do you
use economic keyboard or any other
solutions to help paint typing like hand
problems yeah pen yeah
do you use urban ami keyboards or any
other solution to help prevent or
alleviate pain right but you are using a
mechanical
[Music]
some okay donate to Israel so can you
like do you guys too many people they're
like come to us I mean you guys like
come back oh you know come to us smoke
here
you know what you know because Chinese
Oh Mexicans do that like we make money
here then we come back and you know live
in China has been you know because it's
much cheaper there do people Israel do
that
[Music]
b-but because us is not so good I see
okay so about the bear so how is this
how did you do it
[Music]
see right okay okay that's about a pair
okay what about the culture I mean what
things you were thinking what so the
u.s. culture
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah I'm saying yeah
the Chinese culture you you respect
sisters and respect your elders that's
that's one of the very core element of
Chinese kind of you know philosophy or
you know way of life culture so he
always respected you know yeah
oh yeah
the further generations away for monkey
oh right okay I see what you mean yeah
yeah but what but what about the science
aspect well that's kind of more
scientific oriented
I see I mean some in Israel this was
right with with the neighbors yes so so
we do be able to decide so what's like I
have no idea what's you know what's the
Middle East situation I mean so why they
like would you be able to describe so
why you know people they fight you know
I see that a dispute on inheritance
[Music]
I think it speaks with much more in line
with traditional yeah you know like I
really have like very ignorant about the
issue you know what it's not a you mean
what do you mean what okay okay yeah
yeah
so what else we been going for one hour
okay so okay so yeah right I got one so
let me know what do you think so so so
so I think that the Western for us
culture of Ravi waste and war in general
that they never thought are in general
like they they are more focused in the
video of freedom justice materialist
materialistic worldview
you know logic and also watching logic
in math you know so I mean so
individualism freedom justice logic and
math kind of you know that so as opposed
to Chinese ASEAN which we don't focus on
any of these concepts and democracy you
know well because for example there is
no because in in general the Chinese
tradition they they don't they don't
award I mean the society do not have
high regards for craftsmen or
mathematician or magicians like like you
are the low if you if you are you know
mathematician Westman you are kind of
the low very low respect or kind of in a
society like we don't it's not something
we elevate you know we respect you know
beside that so I mean
yeah but so Chinese philosophers they
are not based on logic at all they you
know not like the Greek you know Rhys
Rhys total you know whatever nothing
like that
they came 100 I think you guys okay yeah
so okay yeah so I'd somewhat yeah I
didn't know no but it so anyway yes I
was saying we don't when a discuss
philosophy its small about like things
like social norms I mean they don't use
logic at all I mean also it's because of
the Chinese language there's no logic
this is like in Weston you know society
when you talk when you give a lecture
over you debate you know even you have
the word debate that that almost like
exists so in Chinese so what I'm saying
is that the Chinese culture you you kind
of you don't have kind of the logic or
reasoning or rationality kind of concept
so that's why for example example
quickly for example when you hear you
know Chinese Tao oh you know Zeno you
know you sometimes hear that in
communities so it's always all kind of
roundabout you know whatever they say is
you can have 100 interpretations you
know it's kind of like that
yeah and young you know so Chinese you
know do you see what I'm saying it's
like that
[Music]
well well if I can say I guess we are
more strict with our children I mean I
mean the the Emmys not I mean they are
great mathematicians in in in China and
and you know history of maths and some
great things are from China but so so
it's not and also they are all God you
know great engineering in China no no
[Music]
okay so so so what I'm saying is like
the Chinese culture in general in the
way people think the culture the
ferocity he said we don't we don't it's
not like Western like we do not
emphasize or bring out or focus you know
logic reasoning rationality but even but
despite that of course we do engineering
you know we still do we have astronomy
engineer well you do you do have you
obviously you have to have you know math
is very logical thing but I mean yeah I
know maybe it's hard to explain but I
mean we don't okay so
these expenses I know
no no it's it's there I mean so the
issue is I'm not able to I'm able to
show you exactly what I mean well okay
maybe it's like this you know like the
way we are arguing I mean you know
talking about this subject right now you
are being extremely logical like you are
chasing me you know like I'm saying you
know this no and you are saying you know
but but they have magic otherwise how
can you do it you know yeah and I guess
what you mean
[Applause]
and what you mean but we don't tell me
we don't that that's the thing I mean
this is about culture and thinking in
general I mean that the way you perceive
things yeah yeah I mean it doesn't mean
you don't have logic it doesn't mean
when you do math you throw away logic
because you throw it out you cannot do
math you cannot you cannot have
engineering because engineering
everything is you know very everything
is physics you know materialistic you
know you have to do it exactly the way
to you know to engineer but but the
thing is what I'm saying yeah yeah yeah
yeah so so you don't see what I mean I
think I see what you mean but but I
think i think that illustrate the point
like when we are talking about you know
we are talking about this thing you are
choosing logic you know you are saying
[Music]
no I agree I agree that's that's yeah I
I totally see what you mean but that's
not the like we're talking about like
the general culture you know Western
society you are saying describe is
specific you know like today
okay all right I think I see what you
mean so so maybe maybe that is because
that that's a problem with me into
logical you get into this situation
becoming a logical at all anyway yeah so
I think we've been going on for an hour
and 14 minutes so maybe
hey if romantic hey mo Matic so maybe is
anything else you like to say from me
neither me neither yeah neither yeah and
also we excluded you know I haven't been
thinking about Middle East you know your
conscious culture so anyway
[Music]
okay yeah we think maybe we can talk
about that yeah so yes hey info Matic so
I think we gonna wrap up informatics any
questions we got five guys watching so
anything else you smell anything you
want to say some guys is good my channel
doesn't have
okay so that let's do this again then
it's you know we we chat off I and and
you do this again
so thank you for coming by and see you
guys bye