good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of s talk show we are going to
code emac disp today a lot emac disp
probably one hour okay it's just going
to be pure emac dis
coding uh so I'm going to write a
command there are several commands to
write so one of the command I want to
write is to write a command to normalize
is YouTube url you see YouTube Ur
YouTube in the past few years introduced
several variations of URL for example
you have
.be then you have the normal
youtube.com/watch
something uh then you have slash live SL
something they introduced this like few
month ago so it's annoying so I want to
canaly you know write a command so you
press a button and the YouTube url
becomes becomes I would say this one
okay which is shown in the URL field of
a of a talk of of a YouTube You Know
video so I want to canonize them into
this wrer command so that's one of the
emac command and there are several uh
resize images convert to jpeg so there
are several other things to
do okay so if you are here say hi okay
hello six okay let's begin let's just
start to code uh so instead of me
talking nonstop hello B okay so let's
start to code um yeah S Talk Show so
today so let's begin to write a command
emac lisp okay now let's go to let me go
to let me get the problem here
okay
so here is the description of the
problem and let's just start to code
okay so iMac this so write a command to
normalize uh URL let's copy
that put it
here
[Music]
uh okay
defend uh defend
so this will be named
Kar
HTML
YouTube
normalize okay on the pink window you
can see all the command course and uh
and the command name and uh the
keystroke I'm using sofly
keys and I'm using V keyboard okay you
can just search it and you'll know what
it means okay
so so doc string let's why don't we put
this in Doc string
so
normalize YouTube url okay and the
version today's date okay and uh
examples of YouTube url
okay so the first one is the normal
that's what's shown in the URL field of
a of a YouTube and then you have this
variation okay
so and then you have this live variation
okay so the first thing you need to do
is to grab the YouTube video ID you see
for every YouTube video there is
this
um
uh 11 characters sequence of characters
that's that's the YouTube ID so you need
to grab the YouTube YouTube
ID you know you you need to pause it um
so let's describe what we're going to
do algorithm algorithm steps
okay
uh grab the current URL under cser find
the YouTube ID 11 Char stream
sequence 11 chart sequence okay then
then
um then okay so
let's then uh
then once you have the ID
then delete Cent
region okay then you just
insert okay that's the steps algorithm
steps so now let's grab so first of all
you need to grab the the line yeah let
me show you so for example uh S Talk
Show and uh for example here is today's
talk show you can see this is the link
showing browser you see this is link so
when you put your csor on a URL you want
to grab this region you want to find the
beginning position and end position of
this okay so uh that we can do
by okay let uh thing at Point okay
actually bounce of thing at Point okay
that's the command you want now this
command this is a library bundled with
emac what we what this will do is that
it will return a cons pair of the
beginning position and end position okay
so in here this will be just the URL so
let's describe function let's
see yeah so actually I don't have it I
mean in my template okay so that will
Returns the bound so let's let me do
that
let
BDS
boundary okay let boundary is equals to
that
then so that's a cons pair then okay so
I want to Define a variable xp1 xp2
that's a beginning position and end
position okay and here let's just say
set
xp1
car
okay then
xp2
color Okay so this this section will set
xp1 and xp2 to be the beginning and end
position of aurl under the curser
okay so now we got that so for example
we can we can print you know uh okay so
hold on a second let me show you so now
uh now let's define X URL Now by my
variable naming convention I start all
my variables with X it used to be a
dollar sign but dollar sign too too
confusing dollar sign is a standard
um uh the standard am Pearl PHP and even
Ruby in many languages but it's too
confusing in IM LP so I now I start my
variable name with X why do you need to
do that you don't need to do that but
however this will make the variable
stand out so as supposed
to you know so this is this is
advantageous this is part of the issue
of programming language syntax design so
in many
languages you by simply looking at the
variable name or function name it tells
you it gives you several information
about what that variable is or what that
function is for example in many in
Ruby if I if you have a
variable a function name ending in
question mark that means that function
always either return true or false in
Ruby in scheme okay in lisp that's
typically P but it's not it's not strict
so some function that returns true or
false it doesn't end in p some other
function end in p but doesn't always
return true or false so in lisp case
iMac lisp and common list I believe
common lisp to it's it's like a up
system so in Ruby in scheme in closure
Lis whenever you see a function ending
in question mark that always just return
true or false and in wolam language
that's Q okay I have an article that on
that uh
so you can just search for S predicate
predicate in programming languages and
naming okay so that's the article uh
okay so you can read that I'm starting
to digress so here's some example in
lisp here is wam language they all end
in q and in Ruby they all end in
question mark same for scheme Lis and
closure okay so anyway that's a
deoration so let's continue to code
really learning a a lot thank you just
want to say hi thank
you okay you guys you uh if you like my
stuff pay me okay because pay is the
most important um you you know that that
would be uh very much appreciated PayPal
or patreon Okay so let's go back so now
we got uh we got the beginning end okay
so let's define the URL so let's also
set let's also set the URL
here uh what do you want uh so so now
you have a beginning and end position
you want to grab the text in between so
that would
be uh both of subring no properties okay
so xp1
xp2
okay uh okay so we need to put this uh
inside
here okay so that is
that okay so X URL is a
string now why no properties what what
what's with the no properties because in
emac every string they every string they
actually have a property attached it
attached to it what what does the
property do for example syntax coloring
how does emac know this part is red how
does emac know this part is bold how
does emac know this part is purple
that's text properties okay so in emac
any text or
string may have properties attached to
it but you but sometimes you don't need
it so that's why you say buer substring
you grab this string but you don't want
the properties it usually doesn't matter
you can you can for example you can also
do that will work too
okay okay so so the URL is a URL okay
now now what you need to do is find the
YouTube vid ID okay now I believe I
already have a command for that so let's
try to find it so let's save save us
sometime okay so let's go to ca HTML mod
so let's go to to S HTML
mod uh okay open the source code so
there are 5,000 lines of code and search
for YouTube Okay so this so there it is
HTML get YouTube ID so yeah so you just
pass a URL and and you'll return an ID
so this function you you can see it
tries to use a regular expression to
match the string and basically you want
to grab 11
characters so this function let's let's
just use it okay so let's use
it okay uh okay so you need a
URL okay so now you need to Define a
variable
set vid ID
okay okay so you now you got a video ID
fantastic you don't need this comment
because this comment it's obvious from
this you know this so there's a there's
a tip for writing comment in programming
language you do not want to comment on
something that's patently obvious for
this for example this one HTML get
YouTube
ID you know this function name so it's
obvious so you don't need this common
okay so anyway so let's put uh declare a
variable there there we have it so now
we got a YouTube ID now it's all simple
now it's almost done so now we just
delete the region okay let me just write
it delete region delete region from the
beginning and end position of the thing
then then just insert insert the new
canonized YouTube url which is this one
okay so let's insert this uh let's
insert uh let's see where do you want
okay so you want
format okay so this part is the ID
remove that it's there and uh you add a
variable
there okay so that should be it remove
the beginning that should be it that's
that's it for this command I believe so
okay delete region insert okay I think
that's it
now now let's let's just uh shrink it so
that prey the documentation you know
okay eval the buffer so now emx knows
the command now let's go to uh let's go
to okay so for example this is today
today's YouTube okay we're going to call
the command on this and see what happens
okay HTML
YouTube normalize HTML there it is okay
do
it fantastic it seems to work showing
browser okay well we we we changed that
but we didn't change this part
so okay so let's paste it there and
showing browser there it is fantastic
now let's try
it let's try it on the uh several
variations so for example all these are
variations uh let's just make a link
l so you can see all these variations
now let's just try each one of
them
uh
okay do it
here do it
here do it here okay
now we changed the source source source
URL but we didn't change change the link
text so let's fix that so let's call
command to copy all the
URLs paste it
here relink them all make a list okay
now go back to the top we don't need
this part anymore deleted showing
browser you can see fantastic they all
have changed into this same format in
fact I can watch them actually most of
them are I believe my talk show yes so
click on
that click on oh this is a fantastic
movie uh I recommend you guys watch it
I've been watching it for three hours
yesterday it's a India movie but I mean
it's just four minutes it's a funny uh
snip okay so let's open
that okay that's another okay that's the
same movie open that that's my talk show
okay fantastic we done this job good
job hi okay hi
Su any questions any comments is it good
15 Watchers say hi okay now we can take
a break 22 minutes let's get on to the
next
problem fantastic now we forgot to paste
the code let's put the code back here
so one last double check code review is
there something else you forgot okay no
I think that's it uh and we don't even
need the
common okay but anyway so okay syntax
color showing browser so we got what we
want and we don't even need this P
anymore okay so that's one thing
done clean up we don't need need this
anymore okay that's one thing done let's
next
problem uh okay copy this URL because we
talked about that's one of the things we
talked
about naming a pedac code in programming
languages okay and uh this EAC this code
let's copy it and move it here showing
browser fantastic kasar HTML mod okay
next
problem okay we did let's refresh okay
so let's see what's the next thing we
want to
code okay let's code this one okay let's
let's code did that
one say hi okay say hi hello any an
aside question what are you using as a
pointer device okay
uh I think I showed that almost in every
one of my video let me let me tell you
okay so anyway so what is this uh given
the list of file path open them all okay
let's call that um
okay uh
whoops you see I want to you see here's
a let me show the pink window so you can
see all the command names so you see
press a key to select this HTML unit a
section okay and uh I can press a key to
select it and cut it or undo or I can
just simply press one single key it will
cut it okay save it close and back to
here paste showing
browser so this is our next problem
given a bunch of file path file
path you press a
key emac will open them all in a buffer
in each one in a buff okay that's a
problem got a problem yes got solution
yes right
now okay so let's start uh what's going
on start emac this
okay Define define a function so EAC is
very
easy okay Define function doc string
let's write documentation the all
important
critical most programmers they don't
write documentations because they don't
know how to think think logically and
they they don't touch type
and it's true most programmers they
actually don't touch type and and then
then they have excuse you know they oh
touch typing is no good because all my
friends who touch type they they have
hand
painted you know so the best advice is
never become a professional you know if
you are not a profession all the
professional professional
boxers profession professional football
star professional Bas basketball star
professional karate you know they all
have lots of injuries you know so if you
want to be be the best runner you know
best marathon runner doesn't matter what
sport gy gymnastic marathon runner they
all have injuries so according to these
Prof professional programmers who don't
touch type the best way is do not go
into a
pool just don't code don't code you
never have
problems so anyway so um let's name this
function open all file
path open all file path okay so that
seems to be the right function name
that's okay that's
reasonable
uh okay so open all file path under
cursor okay that should be
it okay so now just like before the
first job the first task you need to do
is you need to
select uh kind of the current block or
the current
paragraph uh let's see let's
see how do we going to do
this yeah so assume so you have a block
of uh uh uh you have a block of text so
assume the block is separated by empty
line above empty line below so you got a
block of text grab that and then you
assume each line is a file path
okay and then you just go through each
one and just open them very trivial okay
so uh so actually we have written code
already so yeah let's just use my code
because last year
2023 you know had almost I did about 100
videos on emac disp coding okay every
video is pure emac disp coding so I've
done this you know what we need to do
now like literally 100 times you know
because some sometimes people watch me
will say oh but you where can I see you
code lisp I want to see emac lisp coding
yeah but I already did a lot uh you know
so so let's just use my command instead
of um okay let me show you where is the
command Okay so go to emac blog blog
okay search uh just search
fora uh get there it is get thing so
this is like the get thing at Point
point before but it features some other
features so so what we want is get
bounce of a thing
okay
yeah okay so let's go back so we just
call this function and this is free you
can get you can just download it okay
the source code is here okay so get
bounds of a
thing unit unit is going to be a
block
okay yeah
so so what does it return let's see
let's double
check I believe it returns a cons payer
too
so oh it returns uh
what return the boundary of a unit under
Cruiser return a conel okay just like
just like thing at Point okay so like
before xp1 xp2 which is a beginning and
end position and
then then let's declare a local
variable okay so that's a boundary then
set
xp1 car
bounds
xp2 C
the bounds okay and we let's add a new
variable x uh uh text okay so then set X
text to
be both subring no properties just like
before
clean up the code there it is so now you
get the beginning position of the block
of code and you get the text okay now we
just
split okay split string text split
string by by the new line character okay
let's see what is the
default
describe function split string
separators okay
separators
uh if it's n Neo it should be a regular
expression um but it's not if it's NE it
defaults to yeah it defaults to this it
basically defaults through y space
space space um
yeah wh space Tab and so on so no we
don't want we want our own
okay and just say that okay let's forget
about Aid nose
Okay so split string so let's add a new
variable lines okay let's say paths okay
then
set a of a list of
path okay so now we got a list of path
now for each one of them we just open it
so easy map c will map a function to
your list of path and what does the
function do it just open
okay so it just uh so in emac the
function to open a file is called find
file okay so you can just say f file
okay and
uh let's look at the documentation fine
file uh yeah file name okay so in fact
you don't need this lamb do you just you
can because that's a function we want
you don't need anything extra okay so
that's it make it pretty let's prettyy
our
code that's it okay I believe that's it
convenient function because often when I
you know I started to you know often I
need to open a bunch of file path so I
think that's it so let's try
it okay one double check last double
check
uh yeah so find file okay so evaluate
the code now go to the talk show
okay let's open let's put them okay
let's put a empty line at the beginning
and at the end so okay and now if I now
call the command it will open all this
file path but first of all let's check
this is my list of buffers right so you
only have two open so now all the others
are the emac buffers like the messages
and so on
okay now close that now if I call it
should have like 10 you know also okay
s
open
uh oh yeah that's it do
it there it is showing browser PE book
survey
2002 I have the Larry War personally
signed one of my book
okay
next uh next next next open Pearl logo
fantastic a history of pearl
logo okay that's one of my article next
showing browser programming language
comparison Pearl python Ruby JavaScript
PHP lisp okay one of my article uh which
one is easier to learn which one is most
easy to learn which one is more support
functional
programming which one is more
objectoriented which one is better
designed which language is more of a
code okay so I give you a ranking of all
these
questions which one has the best
documentation okay so you can read this
article okay next showing browser
programming blog archive okay 2011 10
years ago so you can for example let's
show one of them the day Steve Jobs
died Apple and Google website
screenshots so you can a record of
History so I record
them uh okay so let's see next article
showing browser on the survival
strategies of Larry W versus Richard
strowman now this is a lot of people
don't know who is Larry War anymore
because my phone that's Pearl that's a
creator of pearl for about 15 years
Pearl is is the most popular programming
language from about
1997 to 2007 okay the most popular
language top three I'll say top top
three C C++ Pearl okay to about 1997 to
2007 about that range most popular and
Larry W the Creator Paul parel is like
you know spread all the fake garbage you
know like the best the best properties
of a programmer is laziness you know
this like Unix
spread you know so he's responsible
for introducing a lot forse information
like P you know Theory versus practice
you know like the the he gives you gives
gives gives you the sense spread the
sense that computer science is oh it's
overrated you know Pearl is the best you
know you just do this this and you can
solve this you know you know those kind
of thing like you know spread
misinformation this Larry W
skum you know for 10 for 10 years it's
most popular and every programmer liter
basically almost every programmer online
you'll see they have a signature like
you know Pearl something something like
you know and many spread Larry
was crap you know he likes
those sound bite you know little CPS you
know like it sounds
fancy anyway so that's one of the
article uh okay that's the some of the
Articles I've written so close close
close showing browser close showing
browser close Okay so we have done this
job okay 40 minutes so far we can go on
to the
next emac dis code or let's clean up
first
okay okay put this back
um syntax cor showing browser okay
today's talk show that's one problem
normalize YouTube H URL okay that's done
the second problem open all file path
that's done you know before without this
command you can do it uh you can just do
it each one okay open it go back open it
go back open it you see go back you see
that's
tedious so now I can just open them all
in one
shot
close Okay so great and here's a code so
let's go on to the next problem you see
these are the things I need to do myself
sometimes you know so I thought let's
make a video of it meanwhile so okay
refresh let's see what's the next
problem so let's do one more okay now
it's 40 minutes
oh you your question about my pointing
device okay just go to uh s keyboard
block and go to the mouse section and
you have my mouse reviews let's
see so I show you how to choose a
mouse what are some of the
criterias uh uh and uh why 10 buttons
Mouse is great thing and does
DPI matter what is DPI and what about
polling rate you know the gamers when
they talk about M about Mouse they're
talking about these things the polling
rate does it matter what is polling rate
okay so and Optical versus laser mouse
which one is better you know some of the
gamer you know in the beginning it's
just op Optical like around year 2000
it's you know Microsoft first invented
Optical Mouse before that it's a roller
ball you know I don't know if you
guys have seen
that uh let me show you some okay Mouse
and maybe that's it for emac coding is
does anyone likes to see more emac
coding tell me okay otherwise let's just
talk about Mouse for a bit then that's
it okay some of the you know there's a
lot quite a lot interesting
um track B and
uh okay so let's see actually search for
ball and for
mouse mouse history okay so there it is
so you see this page is Mouse history
this is the first
Mouse by the famous Douglas angle B very
famous
1968 so that's the first Mouse then in
the 1980s and 1990s Power Station this
is before you have personal computers
but on Unix machines and list machines
list machines you have a mouse with you
need a optical
pad specialized pad to use it typically
three buttons so this is known as
workstation Unix workstation on Solaris
and so
on then you have so this is mouse
Evolution from 1985 to 1995 so you can
see next computer Apple's Mouse Apple
Mouse IBM Mouse and so
on okay that's some of the mouse history
and and uh then you also
have apple Mouse history uh okay
so so here's some so the first Apple
Mouse looks like that from 1989
something like that then this one about
1990 I used I used all of them I use
yeah literally all of
them most of the time I own each one of
them because I was a Mac User for you
know starting
1992 so Apple Mouse
history then okay so you
know but Apple Mouse is actually the
least ergonomic okay I don't recommend
Apple Mouse the least
ergonomic so Apple Mouse I wanted to
show you uh so this a track boo key
board and here is a do it yourself track
B it becomes fairly popular today uh you
can you can very
nice okay so let's show so this is a
keyboard with track B you can still
buy uh and this this this this track B
is very interesting it got two score
Wheels okay now this track ball is made
by this company um A4 A4
Tech okay but the track boo quality is
pretty bad this company I forgot it's
from China or Taiwan but anyway two
track bow I mean two score Wheels this
is a fantastic idea okay this is the
best if you actually have a quality
mouse or track ball with two sore wheel
that's the best because squore wheel is
the
most uh suitable for a lot of reasons
for scrolling page for uh for scrolling
the tab for example previous tab next
tab for example next next previous pre
previous
previous and this one also got two
square Wheels okay so anyway so so for
any task any command any task you need
to do that involves previous and next
you want a score wheel okay including
previous tab next tab or previous window
next window next next next window next
window previous window okay previous tab
next tab previous window next window or
previous workspace next workspace or or
if you are in
um
uh let's go back to emac okay so for
example
previous
uh previous
paragraph next
paragraph previous file previous file
previous file next file next file you
know I'm going I'm going into a cycle
because I only have two files next file
so anything that involves previous word
next
word anything that involves previous and
next also previous
page next page okay anything involving
previous next you want on the squore
wheel that's the best thing that's the
best most optimal okay so that is
why um this you know this this great
idea so what about the modern one that
has that let me show you okay A a modern
Mouse so a modern mouse that have two
wheels is this one okay I recommend it
Logitech MX Master now they have like
several versions now they have the
latest version um but anyway the other
wheel is St wheel okay so you can buy it
go to my website and buy it okay let's
let me copy your link let me do some
self
promotion
okay I think that's it for today so let
me finish talking about Mouse for a few
more minutes okay
so
so and uh Apple Mouse history do it
yourself track ball keyboard with a
giant track
ball uh a mouse or track B with two
wheels fantastic but however they the
company doesn't make quality product so
and also this is Asian this is like 20
years ago they don't make that
anymore and here's this one this brand
is also a A4 Tech I think it's from
China and then this idea two track ball
track ball this is also fantastic idea
okay when you have a ball it's
essentially just you know it
it contains the functionality of a
square wheel so you can think of one of
these ball as a square
wheel ite it subsumes the functionality
of a square wheel but of course it can
do much more you can you know turn
sideways so anyway uh two track B is
also a great idea
okay then you have Mouse history okay we
talked about this the first Mouse um I
wanted to show the mouse mechanism uh
somewhere on my page you know you have a
ball literal a ball underneath the
mouse uh okay I didn't see it but anyway
so let's open let me tell you so what
what mouse am I using okay so so these
are recommendations for Mouse uh let's
see so there's another issue squore
wheel do you like it notched wheel or uh
let let me show you so you can see right
now the mouse my this is my mouse this
is got a spin wheel so if you know it
can spin for like 20 minut 20 seconds
fantastic so on the mouse wheel issue
you have the notched scroll
versus versus
smooth and uh then also you can spin the
spin wheel is O only available on the
Logitech okay and I considered it a like
necessary so that's why I stick with
Logitech mouse I believe they patented
it that's why other Mouse makers cannot
make a spin wheel I believe so anyway
there's also smooth or notched so that's
a issue you have to
consider uh then of course then you have
a sing wheel here a video actually I
talked about it quite a few
times it spin for like
um for like 25 seconds okay then there's
a mouse size comparison there's mouse
weight
comparison uh then there is BAS Mouse
Mouse for programmers okay yeah these
three I recommend so if you ask my
opinion about Mouse these
three I recommend
okay uh yeah that's about it that's
that's about it okay that's it for today
I
think let's see how many people 14
okay 15 minutes okay bye
guys
I'm just going to copy the links to my
website so
that so that other people can see okay
so great
Mouse CL Apple Mouse history close do it
yourself track ball close keyboard with
a giant track ball
close Mouse with two scrore wheels close
Okay close track B with two
balls close history of mouse the first
Mouse close Okay showing browser
refresh
refresh there it is thank you guys
bye okay pay me okay uh this you know
this is sponsorship sponsor today's ad
is sponsored by you okay patreon me
Amazon GI card me PayPal me or you can
buy my entire website how
much no just $300 six
6,000 files of technical info the entire
you know as a donation so yeah okay
bye