good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Santos
show today's topics is Emacs
why does Emacs not have a such files in
directory feature why does it does it or
does it not we are going to find out and
a bunch of associated problems with that
you know Emacs yeah
searching file single directory not
searching files in one single single
file but in a directory that is the that
is what we are going to focus on today
okay excuse me let's see if I'm live
okay I'm live and so we wait so ok so we
wait wait for a few minutes for at least
one people to come out and then you know
meanwhile let's talk about this keyboard
so this is a new keyboard it's it's a
do-it-yourself keyboard this one is from
Japan and you know what's interesting is
that it's it's the entire or every key
the shape of a key is a hexagon so the
entire key arrangement is in this
honeycomb grid or triangular you know
it's also called triangular grid so
that's interesting about that but as you
can see when you put your fingers on it
basically your your middle finger is
gonna be half a key higher than the
index finger or ring finger okay and
your pinky will be half a key you know
half a key lower so index finger is half
a key higher and pinkies one is half a
kilo er you know and you can see
different angles of the keyboard
so this arrangement in the you know
middle finger have a key higher and
pinky 1/2 a kilo is this a optimal
arrangement is this a you know good
ergonomic arrangement that is a question
if because if it is let's say if it is
the most optimal you know arrangement as
far as flat you know flat surface
keyboard is concerned if it is optimal
for that case then this keyboard will be
excellent
you know you'll be one of the excellent
because you know because first of all
it's got this you know optimal
arrangement but but then but but so as I
you know I try to answer that question
and I think the answer is no that is not
a optimal arrangement
you know it's most likely it's just a
fun arrangement because of the hexagons
because hexagons for some reason has
high you know has strong association
with in science in science fiction in
particular you know hexagons you know
they always looks like so sci-fi so why
is that why is this why is this
arrangement the middle finger have a key
higher and pinky 1/2 a kilo why is that
arrangement bad well because I look at
you know all the existing ergonomic
keyboard designs and for many of them
they also raise the mid the middle
finger position and they also lower the
middle finger key position let's look at
some examples so by looking at all the
all these examples some of these people
for example this guy this guy who
created this keyboard who goes by the
name of oppa I think yeah I think oppa
on Twitter and elsewhere his name is I
got his name somewhere on this page but
anyway
the creator of this keyboard you know
you can also see that the middle column
the column for middle finger which which
one wait am I like a bit stoned anyway
so so the middle finger what's going on
yeah the middle finger is here you can
see also they they are not exactly
higher back actually a little bit they
also have they are not totally flat but
anyway there is a this layout in diagram
you can see so you can see that the
middle finger is you know just a tiny
bit higher but the pinky weight this is
a middle okay so okay that middle is not
you know somewhat okay higher then you
know like 1/4 1/4 higher than the ring
finger key ok so the middle finger key
is a quarter key length then the ring
finger key and the pinky is about
exactly half key lower so for the pinky
part we got confirmation because this
guy has spent a lot of time designing
the keyboard so you know we can say his
his judgment is probably good you know
so pinky won't have a key lower so that
we can confirm okay that's good but but
the middle key do we ever have a have an
example where the middle key is have a
key higher
let's look let me show you funky words
do-it-yourself keyboards we have an
example here you can see so this
keyboard is called a verge 3 you can see
the middle column okay it's not like one
half key higher
no it's and also we can see over dogs so
the middle finger is a bit higher about
1/6
maybe 1/6 of a key length or width so
1/6 hired but no more not not half a key
higher so you can see various examples
they decide they don't the middle key
I've never seen any I don't think I ever
seen a keyboard where the middle key is
as much as half a key higher let's look
at some more examples maybe ok you can
see here you see not much then you have
a go - oh go - you know so usually the
pinky is a bit lower but of all the
keyboard I've ever seen the lowest the
pinky go is by half a key like the
keyboard I oh yeah keyboard IO is one of
the the most extreme so yeah so you know
so our conclusion about this arrangement
is that you know I you know it's
probably it's ok it's not very bad for
sure but it's probably nowhere near the
optimal as well for the reason that the
middle key is half as high you know have
a key higher than the rest then then
your pink ring ring finger or index
finger key so that's that's about that
keyboard so ok let's good afternoon
Isaac so let's talk about the main topic
we we are going to hear here today which
is this Emacs issue so so some you know
this guy post reddit question you know
he basically he says
he would like you know he mentioned that
he found he he wants Emacs to be able to
search files such files or files in a
directory without you know using
external tools if that's possible
basically is raising this issue because
in particular on Windows for example
when you on Windows you want to you know
you heard Emacs is a great editor you
download it you use it for a month
everything is great but then one day you
try to I try to find the files you know
find find a stream in order you know in
you know to see which file that contains
the straining or directory or folder you
cannot do it with Emacs because then
because you need to install some other
programs in about to do this the
question so he raised this issue so this
is particular self on Windows so do you
think this this is good I mean this we
have a text editor you know every tech
are there is there any text editor or
IDE for programmers that do not let you
search a string in file single directory
you will find no such thing they don't
require you to install external
libraries like it's not like when you go
download or you pay them you buy them
you say oh you download this but by the
way you if you want me to search
directories you also need to download
this module that you know there's no
such thing like that you just download
the whole thing every text editor and
the IDE has that feature built in you
know but Emacs doesn't and well Emacs
doesn't okay now if you are on unix
linux virus you know any of the unix
where Emacs came from basically or if
you are a Mac which is also UNIX because
since 2002 you know Mac OS X you have
you know it's it's a UNIX essentially so
meaning that you have so when Emacs is
running on UNIX platforms it's not a
problem
because on unix platforms you have this
grep command and you have this command
named find both our UNIX shell tools you
know it's a little text textual program
so on UNIX platforms you have this clip
and find utilities you know you call
them utilities so this includes a Linux
no problem or Mac no problem so in
practice it's not not a problem for
Emacs but if Emacs is running on Windows
it is a problem you know when you when
you don't have this scrap and find then
you cannot you know use Emacs to such
files in a directory but on Linux you
have crap and find you know utilities so
Emacs will actually call them like in
Emacs when you go grab let's see let's
see I mean email okay this is my Emacs
file Emacs blog so I'm going to do a
coop grip so hold on a second it's saw
start command log so you can actually
see the command I call okay and you know
that's a good thing because since we are
talking about Emacs stuff I'm using
sulfa keys so so everything now you can
see all the commands I call on a left
left window so I'm going to tell okay so
let me let's cook grab so MX g IEP you
know grab and I call it and then Emacs
does a prompt it says run grab like this
you know grab - and capital H - no - e
then I have to type something let's say
has go okay
you know so I'm trying to such has cow
in all files in this directory you know
my my Emacs directory so this directory
is got 800 files
oh why is it taking so long because I
forgot to use I forgot to filter out or
image files they are not mine they are a
lot image files and possibly even video
files so it's gonna take a while
actually let's stop it anyway I forgot
what's the syntax to filter out it
because I haven't been using it for a
long time now so anyway this is how it
works you see what happens is that when
you call grab grab grab is by the way
also Emacs command so you when um x
squared
Emacs will call the UNIX external user
utility grip to actually do the job you
know find locate the file that string is
contained then it returns the list of
files then what Emacs does is that Emacs
takes the greps output show it in your
Emacs buffer and and color them you know
and you can also they put properties to
the text so you can for example you can
click to jump to the location of the
file you just open the file so this is
great let me actually let me I'm trying
I want to stop this and we do but except
the problem is that I forgot what's a
great command to filter out HTML files I
mean I don't want image files I only
want HTML files good morning Daniel hey
do you guys know what is the great
option to you know I only want our HTML
files you know to to specify a file
suffix I'm I'm not even sure I can do
that but anyway back to the topic ok so
in Emacs when you want to such a stream
in off a single directories when you
want to such a directory Emacs requires
requires you to
Emax uses the extra extent external UNIX
utility grep and also find in lots of
Emacs commands you often see that Emacs
needs one or both of these okay so so
this is so and so this guy made a reddit
post and he's raising the issue and and
I you know I because I also run into
this problem
I do find we face all the time so I have
written a package so find you can see
link here that does the find find
searching or directory written in pure
emag Lisp so once you install this
package you don't need to install you
know UNIX Square or find and and you
know so so I have this find that year
package with an email-based and okay so
so this guy is recent with raising the
issue but then a lot they are like two
people mostly you know they vote
basically they don't they don't you know
they want to say something they want to
suggest like something else is better
okay and and and I I think I don't you
know I disagree like they are kind of
you know pushing I think they are you
know some of these people are pushing
for a ideology and you know to to to
aspect of it one is either ideology they
want to push is kind of the open source
you know they want to push it the other
part of the the thing I see you know
they are pushing is that they like they
want to try to tell you a right way you
know the like I talked about many times
this elite type of people they they they
are trying to impart they want to tell
you to do something in a certain way
because they think that is you know
better
so so on the whole issue I think the I
think the I'm going to tell you why
there are this is a critical problem
this is the problem Emax relying on
external external tools to such a
directory is a major you know it's such
a happy obvious problem it should be
corrected okay this is one of the reason
Remax Emacs is not not popular among
many other reasons like every time you
know someone says he or Emax you know we
should do you know you max is not
popular and people then you know they
are curious usually this open source
fans they they will say oh I'm curious
but what what what is a possible
suggestion to fix you know to get Emacs
more popular you know that usually they
you know they are they are genuine and
honest they they are sincere you know
they you know they are curious but you
know to me I think they are just they
are your code they don't know it okay so
you know you you can get out of it if
you really try to look even you know
you'll get out of it you know and so to
me it's like to me this problem
Emacs relying on external program it's
absolutely to any dummy okay should be
able to know this is a problem this is a
usability problem this is this is a
problem for advancing your software you
know you don't tell people to download a
text editor then when they want to
search some string or directory you say
oh because you need that other module
you need to install that's a bad thing
okay so I don't so these people
apparently they don't see this problem
in fact they are directive they're like
they they are telling you no you should
it's a better way to to you know on
Windows you need to
there are many implementations by the
way you should go install them and you
will be much faster
besides because these are you know
custom writer name and so on you know
blah blah you know
like so so in my opinion it's like Oh
totally utterly whacko opinions you know
it's not you know they are you know fact
are not facts and you know it's just
totally wrong but to them you know I can
tell you know you can tell from from
their the way they say things okay they
are like about 20 messages you can read
so from their perspective you can tell
by their tone and attitude that they
think you they think Casali you know
this sorry package is just wrong okay
okay you know it's it's not the right
thing they did they tell you you should
you know do this or that so we got this
issue so we can see the opinions differ
okay so but I'm going to tell I'm going
to put my point of view I'm going to
explain why the Emacs this this this
Emacs relying on the several detailed
reasons about why this is a bad thing
you know we're not relying on other
external tools by the way first of all
it's no big deal okay because Emacs
because we have to also consider the
history of the things and social context
you know Emacs
you know it's a the history I mean
basically Emacs is implemented for Unix
you know and for the first you know 10
20 years it's primarily used on UNIX
platforms and also Emacs is a the you
know almost the number one project of
the new foundation you know software of
free software foundation you know the
they are they want to free the idea of
free software that is a it's very Cosmo
you know they want to spread that and
Microsoft is their enemy you know
ideology enemy because the you know free
software hates the Microsoft proprietary
and you know claiming other things so so
in this situation since the email
it came from glue you know from from the
free software foundation of course they
don't they may not you know about
learning Emacs and Windows you know you
have to install other programs to do
basic things you know maybe they don't
care that's reasonable you know because
they want you to use the leaner so you
know think they don't want you to use
Windows but however they provide you a
Emacs you know for Windows if you want
then you run into problems and they it
gives them an opportunity to spread
their gospel you know to tell you hey by
the way you know we we are proponent of
you know free software so you maybe you
should consider Linux then then Emacs
will be much faster and smoother you
know you don't have these various minor
problems you know so it's understandable
you know given the background social
backgrounds that that Emacs does not you
know does not walk out of the box so to
speak to to be able to search files in a
directory that's understandable but what
what I'm saying is that the whole thing
is just no good ok yeah well I mean yeah
you know for example on UNIX
why does Emacs not you know bondo its
own search directory features because
because first of all in practice
everything just already works because
every unix where Emacs runs you know
have great and fine
you know it's like country 100% it's not
you know yeah you'll always have the
program there's no problem so so
practically speaking you don't actually
need to you know code alright another
you know module within Emacs you know to
do that so that is why you know so so on
this issue I'm not particularly saying
that Emacs should you know should should
kind of take you and find you
make it internal things like that but it
is it would it's actually a very good
thing okay it's a it I would even say it
will make Emacs much more popular
especially on Windows maybe okay the new
people that we serve our foundation
people they don't care about the windows
they prefer the fact that that Emacs on
Windows you will become very lousy they
actually put they intentionally actually
do that you know this is no secret you
know they talked about all the time they
intentionally want the Emacs on Windows
version to be inferior same thing for
Mac they only their primary you know
Emacs platform is Linux for now
actually it's heard anyway so I'm not
saying that you know I'm not saying that
we actually should that that we must
Emacs must ponder its own such file such
you I'm not saying that it's but it's
very nice to have okay and you know you
would be very nice and let me let me
start to discuss the problems okay so
yeah include right that's that's the
that that is option when you use scrap
you want only dot HTML files you then
you can say - - include I have
everything you know I know the details
of that very much because I explained
everything in detail in this article so
I'm going to just going to talk about
this article this article is problems of
calling UNIX new UNIX scrub in Emacs
this is written in 2011 the the first
version so I'm saying you know Emacs
the fact Emacs that the way when you go
crappy Mac's all find in Emacs you run
more than one issue not just okay
this program is stuck let me create a
cure there are many many issues not not
just the fact that you know external
tools may not exist not just that but
the these are the interface between
Emacs and grab the lots of problems let
me start to explain okay
the first problem is external program
problem we already covered this is bad
for Windows in practice in Windows it's
not easy okay it's not it's not really
not easy to just install a you know you
t lord if you know and expect that Emacs
will just work with it you know right
away no you're gonna spend if you are
lucky and if you are you know very
technical programmer you know there may
be within half hour you can do it
otherwise you know you're gonna spend
our an hour at least you know you have
on windows first of all which one to
download you have sick wing you have you
know you have the the others you know
there you have quite a few options then
you know you try them you explore them
you got frustrated something it doesn't
seems to work right you know on the
other hand you may not you know you you
you are not a Emacs rejects expert
because you Emacs rejects is different
from others so so maybe use something
you don't know you are too not too sure
because you know you just end up
smelling like hours then maybe you think
oh maybe then I should try you know the
VirtualBox maybe I just well you know in
Mac seeing a virtual rack you know
that's that's kind of the road people go
through the path you know normally this
happens to every programmer we see you
know you see it in stack overflows you
know like oh I tried through this but
then then they died you know anyway so
that's external program is a problem
okay it's it's a you know it's kind of
it's like a practical one you know that
you know like every commercial entity
especially those who really want to make
money okay they you know
meaning that they really want their
product to be loved if you are this is
number one concern every application
they always include bundle everything as
much as possible and and necessarily so
you know without becoming app load in
but actually you know as you know most
commercial software they become bloat
anyway they just include everything not
just that but also bloated
you know sometimes duplicate you know
things components in in their software
so you have to download five hundred
megabytes ojika bytes
except browser okay but anyway except
browser because perhaps today they try
to package so small yet a process
functionalities like ten times more than
a max ten times is is an understatement
you know the browser's features
functionality of implement difficulty or
the complexity of the protocols involved
you know the languages you know the
compiler the parser you know and also
the networking networking system
connecting to the internet you know the
whole thing the browser is like hundred
times I don't you know if we can give it
a quantity more come not more complex
more difficult to do more functionality
than Emacs you know so okay anyway so
what I'm okay we are talking about
browser because browser is example very
competitive and it is an example where
they tried to include everything in one
package
you know like today they can even read
PDF files you can open image files you
can you know they they don't ask you
like browser don't ask you oh if you
want to be able to see images please
download this plug-in you know so anyway
that you know the I don't want to get
too far because then we become fuzzy and
everything every quest everything I said
is debatable debatable
well anyway so so external program
problem and so let me take a break read
the comments okay because so I get a
pause and I can you know we focus where
we are you know so I'm going to keep
continuing explaining the problems of
coding graph in Emacs lots of problems
you have Unicode problems you have you
know rejects problems you have passing
problems and you have the interface like
the UNIX prompt problem you know like if
you are a Mac user but you don't
necessarily know UNIX like who maybe in
the 1970s 80s but today you don't expect
someone to say download a browser and
they expect him to know what is some
technical stuff but uh Emacs when you
want to search a directory you have to
understand that grab interface you know
like we just like I just I forgot what's
the you know syntax for graph to filter
out certain files by extension I forgot
and most people they are not UNIX
experts when you max prompts you that
grab thing you know let's try it again
let's look at it you know this grip -
and capital edge - - do I remember them
no and in fact every UNIX system their
options are different you have the guru
versions you have the BST grab you have
before you have you know in Asian F
query and then then you have Mac version
okay Mac version is BSD I guess but
anyway and these options they so it's a
problem you know I don't know I don't
remember what this option these cryptic
options I am let's say I'm interested in
Emacs not necessary you know I don't
want to run UNIX script for example as
an example and also in Emacs that the
regular expression is different from all
the other language
Emacs regular expression so I everyday
you know I type you know lease matching
lines okay lease matching ice house car
let's say for example okay
and actually I can say this measuring
line is H a and period SK okay that that
will search for any word H a wildcard SK
okay you know I'm doing that what least
matching lines we regular expression oh
okay so that's right I got it wrong so
let's say because there's no need no
such fun so let's say H a wildcard K
okay so we got lots of lines including
Haskell
oh just thanks Packer okay hack thanks
and thanks Haskell okay also a scowl you
know so we are using a regular
expression when we call list matching
lines there are a lot MX commands that
also use regular expressions and they
are all Emacs these regular expressions
okay Emacs regular expressions which is
different from the grab
regular expressions so when you try to
find files in a directory suddenly Emacs
pops up this script prompt like what are
those you know you understand what they
are but even if you do then the regular
expression you're going to use is d is
not the Emacs version you are used to
you know so so in this one text editor
you have to learn to regular expressions
like why is for Emacs when Emacs call
Emacs internal command then the other is
the when you max kawaii external command
you have like to you know version of
reverse but that's that is a problem
that's one of the problem ok no external
to is a
problem we explained I mean depending on
dependent on the external program is a
problem we explained and the other
problem we also explained the rigger
expression is not compatible to Emacs
rejects so when you depend on the
external grab you you essentially
require the user to learn different
rejects than the Emacs rejects okay and
dependence on familiarity of UNIX shell
syntax we already explained you know
like most people you know unless they
are UNIX hackers they don't know what
the is these options and as I
mentioned the option changes on each
depending on where you download your
Emacs or depending on your whether your
Emacs are is on Mac or Linux or what
distribution it changes so when you are
using Emacs every time you 2m x squared
you get you know depending on which
platform you are the option will be
slightly different like so if I'm
working on Macs but sometimes I do on
windows and unix linux right and so iris
before so I haven't used Linux for a
while but if I today I do then suddenly
the grab option is different then I have
to look up or what what are that you
know options are you know look look up
main page then you know that's that's
the entire thing because grep is kind of
the UNIX it's okay I mean it's technical
it's it's for programmers okay it's not
a lot you know Emacs fan like to say oh
we are not it's not just for programmers
a lot eMac you know non-programmers
writers also like to use Emacs you know
phone already novels and so on but but
then this in this example you can see if
you depend on external grab you are
requiring them to like pick up quite a
lot of rather technical things you know
the UNIX crap option you know and then
because it's a nature of Unix then you
have to man page so code man page it
then then it's like direct directly
direct to her hell okay this no escape
starting to read man pages okay so we
already covered mentioned several
problems I'm gonna talk about us but let
me read the comments good morning base
so base you just arrived so let me read
the comments so daniel says daniel says
daniel has said a lot of things
he provided the great option
it's bad you know eunuchs scrape and
find I tell you right now that's one of
my major issue with the UNIX philosophy
philosophy I'm starting to swear but I
thought you know in this video I try not
to do that because you know there are
other people involved so anyway so yeah
you know I talked about this topic theme
often and often people questioned me
asked me to buy the UNIX philosophy
that's you know this is a very good
example impromptu example of how UNIX
you know UNIX philosophy one of the
things they say is that things should be
do one thing well okay everything should
do one thing well and small it's
beautiful okay and do one thing well so
does UNIX utilities to one thing way out
no they do they do not do it well you
know and then that is okay let me
explain
this so this is a good example you know
great grab is a tour to search to locate
a string in a file now if you want to
grab a whole directory now UNIX in UNIX
you have another tool which is called
find ok UNIX utility Fi and define the
purpose of that is exactly to traverse
directories so you will visit every file
in a directory or sub directories that's
the exact purpose so if you are thinking
you know by the general pattern of UNIX
okay you combine combat commands you
know to you chain them together you know
so they everything every command do one
thing very well and you can combine
another command that do another thing
very well you chain them bit together
they become very powerful this is
actually a idea of functional
programming
it's called composition okay
I have written rants about this topic
like Tim more than 10 essays so I'm just
going to point them out so you could
read them if you want so this article is
called the nature of UNIX philosophy
actually not this article I'm going to
show you another article okay this one
UNIX pipe is functional language this is
actually one of the orange and have a
frayed a hole said that he is the
inventor of oak you know a frayed a is
his name in oak the UNIX utility so he
he actually said the UNIX pipe is based
on the idea of functional composition
okay that's what he said
so but so back again the UNIX says you
know SMO is powerful and you can Bank
programs together small you know do one
thing well but does UNIX command do one
thing we all know example grip and find
so by the ideology of you know UNIX
philosophy philosophy what should happen
is that great does not have the option
to should not have the option to such a
directory because that's not his job his
job is only such a stringing a file then
you have the find utility whose job is
to you know go through mini files so you
combine them but that's not the case
actually so grep actually do provide
very cumbersome you know idiotic own
options this is true for like all every
Unix Linux commands like each one they
don't do one thing where at all and then
but then they have like hundred more
options that do wildly various things
that other programs also to so it's like
the syntax is not consistent you know
someone - - -
- letter letter like I explained in this
article in detail you can see about the
syntax abused like ambiguous like
totally you know ambiguous you know
programmatically ambiguous the the UNIX
command-line syntax and it's just like a
huge noodles
you know syntax soup and semantic noodle
okay so it doesn't so grab and find so
okay so if you have crap and you have
fine you use combine them that's perfect
right yeah ideally but not the way that
you'd need in UNIX in Linux for example
find you know it is so stupid
find now has its own option to call
command okay but not using the link your
UNIX pipe which is the connection
between every small programs fine has
its own option like - II to execute okay
then you put put a command that's that's
fine internal command not not external
okay not not great so so fine as but but
how many commands are they of just full
fine to do not not not not many like you
have delete I think that's it so
according to the UNIX philosophy what
find should do is really just just go
through directories and each visit each
you know Walker directory that's it then
you pipe you know use Python macaque
mechanism or some other general to then
you can delete a file or you can grab
the file or you can whatever that's
ideal then everything will be beautiful
you compose things together that's not
the case you know you have grip you have
find you and then and you know and also
yeah that particular thing you know that
it's extremely ugly you okay for
up x ox XR case one another one
of the more
I'm texting and it's often required in
fact to use the in combination with find
okay so the UNIX you know the UNIX
philosophy yogi it's so that that is why
why I say I say this since like 20 years
ago UNIX C program in C language and
UNIX are the the father of everything
that sucks in computer programming
industry they are the bad design they
spread idea of bad design virus
you know crap like like voodoo you said
yeah the nature of UNIX philosophy so
let's so we are almost done let's show
what is that techno techno man see
techno man sees a guy who who created
the keyboard and he is also the keyboard
let me show you
techno man see take no man see is a guy
who created this way I can remember the
name also know author
so techno messy created also created the
Emax closure Atreus okay Atrix he'd
created the atria skeeball
he's also Emacs user and Emacs Lisp
programmer expert
he created the crochet the package for
closure in Emacs he also created
he helped at least but he also created
by himself
the Lanigan which is the closure
installation packages so actually I have
lots of tutorials on these so let me
show you
sorry closure cider
yeah cider is the package name for for
Emacs to do closure stuff so let me show
you some articles I've written so
crucial Lincoln is the closures
installation tool like you know and
techno Mansi wrote it and so I have a
tutorial about that but this is like
four years ago though I'm not sure how
much has changed
Selena GaN crucial in akan then you have
closure cider cider is a package for
Emacs to interface closure and also you
know for closure mod so you can run
closure code inside Emacs interactivity
which which is it's very good by the way
and now it's maintained by the other guy
also very popular the projectile author
okay so that's email exciter in Lanigan
closure so I you know I because they
they are we are mentioning them because
they are all created by this techno
Mansi guy say that so let's look up
what's this Daniel's link
so take techno messy he's obviously are
very expert
very good programmer you know expert of
Linux no expert in mclees closure and
also you know it also Lua you know he's
you know he's doing dua programming
language it seems like he's he likes it
I don't know anything about Lua
anyway he by the way Sacha also has
video interview of techno man see you
might check it out his his real name is
Phil hackleburg you know on his kid hub
yeah so so you know you might check out
his stuff it's interesting so let me get
back to the why you know Emacs today on
crap is a problem they are - I think to
most small things I want to mention then
I'm going to read the comments okay so
problem
Koni okay so UNIX shell quote escape
problem so let me let me just summarize
so external well let me just say UNIX
shell quote escape
problem that's another problem okay for
example if you are trying to grab some
some regular expression let's say okay
let's go to my let's go to my Emacs blog
and that's such for let's go to rejects
okay so I open a file that contains my
Emacs regular expression tutorial for
Emacs Lisp so let's see I want to grab
this line okay let's say I want to grab
this line okay so let me show you what I
mean okay so I know I know there's a
string of text because in my file I have
that string of text which is this
this text happens to be a regular
expression string okay it's a regular
expression syntax but I don't care about
that oh oh I kill it right now is that I
want to find out in in all my websites
you know five thousand files I want to
find out if another file of my file
contains this stream okay so what you're
gonna do okay you go grab right he makes
the normal way you go grab and how you
gonna pass this how you gonna pass now
you if you just pass directly in this
string it's gonna it's it's gonna choke
because there are many escapes you have
to deal with so how do you do that it's
almost it's essentially you practic it
it's very difficult it's impossible okay
one way to do it is to put this text you
want to search into a file like save it
like right now I save it let's say xx
dot txt okay
I saved this file then I call grab then
I call grab I don't know remember what's
the syntax but there's an option that
you know a file option so you specify
our filename and the in this file name
is a string or regular expression back
web we are used to such you know the
stream but it's a problem you know
because I don't want to save to a file
first you know that that's a major step
we aren't you know that's a major thing
but so wherever you have a string you
want to search it doesn't matter whether
you want to just plain text search or
regular experience expressions such when
you have a string that involves lots of
back slashes of quote you have a problem
of calling external to web because the
interface the the the crowd to unquote
them you know it's it's practically
impossible to solve you know all the
specs such end quote and different
shells there
different syntax you know so so that is
also that is a problem by the way this
is not just a like a theoretical problem
okay I run into this problem then you
know I run like right now I cannot do it
unless I save this line into a file you
know like sometimes when you have to you
know do your walk in a day job you have
to such vows many times you don't have
time to each time use such a file you
have to save the file you know you know
if they save the rich regular expression
in a file that's you know City yeah I
run into these problems you know like I
tried to such a queue cannot you know
it's just not sometimes it's at foot for
example let's look at this my Emacs file
you know Emacs this regular expression
tutorial then this line is a JavaScript
code that's part of the Google Ads
thing you know JavaScript code you
tracker you know every website uses use
it okay so don't worry any website you
visit you will have a Google tracker
with it so the purpose of that is you
know it tells that you statistics about
how many people visit your page you know
things like that and Google also provide
like male/female what age group you know
things like that because you know that's
a big business PD a multi-billion dollar
business marketing so anyway so you I'm
sure you use a lot of you if you are
blogging you probably are you know
already you know what it is you are
using Google trackers you know Google
Analytics to help you get a view of how
you know who is visiting your site you
know like how how busy so so this so you
have to have this code in every file you
know basically if you want to track that
file okay so but let's say I forgot you
know I want to double make sure every
file contains the string so what I have
to do I have to search this string I
have to search this
Katie javascript code how can you then
then you have a problem with external
grab because then it's gonna be very
difficult to quote this single quote
double quote slashes or back slashes
that may exist there you know that's a
problem but if it's all buting Emacs
it's not a problem for example let me
show you okay
for example let's just okay let's copy
the whole line let's not save I did
something wrong here okay so let me show
you how I have my tools okay let me show
you so I call I call this sapphire text
command and I just paste the whole
complicated string multi-line JavaScript
code and I say enter it asked me which
directory I want to find okay that
directory and dot HTML files enter then
it prints all all existence all files
you know containing that that string I
don't have to worry about coding and
stuff so this is Mike's a find package
we mentioned you know so you can see all
these files like about 800 of them and I
can you know press Enter just just open
that page at that location you know so
so that is why you know oh this is
written in you might be you know I did
that to solve these problems so okay so
that's one problem where when you have
complicated string another problem is
that when you have you Unicode non-ascii
characters in your search stream for
example for example as you know I have
these
let's go here I have this Unicode
website where you can see all the
Unicode emojis or other symbols suppose
I want to find if okay so let's go let's
copy that let's let's go to my Unicode
file directory this is this is the
directory okay let's go to the directory
so you can see all these files are
Unicode stuff you know they correspond
to you know each of these pages now but
I'm wondering if maybe I have one of the
characters we duplicated somewhere so
let's copy this character let's say
Hospital copy go to Emacs then such I
want to search I want to find this
hospital character in all files in this
directory so normally I just do grab
right I mean you would normally do grave
so let's see if we can do that I pasted
the hospital enter oh I forgot because
again it's trying to search your image
files and as we know last time it's take
10 minutes and still running close ok
let's close it cured yes ok so
that's a that's a external tool problem
I rather just use something building so
let's try again using my saw fine
command you know on the instance in
within two seconds it's done so all
these so I have these files highlighted
in pink that shows the you know that
shows the character I can press ENTER
and you can see in this blog post I can
show in browser in this my blog back in
2015 I have mentioned
that hotel characters somewhere here so
let's see places emoji yeah right there
you can see that kind of motel symbol
okay close that so that's and that's the
problem of the Gramp okay so in summary
let's just make a summary and that
that's a there'll be it for this topic
external program problem for example on
windows you don't have you need to
install it that's a problem
unix shall quote escape problem okay
dependence on familiarity of UNIX shell
syntax that's a problem regular
expression not compatible to Emacs
regular expression that's a problem
UNIX stream problem you know when you
have Unicode like you know you cannot
rely on we're processing it correctly
because the issue is complicated because
Emacs first have have all have to pass
the argument to the shell square and
when you have unit and an ASCII code
sometimes encoding or escape is involved
you know that's complicated so sometimes
it will pass through the grab wrongly or
for some and also when grep finds all
the occurrences it returns to Emacs you
know Emacs takes its input again you
have to deal with non ASCII characters
and that is often a source of the
problem because during this
communication characters get up
you know because the único is especially
I mean even today it's a problem I think
for example there is this actually a bug
okay actually I have a lot more I have
like 5 more reasons okay but I'm not
going to go through them you can see on
the screen
or just you know yeah you can you can
read offline did you know so the so
that's it yeah that's it about that
topic you know you really got lots of
problem but but simple you know for our
reasons you have people saying that oh
it's no problem and you know this or
that but by the way they they they're I
have been searching I've been trying to
determine whether there exists features
in emacs that allows you to search
directories you know rittany emag wisp
actually I never got a firm answer on
that I think that the times I spent
basically answer is no but I was never
100% sure and in this where someone
mentioned multi ocher let's go to my
Emacs blah
so people has mentioned several packages
I mean commands multi aqua multi I
search for project find rejects so I
have to look for I don't know now
project might replay rejects is that a
let's see if I is i building
let's to describe function let's see
project fine file is an interactive auto
load compare function in project RTL
so let's visit project da da where does
project idea came from okay
project idea is part of Emacs so project
fine file says visitor fire when in
current projects routes oh so so that
does that but the question remember the
question is does it rely on the external
tool so actually I have to you know it's
gonna take a while to look into that but
in a past of the times I've spent
basically the answer is yes they did you
know I have not found a email into
implementation yet
let's try multi ocher let's see what the
heck
so Mota ochre is an interactive compiled
list function in replaced RTL okay let's
go to replay start year and let's see
the code it's calling a car I think it
is calling a car a car is basically just
leased matching lines so obviously yes
obviously so Emacs can such directories
you know all you have to do as is
actually just call this matching lines
on each file and yeah but is that what
multi occur is actually doing or is it
calling grab I don't know we have to
look into so I was planning to do this
you know to find to try to find them in
real time but I think we already talked
long today
1 hour 5 so should I like to so I'm
going to answer the comments ok read the
comments then the next question is
should I you know like to live streaming
of trying to determine whether Emacs has
building such the command okay let me
read the comments
so Daniel says by the way for project
management and quick access to project
files in Emacs there is this on github
fine fine oh oh yeah okay I know I heard
of that
I don't you know so so that is probably
good you know to you know it's probably
a good program but you know I have my
own saw fine so I don't you know I don't
need I don't need those others you know
I you know I you know you K you can try
mine you know you give it a shot
since ace works on Windows yeah okay
okay so it works on blah blah blah and
the only dependency is PST you'll find
then that's makes it worthless in our
context you know that's let's see that's
a point
so Daniel say as soon as I experimented
with using AG from inside you max there
is a AG Dahlia five to ten times faster
than AK okay yeah so these days you know
I yeah this needs ten years ago there
you have lots of grapes replacements and
each one claims to be faster than the
predecessor so you have the you know you
have the ACK I think that was the first
I have article on that you know listing
them all but then the two years three
years ago you have this AG kind of you
know claim to be over we I'm the fast
I'm a fast of them all no before ACK is
like I'm the fastest there there are
these three of them well known like you
know like you facing each other but you
know that's very good but today you know
so we can see that's one example of how
technology is advancing as in society I
mean literally we have exponential
growth in sciences in engineering and
this terrible you know scary AI is
happening you know and what you know one
example of tech progress is this today
we have like new languages every year
almost every year or more than one
languages not just like single person
you know nobody five five users language
but each one has like let's say a
thousand you know a few thousand you
know it's like good robust well then you
know new languages every year you know
and usually at least ten thousand
followers and you know so that's that's
great let me show you article I need to
show my articles XRD proliferation of
languages ok this page you can see some
of the examples of the growth amazing
popular you know amazing growth of new
languages like you know you see all
these names
so this archives proliferation of
computer languages just such sorry that
you'll find it and you know so
originally this alga is written in 2008
because that's when I first begin to
notice you know I'm trying to document
my observations it's kind of like a log
a history ok so the you know so
historians may you know the future
generation may think oh when did people
start to perceive that language is
becoming you know growing a lot then
they maybe they find this article oh
it's around 2008 at least one guy you
know thought thought of it that way
so anyway back then that's 2008 but
today you have you know for example
voila gee
any factor Fantin CoffeeScript start tab
scripts ASM rust Julia or meta O'Mara's
old elm hacks
hacklin ed Jason what is edges on a
pattern of matching language have
forgotten okay Swift elixir cutting Ming
NIM LAN Ning pirate pirate from the
scheme this guy they the the fact you
have pirate it which is basically Python
lists
in Python syntax okay that's that's like
like the nature of pirate that's from
the racket people like a scheme these
people the very fact you have pirate
means that means that they gave up our
list then you have pure script P
language Ling cake ml and you have a lot
more you know I start to get tired of
adding to this page because he's like
you have to just keep writing it so so
many languages so back to you yeah so
that's one example of you know the
advance of technology and also shell you
have like a fish you have you have this
fancy showers every few years now but
but you know then again like we have
came to the point where like it's we
find we start to find them to be noise
you know like we don't need another
angry anymore we don't need another grab
we don't really need another bash or
another interactive shell you know like
people get tired you once you learn this
tomorrow there's a new thing that ten
times better you don't need it I don't
need it you see that's a that's one with
the problem of this today's
raishin you know so maybe next year too
you know after two years another graph
will replace a G so Taniya says let me
back go back keep reading the comments C
C sharp has a pretty optimistic future
so Daniel says of course searching using
get grab fast and already know to skip
anything in github oh yeah github me I
mean get many people are starting to use
skit in replacing the traditional UNIX
tools I haven't tried good grab but you
know I've tried git diff you know like
using git if instead of the teeth such a
good rapport like ninja Emacs users have
VC kid web oh yeah
so Thomas war says I you see here I
haven't seen your comment before
so Thomas wall says what's your view on
c-sharp programming language Oh
c-sharp I don't know any I don't know
any c-sharp at all
I don't know C I don't know C first
purse I don't know c-sharp I typically
don't know low-level languages the only
exception you might say is I know Java
I know Java and I know :
that's the lowest level languages I know
so since our community is quite strong
so base say some base says I'm also
interested in knowing what you think of
C shop yeah I don't know C shop so you
guys are doing dotnet day okay Thomas
Ward says I've always preferred the Ruby
and this syntax yes I think Ruby syntax
is very elegant and this is you know
very regular what you know excuse me
okay more C sharp questions
it's magnify
so and something is a cool guy so why is
this post blocked YouTube
okay my eyes are starting to go cross I
need to cover it up one eye so I can see
better
lot's of crazy stuff coming from
Microsoft lately Darnell already is and
they cut down call of refactoring
anymore
new application should be building
Darnell Cole not sure honeycomb pretty
much I think we see Microsoft two more
cross-platform stuff too
okay that's it for today I think thank
you for coming any questions
ten more seconds ten more seconds to
type your question and there'll be it
for today
thank you guys for watching bye