Everyone welcome to another episode of
talk show. We are going to do advent of
code 2025
day two problem two. Can you see me?
Yes. So let me introduce you my
keyboards. This is UHK
80 ultimate hacking keyboard 80.
Fantastic. I have reviews and unboxing
on YouTube so check it out.
Uh so let's begin coding. Okay. So let's
see. Uh if you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed minimum or at
two times speed twice as fast. Uh if you
are watching this now, say hi. Love to
see your comments. Okay. So, wuam
language we did uh advant of code day
one day one problem two day one problem
two take two then day two and today's
day two problem two
we are just going to go easy relax and
have fun okay so it's important you play
at 1.5 speed when you are watching this
offline because otherwise it's too slow
it's going to take 90 minutes
okay so let's see So woofam language for
programmers that's introduction about
wufam language if you search it on
kasali.info
http nos you can see a complete tutorial
on wufam language from the ground up for
programmers. So if you have some
experience in programming Python,
JavaScript or even C, C++, Rust,
whatever, you'll find this very useful.
Uh, Wuam language, Wuam Research, the
guy, the the the company who created
Wuam Language, they have lots of
tutorials. They have like over a million
pages of all kind of things. But my
tutorial is kind of different from them
because I focus on pro programmers.
They also have a introduction to
language for programmers but I believe
mine is better. Mine is more classic
anyway. So it covers uh you know the
basic print show function function help
uh find function by name comment print
string string functions substring and so
on numbers how do you input numbers
binary numbers and arithmetic operations
or hexadimal
number comparison
force numeric result boolean and list
and so on.
Okay. So, Wuam language is very
advanced. It's in fact I would say it's
a magnitude higher level than Python or
Hascal or Lisp. So one line of wam
language would be equivalent to 10 or a
thousand lines of Python literally
because Wuang language also does lots of
mathematics like solve equations, matrix
equations, linear algebra equations,
differential equations, partial
differential equations or um or polomial
equations or other advanced mathematical
functions or integrals or derivatives or
calculus of variations and so on
optimization problems you know so so it
also does all kind of mathematics so for
those
kind of programming one line of wam
language would be equivalent to like
10,000 lines of Python in fact most most
of the time Python cannot do it even if
you load all the you know fancy
libraries like numpy or whatever
so a magnitude clude
higher level than all existing
programming languages literally I would
say include Maple which is another
algebra uh computer algebra system or
mat lab mat lab is mostly numerical or
there's also other software statistica
and so on but anyway so check out my
woofam language tutorial okay and you
can download it for free uh just go here
download for free for developers
beginning about five years ago. So you
need to learn JavaScript.
Okay, that's introduction to firm
language and let's talk. Let's start
coding. Helloamio
ching. Thank you very much.
Ofio says would you say wuam language is
smarter than chatbot?
Uh yes and no. Smarter. Well, that
depends on what you mean smarter. But
the short answer is chatbot is versatile
today's AI chatbot
because it's a kind of new technology
based on neural networks
uh one of the method for artificial
intelligence new neural networks. So
beginning about three years ago with the
chat GPT it made a revolutionary
advancement basically a chapter in human
history. So today we have AI and I I use
it every day. Uh for example, you can
you know like today I have a problem of
upgrading Windows 10. Right now I'm on
window Windows 10 and ex expired and
there's lots of issues like you need the
TPN module to be able to upgrade to
Windows 11. You need to find out whether
my machine has that module. How do you
turn it on? What's the effect of that
module? So I just I just ask AI. So for
example um you guys know this already.
So you know Windows 10 end support what
does it mean exactly? So AI will just
answer
and you can you can ask it all sort of
question. So that's AI chatbots guac
chat GPT Google you know there's lots of
them. So they are versat versatile. So
you can also ask your live questions.
uh like you can also ask travel
questions airport how do you get there
what what for example I ask what's the
difference between gate and terminal in
airport uh all sort of questions or
personal questions you you can ask
dating questions you can ask law
questions related to law uh you can you
know so it's versatile
and you can also ask ask a programming
questions or mathematical questions
But wuang language is
is basically all
uh all algorithms all computer science
in one. So any possible computer science
if it's possible to compact it into a
function any algorithm algorithm
database what whatever technology
graphics it is if it's possible
practical to compact into one single
function it it is in wam language okay
but ultimately it is not a like AI
chatbot it's not like you just ask any
question you you can for example
Example, you can ask it any scientific
question.
Um, let's start wam language and it'll
answer
but
I use it. So, wu language is just good
for you know consider it it as a most
powerful calculator. Okay. So, let's say
three shift enter.
So, that will start the kernel. you
know, you just type something to to
start the uh evaluation or 3 + 1 or
whatever. Let's magnify and you can ask
any question. So, type a equal sign.
That's a syntax for ask any question.
So, how many how many types of atoms
are there? This is a silly question
because atom is there only one but you
can ask it. Then it functions like the
wuam alpha which is a computational
engine to search the solution. So it
says
uh how many types of atoms are there
result atom word narrow term list. Okay
carbon atom free radical hydrogen atom
isotope monad nuclear isotope. Oh that's
interesting. Nuclide radical cycl micron
fly spec grain grinding what what
identification pass particle so I I
don't know physics well so I don't know
how to judge that answer but apparently
it tells you what type of atoms so but
in chemistry if you are into chemistry
or you can ask what type of biological
cell or whatever then you for example in
astronomy How many uh black hole how
let's say how many black hole how many
non black
or
then it will show you okay so what is
this block mean
black horse
uh
okay so it's giving you a matrix
wait so what does this output Mean
what?
Let's try again. How many non black
ores?
Okay, so what? Let's see. Expand
plus.
So I think uh wait what
plus
assuming okay so that expand the answer
assuming black holes is referring to
black hole data uses a formula instead.
So yeah. So it's so here is the result.
Wait, how do I expand?
Uh okay. I forgot what's the key. So So
it gives you a list of black holes.
Yeah. So there is then properties
distance from earth mass
shrush child radius effective density
event event horizon area event horizon
interior volume event horizon surface
gravity entropy lifetime degree of
freedom so I don't know about um
astrophys physics I don't know about
these topics but anyway so this is an
example of wuam language which is
when you type in this syntax it
functions beyond programming language.
It connects to basically the wam alpha
engine. Wufam alpha is basically just
wufam language. Okay. So it uses human
interpretation of human languages and
came out some kind of database. Okay. So
the nature is very different from chat
GPT or any chatbot. chatbot is much
easier to friendly to use. But if you
are a scientist, okay, if you ask these
questions, if you are a scientist, then
wam language tends to be much more
accurate because it because it's
technical information, molecules or
whatever or um or you can ask how many
countries has area larger than whatever
or how many countries list list the
names of countries that has population
of certain size or population of certain
density. Let's just try some something.
Okay, these countries that has
population
density
of
of let's say
let's say 10 uh let's say
what's a good number density of one it
usually is specified in terms in square
kilometer
So one square kilometer let's say 1
million in
uh square
kilometer
list these countries that has population
density of 1 million in square kilometer
let's say let's say that
okay so it's actually going to b it.
Interesting. So wait,
Tov says, "Suam Alpha was very useful
for me to cheat in math in high school."
Fantastic. That's a good use.
Stefan BP says, "Hi, how is going? Hope
you all having a nice day." Thank you,
Creeper. You are the creep um clipboard
something guy.
Okay, this is not good.
What does this mean? Empty.
Now, let's try this in uh
let's try this in guac. Okay, so let's
go to guac and ask exactly the same
question. Your question may not make
sense, but the AI try will try to make
it make sense.
1 million in a square kilometer but
basically that's zero I think no country
have a population density of 1 million
people per square kilometer
okay so you see so that is why the wuan
language one language plot and empty
okay I think let's go back to shall we
go back to the advent of code.
Uh yeah. So would you say wuam language
is smarter than chat chatbot? Yeah. They
they they are kind of different nature
but chatbot is much more general. Okay.
Wuam language is good for any technical
computation. Okay.
Okay. Let's go. Let's start with um
advent of code. Okay. So today's
question at the end of code day two. Now
if you don't know the problem go to the
previous talk show okay advant of code
episode 724. So we did the day two
problem one. So here's a video summary
generated by AI and uh my solution. We
are we were using a regular expression
to find any number
that
that basically has repetition of digits
into two parts like one something digits
some some digit
then followed by exactly the same digit.
So we want to find all such numbers. So
we use the regular expression solution
and the solution is basically one single
line here which you can make make it
into one single line because you don't
need redundant variables. Each variable
is only used once. Okay, that's the last
solution.
Now continue to part two. Okay, so let's
go to this uh advent of code. Continue
to part two. Okay. So again, ad advent
of code their formatting is hardcoded
very, you know, I don't like the advent
of code
style and uh stuff in general. They they
they hardcode their website. So you you
then okay so let's see. So the problem
okay you actually you need to enlarge
this.
Okay, day two gift shop. You get this uh
day two gift shop. Okay, we covered that
the the problem two part two. The clerk,
you quickly discover the clerk quickly
discovers that there are still invalid
IDs in the range in your list. Maybe the
young elf was doing other silly patterns
as well. Now an ID is invalid if it is
made only of some sequence of digits
repeated at least twice. So 1 2 3 4 1 2
3 4 is 1 2 3 4 two times 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2
3 is 1 2 3 times and other examples.
Okay. So now it can repeat several
times.
So and 11111 is one seven times are also
invalid. Okay. So so whenever sequence
digit repeat it's considered invalid.
Okay. From the same example as before
now they try to detail exactly the
problem. So 11 and 12 are invalid
because okay 11 is one one repeated.
Okay. 99 is invalid
because 99 and 111 is invalid because
that's one repeated three times. Okay.
999 is invalid. That's n repeated three
times. One zero one zero is one zero
repeated twice invalid. Okay. And this
this number 18885 1185 is invalid.
That's true. Now 22 22 two2 is also
invalid. That's because two repeated one
two three four five six six times. Okay.
So okay. Okay. So uh 385
9 3859. Okay. Nothing special. 565
656. Okay. 824 824 824. Okay. So now
basically before the problem was check
all numbers that repeats twice.
Now
now the problem is check any number
repeat twice or more than more than more
than once. Okay. So as long as it
repeats. Okay. Adding up all the invalid
IDs in in this example produces this
number. Okay. So what do you get if you
add up all of the invalid ID? Okay. So
basically this part two is just
extending the part one problem by saying
that it can repeat more than one time.
Okay. So let's see previous solution.
Let's copy our previous solution and
work from there. Okay. So
copy it. Any questions, comments? Say
it, guys. Okay. One more uh answer. Um
so show in browser so today's talk show
so let's add a new section here
okay so this uh wait so add a wolf from
language paste it okay and remove the to
remove the date okay and pop it out so
this is our problem now
now this is our personal input now let's
try the easy input first So go to
previous. So what what's where is the
easy input?
Uh yeah. So the easy input is the
example input.
Copy.
Yeah. So comment this out. So we try the
easy input first. The easy input the
solution should be this number 4174
something.
Okay. Now,
okay. Now, like before we split the
string, the input string by comma,
then we split it by a hyphen. Then turn
it turn each string to a number. So for
example,
so for example you got um
for example 95 to 115 those are strings.
Now we split it by hyphen
turn it into expression
then apply the range function. So that
generates a whole range of function from
95 to 115. Okay. So apply this function
map it to the
to to our comma splitted input. Okay. So
now we got a list of list range of
functions. So we can actually run it and
uh
okay so
actually it's easier if I run it in
language. Okay. So, so to that we'll
show you
paste
the output. Okay. So, you can see we got
a nested list and each element of the
list is a list range of numbers. You see
that's a second element, third element.
Okay. Then we basically map
this function
we map this function to this new
input.
Okay, so the new input list
is this, right? So that's a new input
list there. And we map
this function
to that list. Okay, so what does this
function do? The heart of the function
is this part regular expression. You see
the heart of the function is this part.
String match
turn the number to a string.
Then use a pattern regular expression
uh digit sequence.
Okay. So h so can we still use regular
expression?
Yes, we can. But um okay, now we run
into this issue.
So far so good. So
Stefan says
uh so Aquina says Aquina says did you
complete Emacs Python markdown to HTML?
You having to install the pip install
library? Yes, I did. We did that like a
week or two ago. We finished that
in live stream.
Yeah. In fact, I can show you it works.
But anyway, let's focus on this problem.
So, okay. So,
now you check [sighs] you want to check
the number if it's repeated one more
than one time.
You know one of the easiest way
is to
Okay. So I need to think about this.
Okay.
Um
so let's let's make it larger so people
can see.
Okay.
In fact, let's remove this big chunk.
Okay. Let's worry about that later. So,
now it's just this. So, before we do
anything, let's just let's just use a
simple example. Okay. So, forget about
all that. Let's put it back
uh and let's create a new one. Let's
just do a single like example of regular
expression
and also this input let's cut it close
it and let's put the input here okay so
that's a custom input for each person
and this part let's syntax color
everything show in browser
okay we got that so but now let's work
on this single example now let's choose
a number. Let's see. The number is uh
one two one two one two that's one two
repeated three times.
Okay. So okay it needs to be a string.
So let's put that there. Okay. Now we
want to make this return true. How how
do you do that?
Okay, I think I think this uh can easily
be done.
Okay, so let me just do it. Okay, I
think maybe it's so trivial so that such
that I can do it so easily. So let's
repeat it twice.
Uh, wait a minute. Wait. So, hold on a
second. Okay.
So, that's a previous. Now, this is new.
Let's modify it.
So, this this is a number captured.
Okay. A sequence of digits. Then this
slash slash one means the previous
pattern repeated
you know appear here again.
Uh
you know there there's many ways to
solve these one one of the ways hack
because you check how many total number
of digits are there 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10. So the total possible digit might be
10 no more.
So you just repeat this you know like uh
I don't know if you guys see what I'm
saying. Do you guys see what I'm saying?
Say it. Okay. For example, you all you
want is just this regular expression and
you say or uh what
you say or
O is um
regular expression or now in wolf from
language that's just that okay you just
um do this
do this
okay so let me show you
something like that. So, so one of the
issue is you want to know how many total
number of digits are possible in the
input. So, select that. Wait, select
that.
Um,
so that's nine characters.
So,
we know that the personal personal input
is maximum of nine characters, nine
digits.
I assume that's a maximum you know
because we are making assumptions from
our experience advant of code does not
make very good specifications
so you let me explain this part okay
advant of code does is kind of lousy I
mean it's fun so that's perfect for the
purpose but in some technical sense it's
very loud policy because for example in
this in this problem it does not say
what is the maximum number you might
have in the input that's important
that's critical because that affects how
you going to code this problem okay now
given given my own personal input we can
tell the maximum number of um
digit is just nine. Okay, but you don't
know. But maybe some other people they
get 10 digits or they get let's say 20
digits. You don't know. It doesn't say.
It doesn't say the maximum number of
digit is just n. It doesn't say. Okay.
[snorts] So when it doesn't say
and if you are a diligent great coder
then you cannot assume it's just a
maximum of nine numbers you cannot
assume that okay but how however it's
likely
it assume that so if you do not assume
that that that the maximum number is
just nine digits
then your code has to be more complex in
sometimes far more complex because you
take into the account you know you you
you you consider everything correctly
but often times like half of the time or
something the problem like you are doing
over assumption you know the problem is
just like they don't they don't care so
when you actually take care you know
think deep create a efficient algorithm
for possibly covering all possible
outcomes
by the specification of the problem you
are overdoing it. So you you might spend
five hours, 10 hours, but meanwhile some
sloppy idiots, they don't they don't
think too much. They you know they just
see it and code it right away. They come
come out a solution and they submit
that's correct. So for them it seems
they are doing far better. You know they
finish in 10 minutes but you you finish
in five hours and your code is like 100
lines their code is 20 lines. So it
seems you are you are so bad but in fact
actually those easy solutions those th
you know those are bad because they they
didn't pay attention to exact
specification the problem nowhere does
it say the maximum number of ID is just
nine nowhere you see this is critical
because if the maximum ID is just nine
characters then we can do this okay we
can do this like cheat regular
expression this is going to be slow but
it work okay like or
in fact we can do something like that
okay so let let me just quickly do it so
turn this into uh one remove the space
okay
okay remove that so this is a sequence
of all regular expressions so this means
something digit repeated one times or
something digit repeated twice okay we
got repeated here. So, okay. So, let's
remove that. You know, one times, two
times, three times, four times. We just
manually like hack do it. But this
solution has a problem. You don't know
how many um like this this repetition.
This cannot be like like if there's 20
digits, then you have to repeat this up
to 20,
right? Because you need to cover the
case of one one 20 times.
But if the digit could be 30, could be a
million.
If it's a million, then you run into the
big num problem [clears throat] because
then that's another whole step of
coding. You you need to use a big
integer uh the integer the size of
integer is beyond 32 bits binary, you
know, beyond most programming languages.
So in C that's a you can't even do it.
You need to use specialized library
bigum infinite precision you know
infinite digit
and if you are in that realm then you
need to consider efficiency because your
program will finish in after one year
even though it's correct so you need
some kind of like specification how
large is this number this so-called ID
this idiots but it doesn't say you see
that so I'm very annoyed by this
advent of code. The creator, I don't
like his style. I think it's kind of
idiotic.
It punishes those who think deeper, who
come out with correct code.
It promotes
sloppy sloppy coding, you know, just
just trial and error, you know, like how
fast can you come up with the answer
that's correct.
So the the the the effort you spend into
about algorithms about efficiencies you
look at all aspects according to the
spec okay we are not like going into
fantasy we are following the spec it did
not say the number must be just nine
character it didn't say
so normally that means the number could
be 20 characters or 30 characters or 100
characters because it didn't say this
there's no such limitation right but if
you do that then then you so I I
I kind of despise
this is this is my um kind of my on
ongoing for the past 20 years that I
despise this industrial brainless coders
which I consider the creator of the
advent of a code is one of them okay so
anyway if we use the would it so would
this hack work. Let's, you know, let's
we can try it. Okay, let's put it there.
Let's just This is This is just insta
insta hack, you know, one immediately I
thought of.
Let's see if it return true or not. If
it's true, then this works.
Okay, invalid syntax. That's because I
need to escape the um
vertical line maybe. Let's see.
regular expression.
So, do you guys see what do you guys see
my point? Am I talking in vin?
So, how many people watching six? Okay,
say something guys. Do you do you guys
see what I'm saying? On the other hand,
you could say, well, it's just fun code.
What are you fuzzing about? No, you
know, there's quality in in
specification in puzzles.
Uh okay. So let's see the regular
expression. Do I need backslash
backslash for the
uh syntax? Let's see.
No string matching that or that. Okay.
No. But then do I need
maybe you need more parentheses. Okay.
He added syntax before.
What?
Oh, wait a minute. The Oh, wait. This is
actually incorrect. Let's fix it. Okay,
this is incorrect.
Okay, so let's fix it. Actually this is
incorrect. You need to
because there's no reference to so there
is so you can say
yeah so one way is just that
that two times.
This is so funny. So copy. Okay. Wait,
wait.
Okay.
Okay. For
um let's just try that. Okay. Let's
before before we we go into this ordeal.
Oh god.
See this just would this work?
So
one one repeated one time. So we don't
need this [clears throat] part. So one
one one.
Okay, let's just try that.
So this is one two one to one two three
times. So this we got one one one
we got three times. So, let's run this
code.
Oh, invalid syntax. What the
Okay. So, you need to put the because
there's a grouping problem. You need to
put this in front of each one. Okay.
There.
Yeah. Let's try that.
Uh,
invalid syntax in or before string match
Q.
What the is invalid syntax? So,
let's let's get this right again. Do I
make sense, guys? Do I make sense?
Question. Stefan says, "Do you recommend
getting the UHK version two
given that?" Okay, so this the keyboard
I'm using is called UHK80,
not version two. Version two is UHK60
version two. Okay, so do I recommend
this?
Yeah, it's almost like it's uh quite
expensive.
I you know I I think it's high highest
quality okay it's the highest quality
keyboard but for this kind of uh setup
you can get much cheaper you know so
I don't want to talk about keyboard
today but let me just go over for few
minutes okay so when you go when you
think about buying a expensive keyboard
search for kasali keyboard blog kasali
keyboard guide on saudi.info
http no s you'll find 1,000 articles on
keyboard and mouse and everything. Okay,
so if you want to shop shop for a
keyboard that's more than let's say 200
or $300, you have these kind of choices.
I highly recommend you know uh you know
I I talked about this over watch my old
videos. Okay. So, you got these choices.
Then you got more more kind of more
common. For example, this is over 100
150 something. Okay. Then you got more
common like this one $100 something
China cheapo.
And then okay. So then you also got
Kinesis Freestyle kind of like UHK.
Okay. Kind of like. So, what I'm saying
is that if you want to spend over $200,
then usually this type of curved
uh keyboard, this these are over 300.
This is 250. Okay? So, those are kind of
in that class.
But if you just want flat flat and
split, there's a lot. Uh for example
there's there's this
and there is uh okay some of them are
also quite expensive. This one is not
mechanical. So is it I don't think it's
uh wait it is.
So anyway so if you just if you just
want flat and split into two then
there's a lot of them. uh and and
usually many of them are like $200 you
can get it. Okay.
So,
so why do you want to buy UHK? Why do
you want to buy this one? Well, that's
because UHK they provide
there's uh quite a few things going for
it. For example, this is uh Ultimate
Hacking UHK60 because of the 60C keys
version two. Okay. So, the uh UHK80,
they got several things going for it
because for example, you look at you you
got this extra thumb keys. Okay.
And uh the this highly program that's
the most uh programmable of them all
with auto hacking keyboard software. I
showed before. Watch my video. Okay. So,
if you want this kind of flat and split,
however, you also want these thumb keys.
You want the highest quality, highest
quality in build, highest quality in
every design. And you also like, you
know, this kind of extended mouse, you
know, you have to pay extra, then this
is for you. It's also Bluetooth and also
wireless dongle with USB.
You see,
but if you all all you care is just, you
know, I just want to split flat
normalish, then there's a lot like $100
150 or something. Okay, so that's what
I'm saying. So but if you really want to
spend like you know 300 400 then usually
it is this kind of curved keyboard that
you cannot get cheaper. Okay. So
so ultimately should you which one
should you pick? So I I would say it's
up to you. It's up to you like you
consider portability consider price you
know price depends on people because a
lot of people programmers they are rich
they are fairly rich you know they can
buy you can they can buy any many of
these they pretend they are poor but
actually they make a lot of money in a
month they can buy like lots of these
and all and then but if you are really
really poor then then you then you don't
want to think about these just, you
know, ju just just get uh the flat, you
know, also depends on how much you type,
how much you type, how portable you want
it to be, how abnormal you want it to
be, or you know, this um this is Kinesis
Wave that came out last year or this
year. So anyway, it's up to you. All I
can tell you is that both of them, the
ultimate hacking keyboard 80,
okay, the ultimate hacking keyboard 80
I'm using right now and the glove 80. In
fact, I was just using it yesterday. I
still use it, you know, but I want to do
live live stream with the UHK for a few
months because I've been doing live
stream with the glove 80 for like three
years in the past three years every
almost every day. So I want to change a
feel for myself as well, you know,
change you so I can feel the their
difference. So all I can tell you is
that both of them I'm very happy with.
um very happy with I can switch one to
or the other without
like hesitation which one is better. Um
yeah you know so this a lot details it
depends you know like I can go on and on
for an hour about the the specific
details why do you know but then it
doesn't apply to you because uh even if
you you know you you will find you know
it's my situation is not your situation
you know we use keyboard for different
purposes different habit okay so but I
can just tell you both of them are
superb
So the rest is up to you which one you
want to uh go with. Okay. Okay. That's
that's about keyboard. So let's get back
to uh quickly um about this regular
expression.
God we going to a lot digression. Okay.
So why would this syntax error? So let's
see
why.
So if we just shorten it, would it work?
Invalid syntax in or before string match
Q. So what the
Okay. So, this is taking our time. Let's
see. Let's do this in wam wam notebook
if we get
Oh, you got the extra
square bracket. Bucket. We got
extra square bracket. Okay. Rain it
again.
Force
one, two, one, two, one, two. So, oh,
you missing the two uh two case. Okay.
So, let's modify it. It's just two.
Okay.
Uh wait.
Okay. Delete. Delete.
Run it.
force.
Why is this force? One, two, one, two,
one, two. So this captures one, two,
and then one, two, and one, two. So why
why would this false? I don't know. So
what if we remove this uh
run it?
True.
Okay. So
what happens is that there is some kind
of grouping issue. Now we need to create
a group such that it does not capture.
regular expression is very annoying.
In fact, we can use this, you know,
there there's another thing
we can use instead of hard coding it.
But uh but let's do this first. Okay.
So,
so if we
group it,
group it and it should be true.
False.
But if you do not
if you just have this part,
it returns false.
Now if you remove that
true okay so you add extra group it
become false
uh you want the grouping that's not
capture okay so usually it's colon
question mark
but wam language documentation is not.
It's like it's not complete.
So, Stefan, did I answer your question?
Because I spent 10 minutes answer your
question. Did I answer your question
about Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80?
Oh, so almost up. Okay,
thank you guys.
Thank you. Thank you. Um
OV, so we are back to this um
this this we were testing this. Okay, so
those are the outputs. So you can these
are the things we just did.
So if you add a parenthesis then it's
false otherwise it returns true. Okay.
So,
so we want what what we want is we want
a grouping
such as this parenthesis but without
capture because
because if you for example if this if
you run this one
uh yeah so because you got extra uh
bracket
Okay, run that one.
That's force because this is one to one
to one two. This only capture repetition
one time. Okay.
Um
but
if you run this, it returns true. Okay.
However,
however, if you
add a parn to the hole,
then it return false again. You see,
it's not good because we need to have a
bunch of all. And if you do this all,
let's let's run it.
It's also false.
Even though this second part
should match one to one to one two. So
you see because here uh because because
here it matches so matches. So there's
some tricky issue going on. Some tricky
issue we need to so right now I want to
create a group so that we can have bunch
of all but without capture because
otherwise you affect that. Um and also
do you have named capture
and set options. Okay. God
digits or P1 P2.
What about
you know so we need to figure this out
but but we can jump ahead and forget
about this technical detail and we jump
ahead by
by trying by trying this uh
this
one or one one or let's say 20.
Let's see if it return true or false.
True. Okay, this kind of so this will
solve the problem. So let's say one to
one to one two and let's add another one
two and run it.
True. Okay. Now if um so now but let's
see if it only repeat twice. So one two
one two
do it.
True. Okay. So far so good. Now let's
try something that does not work. We
already return true. 1 2 1 2 3. Okay.
Run it.
False. So we got our solution already.
The solution is just this line of code.
Basically we solved the problem I think.
But now but in our exploration we dis we
we were trying this manual code and we
discovered so one of the problem is how
do you specify
a grouping without actual capture. Now
the wuam language documentation doesn't
cover it like normally in other
languages such as Python you say now do
you guys know what I'm saying
okay guys you know answer okay so for
example in Python
show in browser Python tutorial my
Python tutorial you go to the there's a
section on regular expression
rejects okay So regular expression
Python regular expression tutorial find
and replace tip regular expression
functions regular expression objects and
methods regular expression match object
regular expression syntax. Okay. So you
go to the syntax section in Python, you
have a grouping. Okay. So that would be
here's a repetition.
Uh so let's see. Uh
so wild cards
which is a class of characters. Okay.
No also known as character class. Then
you got um yeah character class. Then
you got repetition quantifiers.
Okay.
And you can spec specify exactly how
many repetition or from two. And you got
back back slashes escape. Okay. Then you
got boundary anchors. Okay. Then you got
alternatives which is what we are using.
And here is capture. Okay. Pin. Now
however sometimes you want grouping
without cap uh capture. Okay. So that is
the um this is named capture. Okay, you
can capture a pattern and give it a
name. So let's so you can see
if you don't give a name normally is
first capture one, second capture two,
third capture three, you know they are
named 1 2 3 4 5 but you can give a name.
Then you can what we want is this uh
this is match whatever text was matched
by the earlier group named. Okay, this
is reference to previous named capture.
Uh
wait so where is it named here? Here.
Okaying
version of regular parenthesis. Okay.
Yeah. So, this is just grouping for the
like operation precedence.
Do you do you guys know what I'm saying?
Like, am I just talking to myself? Do
you guys know what I'm saying?
Okay. So, we we need this. Uh can we try
this in wra language?
We we could. So, let's see. Um
let's try that. Okay.
So
if so you uh wait first of all first of
all is this true?
Yes. Okay. But now
you add a par to the whole thing
and
using this question mark colon. This is
Python regular expression. I think it
also works in wam language. Wufam
language didn't document it. So do it
true. So indeed that's a syntax question
colon is for grouping without actual
actual capture. Okay. So go back to wam
language regular expression
documentation. Did they document it this
part? No. So this Wufam language
documentation is not good. It's
incomplete. The other day we also found
it doesn't uh you see this P braces M to
N that's also incomplete because you can
have just a single number there. So Wuam
documentation on regular expression is
incomplete.
uh and wra
language regular expression is based on
that pearl something something library
regular expression I believe if you read
the details.
Okay. So it supports most of these you
know Python
kind of the common regular expression
syntax but it didn't document it.
Why? I kind of know why because they
they want you to use the wolf native
uh string pattern called string
expression. Okay, there let me let me
show you guys. Okay, string expression.
So let's see there. Open it. What?
Open it. Okay, open a new tab. So wait,
not this one. Two regular expression.
No, this string expression. Okay,
can't you just open a new tab there? So,
string expression
is like regular expression but in Wuam
language syntax.
So, it follows a syntax that's basically
much easier to read
uh and uh consistent with the wuam
language symbolic patterns. Okay. So I
suppose that is the reason Wuam
language's regular expression
documentation is not that much complete
and just a few examples
but but the string expression
uh
do they have they they also don't have
much examples anyway so I think there's
a it should be improved because regular
expression is like a whole chapter you
can have you You know there are books uh
entire book written about it. So there's
lots of complex details examples
especially
if you are not uh have not done regular
expression it takes a long time to learn
the full detail.
Okay. Anyway so let's so we kind of so
this part works. Okay. Let's just solve
the problem now. So this this uh this
works. Okay. We just assume that's
maximum character is 20. Okay, let's
just assume that's true. So, copy that.
Okay, let's clean this up then
uh what is this? So, that that
okay break then let's remove that. Okay,
so this is a uh experiment on the
matching regular expression. Okay, put
it back and and the syntax correct show
in browser.
Okay, then let's work on the final
solution.
Okay, our regular expression is
this thing.
Copy.
So we just need to change this part.
Okay. So in fact we just need to change
this regular expression part
to something like
that.
Okay. Now let's make sure. Okay. Comment
that out. Maybe that's it.
Okay. So remove this because that's
custom input. So let's let's run this
and see what happens. Okay,
run it.
So result is 417437
417 437 9265. Correct.
Perfect.
Now let's just Now let's uh use the
custom input copy. Okay, now let's just
get our answer correct. Custom input.
Okay, let's comment that that part out.
And now
it
Okay, it takes a while.
There it is. our answer.
So, copy it. There it is. Put it back.
Syntax. Showing browser. Go down. Go
down. Go down. Go down. Go down. This is
our answer.
Copy it.
Answer. Paste. 761
69125915.
Submit.
That's the right answer. You are one
gold star closer to decorating the North
Pole.
Fantastic.
Thank you guys for watching. That's it
for today. If you like my stuff, go to
kasali.info,
okay? And pay me,
okay? Sponsor. This video is sponsored
by you. That's the That's what it
matters, okay? So, pay me $10, $20. Go
all the way to the bottom on.info.
http no s. Okay. And go down and go down
all the way. You can patreon me $10 a
month or gift card me $99 or PayPal me
99 bucks. Okay, do that. If you have a
job, pay me.
Thank you. Okay, that's it. We shut down
in one minute. Is there any more
questions?
Let's see how how many people are
watching this.
So, we finished at the end of code 2025
day two part two
and everything is smooth. We got nine
people. Okay, we shut down in 30
seconds.
Let's check
code our notes. Okay, that's custom
input. That's the experimentation on the
heart of the solution using regular
expression to match multiple
repetitions.
We began by manual coding the repetition
just trial and just you know that's just
first thing come to mind. Then we then
we know
we can use this repetition syntax for
arbitrary number of repetitions and we
assume it's just 20
again you cannot assume that because the
problem didn't say the total number of
digits is less than 20. So you can put
there in fact this you know I don't know
regular expression how how large that
number supports actually there's a limit
I think I'm not sure
anyway the final solution is this one
okay and we can make this into one line
okay can we yeah show shall we do it
anyone okay nobody is uh commenting bad
uh
you know the whole thing let's put it
back syntax new
uh wuam language mode the whole thing
can be put into one single line because
this input for for example this um
that is just that okay so remove that
and this new list is just make it one
line. Remove that semicolon. Cut it and
uh put it there. Remove that new. So
this one single line of code. Okay. And
uh remove that and make it one line
single line of code. So if you run this,
run it uh uh you need to save it. xx.w.
Okay, hold on a second. Cut. Close. Uh
close. Let's put it back here.
W language. Paste it. Copy it out. Run
it.
You see that's the power of wam
language.
Single line of code. And this can be
simplified. Okay, let me show you
quickly. So, this can be much simplified
because uh you guys don't know what I'm
doing. But I kind of know what I'm
doing. So let's just see. Let me let me
show let me just get to the result and
show you. Okay. So this function this uh
big ass function uh
Uh,
okay.
Wait. Okay.
Okay. We are closer.
Um
and this apply range apply
this is massive science of syntactical
science. So that becomes this single
line and uh and this map also uh
select function. So,
so here you can
become that number list is just that.
Okay. So that becomes that.
So this line becomes this. Okay. And
there's more. Uh
so actually there's quite a few more.
Okay. So
Okay. So what
then you need? Okay. Get rid of that.
that and uh that
that that that that
okay I believe they are the same. So
this line becomes this. Let's run it.
Hopefully there's no syntax error.
Please correct.
See,
so same result.
Let's comment it out.
Equivalent.
What? Equivalent.
What? I don't have that a brief.
All right.
Should be equivalent.
syntax.
Okay, let's say shortcut syntax.
Okay, that's how these are.
Bye.