yes I'm going to show you some Emacs
commands for manipulating images for
example converting images to from jpg
JPEG to PNG or vice versa and shrink
images and and other stuff so let me
show you let me show you so this is this
is my blog you see all these images ok
so I'm gonna just show you several
commands ok for example this one mask
mask of the Red Death
okay that's a pretty image now you see
this is the link by the way on the other
window you can see all the commands I'm
calling it shows on this window so
anyway so this is the image this is
image pass I open it and you see an
image but this image is starting name is
CT and I don't want that because that's
my old format that I have a new format
so I open it I want to delete it so I
press a key and the command is called
Satyricon file you know and so that's
good so I know if I open it it's it's
you know it doesn't exist anymore so
okay so I remove that now open that file
and look at in the browser you see this
is a huge this is the original image and
let's go here so it's it's this one and
now I want to shrink it so I have a
command look I call that command it's
called uh create thumbnail image so you
asked me what width so to 250 pixels is
good so I press enter you see it
automatically insert the new files path
for me so I can open it and you see this
is a new one so notice the name is it's
just the file name with the size
attached at the end so I can copy that
close this buffer and we are back to
where we were
and paste it and kokum and excites Jenna
you mention ink of ice so there it is
had a break and look you see so this is
a new file you can see if we open the
file go to the directory this is the
file and the file before was this one
you know I just changed the format so so
so the same images have the same
starting name you know basically
basically so you can see the ZT and
there are few other I want to do this
one is y out it so it's let's do it then
okay open delete the original files
without this TN that's right so call the
command a new path make a link delete or
old path save go back here reload you
see it's it's basically the same maybe a
bit smaller so so that's that's what I
want to say so that's one of the command
now let's look at another one ZT n so
that command I just show you is a it
lets you create a thumbnail of any sizes
you specify and and it has an
interesting interface such that you do a
directory in HTML him like in your HTML
file that links to that file without
having to open an image and to encode a
command on the image so so that command
is called it's this one so I'll create
thumbnail image remember remember the
interface is from HTML file itself
because I'm gonna show you something
interesting about that in a bit
so ok so here's another one okay I don't
want that anymore right so open
I ate it and the original file is this
one so now I want to let's see um okay
so so let's say this one right this one
is over here and I want to let's say I
want to convert it to PNG typically you
want to convert PNG from JPEG
I mean JPEG PNG to JPEG but yeah I don't
have an example well let's just do this
one this is convert jpg to PNG yeah so
let's change it to now this is not a
good example actually so let's not do
that one let's just do this here first
okay anyway so okay this is a good image
to try to convert okay this Alice in
Wonderland so let's go to Alice
so here is the image okay it's ZT and
again I need to change that okay but um
let's go to here how does in Wonderland
know okay um let's go here okay let's go
to the top that here is the image PNG
rabbit white white rabbit so I want to
this is PNG I want to convert to jpg so
I just call command this command he's
already done it so fast it's not hate it
done where is that right
yeah it's already done so you see
there's a jpg file of the same image and
this is the old one so the command is
actually excellent let's do it again
so I just delete that okay so this is
the image I can do it inquire in the
image or entire buffer so let's do it in
in the image so I call the command the
command is called
usually I use a key so I don't so the
command is called let's see this one so
satire to jpg and the key is just f10
comity that's that's my war a key so
anyway so let's call that command let's
do that so open the file call MX satire
to JPEG then now it's asking me to
revert but for a student there's some
issue there I don't know why it's asking
me because he actually created a
different file refreshed tired buffer
you can see they create a different file
here now if I have a jpg file I want to
convert it to
PNG I came as well so the so what are
the commands you have that I have let's
see these are the commands so create
them now image auto crap that's that's a
good one
show metadata Dyer to drawing that's
basically to PNG but reduce a color to 2
or 16 or 256 that we are drastically
reduce the file size scale image open
opening and Dyer to jpg and removed
metadata so let's try the metadata one
there it is
here's okay the command the key is this
so tired show me the data so you can see
the meta data like like especially when
you have a photograph sometimes it
contains the GPS location and you don't
want that so you know that's come so you
can you know convenient you can look at
what made up data the file have and you
can call command to remove it you ask
you sure to remove yes you know removed
metadata so so that's the file that's
the file commands what is this okay I
mean so that that are the commands you
can see or the oh these are command
image related commands so I'm gonna show
you actually I have it in my tutorial
somewhere here okay human pack so okay
so in this website in this URL you can
see I have it all documented here in the
code so you can you can you know copy
you know copy it grab it and use it
okay so image so all most of these
images they either work on the image
file itself like on I'm like I you know
in this buffer well you have an image
open and you can call one of those
commands to scare it or let's try it an
example it's okay let's try so this one
others so you can work in a buffer or
you can work in tired so let's try this
one so I want to scale you see this this
I want to scare let's say 50% so I call
command you see that's the command so he
asked me scale percentage I say 50 yes
and you ask me if I want to shop it yes
and there there it is a new file you see
it's it's smaller okay
so the command is called solder it's
scale image so that's scanning an image
what else I wanted okay so there are two
you you know these commands can work in
tired you can actually also select a
bunch of files let's say this one that
one and whoops and that one and you can
then then when you call the command here
work on all these files let's try it do
it oh okay you just come out to jbjb
yeah that's that's what's supposed to
happen okay so now we don't want that
it's mark for delete and evideos
okay so what else let's see oh yeah so
they working in the diet in tired to
edit you know diet interface or you can
call the command on the file itself
however they are different from the
earlier command I showed you create them
now image that one works from HTML file
itself so so let's go through the code
so this is the this is a file that
contains all the code for these commands
and you see so now I have two different
interfaces one is working in diet or the
image file
the other one is working in HTML let's
see the nail so yeah so this command is
working within HTML you know what can we
think in HTML is very convenient I
actually find myself you know going to
diet is one more step you know usually I
don't want to go to diet so you know I
can for example this this I can just you
know create a thumbnail or something oh
if I want to scale it or convert to jpg
for example this this one is PNG so
let's convert it to jpg so if I want to
do that I have to open it first then
call the command then then you can see
there's a JPEG version but you know it's
like I find myself that it's an extra
step you know having to need to go too
tired so so the late the the latest
command I wrote is this is this create
thumbnail which which uses you know
directly from the HTML HTML file so you
know I can do that and there it is you
know new image
I don't have to you know go to diet is
this this is communion because you know
for example if we do this one convert to
JPEG open it come up to JPEG then I have
to go to diet then I have to grab the
file path close it close it close it
wait close it and put and pasting the
file path and you know make a link so
these several extra steps ok so I have
been thinking let's go to the emag this
file for these commands so i've been
thinking to convert all these all these
image commands into to be able to use
both interface so for example when you
are in HTML file then it will
automatically grab the link you know
grab the link as the file path input to
work on image to work on but if you if
your buffer is an image file then you're
just you know use the image file as a
input as the input and if if your buffer
is a tired buffer then you just use
whatever marked file if there's no mark
file just use the current one you know
the one under coozer
so that you know so that's the task to
do let's go back to the yeah so you see
all these commands that's the thing I
need to write so so to do that you're
taking our I think you know no you know
wow is probably it and I was going to
show you I want to show you know but
maybe next day but because this video is
already 15 minutes or something like
that so so yeah so okay that's that's it
for today
thanks for watching and remember you can
you know
use these commands if you have some
thoughts or comments yeah coming you
know coming on YouTube and you know let
me know and let me know what do you
think or what do you like to see in the
future and I make you know I might do it
you know the emag this coding session
for you know for this task yeah let me
know if you want to see that thank you
for watching happy new year happy 19
2009 2019 Wow okay yeah it's 2019 so one
more year is 2020
it's amazing the technology advancements
in yeah you know you wonder what the
future is gonna be so anyway thank you
for watching and have a good day bye