good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of excel talk
show today is 2021
june 2nd and today we are going to do uh
wufang language
mathematica tutorial wolfram language
okay i'm going to do
i'm going to give you a basic tutorial
of wufang language
from the ground up and uh
so you you can see here on my screen you
i have my python tutorial python 3 in
one hour
that covers the most basic things for
example how you do string
um how you do string how you do
substring string methods arithmetics
plus minus
divide multiply quotient and how you do
assignment assignment operators and true
and force what is what does
true what is pulling you know boolean
values
and condition if they else loop and so
on so this
tutorial and list then we we get on to
data structures
list in python you have list turbo
then you have sequence types then you
have dictionary which is a hash table
key value pairs then how do you loop how
do you do loop through hash tables or
list
then you have writing a module loading a
library
then how do you define a function then
how do you define a class and object
in python and how do you write a module
so that
is the basic structure basically every
programming language has this kind of
thing
basic structure of learning language
what you need to know
so that's python three in one hour so if
you
like my stuff check it out okay just
search for xali
python tutorial uh then
i also have a javascript in-depth
tutorial and
for example let's go to javascript
basics
it's basically the same thing how do you
run javascript
what's a common syntax how do you print
stuff
then you have strings how do you do
strings then string
substring join string string length
string methods
arithmetics uh assignment number and so
on and then start
uh variables data types list um
and same thing so and
so today i'm going to do the same thing
i'm going to actually write one
for mathematica for wolfram language
okay i'm gonna
i'm gonna uh start to write one so let's
let's start so let's based on
let's base it on javascript okay i mean
uh based on java my python tutorial so
let's begin
uh if you have questions comments posted
okay
uh uh related to programming or
mathematica okay let's make it
focus on that today hey good morning
emily fantastic great to see you emily
the most technical uh
uh people in our group uh
and good morning lucas zambia and good
morning cd hi guys
so let's begin mathematica so let's see
let me show you okay so mathematica
let's start mathematica three plus two
okay
three plus two uh what is the
you have to press shift enter but i have
a shortcut key
yeah let's forget about that okay so
let's magnify the screen so you can
actually see better okay
so mathematica so we're gonna start to
cover that today
so how do you do strings uh strings is
basically same thing this
is a string so string is uh done by
curly quotes i mean uh double
straight quotes okay i need to find my
key for mathematica enter okay hold on a
second let me show uh
let me find my shortcut for shift
enter let me explain what's that about
uh oh okay that key okay so
so shift enter so so in mathematics so
for example three plus three plus three
okay
so if you press enter it's just going to
uh add return so
if you want to evaluate this part you
have to press shift enter
so so i do have a shortcut which is this
key yeah so
okay so so we covered stream so let's uh
let's start to write out
uh documentation okay so first of all
let you know let's uh so you are looking
also looking at my emacs workflow so
let's uh cover
strings okay some of the major topics
so we're gonna cover string so what else
we're gonna cover let's see
we're going to cover strings
string joins
string length string functions in
general how do you manipulate strings in
mathematica
okay then arithmetics okay
okay we're going to cover that then we
have convert to inflow you don't have
that issues uh with my
assignment okay so assignments
okay then you have we're gonna cover
assignments and true and false
true and false in in wolfen language and
conditional if then else okay if
then okay then loop iteration okay then
loop okay then we're gonna cover
least okay this mathematica wufang
language
is a you you could say it's a family of
the lisp language
so so that means everything the entire
language
is based on list this is the most
fundamental
uh data structure you don't have things
like turbo
they added hash value uh
in the past few years but we can ignore
that for now but anyway
let me continue so then we're gonna
cover so we let's
skip that so i'm gonna cover the most
fundamental
so after watching this video you'll be
able to program mathematica
so loop through list dictionary so okay
so then
uh loop through this how do you iterate
you know going through the list and how
do you take uh
and these operations okay these
operations
parts slice
uh conditional
extract okay
extract element okay when you have a
list you have several operations you for
example you want the first element you
want the
you know the the the sub list from a
list you want
uh you want a nested list you
you know you want uh so list so let's
also cover nested list
so again wufang language is like list so
list is the in in the whole entire
language is a list okay
the entire language is at least actually
i can show you okay so
and this is the most fundamental data
structure you know essentially the only
data structure in
ufam language they have others but
basically this is the only data
structure so everything is at least
so when it comes to these you know
operations on these
there's tons of them you know ten tens
of them uh
operations on this because the wolfram
language just like this they focus on
idea where you only have one
single data structure then all your
functions can
all work on that data structure so you
have combinatorial power you know
flexibility
so because every function works on a
list so
then you can you know you can you can
combine compose those functions
so you have the most powerful uh
uh functions to operate on the data
so this this is the one of the primary
fundamental
uh idea or the advantage of functional
programming
so this this in contrast to object
oriented programming in object oriented
programming
every data is one type you know because
that's what classes
are you know when you have a data type a
number then you have a bunch of
functions that just
only work for numbers when you have a
string then you have a bunch of
functions that only works for string
they don't mesh okay but each one
becomes
object by itself with uh you know with a
set you know bundle the box of functions
that works on that data type
so this is the object-oriented
programming philosophy
where you have 1000 datas each data is
bundled with a bunch of functions you
know
1000 data types on the other hand
functional programming is the
kind of the extreme contrast you only
have one data type in general okay
in general then every all your functions
all work on that
that data type then you can compose your
functions to do
to get what you want okay so that's the
basic basic idea the contrast
philosophy of object oriented
programming versus functional
so this list is the most fundamental
data type in wufang language okay
then i'm gonna talk about okay so what
else to talk about
then define a function okay function
okay
uh then define a function and
you don't have class and object in
wolfen language those are following
things you you could
you could write them but you know that's
not the fundamental core idea
uh writing a module that's more advanced
we can skip today so
we're gonna cover these these topics
today okay
uh time is uh tight i need to go fast
hello jason hello justine hello justine
so let's begin okay one more check
am i alive yes alive and kicking
okay strings okay so we we already
already did strings okay
string uh let's let's let's copy okay so
so let's let's let's write the tutorial
on the fly
string is quoted by
double straight quote
okay so so
from okay
okay so okay so we have an example
that's a string
um okay string join string string length
string functions okay
join string join string is done by
let's let's uh
let's paste a lot of these uh
things so we have uh
you know save our time um
you know uh templates
so how do you join string okay join
string join string uh
join string is a you know in when you
program in python pearl ruby php
you know all these languages scripting
languages string
is one of the most fundamental uh data
type
because you work with strings all the
time text processing
pearl python php and javascript almost
all the language
even golan even see you know string is
one of the most fundamental type because
you
do text processing you manipulate
strings or by byte sequences
that's not the case in mathematica in
wolfram language because wu form
language is not
a language designed originally created
to do do strings you know
that you know wolfen language is
originally designed to do mathematics
computations
symbolic computation so but however the
string
function functions uh it's it's it's
more powerful
i would claim it's more powerful than
than any of the pearl
python ruby okay the string functions
it's more powerful but it's not it's not
so often you're
uh used okay so so join string this is a
function okay let me just
uh join string okay
okay uh now string join is a function
now there is a shortcut key to enter the
to enter the whole template
uh i wanted to do that so
so here's the documentation join string
join you can you can
you know search for that ufm
documentation it's exactly the same
thing
you'll see on their website so string
drawing
now there is a shortcut i i don't i
don't remember the
anyway let's not waste time so that's uh
abc
okay so string showing you can do it
this way abcd okay
so enter so that's a string join okay
copy that
okay we got join stream and uh
there are many syntax shortcuts i talked
about in my one of my last video about
ufam language
a systematic syntax shortcut so you
should go watch that
so for example the drawing string you
can also read write in this way
okay a b then that cd
okay so you see you got abcd it's the
same thing
and and so that's a syntactic shortcut
okay
and this there's also you can and also
in general
you can also do it this way uh
tiered then the function name then
tiered
then cd okay so this is the most general
so you
so look at this syntax okay this is the
most general
infix syntax for any function now
wolfram language has about 6000
functions out of the box or building so
it's unlike other languages where you
have to load libraries
by default you only have you know 10
libraries or
20 functions 50 functions building then
you have to load libraries for
reading files for reading directories
for uh you know
no libraries typically in all these
industrial languages
ufam language is very different out of
the box like right now
i have 6000 functions let's see let's
show you okay uh
what is that so
let me show you uh
what not sure what is that i want to
enter the asterisk
okay so that so
so out of the box you can see uh
incomplete expression okay hold on a
second
uh okay it's returning uh basically
right now it's returning 6000 functions
okay you see
no no no you no need to load libraries
okay we need to delete that this is too
much
uh so so how did uh how do you get um
uh let's skip that okay anyway six
thousand functions okay so
okay string join string so how do you
get substring okay
sub string
string part okay string part is a
function to get a substring
so so for example string part
abcd uh abcd
e okay then let's say the third
character
okay that's how you get substring
copy that
paste it okay showing browser okay
string substring
string join string length okay now
length length is just length
okay now another thing you'll notice in
math in wufang language
every function is have the form function
name and
square bracket then argument entire
the whole language every every literally
every function
is of the form so you you don't have to
use the plus sign if you don't want to
for example
if you want to do 3 plus 2 you can say
plus
3 2. okay again in my in my previous
video i covered this in detail
a systematic synthetic layer
so every the 6000 functions all have
this
form function name square bracket
arguments
and then you have shortcuts such as you
know such as things like that
or since things like plus minus sign or
the
curly quote for least and so on so
anyway so length
let's cover length abcd okay
uh oh okay you have to say string length
yes string length not not length okay
abc okay so string length is how you get
the length of a string
let's put it here string length
okay i think that's enough about string
let's move on okay
uh then stream functions okay what about
string functions
uh so here is how you do it what about
all the string functions you type that
then here's all the string functions
okay
so you have
so actually i want to get a list i don't
want this uh user interface
kind of thing i want at least so
you know so anyway this is one of the
way to
it's it's kind of like a help system but
but there is actually a form i believe
it's help
um
i don't remember what okay let me
let me uh let me
let me go hold on a second let me um
anyway so so you yeah so we are talking
about stream functions
so you are seeing you know you are
seeing the 20 or so
the 30 also string building string
functions for example so
let's go let's go through some of them
uh string
byte count string cases cases we extract
certain strings okay if you want uh
string content
contains q that means if you want to
know if a string contains some substring
now over from language that that our
predicate
has the convention the function name
ends in queue
capital q q means question okay so
string queue
means whether the argument is a string
type
so string part returns the you know part
of the substring
we covered that for example string
contains q you click click that you
you see the documentation uh then you
can click this i
symbol to go to the full you know
detailed documentation
so string contains q to test if a string
contains
some substring then you have string
extract
string and skew string drop you want to
delete part of the string
uh string format string free
string insert string join string length
string match queue
and you string split you know for
example a string split
that chain turns a string into a
list yeah so
so that's that's about stream functions
okay
so stream methods okay let me let me let
me show the
okay to get a list
okay hold on a second to get a list of
all string
functions type
question mark string uh wait
question marks string asterisk okay
showing browser so there we have it
okay so that's string functions so we
are done with string so let's move on so
let's
uh string join okay so string join
string links
let's just say string functions okay so
here is the
stream functions section we covered that
okay so showing browser perfect now
arithmetics
now arithmetic is super easy okay so
one plus you know three plus two
addition three minus two
that's uh okay 3 minus 3 is 1 3
plus 3 multiplied by 2 3
3 divided by 2 okay now
it returns a fraction now this is
interesting now remember mathematica is
symbolic that means every result
whatever you compute by default the
result is symbolic
so it doesn't return you know if you do
3 divided by 2
it doesn't say oh you cannot divide
integers with a float or it doesn't
return the just a quotient like one
remainder one it the symbolic
result of three divided by two is the
fraction three over two
now if you want a numerical result you
use the function n okay
so n 3 over 2 is 1.5 or
or if you already have you know
if already if you one of your number one
of your input is approximate
number such as two point something then
the result is automatically also
approximate okay
so but just remember by default
everything is symbolic
so arithmetic okay i don't i don't i
don't i don't want to
you know i don't need to type that so
you know you get that
so what about other arithmetic functions
um uh for example
modular arithmetics you know the get the
remainder
or the exponential okay three
is exponential is you know uh
with the correct okay so what else
and the sine cosine you know sine cosine
is very
simple so sine 1 so sine pi
is 0 so pi is symbolic so the value of
pi
is symbolic here so you can see
so if i type pi it returns pi because pi
is a symbolic
representation of pi so if you want
numerical result you say
uh n pi okay so that gives you number
numerical result or you can say 2 100
decimal places
okay all right and you can say you know
one million one
10 million decimal places right away it
gives you the result
okay so this is a huge number
okay so we need to delete that so this
is pi 2 10 median places or something
okay too much
let's just say 100 okay so so
again the this n is very
frequently used function whenever you
want numerical result you just slap a n
to the whole thing
and it will and then you can the second
the first argument is any expression any
complex
1000 lines expression the second
argument is a number of decimal places
you want okay so it's a
it's one of the you know this shows this
function this expression illustrates one
of the
kind of philosophy and nature of wufam
language
that is it automat automates everything
so you don't have to worry about how you
get you know
how you get the computation or things
like that you don't have to worry
basically you don't have to worry about
what is int float double lung whether
your data
type you know what exactly it is or
machine
or you know you don't have those kind of
thing it's
it's design the philosophy is that it
does computation
it will you know you figure out how to
do things okay
all you are concerned as a programmer is
how do you get the results
i'm a scientist i'm a researcher in
physics in mathematics in
engineering you want the heat flow of
some space shuttle
you want to know the result okay
differential equation solutions you
just type it mathematica uh give you the
solution okay
that's how most people use language
anyway it was a fantastic graphing
calculator
but right now what i'm teaching you is
the
actual programming ufm language okay so
like i'm going i'm covering the like the
industrial programmers
their idea of what's programming you
know the
manipulate the things so these are the
all the basics okay so
uh so so we cover that so arithmetics
i'm not going to type it now so let's do
assignment okay so let's move on
to assignment so assignment is again
very simple
x equals to four okay so this is
assignment you don't have to worry about
declaration
you know declaring variables or
declaring types there's no
traditional sense of types in wufan
language okay
into in traditional language you have
int float you know
string those are data types or list
array or turbo you know things like that
in google form language the
you you don't really have types uh very
well you don't need okay so it's a you
can
so you say it's a dynamic language you
don't you know
dynamically type language you don't need
to worry about types
and you can reassign
you you can reassign variables okay
but value has a type okay so three is a
type
you know so so so is there a
is there a type function so let me let
me
let me type this okay
in general there is no type okay so let
me just go on
to tell you what uh you know to tell you
the gist of wu from language philosophy
so you you know much better instead of
getting bogged down by technicalities
so ufo language so you don't have types
so but value has types
the type of value is based on
mathematics okay it's not
based on uh implementing a compiler or
isn't you know
in flow long double what's that what the
is that it's based on mathematics
so there's a there's no distinction
between
integers and float you know that that's
that's
that's that's that's compiler idiocy but
there is a distinction between integers
and real numbers okay now that's a
mathematical distinction math
idea integers versus real numbers okay
so for example pi is a real number so
let's so let me show you okay
real uh q is your thing um
i i i okay i'm not
um so what is real so so let's see
rio is a head used for real floating
numbers so okay so that that kind of
indicate
okay that that kind of indicates the my
sense
what i'm trying to say so you have this
function
okay this this is getting more advanced
so rio is the head used for real
floating numbers
okay i'm not going to explain that but
basically what i'm saying is that so
mufam language distinguish the type of
values
and what other type of values those the
type the concept of type is based on
mathematics so there's integers there is
real numbers
and there's complex numbers okay that's
a essential
uh values type then you have booleans
okay but
then you also do have booleans okay
balloon type then you have string type
you then you have least okay
okay that that that's the type in
contrast what you
do not have is you don't have reference
you don't have reference type
you don't have pointer type you don't
have in flow double you know those kind
of thing
you don't have something that's
inconsequential to
a programmer that's that's a byproduct
of compilers
of cpu implementation details you
you don't have those concepts
okay so so let's move on so arithmetics
assignment okay and variables okay so
variables let's talk about variables
so uh assignment and variables okay
okay so we have seen so so these
variables x equals two four four
those are global variables now if you
want local
uh variables you do these okay
uh you know this might seem odd but
the name might seem odd to you but
that's how you do okay so for example x
for example we define x before so if we
if we type x
it's five now you can say module okay
so module x equals to um
let's say x equals to three
okay then then
okay then you can do some computation
okay then then you can say
x uh squared okay so that will return
nine three times three three times three
is nine okay so
for example let's do it nine so this
this is how you do local variables so
here you declare the variable x
as a local variable then anything inside
this part is is just local okay
for example now if you say x it's still
five you know so
this is the local variable this is how
you define local variables so
let me copy that uh
local var okay
do it by let me type that
so module
x y dot dot and uh
yeah okay okay okay so let me
let me um then
let me type the whole thing let me so
you are looking at my
emacs workflow okay
show showing browser so variables
okay so variables local variable do it
by uh
by this form module curry quote
variable names then expression the
expression can be
a compound expression so here's an
actual example so that's uh
and and this this variable the scope of
this variable is
lexical okay so this is a lexical
now for those of you more advanced you
know lexico
scope let me write it okay
now you also have dynamic scope okay if
you want dynamic
scope you you say block block okay so
just just like module but except you use
the word block
block okay so i'm not going to cover
that
basically you always want to use module
lexical variable
okay so let's cover true and force now
hold on a second let me read the
comments and how long have i been
talking
um 33 minutes okay so
actually we're doing not bad okay so
so does the wolfram language you have
named turpos
no it doesn't hey daniel langlois i'm
kidding
uh
you know i i i want to start to rent you
know attention about the design
you know so muffin language everything
is based on okay let's not begin that
so look look how zombie says mathematica
seems to be one of the easiest
programming language
indeed but however it has a reputation
of being difficult because
because it's unusual let's put it this
way okay so if you are a beginner
programmer
you can learn many languages you know a
man python per ruby
c c plus plus c sharp java javascript
or you can learn uufam language okay now
if you are a beginning programmer
you're gonna spend let's say half a year
let's say one month
learning the language which one would be
your easiest
i would say wufam language would be the
easiest
but however that's not the common
perception
to industrial programmers why because
industrial programmers you know
you are used to you know you are all
your surroundings
all the colleagues co-workers at all the
big companies
cc plus plus uh by python java ruby and
bash you know they they are all
of the same class like they are all
talking about
int float you know declaration of types
uh
so they are very different so when
in that context so so so to them wolfram
language
is firing you know so they so
so when if you are a typical c you came
from c
or or java or ruby python you'll find oh
this
is strange how you know you might get
that sense so
anyway it's going to get complex okay we
are covering the basics but then
then then later on you'll see the
symbolic nature of
language then then then you can get
starts to get very complex
you are uh when you start to do pattern
matching
you know um you know symbolic
computation
so but but let's go on with the basics
okay
um yeah let's continue with the basics
so we covered
uh module so let's let's so local
variables
then okay then let's do true and force
so what is true and false
now truth and force in wufan language
there are two only two values literal
expressions for true and force okay one
is this
capital k is true okay uh and the other
one is force
now not not lowercase it must be capital
this is these are building symbols
true true and fours are building symbols
okay
so when you have an expression
you know let me name so this starting to
get interesting about the
symbolic nature of wufan language in in
many other languages okay
in in in in python for example
so you know you have a bod in literal
true true
enforce in this in the case of python is
exactly the same as
wolfram language you know capital
capital letter true and force
but then if you have a if
statement then if you have a value
that's not either the building symbol
true and false what happens
well in many languages they they just
have this
kind of ad hoc way so if you have a
if you have number zero then that's
considered false
if you have a float zero you know float
you know that's also false if you have
empty string empty this empty turbo
that's also considered force in python
okay in perl ruby
is different okay the the
basically all industrial languages are
like that
they have a ad hoc way of to decide what
is true and force
and in imac this it's a bit it's kind of
it's again it's the same in imac this
the only
you know the only thing is is
false is neo and empty list everything
else is true
so anyway in all these languages they
they are their way to decide what is
true and false of
expression is just basically ad hoc
every language is different
now in language it's a bit different
okay so
when you have an expression so let me
let me show you how to do if okay so
let's say if
three greater than two so if it's true
uh let's say you want to return uh yes
okay let's say string yes
if it's false you say no okay so this is
how you do
if statement okay evaluate it so it
prints yes
now what what if what if you have an
expression that's um
you know you have some expression x here
where
x does not evaluate to the literal true
and false value
what do you you know what does rule
language do it returns the expression
unchanged
so that's what it returns so the only
when something is considered true only
if it's a
the literal value true okay
and all the digi or it'll be considered
false if it is only literal value force
if it's not true or false then it
returns the thing unchanged
okay that's kind of the important thing
to know
that's a practical thing so if you want
an if statement to actually
re evaluate to something else you know
to to to get a result
you have to make sure that your
test it actually returns you know one of
the these
true or false okay so anyway
that's how you do if okay let me copy
that
pc here okay so showing browser um
so we have if then so um
okay but but what about other
conditionals okay um
you know i don't use you know you uh you
don't need it you don't use it much but
let me show you
now let me show you how do you in
general find out
uh certain functions so right now
we want to know what are the other
conditional uh
expressions by the way in wufang
language just like
other functional programming languages
everything
is an expression there's no statements
okay
so this if is a state is is a
expression it you know so you it takes
three arguments
the first one is a test then the second
expression is
returned if it evaluates to true
otherwise the
you know the third expression so this
if expression returns a value
so for example let me let me do some
more com
com let's start to do some compound
uh computation okay so for example three
else two then let's say plus
plus two okay so you can you can
actually evaluate that
let's say plus twenty so everything is
expression that means you can combine or
you know any part of
your source code you can just start to
combine them okay so that's one of the
again that's one of the advantage or the
philosophy
the the functional programming
everything
is an expression any part of in your
source code you can grab the unit
you can mix and you know you can place
you know move in to anywhere
everything is an expression so this if
expression is analogous to c languages
you know so-called ternary expression
which is
you know i'm digressing but which is
question mark uh you know uh
true statement you know
so that's the
you know that's a ternary expression in
in c like languages
which is everywhere a a virus
so anyway if and if okay if then so
so now let me digress to so what if you
want to know
so let's see let's type if okay so
right now we want to know all the
functions
that related to uh to booleans okay how
do you conditional
you know branching branching construct
we want to know or
you know what are the others i like i
don't know i don't know right now i
don't remember
basically you basically just use if okay
so for example is there a witch is there
a switch
is there a conditional construct i want
to know so how do you know that
so first of all if you know one of them
you type you know you type that
so it gives you the documentation of the
if function
then you click the help okay so you got
the full documentation of the if
expression then okay then you go down
usually at the bottom you'll see uh
c also okay there it is so it these
are related uh functions that
you know related to to this function if
so you can see there's also
switch statement okay here's the syntax
now go back there's also which
statement okay basically you don't use
those okay
now later on in another day you know
later
in my later videos i'll start to get
more advanced in uh language
programming then you'll start to know
about programming styles
which one is more suitable for woofer
language which one is more powerful
certain things you just never use in
language
uh you know the basically the
anyway so
so so here uh so you know we switch is
useful and and uh
switch yeah yeah basically you don't use
that
uh in general okay when you program with
a language
um you don't use that and okay so
so back to so how do you find the
related functions so that's one way
c also but here is also other important
thing okay
so here is a tutorial now here's the
article all about relational
logical operators so you know it's
related
so you can find out all about related uh
you know
let's magnify okay so you can find out
all about um
let's magnify again
okay so so at the bottom you can see see
also
in tutorials okay then or everything
about conditional so click on that
so there there you have it all the
conditional
operators okay then
and related guides okay so i mean they
have lots of tutorials
in a sense my tutorial is kind of um
uh redundant you know but people
like to watch videos okay okay okay
that's it that's about that that's how
you find
stuff oh
hold on a second let me shrink my window
here
okay so back to uh back to if then okay
so what about loop okay so loop
loop is an interesting topic so first of
all i can show you
so so what are the common loop
constructs so you have
for loop while loop
uh four loop while loop uh
for each loop you know these are very
common
uh loops especially four and while and
the do
okay let's see how i want to cover this
because
um
okay okay so i started to let's see
how long have i been talking 46 minutes
i need to
go faster so any comments
no comments okay i mean i still going
yes
so so okay so uh um
so ufam language supports all that okay
but usually you don't use that okay so
for example let's
let's show you do loop okay let me let's
show you for loop okay
now for loop is a procedural um
programming construct
so here is the syntax for for loop um
you know so let me let me show you okay
four
uh takes four arguments just like c okay
it's a
model after c so you start with i
an expression i equals to one then you
test okay so so i less than
nine then you have increment okay so i
plus plus again that's also supported in
language i plus first
then you have body okay so you can say
print
i okay so that should work there you
have it so that's a
for loop okay copy
uh but anyway you don't you never use it
okay so
if you want to be a good wolfram
language programmer you never use this
because it's not the right style
more specifically because it's not
efficient it's not
efficient it's cumbersome okay because
in wolfen language functional style
you have much more powerful and simpler
and the more suitable more you know
easier to understand faster simpler
and uh constructs to do loops okay so
i'm showing you this you you know you
can start to use it but uh in general
you don't use it okay
now also let me also mention there's
also why a loop okay
again it's just modeled after c okay
you know so you have while roof you also
have two okay so let's see
do okay do
expression n times this is when you know
how many times you want to loop okay you
so you have two
then you have uh more um sometimes you
do use two
but in general okay you don't use do
four and while so what you use
okay so then we start to get into um
so you in general you use okay so let me
start to say okay so
also while loop okay then you also have
do loop okay so let me write it
in general you
use functional for
you use functions
you use functions you you use
functional programming functions
for loop or
iteration okay so for example
let me show you for example okay so for
example
nest okay next next list
map table
range uh let me just cover some of these
okay so let me
cover starting from the most useful and
basic first
okay so we want to cover in this way
okay
table range map nest nest list okay so
let's do it so so so let's do range
first okay range is the simplest
range range is just like python's range
okay three two uh two
to one hundred let's say three to twenty
okay
so you give you you know three four five
you know three to twenty
then you also can add an increment in
instead of two okay
and you can also have a negative so
let's say
uh negative 20 to 20 instead of
5 okay then you can also have reversed
uh you know
for for example from 20 to negative uh
20 then in increment of negative five
so wait does that work yes okay
now note one thing to notice these are
very powerful this
these are far more powerful than pythons
because you try this in python it won't
work
try it in in your favorite language in
ruby php you know it won't work
so mathematically it works then let's
try this something let's let's
try let's say in a fraction
so 22 negative 20 in the step of a
fraction negative 5 over over 2
okay there you go you got the symbolic
result now
we start to show some of the power of
symbolic computation
let's say in the step of pi in instead
of negative pi
symbolically okay remember symbolically
not
approximate number pi okay
do it there it is symbolic result now if
you want numerical
just again just like i mentioned before
apply the
end so for example let me let me show
you this okay
so you see now if your number recall
result you do that
uh or okay so so
so so here's so that's range okay that's
range okay so
i need to add some of the examples to my
tutorial
so example range okay
so there there you have it okay we
forgot to write about true false
okay but anyway uh
loop where is our loop yeah loop through
at least okay oh oh
actually this should be
loop operations with list operations
okay so let's just say loop here okay
if loop wait ah wait
oh okay here so
okay if then then we have the loop
operations now we showed
range now what about table okay table
table is when you need
nested for loops okay so table actually
so let me show you a table it's just
like range okay
uh table is just like range uh in fact
actually let me just
show the uh show the
the help document so you can see over
there uh so table is just like wrench
range okay so so the syntax is like this
uh the first argument is a expression
any expression okay the second argument
is kind of the
it the the what's called um
um standard um how do you call this i
forgot what's
anyway so let me just show you okay so
let's say it's three okay
so that means x goes one two three so
let's say
3 to 10 let's say 3 to 10 okay
so this means x goes from 3 to 10
in increment of 1 of this expression so
you got that so it's just like range
okay so again you can have in step of
two
okay then again but the first part can
be any expression that's
you know that's that's why it's become
uh for example
x x powered okay so for example let's
say
square root okay let's build some
complex expression
sine x divided by
pi raised to x okay
sine x divided by pi over x x go from
what 3 to 10
instead what step of two okay
so you got that and you if you want
symbolic result i mean if you want
numerical result n
okay so n now percent percentage
sign stand stand for the last expression
so you can do
so there is a numerical result
okay so that's the simplest use of table
okay so let's copy that
okay
okay so
okay now let me show you
table takes more than one argument more
than two arguments so let me show you
okay so
so table um
table let's say let's start simple okay
let's just say sign okay sign
let's say one two one two three x goes
from one two three
let's say sine x times y x goes from one
two three
y goes to uh let's say seven to nine
seven eight nine okay
enter so you got a matrix you got this
basically you got the
nested uh matrix
okay let's say and and let's say y goes
from
7 to 90 instead instead steps of 10.
okay oh actually it simplifies okay so
actually we don't want it to
let's say divide okay
okay so again so it can take arbitrary
number of arguments so let's show you an
example of three-dimensional matrix or
four-dimensional matrix so let's say
let's say uh so let's say this okay
let's just say at least x y z so x
from 1 to three
y from one two three
z from uh what
z from one two three
so you got a three-dimensional uh
matrix and it can be four-dimensional or
ten-dimensional you know
so it's a it it's a field so
in python you might call this um
um
how they call it in python i forgot the
moment so javascript basically closed
that python
numpy array no no no no that's not what
i'm thinking so
the i'm thinking the the python the
wait i i i remember i must remember the
word
i must remember it i don't remember
why i'm doing video
so um
oh yeah this comprehension how can i
possibly forget
so in python you have to construct this
comprehension okay
so it that is a construct that
lets you do um arbitrary nested list
okay
that's idiotic actually you know i have
an article just search for
this comprehension sucks search for
exactly this comprehension
that's an idiotic concept in so but
anyway
the the the purpose of this
comprehension
is exactly the same as languages
table table function okay
now let me let me just let me explain
let me let me tell you why why why okay
so
why this is much better so you see you
have one
consistent syntax you know table is a
function
consistent with all every other function
in language
consistent and no no arbitrary you know
like in this comprehension all of a
sudden you have a
you have a new syntax within the python
language
you know like within the list
comprehension then you have a new syntax
for
you know for you know for something in
something
you know that four is different from the
for loop four
so you are basically essentially you are
building a little language
you know with special syntax when you do
the this comprehension that's what this
comprehension is
okay a special specialized syntax within
a language
but look at the mathematica form
it does exactly the same this
comprehension you know you know to build
a nested list
okay exactly same power in fact it's
more powerful
but the syntax is not special
everything you know about wolfram
language the syntax
applies here so you don't have to like
you don't have to oh when you use this
you have to know
you have to learn a new syntax and
exceptions and all that
everything is regular so and
anything can be
a complex expression for example this
list let's
square it okay so you can square this
here
uh then you can actually you can build
arbitrary complex power so
let's say raised to the power of
uh 2 plus pi
times e e is the natural logarithm you
know the number okay
so so you you can can you see that
simpler simpler to read and you know uh
much more powerful so that's that's
something that's that's about language
design
that's so that's the reason this
comprehension is idiotic
they have that in haskell too also
idiotic
uh most people they don't know that
industrial programmers i argued with
them for 20 years
they don't understand what i'm talking
about
so anyway so so here's that's a that's
table so that's an illustration of the
table function for building
these arbitrary lists very one of the
most useful function
in wolfram language okay so that covers
loops
loops okay so that covers loose
then you also have map okay so map uh so
let's
talk about map um so we
actually we covered at least okay so
this is simple we already covered it
because uh list in in
language this is a list okay so 345
that's a list
so let's copy that list
um and so what about
getting part of the list okay so so
let's say um
so let's say x equals to uh at least
okay
so if you want the first part this is
how what you do okay so this is a
shortcut syntax
let's see that you want the first
element so that's what you do
and the full form syntax is is this okay
part
so you can see the documentation it
shows you the full syntax and
it also shows you the shortcut so the
part the first
part is the expression then you say the
element okay so you want
part of the x expression you want the
first element that's how you what you do
you want the second element you do that
and if you want
uh
if you want a sequence you know uh let's
say let's say
let's say let's say range okay range
20 that's me that means 1 20. okay
so you want the fifth element to the
ninth element that's what you do okay so
you got five six seven eight nine
okay so that's list so this is
this is a syntax for list and uh
and the part is a function to extract
part of list what about
other operations again like i said
wufang language you have like 20
20 or 30 functions that
operate on list so this is the most
important part
of i guess this tutorial so how do you
find out so what you do is you
like i said before you click on you okay
so you type
question mark part okay
uh enter shift enter then you
you go to the full help then at the
bottom
okay so there are so many examples then
you can see
see also first head last extract
position
replace part map ad tag take
uh pad left and a lot more so
here so you want to go to this tutorial
okay manipulate
element of a list and also the tutorial
picking out pieces of algebraic
expressions getting pieces of this so
they are they have
lots of ex uh tutorials let's see the
first one manipulating element of a list
okay so you get so part is one of the
function
then you have uh vectors and matrix
matrices okay so they talk about table
we talked about they talked about range
we talked about length um
okay let's not use this one let's uh
let's say getting pieces of least okay
this one
yeah so you have take take the first n
element of the list then you have rest
take the you know nth
element rest of the list you have
dropped you have most
most is new since few years ago
this with its last element
dropped okay so you have um
okay so so then then you have testing
and searching these
elements so position give you
um element of list
member queue is is if you want to test
an element is at least
free q is basically the reverse count is
the
count number of times certain things
appears in a list okay
so you have these functions then you
have other you know append
removing modify this element again
all these now it's simple to understand
because wu from language
they don't have special syntax
everything you learned so far is
you know like just today you or you
already know already
you already know the entire uh language
is syntax
you see everything is a like take the
functional form
so i don't even you know i i you know i
don't have to demonstrate this
it's very easy to understand
then you have combining lists join union
uh refill in
referral is new what is what does refer
refer to interleave element of list
then you have lists and sets
intersection complement subsets
okay so anyway so this
page you know i'm going over now this
page is the most
important thing you want to know so you
know we cover as many the basics
but wufang language like i said is about
all about this
so if you i want to master programming
list
in wolfram language this part you want
to be familiar with them all
okay partition go and then order sort
ordering
you know it's all about money
manipulating this
okay uh that's it and last thing let's
talk about functions and that that's
about
that's about it for today
uh greeting spot comprehension this is
the list okay that's the
okay one more thing i'm gonna cover and
that's it for today
um one hour and seven minutes okay one
more thing how do you define functions
okay
so functions you you can you you just
define it this way okay
now function actually there are many
ways to define function
uh because wufang language is a pattern
matching
rewriting system okay uh we haven't
talked about that yet
it's starting to get advanced pattern
matching symbolic pattern matching
okay so in some sense you can think of
least markers
but it's like a magnitude more advanced
uh symbolic pattern matching and and
that
that mechanisms you know this the
pattern imagine symbolic pattern imaging
is the
heart of wufan language it's it's
the it's it is its computational model
in computational in in theoretical
computer science you call that
you call that uh
rewrite system okay so let's let's
quickly
show you uh uh
term rewriting system
okay so you can go to uh you don't don't
use woof
uh don't use wool frames math world okay
that's a circus
thing do not use wolfram
you know fan research website math world
that's a circus
content lowest quality content okay
uh in fact whenever it's when
it doesn't matter what it's whether the
topic is mathematics or computer science
or programming
don't you know i recommend not use
wolfram math word
so you want to go to uh you know
wikipedia is better okay so
wikipedia rewriting okay term rewriting
system
so for example in mathematics computer
computer science and logic rewriting
covers a
wide range of potentially
non-deterministic
methods of replacing subterms of a
formula with other terms okay anyway
it's called rewrite it rewrite systems
and uh
and this is one of the approach of
algorithm
and and it's mostly useful for
you know proving mathematics or computer
algebra systems
and declarative programming languages
okay for example the
for example in haskell in haskell or
camel ml they all have that
part of it pattern matching okay so when
you talk about rewriting systems
the heart of it is pattern matching you
you need to have pattern matching
so so what's the difference let me
explain so first of all what is pattern
matching
so think of regular expression in perl
in python okay you know
you know regular expressions so you have
strings you want to re
rewrite strings so you want to replace
part of the you know words or
a pattern of a sequence of of strings by
another string so you use regular
expressions okay
so regular expression is for strings
now pattern matching the reverse system
so regular expression is kind of you can
think of it
of it as a rewrite system except it only
works on strings
now pattern matching in general they
will it's just not for strings
it's for source code okay so fulfillment
language is
for example this smart course that you
can think of it
also as a rewrite system because when
you have a list marker or any
marker in other language or c c plus
plus template
you essentially what you are doing is
you are re
rewriting part of your source code okay
by this pattern you rewrite it okay
that's what rewriting is about c
plus c c plus plus templates or this
macros
now of course different languages they
have different power and some some of
them sucks
but but in but you don't call
these markers or the c prosperous
template system you don't call them
rewriting system
because they are not a system they are
just ad hoc
one time like one time pad one time pad
in crypto now
in crypto analysis you use it one time
one
one form you know you just you know it's
not systematic
but however if you have a rewriting
system where
your entire programming language is
based on
rewrite based on the rewriting
mechanism to do computation then
you have a rewriting system term term
rewriting system okay
that's what mathematica is okay that's
what wu farm language is
so and it's different from uh haskells
or
or camel or mental language is different
from theirs because
it's the wolfram language rewriting
system is symbolic okay
very important symbolic based rewriting
system it's not based on
uh in haskell it's type type and value
based
you are manipulating symbols in other
words
you are rewriting your source code your
the heart of wufang language the engine
most most you know heart of it most of
it is
about rewrite rewrite rewrite your
source code
you will keep rewriting rewriting how
does
language do computation rewrite you keep
writing until the result no longer
changes that's your result
okay let's show example okay
uh so i'm talking about functions let me
name just function
finish function so how do you define a
function in
from language there are many ways the
most typical way
is to use the rewrite system so for if
you go to wufang language tutorial
you'll see it for example
i want to define function let's say x
plus 1.
so we define a function f x
we want to return x plus one okay that's
how you define function
so now let's call the function x2 f2
it returns three okay that's how you
define a function
now let me tell you another way to
so how you do you you do this by this
way
f equals to let's say not f
let's say g let's use a different symbol
so
g equals two function then
variable x then x
plus one okay now remember this form
looks familiar
it's just like the module we had it
before okay
okay so this is how you d oh
this is the alternative way to define a
function so let's try it
so now you say g two okay
enter three okay now so you have seen
two different ways to define a function
in wu time language okay one is this
way one is this way now the second way
this way is a much simpler
one this function thing is basically
lambda in other languages or is it
it's basically like this slam da you
know
uh so you don't call it lambda you just
call it function so
the first argument is a list of
variables local variables
the second argument is the expression
you know
that's how you define a function in
language now what about this one what do
you do this way this
this is becoming complex this what
happened
here is actually pattern matching okay
so this actually this tells mathematica
you want to define a pattern okay you
want to have a pattern that looks like
that
okay f square bracket then anything
inside
so if you are telling mathematica
whenever
you see a form a symbolic form
where it begins with f then square
bracket then something
replace it by that's something plus one
okay this is pattern matching so
you know this is also how you define a
function one one of the way
but actually more precisely you are
defining
a pattern matching or a rule
replacement rule that's what this uh
colon equal
means so so let me show you the full
form of this
okay let me show you uh the full form of
that syntax i talked about in my
previous
video a month ago you should go watch
that so let me show you the full form of
this syntax so
rule delayed
okay rule delayed two arguments
the first argument is f
square bracket
blank x okay
that's a pattern the second argument is
plus x
one so i'm telling you this
this this you are seeing
is syntactically equivalent to that okay
let me double check okay let me check
let's check if that's true
so you say full form
then paste that expression okay
okay so you have to say hold
you have to say hold otherwise it
otherwise whatever this
expression just get evaluated so you
don't see it so let's do it this way
so there it is so you can see
oh i i got something wrong so anyway
here is the full form okay
pattern uh okay so let me correct it
so so f
uh f should be here should be a pattern
okay then
okay there it is okay so here is a full
form
full form for for that
for this so i'm saying that this
is actually a definition of a rule to
tell mathematica whenever you see the f
something just replace it by x first one
and how it works you can understand how
it works by looking at the full
form which means the full syntax of that
thing
so it's a first of all it's a rule
delayed function you can see
uh wait so we are missing a
we are missing a bracket wait
uh wait so we are
missing a bracket somewhere
oh here yeah
so first of all you have this
you have this rule delayed thing so that
tells
wufam language you know you are creating
a rule a delayed rule
then it takes two arguments
the first argument and the second
argument the first argument says
it's a pattern okay it's a f something
then pattern
pattern is a blank that means anything
then this pattern is given is named x
okay
basically you are telling wufang
language to replace that whenever it
sees that
replaced by that so that's how it works
so i think that's it
for today thank you guys for watching um
yeah i think that's it for today any any
questions any questions
let's see how many people are watching
11 people
okay if you like my stuff you know
donate gonna you know go to my website
any of my website
saudi.info saudi info then
you know you can see
you know it's just uh you know put money
in my pocket support my youtube
channel and stuff you can patreon me
amazon gift card or paypal or you can
buy my tutorials on
emac list emac this emacs or javascript
in depth
so i have a bunch of lots of tutorials
on programming languages
anything else any questions
okay so that's it we're gonna shut down
in two or three minutes i'm shutting
down in two or three minutes now i'm
just going to do
clean up uh
let's see so i'm going to finish this
tutorial offline
you know finish you know type stuff we
talked about
a very basic tutorial um
[Music]
so we talked about list we talked about
nested lists
we yeah we should we have nested list we
have these
operations all important then we talk
about functions
then we started to talk about the
pattern matching and rewrite systems
so so what's the relation between
well the rel the relation is that
when you have a rewriting system
of a programming language you need
pattern matching for it to work
essentially yeah just like regular
expression you know how do you
if you have a regular expression you
know regular expression if you want to
do string replacement
you need find and replace and one of the
mechanism is regular expression
so or you could say it's a pattern
matching you know
regular expression patterns pattern
matching so you need
pattern matching to do string
replacement finding replays such as in
microsoft word
okay you need pattern matching to do
three string replacement
and regular expression is one of the one
one of the standard way
in the same way you need pattern
matching
to do rewriting system now
the context here is different from
string replacement find retracement
replacement because
when you have a rewriting system a
general rewriting system
you are dealing with source code not
just strings but your source code so
it so there are many types you can do
symbolic pattern matching
rewriting system such as language or
haskell or camel they have value and
type
based pattern imaging so that's a
relation you know
pattern matching and and
and rewrite systems
very interesting okay you should read
because rewriting system
you know it then it gets on to formal
logic
then it gets on to the heart of
mathematics the foundation of
mathematics
proof systems you see theory improve
improvers you know and so on
you know it's kind of it's quite
interesting fascinating that
how the simple idea of string
replacement
is actually the foundation of
mathematics
yes
okay bye guys
yeah i i think uh what else i what else
i
okay i covered language i think that
covered all
so you can start to program more from
language now
uh and oh yeah last thing by the way
wufang language is free
so you go you go to my website just
search for saudi wufang language
then there are two videos there are
there are four
five videos i did before uh you should
go watch them
they are all about wufang language uh
then you go to download download wufang
language for free so
you know you can either get it cheaply
or get it for free
but i recommend you just buy it because
you have more
benefits by the way you by the way you
don't get crippled version whatever you
get is
the full version
essentially i mean i don't i mean they
don't they are not like
every five minutes they're gonna pop up
oh you need to pay remember to pay
nothing like that or disable some
features
but i think the the anyway you get the
wolfram script over from engine i think
by default they don't have
they don't allow graphics i think
so you do you cannot have you cannot
have three-dimensional rotation of
three-dimensional geometric
objects but if you also download the
python
you know that python that that that that
copy of
language notebooks then you can get that
to work
yeah but just buy it okay that's it bye
guys