good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh hi guys so
today's topic is going to be some
typescript JavaScript and let's read the
comments and meanwhile let me maybe let
me start the switch the input let's
start saw start command log so on the
Left window you can see all my Emacs
commands
ok so let's read the comments oops
so bathroom you say is number four
side-by-side comparison of plain
JavaScript versus typescript how does
the wrapper make it better so okay so
let's I'm going to explain some basic
tutorial on typescript introduction to
typescript it's not much really
typescript you know you really just
think of it as JavaScript it's basically
exactly the same except you add you know
little types here and there and bottom
you say is same code snippet in plain
JavaScript in typescript side or side by
side yeah let's do that and in fact we
can do a we're gonna code I have some
JavaScript applications we can convert
it to typescript then you'll see it's
not much at all
but of course just like every technology
there's lots of quacks you know like
sometimes you need to know you know four
simple types like number string I know
it's easy you just say : number you know
I'm going to show you okay so for simple
types it's easy but sometimes you want
to get for example you have a array of
two elements you want to specify that
this argument argument must be your
array and it must be only two elements
then it gets a bit a bit more complex
then you have to look up you know
typescript documentation to see if you
can actually do that so there are things
like that so we're gonna go over that so
let's go to Mike Sontag show
let's see comments keep the comments
coming okay and thought hawks show and
so today is this page this page empty
buffer so we cannot put today's stuff
here
so type typescript
versus javascript live coding comparison
basic intro to typescript okay
showing browser there it is
and okay so let's move this window over
here yeah so okay so Rica
Bethel mule says number eight
recommendations for how to write a good
key blog to see how much to see how much
you type most often yeah I have
depending are you talking about eMac
well you can do that in Emacs if you
type you know vast majority of the time
you type in Emacs you can do that in
Emacs that's the there is already a mod
which is show frequency have you seen it
bathroom you because I've shown it
before
good morning Quinn tech good morning
Matthews Matthews good morning
Bernie Sanders and the money is seen to
and the good morning Z Chong crazy okay
so yeah so the okay so there is a Emacs
mod let me show this some people may not
see have seen it called frequency key
freak mod standing for key frequency mod
so for example this is my lock of almost
half a year or a year's worth of key
typing something like that you know one
problem with this is that it doesn't
show that beginning date well you see
when you install key frequency mod you
know it it and you started you know it
logs every commands you call in Emacs
including you know inserting letters
like self insert command when you type
something that's inserting letters so
this is my log you know one one issue is
that it doesn't have a beginning date
well because every time you create Emacs
it saves the login to a file in your
dart Emacs in
directory then when you start Emacs
again it continues so so I guess in that
respect you don't have a date but you
could add a date you know it should be
an improvement to to have a beginning
date of the log file so you know because
knowing the date is important for
example I have typed these many
keystrokes for inserting letters you
know six 666 666 thousand you know six
six six thousand letter keystrokes
but I don't know how long was this log
it could be one month it could be one
year so knowing the date so you have a
period of time then you know exactly how
much you actually type so anyway this is
a Emacs key freak mod okay the name is
key freak mod I think that's the name so
you can look it up and so use that if
you are using Emacs because it's very
useful too because most of the time
programmers the keystrokes you use are
actually shortcuts you know backward
will delete paragraph things like that
move up you know switch buffer that
happens more often than more often than
just typing letters like this for
example you have to edit now if I'm
going to edit this sentence I need to
move the cursor backward word you know
move to somewhere that's you know those
are keystrokes that's not inserting
letters data entry not data entry so I
have statistics okay let me show you I
have statistics on Emacs you go to my
you know such as such folk sorry max
sorry max you go to Emacs keys all these
articles are related to Emacs key
binding or keystrokes or repetitive
strain injury hand health and stuff and
keyboards and in here you're fine
statistics
let's see keybinding how to Emax
keybinding tips and Emacs pinky okay
here this section is related to hand
health and best keyboards and statistics
Emacs command frequency statistics so I
did this like 2007 10 years ago 12 years
ago
it's statistics of several users anyway
so if you are interested that in you
know look it up one important thing I
discovered is that programmers actually
you have more than you know half of the
time depending on you you know depending
on you know each person is different
some people maybe chat more on Twitter
or whatever you know in that case you
you type a lot more there are entry key
strokes but one thing I discovered is
that a lot of people more like depending
on the person but on average more than
half the time as a for programmers the
keystrokes you type are not actually you
know data entry like just typing letters
but but are about shortcuts a switching
buffer you know move move pager page now
you know edit delete DD were things like
that so so that's that's a discovery
that's you know I was surprised you know
when you study keyboard you know I've
been studying this for like 20 years
like every every few years you have a
great surprise you know like so many
things because for example one thing I
learned about keyboard is that one thing
I learned about keyboard is that you
know you study so many there are many so
many aspects of keyboard there's a key
key cap how it is made what material it
is you know and sometimes it becomes
yellow you learned that you know like
old keyboard you know antique you look
at you know sometimes you see pictures
of let's see keyboard history you know
many of these keyboard becomes yellow
over over 20 years because that is
because the
stick that that is used to make the key
cap that's called ABS plastic that I
think you know anyway there are several
type of types of plastics that that are
used to make the key cap you know key
haptic and and they have advantages and
they have disadvantages for example this
one is most common this is called ABS
plastics this is like cheap keyboard
Microsoft keyboard Logitech they are all
ABS plastic over time like after year
you have this really ugly shiny you know
on you know that's really ugly so that
is ABS plastic and it has advantages to
you know besides being is this is the
cheapest to make that's that's why it's
most popular but also it has some
advantages but I don't remember the
details you can read the article for
example this is a bad case of ABS
plastics and this also happens on Mac
this is extremely ugly you know imagine
you can just you just type on it it
becomes like that after a year to a few
years so that's ABS plastic you know it
has it's got problems this shiny thing
is probably particularly ugly you know I
have I have keyboards over here that's
become this shiny very ugly to look at
then you have PBT PBT plastic which is
which which stands for poly poly butl
and polybutylene terephthalate terrified
tell tale of terror of late something
like that okay that's PBT plastic they
tends to be more expensive and harder
and they are using expensive keyboards
for example this one 200 something
dollars this one this is this is a good
one by the way this is a programmable
with on board member
with the feature of on-the-fly
programming meaning that you can prove
for example if you want to swap the caps
lock to control you can just press some
keys and that becomes you know control
without having to start a key driver or
you know programming software so anyway
the the key key caps then there is PVC
key caps so you learn about key cap
technology and you learn about key
labeling technology this this one is a
basically a sticker kind of like a
sticker on top of the key
this is also the cheapest and most
common you see it on logitech on
Microsoft keyboards and it wears out you
know in fact you can just scratch it off
otherwise you know after after half a
year you know they part of the label is
gone I also have that experience then
you have laser engraving laser marking
or laser engraving which also have
problems speaker it doesn't wear out
however it is it's it is difficult to
make the color contrast contrast very
shot you know you you rather prefer them
to be pitch black you know oh you know
and also it's impossible to make them
white so if you have a black keyboard
you cannot have white label if you use
laser engraving then you have this
technology where you do laser engraving
but you use laser to to to burn burn a
goof then you put paint some kind of
paint onto it so that's that's this one
so you got very sharp contrast but
however it's got a problem you see it
becomes dirty you see those pins become
dirty so that's that's the flaw with
this then there is you know there are
several there's dye scible dye sub
elimination this is getting expensive
this is this is expensive so this is
great
and then there is the this is this turbo
shot injection-molding this is
considered the best because you can see
it's like actually part of the plastic
you know and it never wears out never
because it's part of the plastic and and
you know it's so this is the most
expensive so anyway so that's about you
know you learn about this but one thing
I learned for example you have this Enki
rollover thing you know you can try this
okay we digress a lot to the keyboard
but let's get back to the typescript
let's see how long I've been talking 40
minutes okay so so so I learned you know
over the past 10 years I learned about
the Enki rollover you know you can try
this right now like and let me tell you
hot what to do hold down the left shift
key you know go to a text editor where
you can type something now hold down the
left shift key then hold down the right
shift key now press some other key like
a letter key to and and check if it
shows up vast majority of keyboards as
you know like every keyboard made by
Apple Microsoft Logitech they all have
problems like most you hold down left
and right shift key then some of the
letter keys we are not show up we are
simply not show up you know it's like
basically it's like a malfunction so why
is that you know then you know I looked
into ice you know I started you know
because I'm mechanical keyboards one of
the marquee marketing slogan is we got n
key rollovers you know so you started to
look at what are they you know what they
mean basically Enki rollover means how
many keys you can press simultaneously
and register correctly that's what it
means
so for typically for USB keyboard the
USB technology actually limits the Anki
were over so for USB keyboards even
mechanical ones
and the expensive ones over $200
typically they can do at most six keys
six but there are there are techniques
to overcome that so some keyboards they
have you know full and key go over over
USB so they actually have two USB
internal you know they actually have
like two internal USB or something like
that to overcome this problem anyway so
this thing is called Anki go over and
you know so when I learned this I was
shocked you know I was shocked because
because normally you would think you
know it's just electronic you know on
and off you know you you shouldn't have
this problem I mean what you know we
have nuclear web you know we have
nuclear energy you know nuclear
electricity generators you know we have
hottest technology how could how hard is
it to make a keyboard you know just
press simultaneous keys and you can't
for example on piano a digital piano you
will also have this issue but because
piano keyboard musical keyboard they
have a strong requirement to you have to
have at least 10 simultaneous keys
because that's a requirement because
often you play music you need to press
10 keys together or eight you know so
that's called polyphony but anyway so on
digital keyboards even cheap ones today
typically they have like more than 10
polyphony like 20 more than 10 is
important because because you press a
key sometimes you have the sustain pedal
so you press on that so that so that
note will sustain you'll keep playing
even if you are not pressing it so so
that that is why you need more than tend
polyphony so called polyphony so anyway
our digital piano typically they have
like 30 polyphony you know but I'm a
real piano mcann
piano of course it's like oak you know
it's it's like inky well over okay
because it's not electronic every key
you can press you'll keep you know you
get you can press all the keys together
and it all makes sound so you learned
about inky or OVA or an keepo / and you
realize the reason is because you know
the design of the circuit they need to
save you know they need to save the cost
to make you know it's things like that
that you like you need a diet for each
key and more tired is more expensive so
they created this this way of using a
matrix to save a number of diodes things
like something like that that's why you
know most keys most keyboards or have
this problem because in practice nobody
you know nobody actually need to press
more than you know more than four keys
together at the same time so engineering
is a very much a practical in diva you
know you you have to consider
practicality because you need to save
cost because otherwise nobody will buy
your stuff you don't make profit then
you die
you know your company you die out so
that's you know and you learned about
all these things when you learned you
know like every few years I learned a
new thing
you know the first thing you learn is
about equality the court he you know lay
out you know I learned that the first
time around 1981 it's like Oh Mike it's
like oh my god
you are in stems to be so bad you know
it's extremely of English so anyway
let's go back to the topic where I was
why was I talking about that a peon I
was talking about keyboard key frequency
and
you learn about things okay so let's
talk about so there so I forgot where
how did I begin to talk about this let's
see some of the comments just come
outside of Emacs so if you want to count
through early you need two counting or
key press okay yeah in that case you
need to use one of the key logs software
so let me show you the key lock software
so you go to my keyboard blog just
search for Kali keyboard then you go
through the software section then you
you go to the you go to the type in
section then you okay actually go to the
software section okay Keela
so this article it's a list of key lock
software so they are SEP there are
several of them and you can try them I
haven't used them because I typed mostly
just in Emacs like every time I need to
type something I typically if it's long
are typically type in something Emacs
and paste for example I have
abbreviation for example Fe o Fe X is
for example so I don't have to type that
much I can type in Emacs and paste
somewhere else okay then I press a key
copy it I switch to Google Chrome one
key press I press another key paste okay
I need to highlight this I need to focus
that so I paste it there you know that's
that's what I do so back to Emacs yeah
so use those key dogs so you know here's
the list of key dogs let's let's do that
so let's let's let's do let's start to
do typescript I guess okay so yeah then
we need to do that it seemed to Matthews
let me read the comments you are in
Emacs you are an eMac stable right does
that answer your question bathroom you
you you just use a key lock software so
Seema's slack says for keyboard can you
get Braille made into keys to you can so
you can find keys more easily to find
yeah I guess yeah you can bow ever
Graham says hexa is there a good way of
integrating a clock in HTML what do you
mean a clock for example oh crap a clock
application for example I have if you go
to
Casali SVG clock is that what you mean
so on HTML page you wanna clock so
answer okay if that's what you mean
because here this is a clock written in
JavaScript yeah we can we can actually
show this as an example of typescript
and in JavaScript yeah so okay so let's
talk about this thing let's let's start
talking about typescript so okay so
so let's this so here is my so I open
that page this is this is that page I
don't have the JavaScript on that's why
you don't see the clock but this is the
page so
okay let's talk about typescript let me
think about where how we gonna begin
let's let's just start to talk about it
okay so let's just speak in random so
anyway so here is the okay let me show
you - let me show you the this this fire
the fire you are seeing the code this is
actually typescript okay but as you can
see it is actually exactly JavaScript
there is nothing typescript here yeah I
think yeah I didn't add any you see so
this is this is actually just typescript
I mean this is just exactly JavaScript
however you can see the filename let me
show you the file name so you see SVG
crop thought TS TS is the extension name
for typescript so I you know I open it
it's in typescript mod
and and let's go back so there's there
is also the javascript file this is the
fire it actually runs in browser because
browser doesn't recognize typescript so
if i open let's open the javascript file
you can see that they are exactly the
same
let's see the file size yeah you see so
they are exactly the same file so for
example it let me let's do this so close
that go to the issue let's say compare
cmp SVG cropped ES and SVG cropped is no
output no output means they are exactly
the same another utility you can use
this diff you know no output no output
means they are exactly the same note no
difference it says you can see it says
here
yeah so so okay so no output so let's
yeah so actually this is a good example
we can start to make it actually type
script you know we can start to make it
so that it you know to use the
typescript type information to help us
you know make less bugs okay so yeah so
first thing to know is that typescript
is hundred-percent JavaScript compatible
so any JavaScript code is already a
typescript so what we gonna do so okay
so this file actually you know if this
file is so simple that you actually
don't need any type you know you don't
need any type and notation sees 8080
lines and because I'm thinking weird you
know what should I add here you know but
because they so this file is not even
this one function here and this function
doesn't even take any parameters so you
you don't need to add you know you
cannot you know you don't need to
specify types for the parameters this is
almost like nothing to do can you clap
in typescript what do you mean by grab
like glob like the UNIX file name
matching yeah I don't know what you mean
so so anyway so let me show you how to
compare typescript so I have this
JavaScript you know this is the
JavaScript let's delete it okay well
actually let's make a backup I make a
backup I have a command on the Left
window you can see it's already made a
backup so go to the finder go to go to
the tired refresh browser
you can see I have a backup here now I
delete this JavaScript code press a key
to delete yes okay we have just deleted
the wait what happened let's close that
we have just deleted that SVG so you see
the the JavaScript version is deleted
but the typescript version is still here
so now I'm let's go into let's make a
let's compile so I open the typescript
code
so normally you compile it compare it is
by your command line you know you type T
as something something but let me show
you how I do it because I have a Emacs
command so look look at the left window
okay I press the key I press a key
sequence and you can see the mini
buffers is running and he says share
command succeeded with no output and the
command I called is sabra and current
file so this command casado and current
file if the current file is typescript
it will just compile it so let me show
you
okay Kesari on current there is a URL so
this this Emacs command commands allows
you to run perl PHP code Python Ruby :
you know it just running it you know you
press a key or render current file and
if it's if it's if it is typescript or
Java it will just compile it so anyway
so but how but let me explain how do you
compare our typescript not know Molly ok
so let's look look at the code
run current file look at the code so
here is the code copy it cross new
buffer paste okay
switch to Emacs li smart search for
typescript typ e t YP so okay look here
so this section it checks what file
extension so if it is if it the value
extension is TS then you call the
command
TSC TSC is the typescript compiler you
know you could you just go to typescript
website and then you download the
typescript compiler very easy there's no
nothing complex complicated so if we go
to the terminal let's see oh I forgot to
yeah
so let's open a new terminal window okay
so let's say which TS see you see it's
installing you solo use a local TS c so
let's say mentee RC okay no man page so
t SC - - help you know so we got a bunch
of typescript commands you know so
normally when you want to come back let
me show you exactly what's the command I
used to compile the typescript so TRC
okay
so actually when if it if it is
typescript I actually call this command
Chris RTS compiled file so let's look at
that so jump to the source code so here
is the code I actually this is the here
is a Emacs Lisp Emacs command that
compiles the current buffer for
typescript file so I have some options
you can oh I wonder if I should show
this because this is about Emacs but
anyway here here are the options so you
have - - target es2015
that means if you use that option that
means compare the typescript - yes
JavaScript es 2015 version which is very
good okay so if if you are if your
audience you know if your web users is
you are targeting users who are using 10
years old browser then in that case you
want to target you know - - target es 5
that is the JavaScript version before
2015 and the option always strict means
you know in JavaScript you have this
strict keyword it's it's complicated to
explain but you can ignore it you can
just ignore the always strict so let me
show you an example then so Satya's
compiled file so let's let's show let me
show you an example so close these don't
save so ok we are back in the typescript
file this is 100% javascript file so far
so let's go to issue and let's see let's
type wait TRC okay I actually I need
more window I need to see
I need I need to look at the options
okay so we are going to type TS see the
file name and - - target and the target
we want is let's say yes 2015 okay that
should work now let's look hold on a
second let's look at the file now this
this file is right now is hundred
percent JavaScript and it is using ES
2015 features so because you can see
those constant those are yes from es
2015 so now if I press ENTER it will
generate a compare your general create a
new JavaScript file and in fact that
file will be identical to this file
because there is nothing to do but let's
try it again enter
okay it's done now let's go to the tire
directory refresh now you can see it
generated this file and let's look at
that fire open okay so it you know it it
it created indentation for you and it
made the code more compact but as far as
the code code goes they are identical
because there's actually nothing to do
because you know this is already you
know this is yes 2015 and exactly the
same there is no change you can for
example you can you know you can compare
for example these four block verses over
here for they are they are exactly the
same okay so that's typescript so let's
close this file now actually now let's
delete this javascript file let's delete
it delete it yes okay now it's good and
if you delete it okay now it's good now
let's compile again let's go to a shell
let's run the command this TS c command
typescript compile then let's change the
target to es 5 ok es 5 is the JavaScript
version before yes 2015 so that's the es
5 ok now let's do it
now the code will be drastically
different because it it compiles it
basically converts or yes 2015 code to
the es 5 yeah so this this aspect is one
of the very tremendously useful feature
of typescript
you see even we are not using any types
but we can we can use typescript to
convert one JavaScript version to a
older version so let's look at the
generated code so here is the file it's
open it
okay that's a different file it's this
this is foul SVG cottage is okay let's
open it you can see they are very
different you can see you can see those
vas bar here you see those vows those
are es v so let's go back to our
JavaScript so on the top so this is
typescript you know yes 2015 and here
those are es v so it's drastically
different so that's how you compile
typescript you know you it's very easy
you go to the typescript website just
download their binary I think they have
a binary version for Linux and Mac too
and Windows of course then you know it's
just going to be a command-line tool
called TRC then you just do what we did
and and that gets you started so so with
that you can already start to use
typescript even without doing anything
you know in any of your existing
JavaScript you can start to do it
so now next thing let's talk about let's
talk about you know typescript is
usually known for the types you know it
adds types to values so let's see some
of the use of that meanwhile meanwhile
let's I wanted this back to the I don't
want es5 you know I want yeah I want to
be bleeding edge around yes 2015 so
let's do it again just let's do it again
just call my Emacs commands so compare
it
okay it's done let's go to the diet
refresh buffer open the JavaScript
version again and you see it's it's
constant again so it's good
so now close this close this okay so
next thing is we're going to we're going
to look at some types typescript type
annotations how are we gonna do that
any questions type it guys type it type
it and make make the talk better
so I guess 20 minutes another 10 of 15
20 minutes we will be done I mean we
that's enough time to cover the basics
of typescript annotations so let me read
the comments yeah this is exactly what
one can you grab so so good no Bernie
says can you grab in typescript exactly
like UNIX carbine but what do you mean
what what do you mean exactly like UNIX
carbine gobby is like a pattern matching
of strings a very basic pattern matching
of strings and in JavaScript you have
regular expression is that what you mean
so in JavaScript you have the feature of
regular expression which is a far more
powerful string pattern matching it's
part of JavaScript therefore it's also
part of typescript you know it's in the
language so if that's what you mean
where are the types yeah let me show you
that that's what we are going to show
right now you don't see it but you don't
see it because this file is so simple I
don't you know there's nowhere it's
nowhere I can actually add type because
this file is you know just too simple
okay so let's be so so now we are going
to show the type annotations so let me
see what file - one example to use um
let's see draw
sherry and John Thomas good ok so this
is a so we are going to demonstrate how
to how to do the typescript type
annotations but right now I need to find
a good example to begin to do that you
know the the best way is actually to
start to write the application is very
simple you know application you know web
page application where you let's see
that means I mean let me try to find a
example okay so let's go to so let's go
through my CSS blog so just search for
sorry sorry CSS you'll find my page here
and I have some let's say back let's see
box shadow so here is some JavaScript
application you can see random color so
what these two what let's let's let's
not use this one let's use gradient
color
hey good morning Danielle so here is an
application that generate random color
so you can see I click random color
random color rainbow or random rainbow
to color only seven colors let's say
random random three colors and random
direction so let's pick that so let's
first of all pick rainbow then seven
colors then we can change the direction
so you can see here is the CSS code it
generates for you so as we change as we
change the input you see that you see
the output code changes and similarly we
change the random color you see that's
the purpose of this application it
generates a random gradient CSS code now
let's look at this file okay this is
written you know in typescript so let's
open the buffer here is a buffer showing
browser in Firefox I don't have I don't
have JavaScript on that's why you see
blank Oh another thing is that you can
change color so let's say to color okay
two colors only and change the first
color to let's see
Wow okay so you can see it becomes brown
magenta and you can also change it
dynamic dynamically by a color wheel
let's see you see I rotate it it changes
so anyway that's the application so
let's go back to the file and let's look
at the JavaScript code search for
JavaScript here this line is a
JavaScript code the the things above
okay so this this this these three these
four blocks of text that's for the all
these widgets HTML input so the
JavaScript code is this one
Oh JavaScript so this one is not written
in typescript oh it is writing in
typescript actually so okay so anyway so
here's a typescript it's this one
actually doesn't have much it's too
simple you know when you start to use
typescript you'd you actually need more
complicated code because that's when you
actually can use type annotations
because otherwise there's nothing to add
but however in this file you can see let
me show you some of it for example you
see this part that's not JavaScript okay
you see these several HTML input
elements you see it occurs in several
phases those are part of typescript
those are not JavaScript so the those
are actually those are coercion of types
why do I need that because let me
explain because okay let's go to the
directory okay so here is a JavaScript
code you open that so here's the
JavaScript code and at the bottom it's a
typescript code so if you go through
this line set rainbow set color rainbow
you go to this this about line 21 okay
which is here you can see that over on
the bottom we have this HTML input
element here but over here that generate
generated code doesn't have that because
that's not part of JavaScript so why do
you need this well you need I need it
because because the code the X here is a
HTML input element the type of this X
you know I want to get a value of that
in this case it's the color okay so one
of these color boxes once you choose a
color there is a value you want to get a
value in order to get a value in order
to get the value so here's this is a
function you call to get the value so
for each you know you want to get the
value of all of them so for each X and I
X start value equals to something okay
that's how you get the value that's a
Dom but the X the the type of the X is
actually a HTML input element that's
part of the dome dome has kind of these
interfaces so anyway this other type is
HTMI improvement input element so you
need that actually well you don't need
that let me show you okay let's just
delete that okay let's just say X here
okay so that's the normally in
JavaScript that's what you do so now I
compare it
okay I'm comparing it it's a stun
actually it didn't give me give me any
arrows did it no actually so it actually
walked because used because usually it
was giving a warning not arrow because
remember typescript is 100% compatible
with JavaScript therefore unless it's a
JavaScript syntax error otherwise it
gives you warnings like this is missing
type or something like that but still
works in JavaScript as long as it's
valid JavaScript so we just compiled a
code so let's look at the JavaScript
code it's exactly the same thing you
know we just actually it's exactly
something so close it close it back to
the typescript code so let's try it
again let's remove this one so this one
this is another you know value so let's
just remove it cut
put it here remove that okay now let's
try to compile I'm trying to get the
warning out okay there it is you see now
it says CSS gradient dot years file line
23 column 48 arrow TS two three three
nine property value does not exist on
type element okay so line 23 let's go to
line 23 it's this one is exactly yeah
not now the arrow comes up line 23
column 48 so column 48 is right
is I don't have where is it column 48
it's right here okay then it says
property value does not exist on type
element so it's saying that X type squib
is assuming X to be of the thumb type
element but however the actual type of X
is supposed to be HTML input Emin
element it's the you know actually don't
don't worry about this at all because I
don't even understand it exactly tom is
very complex anyway this is just one of
the quark of type script so if you do
not want to see this error what you do
you know you learn from experience you
go to slack stack overflow they tell you
you know they tell you okay so what you
have to do is to is to put this here
let's see it's HTML so actually I have a
shortcut so I just type HTML H I HTML
input element hie okay there it is
that's that's how you do to fix it just
just forget that just put that there
then let's try compare it again compile
okay there's another occurrence 926 so
926 that's this one so let's do that
let's just to HTML input element okay
now let's compare that again good no
error no warning when it gives warning
like that the JavaScript code still
works it's just that it's warning about
something typescript so you don't
actually have to worry about all those
warnings so anyway that's that's that's
a quark you know one of the quark of
typescript
you know this is actually not helpful
because we are showing a quirk of
typescript we
actually haven't showed the use the
usefulness of types in typescript yeah
so this is not a good example because
it's too short you know you so let's
close this okay let's let's close this
let me show you let me show you
something that's more substantial which
I showed yesterday
so here is my JavaScript application
let's see I'm trying to find a good
example to show the to demonstrate the
typescript types maybe this this one
something in the water does not compute
this application computes in real time
of the key key strokes you pressed so
that you can get a sense of key
frequency you can also copy and paste so
so that's what these two so let's look
at the code open the file
search for JavaScript okay here is the
code here is HTML stuff the input box
and all that then then here is the code
okay and this is types good okay so this
is this is actually we are starting to
see types okay finally very you can see
it's dramatically different from what
not dramatically you can see it's very
different from from JavaScript now
because you have all these : number
square bracket so for example this one
this is a function create SVG okay so
what does it do here here is a
documentation so it takes the first
parameters P W is a viewport width then
viewport hate so with so width and hate
the question mark means optional okay
and I think that's inside in typescript
or JavaScript I forgot
so let's check the comments
the sirens of your Porsche are loud in
the background what sirens of the
abortion yeah typescript is yeah
javascript hundred-percent compatible
that's a key that's why it's so
successful anyway let's look at this
okay so this is a type script file this
function creates a SVG element you know
this graph is a SVG element it stands
for scalable vector graphics it's not
bitmap so this function creates G SVG
element it takes several arguments the
first one is a hey with the second one
is the hate meaning that meaning like
how large you know how large you want
your Viji graphics the third element is
a viewport now a viewport is like you
specify user coordinates instead of
pixels so view view then the view box
the third option the third argument is
actually a array and each element of the
array must be your number that's how you
specify it in typescript you see :
number square bracket that means this
argument when when you call the function
create SVG and pass some argument
typescript typescript will try to check
if this argument is actually a array and
all elements in the array are numbers
your check for you if it's not your
campaign you'll say compiler error you
know it won't you it will stop comparing
you know so you you fix that
well actually still compiles sometimes
it you know yeah he still works you can
ignore the error but you know it wants
you because because in JavaScript it
does automatically automatic conversion
most of the time so so you know but
sometimes you act sometimes
these type mismatch actually are real
arrows because if it doesn't match your
application is wrong you know it's a bug
so so you know type script check for you
so here's a example okay so here is a
function by the way this is an arrow
function you this for example this this
sex this part is the arguments and this
part part is the body of the function
and look at this this thing now this is
another type annotation it it tells
typescript that the return value of this
function is of this type SVG SVG element
it's a dump
it's a dumb thing it just it just tells
typescript that this function returns a
value of that type so that is typescript
now let's look at the JavaScript code
for this page so let's look at so the
here this file is a compare compare of
JavaScript code so we can see this
function over here create SVG so now you
can see it's much simpler you see is
just one two three four four arguments
you know just parameter names you see
there's no types and over here it's
typescript over here is JavaScript you
can see that's the difference so that is
actually that's basically all there it
is that just illustrates everything
about typescript it's all just about
that that is all nothing else it's
hundred percent JavaScript you just add
you know these type things okay
type annotations and you know you can do
it slowly one by one because it's your
JavaScript so this is useful when you
have large project you know one thousand
line so this file only got 300 70 40
lines anyway let's let's look at the
typescript again so let's show some
other examples of so here is example
here is another function basically the
same same thing here is how you specify
a string type and here is another
example so this this function translate
string takes two arguments and each
argument is must be your number type and
the return value must be your string
type that's that's it
this is using error function error
function is part of es JavaScript es2015
so that's that's really about it about
typescript so it's extremely simple you
see that's why it's very successful
what posh was a car passing by always
inverse the sirens of your Porsche are
loud in the background I don't hear
anything
because maybe I'm busy talking so I
think that's that's it let's see how
much I've been talking so any any
questions bathroom you so anything so
typescript
yeah very simple it's most popular in
industry I recommend it
and the the force you know the the one
reason it's very popular
and great advantage is that it's hundred
percent JavaScript compatible so any
JavaScript is already your type script
so that means you can gradually start to
add types okay and the most use used
feature of typescript is the type
annotation meaning that the company you
know the compilers tries to find any
type mismatch for you and this is very
useful when your code is large like over
1,000 lines but other than that that's
that's I mean this that's all there it
is that that's that's all there is to
typescript so so you know it's pretty
simple but however it does have lots of
quirks when you start to use it just
like every technology you start to run
into little quirks for example one of
the quad we we talked about is is
this thing you see this this this this
HTML input element thing you know this
part is actually not helping you because
you know because it's a dumb thing you
know typescript is complaining this
should be it is assuming it to be some
HTML element but typescript is small
street
so it actually wants
you know it's actually HTML input input
element I mean as a JavaScript code you
don't even I mean these things don't
come come up you don't even know what's
the difference I mean yeah typical
average JavaScript coders you don't
actually need to know these you know
HTML input input element versus element
versus HTML element there are a lot of
them like in don't that's a technical
details of Dom but as far as JavaScript
concern is concerned it you know it
doesn't matter dark JavaScript does not
worry about these things but typescript
because is trying to match it's trying
to be strict about types so it gives you
all these kind of warnings so if you
don't want to see those warnings then
you look up Stack Overflow you know
every time types typescript gives you
some error you know you look you look up
Stack Overflow then people say oh just
put this in front of it then that so
that's after soft sub problem so this is
one of the core of typescript other
quirks are for example for example this
these arguments this argument is
supposed to be a array of numbers so you
have to find out what's the syntax for
to represent a way of numbers and there
are other issues for example if I want
array of numbers but the array must
always have only two elements like
length 2 how do you specify that I am
not sure offhand I mean that's the
things the kind of thing you have to
look up typescript
sometimes it gets complex because
javascript is the syntax of JavaScript
is already already pretty lousy we
talked about for one hour yesterday
well actually we we haven't talked about
JavaScript syntax but it's the syntax
especially when it comes to let me show
you when it comes to
[Music]
function argument D structure this is a
feature in JavaScript 2015 that allows
you a easy syntax to assign values to
variables in yeah and the can can be
used as in as part of the function
parameters how do you have for example
what what do you mean so here's the
example you define a function here the
the the argument is a object then the
object is supposed to contain two
properties Center and radius two
properties
yeah so I'll check you know you have a
property center and a radius so Center
center is array of two elements and
radius is just a number so in this
function when you have the when you got
the argument object you want to assign
them to variables so Center you know you
want to assign them to Center to be XY
as numbers you know the coordinate for
the center of the radius of the circle
and R is the radius so you write this
then you can you know start to draw the
circle but so this is before es2015 now
with es2015 you have this feature for
called
argument de structure so now you can do
it like this
simplify it much simplified you can say
it's still you know it's still one
argument you can see the function still
takes one argument but you can write it
so that it actually it automatically the
XY becomes variables you know the Center
for the circle and the radius R also
becomes a variable name so you can start
to use you know X Y R so this feature
essentially what is what it is doing is
pattern matching anyway this feature
is called argument destructure oh it's
called
this in general it's called this
structure let me show you where okay
this this it's in general it's called
this structuring assignment you can use
it for variable as well for example you
can do it like this you have array of
three elements you want to assign each
element to to a variable ABC you know
you can do it like this instead of you
know before JavaScript yes you know
without this feature you have to you
have to say array bracket 0 to be the
first element assigned to a then same
thing for P and C you know so anyway
this structuring assignment in function
argument is called this structuring
argument argument is structure so it's
here argument is structure okay so but
however it's this is very convenient but
however the syntax can become extremely
very complicated because the argument is
structure is very powerful the argument
can be array or it can be a object or it
can be a nested array and object mixed
nesting away an object and you can use
this argument is this structure to
extract you know things in it in this
complex structure to two variables so so
when you use this feature you know it
gets the syntax for example let me show
you one of them for example this is
object to variable and let me show you
some more complex examples for example
let's say this one okay so this one you
know here is a function it takes one
argument the argument is a object the
object is supposed to have two keys
a and B and it also have you know and
what if the object is not given if the
object if the argument is not given then
use this as default but what if the
object is missing one of the one of the
property then you can you can do this to
give it a default property so you see
this is very powerful but on the other
hand the syntax becomes a bit complex
okay so why am i why am i talking about
this argument destructuring because
that's JavaScript okay that's JavaScript
es2015 now when you use typescript now
typescript have this type specification
you know type annotation when you use
argument destructuring and when you know
for example one of the example we have
there now you want to add types it
becomes extremely complex you know it
becomes unreadable because you know you
have to scratch your head okay which one
is the default argument you know which
one it means you know what type it
should be
it becomes very complex so that's you
know that's one of the I guess you can
call it a quirk or complexity of types
good so that's that's about it for
typescript though anything else and
that's it for today let's you know talk
to have one more minutes and we're gonna
close now I guess anything else
okay nothing nothing else to say now see
you next time I'll see you guys next
time
and you can buy my tutorials you can buy
my tutorials okay so I have a you know
JavaScript tutorial javascript in depth
you know or put money in my patron
JavaScript in depth yeah lots of goodies
thank you guys bye