hello everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show today we are
going to code wufem language we are
going to continue coding the geometric
inversion you know there's a lot to do
so
so we did several videos before you can
see 2021 starting 2021 October 1st then
there are three videos before Okay so
so we did a so we are going to continue
geometric inversion and this time we are
going to do a cube I mean the geometric
inversion of three-dimensional grid
points and we are going to use a sphere
so this this video uh we are going to
use a sphere to represent the point
those points so we do inversion so this
is going to be beautiful and uh to about
you know uh this year February 2nd we
did a video so if you have not watched
already check it out it's supremely
beautiful okay geometric inversion
uh and okay so we are going to do that
uh we're going to start to code so let's
start Wolfram language
and by the way I started to finally use
a chat GPT you know the intelligent AI
chat system it's amazing it's amazing
okay but I'm somewhat disappointed
okay hold on a second so let's start a
wufam language three
shift enter
and let's magnify
I'm somewhat disappointed with the chat
GPT because apparently in the past month
there are tremendous censorship hello
Finley Rudy where you from
so chat GPT you know uh oh I restarted
so head up for example this is chat gbt
hello
um
okay how can I assist you today so
teach me ooh family okay and that's
amazing it actually gives you a short
you know five paragraph is five
paragraphs tutorial about Wolfram
language it's actually amazing
so he says sure Wolfram language is a
powerful programming language developed
by Stefan Wolfram and his team at Wolf
and research it's the language that
powers Mathematica with Alpha and
Wolfram Cloud among other tools from
language is a high level language that
allows you to express complex algorithms
in a concise and readable way
exactly not sure about readable part but
okay then it says it's particularly well
suited for data analysis scientific
Computing exactly and symbolic
mathematics
that's a very accurate and answer okay
very extremely accurate answer you see
this is chat chat GPT and answering the
things on the Fly
by the way Stefan wolf fan wrote A Blog
article you know usually 20 30 pages
last week and he also did a YouTube live
stream explaining explaining how chat
GPT works okay so
so you know so um so I'm gonna talk
something about uh chat gbt and wufam
language and we're gonna start to code
okay so you from Canada hi
Fendi Rudy so chat gbd so then chat gbt
says you know
here are some uh key features of Wolfram
language hold on a second let's magnify
the font so you can read
okay so so here are some key features of
Wolfram language one high level data
structure sufam language has built in
support for a wide variety of data types
including lists array associations and
graphs exactly
you know graphs you see it mentions
graphs vast majority of programming
languages in fact none of it you know
all of the common general purpose
programming languages C C plus plus Java
C sharp JavaScript python Pearl Ruby
they don't have a data structure for
graphs okay haskout including ascal or
camo F sharp least none of those
languages has a data structure for
graphs now here graph graph means
Network okay you know like it's a graph
of mathematics graph Theory where you
have a bunch of dots you have n
connections a month with uh connections
to the dots forming a graph you know
so Wolfram language has a data structure
for graphs okay building okay so then it
says chat GPD says two powerful symbolic
computation indeed Wolfram language has
strong support for symbolic computation
allowing allow you allowing you to
perform operations on mathematical
Expressions as if they were variables
yes and building functions within
language has a large number of building
functions for a variety of tests such as
numerical optimization statistical
analysis and image processing okay and
visualization tools or from language has
many built-in tools for visuals
visualizing data such as plotting
functions in 3D Graphics exactly and
here is you know example we did
this beautiful geometric inversion
and then it says access to external data
sources Wolfram language has built-in
support for accessing external data data
sources such as web apis and databases
okay here's a simple example of move
from language program that calculates
the first 10 Fibonacci numbers okay
okay so you know so that's from chat GPT
so you know and you know I played with
it about an hour and a half for the
first time uh it's pretty good but
however it's not
uh you know
it's not
um
you know so my conclusion of chat GPD
from yesterday is that it's a good
replacement for search engine it's like
glorified search engine or machine
translation so basically you ask any
questions and they basically kind of
like summarize the web results you don't
have to read them you know if you search
for web you have to you know filter out
all the tons of links you have to read
them to see which one is good which one
is Spam and think and and you know low
quality content filter filter them out
things like that but chat GPT is
essentially a you know as a as a as a
result you know essentially it can it
functions a good uh as a good uh web uh
search result okay it just you don't
have to click each link you just read it
read the answer okay however
you know many of the answer it gives is
incorrect you know and uh
uh you know so it's just basically just
like web search you know when you search
the web you see a lot of answers
sometimes they are just not correct
uh so that's my kind of my conclusion of
of chat GPT you know before before
yesterday before I started to use it I
thought you know from based on what I've
seen I thought it already passed tuning
machine you know the Turing test
you know Turing tests is a test to see
if it um you know if if a machine
achieved intelligence I thought it
passed but yes but yesterday my
conversation with it you know I keep
pressing it it doesn't
um it keeps repeating you know oh I'm a
you know I asked him did you pass the
train test or do you think you can it
keeps repeating
template answers like Oh I'm a AI based
language model therefore I'm not
designed I'm not designed to do search
and search keeps repeating that
but I think part of the reason is that
in the past month you know chat GPD has
become hugely popular you know why did
we discussed on Twitter and every
everywhere else
um and there is a huge amount of
censorship we went into it so it no
longer really answers your question
as it does originally so it tries to go
around you know it tries to avoid
answering many of these questions such
as whether it can pass
chewing machine it kind of you know so
yesterday I keep pressing
the question
you know I think
I think chat gbd already passed through
in test however for political reasons
the scientists the researchers the
cooperation behind it you know they
don't want
they don't want
that aspect to be known you know they
don't want because that creates scale
it's scary you know
so
so that is what I think you know I I
think it already passed but nobody wants
to talk about that so but yesterday I
was just trying to test chat gbd you
know just to see whether it's really
intelligent but the result yesterday you
know I can try it now you know but I
want to do Mathematica today so the
result yesterday is that I keep asking
it keeps repeating the same template
answer you know it keeps saying I'm a AI
language model therefore I'm not you
know designed to
pass the dream machine and blah blah
blah it's kind of it it as if it doesn't
really understand my question you know
it it if it's a human you already know I
won't answer yes or no can you do you
think you can pass train test or not
can you answer yes and no you know I
pressing that question but gbd reviews
you know
uh so it was pretty dumb response
yesterday and I presume that's because
there's heavy censorship since since you
know
uh these uh a month ago
so
um so as to the question whether it
actually passed train test uh no I'm not
sure you know
big for example you also asked yet
another question
math question you also fail you know for
example I can again let's do some okay
show uh
what's the derivative of for example
yesterday I said
um
Okay so
uh let me see where my keys are
where did the
uh
I want parentheses
okay X raised to third power
Plus
I don't know where where's my keys on
this keyboard
I'm waiting for them to send me a the so
the the keyboard you are looking at
here
his glove 80 okay search my website us
yet
hello coffee horse
Coffee House philosopher so where is my
plus key
so the first key now again I'm using the
vorac keyboard for a layout on Windows
so
okay so there there is the first
three x third power x to the third power
divided by
x squared okay
okay what's the derivative of that
uh
did I just close it no okay
okay so it's trying to find the answer
let's let it run
so you know it's elaborate but usually
the answer is incorrect
so look therefore the derivative of that
expression is that expression it it just
um it's incorrect okay so for example if
you want to know the derivative of that
expression you can do
uh and
okay so that that
so paste
but oh we didn't copy so
copy that
Ctrl V2 paste
and what these the closing bracket
cat this video is pretty bad okay so
closing black open close okay so now I
got it
okay so there it is
do it shift enter
so that that is the uh
oh with respect to X so
X
so let's simplify now that's a big
expression
together
at
percentage sign stand for the last
expression
so that's the answer x squared minus 1
the whole thing divided by x to the
second power
so you can look at chat GPT that's the
incorrect result you know but it gives
you a elaborate explanation
you know to find the derivative of this
we can simplify the expression first by
using the quotient rule of derivatives
and incorrect okay so
so there is chat GPT so you know useful
but you know it's not incorrect all the
time okay so we talked already for God
20 minutes let's let's do the let's do
the Wolfram language then
okay so let's do we want to okay where
is that
uh there it is okay so let's
let's do some of these
so geometric inversion now you should
watch the previous videos Okay so
geometric inversion is a function
that can be applied to a two-dimensional
plane vectors or three-dimensional or
four-dimensional or any higher Dimension
so it's a family of functions you can
think of it that way so when you apply
to a plane
it basically it takes a point you know
and returns another point for any point
okay except the orange and except the
center
now similarly for three-dimensional okay
it just return a point so given any
Vector of nth Dimension it just return
another Vector of the same Dimension
okay so it just map points it's a it's a
just a function so when you do it on a
plane if you start with a grid and you
apply the geometric inversion function
to the grid points you get that figure
on the right okay so and and if you
start with you know a bunch of squares
you get that and if you re if you you
know what look at the center of the
square that's the difference between
these two images
so geometric immersion then you can
use tube to represent the grid
two-dimensional grid but you use a
three-dimensional tube to represent it
then you get that okay so we can copy
that so we did this um
so copy
shrink let's go here and let's paste
okay there is a code shift Ctrl n to
make it look nice and shift enter to
evaluate it so you can see there is a
grid
and there is a result okay 3D case
so then
if you start with this image then you
get that image two-dimensional geometric
inversion this this is you know this is
using regular polygon so here we have
one two three four we have octagon you
know a bunch of up token
centered on
a rectangular grid points then you apply
it you get this image okay then and then
you can extend the thickness so you get
a 3D image like that so let's try that
that's beautiful
okay so all this we did Cover last time
what is this Library
uh
uh okay because my copy key you know
that happens because my mouse
the the keys for my mouse
can you see yeah you can see so the key
program to my mouse is doing copy Ctrl C
but
but right now I'm using the war rack
you know the borac layout so the Ctrl C
becomes something else the Ctrl C
becomes
Ctrl I so that's why I you see often I
have mistakes so I need to reprogram the
mouse or something like that but anyway
ultimately I'm waiting for a new version
you know with a different key switches
of the gravity so
that's when I really you know get used
to this keyboard
so for now so the copy failed uh so
let's go back so copy so if you now that
that's that is my ultimate hacking
keyboard I have the copy key set up
there so I can
press that for copy and paste press that
and evaluate the code
okay so you can see this is the
three-dimensional version of The Thing
beautiful
okay then we did all that previously
now we just uh now we want to do
let's do it okay
we'll find language so
copy because any comments and questions
posted okay
so let's go back to emacs
so then I can use
stuff like keys
comment questions posted okay
so we start a wolfam language code paste
it there and start to do it okay so here
is a geometric inversion function
um
takes the points return a point
then we want to
we want to have a
list of great points in 3D so
a rectangular grid so so what we can do
is
uh what
coordinate
bounds okay
so let's look up
documentation for coordinate bonds
that basically generates a list of
coordinates so given at least x mean x
max okay so conund
we have
ah
okay X-Men x max y mean y Max
okay X Min is from
let's say
negative two
negative
true
two two
okay
that's X Min x max now y mean y Max same
thing okay so if we just run that
you're gonna get a decent points
so you can see control V for paste the
net
no
oh it Returns the bounce that's not the
function we want coordinate bounding box
coordinate
that is not the function we want what
this returns is that it returns a
the maximum boundaries of a bunch of
Lisa points so but that's not what we
want we want
cornet spawns array okay
so that's what we want
copy that
paste it
run it so you can see
those are coordinates of
a two-dimensional rectangular array okay
now but what we want is three
dimensional
so
let's look at the documentation
oh yeah so three-dimensional you just
need one more
for Z okay copy it back here
paste
shift enter when it so you see each
point is a 3D Point 3D vector and so you
have a bunch of points forming a
rectangular Grid in 3D okay
so
okay so that is our points then we want
to apply
let's apply a sphere okay let's make
them so we want to show Graphics of
these points each point is represented
is going to be represented by a sphere
okay or by a ball so let's look up
sphere let's look at the documentation
for sphere
sphere represents a unit sphere centered
at Point P okay and the second argument
is the radius okay so we have the
coordinates then we just map
fear
okay map
a function
sphere
okay that's the argument and radius
0.2 okay 0.2 radius and we want to map
to the list the list is going to be x
coordinates
foreign
okay and what do you want to map to the
depth so the depth is going to be
negative two
okay because if you map to the negative
one that means map to the leaf of this
nested Beast so the leaf of this Nestle
this is going to be basically the
numbers okay but we want to map the
points so that's negative two so that's
one branch up from the div so the very
powerful map function okay so for
example we can try it here
so you can see Ctrl V paste shift enter
oh we didn't Define coordinate okay so
let's do that here
okay bunch of points then you see now it
becomes a sphere
you know sphere at this Center and with
that radius okay now we just display
that so what you do
FX 3D
GP equals true so GP
yeah Graphics Primitives okay so now
graph GP okay X is true now let's try
that
okay bunch of points put sphere onto it
there it is
so here is you can see
a grid of spheres okay now we just want
to apply the geometric trans inversion
function to each of the points okay how
you do that that's easy okay so
so we're gonna
um
so we can do
let's use pattern matching okay very
powerful
um
uh function Okay so
GP is a spheres then we want to apply
the rule the rule is going to be
whenever you see a sphere okay
so so the rule is left hand side and
right hand side something so the left
hand side is going to be anything
anything
that
um
oh God now I'm locked to Capital key
God problem
now I don't know how to unlock the
capital key for this keyboard
um okay so no worry let's
oh wait because I have
I'm used I'm using sticky keys so you
can see on the lower right you know
that's why
okay so sphere anything
okay anything in this part we don't care
uh
actually
let's say ah radius okay
so whenever you see the pattern sphere
something
what you want to do is replace it by
replace it by
apply the function to your inversion
X okay
yep so that's
so that's that okay so now
show the graphics here and here
uh let's re let's assign this gp2 okay
gp2
equals to
okay now show the graphics gp2
okay so that
that is all
okay so copy all go back to fame
language paste it here
so run it
coordinate points sphere at those points
then we got this grid of spheres then we
apply the geometric inversion to it then
we got this very nice
but we got to so you see this is very
nice but we need to um
you know you know the the radius is too
big
yeah the the radius is now too big okay
so let's
let's decrease the radius okay
so let's go back here and decrease the
radius
okay uh radius let's say 0.8
one
and let's add a semicolon so that
it doesn't show the bunch of points
okay
and
okay let's try that
there is our points of grid
and now it's better but still
so you can start to see
okay so we need to make some adjustments
okay let's go back here
can you please tell your friends at the
banggood Factory
what you're talking about Turkish person
I cannot do things like that
okay so we got that so
let's see a bunch of points and inverted
okay so let's
so what
so how can we fix this once we invert it
then
can we make the so here when we
transform it it's multiply
0 point
three
so after we apply this at after we apply
the geometric transformation we
reduce the radius of the sphere by
by a new Factor 0.3 okay let's try it
so here is a sphere
and here is the that doesn't look good
okay
that doesn't look good
okay now
we can change now we start with the
coordinate let's try three it's not not
enough
um
okay let's do it here not enough points
four okay
foreign
0.1 okay 0.1
okay XR is radius
x r
okay that's a function now
copy it
go back here
paste it run it now it's better now we
got lots of points to work with
you know this part is also interesting
so you are looking at a grid of spheres
now because of the projection it's not
parallel projection so you so you have
this effect you know
so let's uh
you see so you kind of have this effect
and when they are
then then when when they are you know
when you when you are viewing
a certain angle they form different
effects some you know you can see some
some kind of hexagon
pattern
okay so now here is the geometric
inversion yeah so this doesn't look good
because
the you know because you don't see the
center okay so let's let's do this so
instead of
let's start from zero okay so the
so zero and let's add more points copy
and let's show here
paste
a minute
so now we have less points but now
okay now that's
that looks somewhat okay that's what we
wanted to see
but okay so this so I don't think this
is going to look that good you know it's
uh previous
using cubes
or using the um
where's the other okay so our previous
one using the cube or
or using tube
is much more beautiful
yeah so okay so I think that's that's
about it today
what are your specs what do you mean
specs
okay so what we gonna do this with this
we we want to try to make this beautiful
okay
so this is not good
um
yeah so if we shrink it
by
two
computer hardware what's my computer
hardware spec
you know don't you don't you have
anything for Google from language
you know I want I like you guys I like
my readers to actually learn stuff you
know
so you want to know you know your gig
you know your computer's spec your CPU
your GPU that's
very idiotic you know
Chevy Creek
you know so I want you to learn
mathematics in Wolfram language in in
coding that's what we are talking about
today
so you can see now we have a geometric
inversion
yeah but now it doesn't look so good you
can't it's hard to see okay so you need
to turn this I think
this way
then you see some pattern okay it
doesn't look good
so okay so I know I get
okay it's
you know it does not look so good
yeah so this this way is actually much
better
by the way if you want to know my
computer
spec all you have to do is just search
for it okay you know like you know I get
so many questions
uh but all the questions because they
don't you know
if you if you take a minute
or 10 seconds to search it you know
study dot info click on search
and
uh
type machine you'll find it in in a
minute okay
lottery machine programming language and
its machine keyboard Design This and for
the list machine standard type machine
okay for example you know so machine
generated span standalog standard type
machine keyboard design for this machine
this machine keyboards okay just click
on any one of those so here is my
keyboard website then you just go to
miscellaneous Tech Then There It Is
gaming computer Okay click on that then
you can see all my spec
spec and photos of my computer I bought
this computer in
2021 if uh much thanks to you guys
donation
2021 that's my first kind of
computer okay so anyway there it is
okay back to the
um
back to the wufan language okay that I
think that's it for today it failed
so for example let's you know let's
let's random chat with the chat GPT
what is geometric inversion
I asked it yesterday
and it gave a pretty good answer
geometric inversion is a transformation
in Geometry that involves inverting
points through a fixed circle of sphere
it is a type of transformation that Maps
points on one side of the circle
two points on the other side exactly
to perform a geometric conversion we
select a fixed Circle and blah blah blah
you know I explained that in my past
videos
and you can also
you can see
some talk show so all the links are here
Language tutorial geometric inversion
move from language code
and then you can go to
to the bottom here is
you know some of the explanation of
geometric inversion how it is defined
and many interesting properties okay
so back to chat GPT so so it says the
geometric version has some interesting
properties for example it preserves
angles between curves
that intersect
at the inversion Circle sphere yeah
and it sends circles that do not
intersect the inversion Circle to
circles that intersect it at right
angles yeah you know the this wording is
not correct it's kind of fuzzy but
anyway basically that you know it's
trying to tell you about the property
where if you have a image let's say if
you have two lines okay
yeah okay so let me show you one example
so if you have for example if you start
with this
um
let's see if I can let's say this okay
so if you start with the Grid on the
left
you know and focus on two lines in a
grid that's perpendicular
so once then you apply the geometric
inversion and look at those two lines
you know the intersection will be
preserved it will preserve the angle so
whatever you they intersect the angle
they intersect before
after the geometric inversion they will
intersect at the same angle so you can
see the result on the right the circles
they intersect you see here here all the
points of intersection are still 90
degrees
so we say that
the geometric inversion transformation
this function they they are they are
angle preserving or uh
angle invariant okay
so here is Geo G algebra that shows you
this property angle invariant
okay so this
this
um
let's see yeah so this circle on the
left here this is the inversion Circle
and uh
anyway you have to spend some time to to
study this figure you know I I have to I
have to like spend some time but anyway
angle in variance okay that's one of the
property it doesn't change
the angle at intersections
okay so you know then chat GPD is trying
to say that then it says geometric
inversion is used in many areas of
mathematics including complex analysis
projective geometry and hyperbolic
geometry it has applications in physics
such as in the study of electromagnetic
fields and in computer graphics
where it can be used to generate
interesting shapes in patterns okay
you know it's kind of correct kind of
you know it's it's it's
weasel weasel speak so if you know for
example I know geometric version you
know I've been studying
starting in 1990s so I know what he's
talking what he is talking about but if
you don't know what the geometric
inversion some of these answer is
somewhat can be misleading okay for
example geometric immersion is used in
many areas of mathematics
not really
not really many areas that depends on
what do you mean by used
you know because any other thing in math
you can you could almost say anything
you know given any mathematical jargon
you can always say it's used in many
areas of mathematics
but that's that doesn't mean anything I
mean the important thing is relative to
other mathematical thing or mathematical
process
how much is it used for example
derivative integral calculus they are
far far more I mean that those those
things compared to geometric immersion
they are far far more applied okay
so this you know this statement
geometric conversion is used in many
areas of mathematics uh yes and no that
you know it's like weasels
weasel talk
including complex analysis Now that
statement is also questionable I mean
well yeah so in complex analysis
basically
the diversion of complex numbers is
geometric numeration okay so it's
fundamental geometric inversion
from a algebra point of view you know we
are we we have been talking about it
from a Geo geometry point of view but
from a Archer break point of view it's
basically diversion of complex numbers 1
over X where the x is a complex number
okay that's what
geometric inversion is it defines
the version okay that's the definition
of the version of a complex number but
the way chat GPD says is that okay it
has used in many areas you know
including complex analysis
um
no it just you know it's just
it's it's the diversion okay
it's a definition of the version of
complex numbers okay then it says
projective geometry that's true and
hyperbolic geometry uh I don't know
I don't know that topic well
to say to to make a comment okay so then
it says it has applications in physics
such as the study of electromagnetic
fields yeah kind of I guess
well
possibly because complex analysis
complex numbers
complex numbers has
significant application in study of
electromagnetic fields okay
but it's not because of the inversion
you know so you can say complex analysis
has a lot applications in
electromagnetic fields
and
the diversion definition of diversion of
complex analysis is the geometric
inversion therefore
you can say that geometric inversion is
you know used in the study of
electromagnetic fields you can kind of
say that
then it says end in computer Graphics
not really
you know it says in computer graphs for
graphics where it can be used to
generate interesting shapes and patterns
that's very
interesting you know so
so on the whole you see the chat GPT
describe it it's on the it's on the
ballpark you know of things you know it
says it can generate interesting shapes
and patterns indeed that's what I have
been doing
but
you know then you know it says using
computer Graphics not really you know
because generating interesting shapes
and patterns that's not really computer
that's not really
well that's the result is computer
Graphics but it's not really
you know decorated patterns is
if you want to classify as part of
computer Graphics but it's not really
the subject matter of computer Graphics
because the the heart of computer
Graphics is about how do you
actually
make the computer do it you know so
that's not geometric inversion that's
that would be about linear algebra
okay so anyway
I attempted to download woofer
Mathematica but instead I got the
partial trial version and not the full
version how do I get full version
did you okay so you know like I talked
about many times
you know you have to do is just go to
you know go to what is this web blog go
to go to start talk show go to
okay
so let's put this back I think that's it
for today
uh now show this in browser just search
for fam language okay
so Wolfram Lan okay
then you'll find here is my tutorial
and on the left you can see download
free I follow the download from your
site Okay so
uh I attended to download with my math
Mica you know so you have to download
the Wolfram engine okay that's what you
download so you click here download look
for Wolf and developers turn on
JavaScript and turn on cookies okay and
uh
and if you do that
free download okay so click on that
so turn turn The JavaScript you you know
you so you want to you know turn on
JavaScript and accept all cookies okay
so you just follow this you'll get it
okay you are not going to download wolf
and Mathematica okay what you are
downloading is the Wolfram engine
which comes with Wolfram script okay I
have explanation here so you basically
just follow it carefully and don't be
don't try to do tricks okay don't don't
try to Oh I wanna be anonymous or I
don't want to show my email or I'm going
to create a new email and I'm going to
go through virtual you know
website so we cannot know who am I don't
do that okay if you really want to use
it
then just do us what you know normal
people would do
okay if you're gonna do try to do tricks
you don't get it that's your problem you
want you know you you might have a
problem
to uh
to do it okay
so that's that's that's that if you want
to try it free you can that's that's
what to do uh and uh
yeah I would recommend it was like like
I said many times I've been using
Wolfram language for 30 years
beginning in beginning in 1993 I bought
it I bought the student version because
you know after research I find I want to
be I want I wanted to be a mathematician
and I want to have the best tools so
Wolfram language back then
is the best and it is
still is today okay if you want to do
mathematics physics engineer you know
integral you know science scientific
computation
that's one of the best one okay there
are others of course but that's one of
the best ones
and uh so I so I recommend you just buy
a license for for woofam uh Mathematica
I I don't have discount for you okay you
just go the website there's a student
version 200 or 300 or something
dollars okay and I think these days it's
a subscription only I think I'm not too
sure but that's all I can do for you I
don't you know I don't have special
privileges
okay that's it uh
so somewhat disappointing now let's
think about can we actually make this
beautiful using spheres this is somewhat
disappointing because you don't really
see
you know you don't really see the
patterns
of the structure
yeah I don't think we can
let's let's try one more let's make it
nice
okay
so now there's more points okay yeah so
all you get is this kind of thing
that's
so the structure shows only when you
have lots of balls
so it so if you you know
so I don't think it's very um
using spheres doesn't work
okay that's it for today anything else
yeah so this is what I wanted wanted to
do
and this is what I wanted to do and
apparently
so we have tried using lines we have
tried using cubes
that all works well but if you just use
point it doesn't work well yeah that I
should know that because if you use just
points
on the 2D version it doesn't
you know really show the pattern yeah
unless you have
thousands of points that's right I
should have known that
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching uh
I wanted to do a lot videos you know
like um
have you tried to write a Java or python
macro code
now python doesn't really support Marco
nor does Java so what are you talking
about
okay that's it I think that's it for
today so how many people one two people
my video is set you know I I wanted to
do a lot of videos but each time
I'm unsure about
uh what else today okay I think that's
it for today so I mean you know there's
a lot of things
you know I've been busy
doing a lot of coding and lots of other
things
for example I can
okay that's it that's it for today let
me talk random for five minutes for
three minutes then we shut down okay so
I have been working a lot you know every
day you know I work on my website uh
tremendous amount of things to do for
example keyboard there's a lot updating
stuff so for example this is the best
stylus for for Microsoft Surface if you
have that and this is practice of
writing Chinese
okay so let's go back so this keyboard
there is also the interesting thing
about
finger length the relative length of
your pinky with with respect to the
ring finger so one of the interesting
thing to check is if your pinky is
longer than the last knuckle of your
ring finger you know so different people
so I did the Paw I did a poll on Twitter
now here is my Twitter page
I did a poll on Twitter
so apparently uh JavaScript
so yeah here I talked a little bit about
chat GPT
and see
my you know so this is also interesting
beautiful okay this is the foundation of
Western culture Greek mythology the
story of the nights
something like that so here is my thread
about chat gbt you can read basically
what I said today and then there is the
um
lots of work so there's an interesting
the finger length Okay so I did a pole
so apparently 50 people
says that their pinky doesn't reach the
last knuckle of the ring finger but the
other 40 says yes
so this has to do with the design of the
keyboard for example you if you are
looking at the glove 80 keyboard
you know very interesting because the
you have to design the height so that
search and search so that
different people with different pinky
length can use that
okay so that's one of the interesting
thing
then there is interesting Mouse I
discovered this mouse
the premise of this mouse
the design is that this guy thinks that
the mouse button is painful
because you know there is no
yield you know
he wanted
a mouse button that you can actually
press it down so he designed this mouse
so that's one of you know that's
interesting and you know so
that is actually that that that
idea is actually not
unique so for example there is this
mouse that actually uses keyboard
key switches you know Cherry MX Keys
reaches
and uh China you know a company in China
actually did it and I have this mouse
actually I showed it in my video
somewhere a Chinese friend gave it to me
so yeah I showed in this video uh that's
interesting
uh then let's go back
so I wanted to show so gravity okay so
let's go back so I did a lot programming
work
chat GPT okay Google you know a i a i
machine learning it's reaching some kind
of breakthrough period in this year then
HTTP then Wolfram language lots of
update on Wolfram language
my pinky pass it passes it by I think
three millimeters okay similar similar
to me so you can see I don't know if you
can see
oh Eugene you don't you are not seen you
are not you
so you see left and uh so left hand
and right hand
okay okay
yeah I was I was showing anyway that's
it bye guys