hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today we are going to
code emac beast emac beast fantastic so
this is my keyboard exposed Expos I'm
I'm on this keyboard today okay search
my website Saudi keyboard you'll find it
okay my reviews and stuff and today we
are going to talk about we are going to
code emac this
so today this is today's topic so let's
see we are going to code a URL parser
you know emac this passing URL which is
quite interesting and interesting and
not trivial okay in fact I already wrote
it I'm gonna explain that the building
URL password sucks okay and I'm gonna
explain my new code I already wrote it
so
emac beesp okay writing a URL password
okay let's begin begin
okay my keyboard and my video check
audio check yeah good okay let's go
so URL possible okay so let's let's do
it let's do it so show so let me tell
you that building by default there is a
URL password this is this one okay uh
describe function
URL generic
pass URL that's the function name
and it's in this file
urlpath.el okay so you can open it open
the source code you can see it's here
and you can diet jump to jump into the
directory I'm using a vorac keyboard
layout and I'm using soft light keys and
on the left you can see all my commands
and and the keystrokes I type okay so if
you are not sure for example what is
this next window or frame that's a
function name you know I just press that
W it you know it just let me if I have
separate pins you know it let me jump if
I have two pins it'll switch the closer
among the pins if I only have one pen
here just jump through
different Windows okay so anyway so
that's a pink window that shows all my
command codes and keystrokes forek vorac
layout okay so today so there is a
building function
now let me show you a trick so how do
you know if you are writing a HTML or
pass you know whatever you know in emacs
you want to know if there is a URL
passing function now in emac this there
is no namespace there is no
uh you know a mechanism that associate
libraries with the namespace so there's
no namespace so it's kind of a mess so
how do I know how do you find it
basically you go to the list directory
so call describe function describe
function and type any uh you know emacs
command for example forward word okay
that's a very typical command so
describe function that the same then you
can see okay it's in C source code now
that's not the one you want now if I
press enter Because I didn't build my
emacs I didn't compile it so there is no
source code but you can you you can you
can download the emacs source code then
add a link in your unit then you can you
can jump to the csos code anyway so
let's call another command typically I I
call
describe function
tired or the it okay so so that shows
the documentation for the function diet
which is the the diet mod is lets you
see the directory and the copy file
delete file you know rename file things
like that
so diet and press enter to jump to the
source code so you can see here is the
diet source code you know for 5000 lines
then called diet jump this command you
know so let's call it call it it'll drop
U2 diode where that current file is at
so you can see so then you go to the top
all the way to the top you can see
that's how you arrive at the emac this
source code you know that's a bundle you
know so go up directory in diet it's uh
the correct you know the the correct key
so you can see here's all this directory
so you go there then if you need to find
some existing you know if you want to
know is there is already a function
doing URL passing or HTML passing or any
other thing this is how this is the
general way to find it so for example in
this directory I can you know open any
one then you just search for for example
let's say search for the word pass okay
so in this directory search search it
and all files ending in dot El that
means emac these files search it
okay so there are a thousand or two
thousand files it
uh so did I already started search yes
so you have to wait for a while because
it's actually loading the disk disk is
usually the bottleneck for a file search
so I'm right now using the my own
package because I find text to search it
but you but there are many ways you can
use scrap you know so and so on so here
is the um so you can see here is all the
occurrences of those files contains the
word pass and this one is in in this
file uh you know in this
in this emacs [ __ ] and and there are so
many you can see you can see the score
box there's tons of files uh
with containing the word pass so anyway
so that's how you that's a general way
to find if a function is available in a
library it's kind of tedious but that's
almost
that's basically the only way okay
because emacs doesn't have a name space
system and there's no comprehensive
documentation of all the libraries okay
so anyway so
and I know for example there is you
browser okay so let's go to emacs uh
so for example you can how do how do you
know so you go to the browser you you go
to
kasady.info okay so you are here and
click on sorry search and eww okay so
you okay okay you can you can say emacs
browser
so emacs web browser there's a EU web
browser which is a web browser written
entirely in emacbisp
okay entirely and so we can try it now
so for example meta X eww okay Enter and
it asks you a URL so let's say
google.com let's see how Google looks
there it is so you can type for word uh
wait cancel where is my cruise
okay so here xanadi uh e-max okay so
search Google then you have the
uh tab tab tab you know PSI Max's
tutorial let's go there so you are
looking at you browser eww ew that's
that's the naming of the thing written
by this great emac this expert
okay so you know I have a tutorial on
that so you browser is sometimes useful
but um anyway so so you are looking at
my website via the Emax building
you browser written in iMac this so
anyway why am I mentioning this because
I know that there is this you know you
returning email address so with the new
browser it must need to do passing URL
often so I'm I'm guessing so you if I
can look at the source code for you
browser I might find you know some
function that passes URL so that's
another way that's how I you know for
example close this so let's do meta X
uh actually let's do um
Ctrl H describe function okay
describe function type eww and enter so
then here is the eww
um
documentation
tab jump to the source code so you can
look at the source code and the diet
jump to go to the directory so you can
see here is the eww and go all the way
up you can see in this directory it's
everything about net networking
so this is how you know so you can now
try to search for a past URL name you
know so anyway that's that's that's how
you find it okay so for example let's
let's do search okay you can use web but
I use my own command because I find text
okay so
search for
pass Dash URL for example okay searching
in this directory yes uh file path make
your expression dot El
okay so there it is now there are like
20 results so you can see so we have
found actually the thing the function we
are looking for URL generic pass URL so
you can you know pick any one of them
and go to it and you see so this one is
used by [ __ ] you know [ __ ] is a
library that allows you to kind of load
files files from a remote server so try
so anyway so you can see it uses it
needs to pass URL so now you can just
describe function
and type URL generic pass URL that's a
default enter there it is this so
describe function is fantastically
useful okay it it allows you to um
show the documentation of a function and
uh and uh jump to the source code okay
there's a question oh do you put away
your glove I knew that question is
coming up because you
dramatic people like you want to know
which which keyboard is are you current
using oh you are you not using uh X club
that does that mean you don't use it
anymore
no I use it because I want to you know
I'm not using it now because I I'm
waiting for them to send me a new one
with a lighter switch because I have isi
for 15 years so for today I you know I
don't want you know I'm not going to
stick like I have to stick to one
keyboard and next time when you watch my
video I'm using a different oh so did
you did you change your keyboard what
happened you know that's not good okay
that's a phenomenon of you know you you
look at the celebrities what t-shirt
they wear like what do they say oh you
know rust you know what the latest
programming language I you know I don't
do that okay glove 80 is a fantastic
keyboard one of the best that that will
be my permanent you know but I'm waiting
for the new Switch but expose is also
fantastic okay
which one is for you that depends on
other issues there's no one single best
keyboard however there are differences
between qualities of which keyboard are
kind of better than a different you know
lots of others so Expose and
gravity and I will I would also say
Kinesis advantage and the new one this
is 360. they are all superb I recommend
you know they they differ by price they
differ by form factor they differ by so
it depends on you which one is best for
you but anyway
so back to uh emac beasts okay
yeah I'm a celebrity because I was your
kid what's your what's your uh your
computer computer spec what CPU What GPU
do you use
your favorite color
okay so back to e-macbs okay focus guys
focus on emac this today we're talking
about e-magbees okay two people the
poverty of my show you know
you know I suppose you know if I'm gonna
do let's let you know what other ways to
become popular let's just talk about
drama every day if I do that you know my
my viewership probably will increase but
that's not good you know that's the
that's that's [ __ ] you know that's all
the YouTubers are doing so back to emac
this
so now I'm going to rent on the building
so URL generate pass URL it's
this is a old
um written uh like 20 years ago or
something very old okay so you can you
can see the documentation you open that
so here is a source code
so you diet jump again to go to
directory so so this file is URL dash
pass so you can see
this whole directory is basically
related to url url cookie
you know the whole directory is related
to URL but now if you look at this URL
pass go to the top you can see it's
written in 1996 very old 25 years old
Okay so
but it sucks why it sucks let me explain
okay so you see I need a function to
pass URL
why do I need it let me explain okay
what's what's the deal why do you need
to pass UI yeah okay so let's go to CSS
okay show in browser
visual CSS tutorial so this is my visual
CSS tutorial I recommend you go check it
out
okay visual CSS okay uh
and we want to know currently we want to
know URL okay so let's go to dome you
know you you want to know all the things
about URL for example in JavaScript
you have a
object you have a you have a dome
interface
interface you have basically a function
that passes URL but why do you need to
pass it okay let me show you so here is
how to uh open an URL given a URL you
can open in your browser how do you do
that in JavaScript okay so go down and
here is how to get cookies you know
check if cookies are enabled web storage
get URL so there it is get URL so see
you see URL has many parts this uh you
know here is a URL for example this is
local
has many parts okay so hold on a second
let me magnify the font so odd t s
or keyboard functionality okay so now go
here
Zoom size let's say 121 110 okay and
it's that's a bit better okay so back to
URL so today's topic is UIL URL Supreme
so UIL so you have the okay so let me
just directly show you okay recently I
did update on this okay so there it is
different parts of the url url syntax
and number parts you have the protocol
part you have the uh you have the path
in wait wait okay I'm missing something
this this is the domain so protocol
domain Port Port number you have the
path resource path you have the query
string you have the hash
fragment that that allows you to jump to
a specific point in the page so you know
technical details you know this uh URL
okay so you need to pass URL because
uh because for example I'm writing a
command I need it anyway
okay you you you know that's a silly
question you know you need to pass UI
out but let's look let's go back look at
this URL generic past UI okay so so
return a an URL struct
of the parts of URL okay it returns a
URL struct what the [ __ ] is URL struct
the CL style struct contains the
following Fields okay type user password
host
Port spec file name Target attributes
fullness those those field names look CD
that's nothing like today's you know
you know by JavaScript you have protocol
host post Port number resource path
query string URL fragment okay but
however according to this
emac this function you have this type
what the [ __ ] is type user password
you know it's it's so it's Asian that's
a point
okay now you can see
and you can see the pause it says here
the parser follows RFC 3986 except that
is also tries to handle your eyes that
are not fully specified
lacking type and it does not check for
something something okay something
something something something
esoteric and uh basically outdated this
he you know
so first of all you know you have this
confusing Fields but okay so yeah so
let's say I want to adopt it but but it
returns a URL struct what the [ __ ] is
the struct in emac this there is no such
building data type called struct okay
and then it says the CL style CL stand
for common this you know the common is
that that's the the single most element
that
that that made this so bad okay that did
huge damage to lisp you know the the CR
style struct contains the following so
what what is a struct
you cannot find it anywhere
you know this is when you need to go
look up look up the common disp hyper
spec okay so let's see common lisp
shocked what the [ __ ] is this you know
okay the introduction to structures okay
common is you know
so structures yeah see how so hyperspect
okay you know it it's going it's going
nowhere I want the hype I want the
specification okay so let's type
common lisp hyperspect struct maybe
you'll give you a better
um
hyper spec lookup yeah
okay so anyway so that's my point you
know
emac beasts do not have does not have
the stroke data structure but but this
library is is using the commons this
structure and uh you know so it's not
good okay
and it's also kind of outdated you know
so that's my pain that's my complaint I
want to use it you know I it's always
better to use every anything that's
building so I want to use it but I don't
know what is a struct and then it's
common it's it's from common lisp why is
it from common disk because back then
you see this is uh this is 1996 back
then communist and skin scheme this is
the primary lisps and there's uh you
know there's a language what there's two
factions you know they
and uh you know throughout the past 30
years this tremendous effort trying to
upgrade emac this to migrate emac beasts
into one of the communities or skim disp
so there are two big factions worrying
factions to this day there's no
agreement okay
um you know and I first I despise common
disk comedies with everything that's
wrong with this okay the [ __ ] coming
this person you know anyway so
so yeah okay I like to use it but no
documentation and what the [ __ ] and and
then what the [ __ ] is the UI are struck
and it's a firing structure from common
disk I don't want to use it okay and
it's old so because of all these reasons
I don't you know I decided it's easier
for me to write my own okay so that
that's what I did rule your own
okay close close so what is this size
Max blog okay close actually close that
back here open it
so you can see
by the way there's some funny things
okay let me uh but let's let's let's
talk about the uh URL first okay so here
is you know so I wrote a Blog
complaining a record of my complaint of
why common this this this this this this
is just not good okay
first of all the fields are kind of
outdated okay
so that's not that's one of the
complaint then it's using a URL struct a
firing structure not from emac Beasts
that's another that's my second
complaint you know you you can use a
record or a hash table to represent it
in emac this that's building that's
native data structure you don't need
there's no there's no reason that you
need a common this data structure to
represent the result okay so this is so
that's that's
my criticism my patreon my complaint
about this commonly
facts okay you want you you will not
hear anyone talking about this because
they are all nice people they are for
building a better world they are for
protecting women and children and in
black people that's typical
you know in this you know nice people
that's why they have a lot of views
okay companies so I I wrote my own Okay
so
I'm not the best coder I'm doing fine
but you know I can write this function
which works fine okay so so that let's
show that function okay close close uh
close close Okay lots of talk and uh so
uh so where is it okay pass your IR so
yeah so here I wrote the function took
took about uh two hours so describe
function PSI HTML URL pass URL so so
here's my function and here is the
Keys you know this is modern this is
based on you know the browser's
JavaScript functions
so for for example so you can see the
browser
there's get URL this past URL so you can
see this is how you retrieve a URL and
you have methods that
pass the URL so and you can do it this
way so you know so I my I base my model
my function on this JavaScript thing
okay so and and uh so I it's part of the
HTML mod so let's go to it
so here is the function
uh you know 100 lines 50 lines so you
know 89 something like that okay so
actually so this this to write this
function actually is not trivial it's uh
it's interesting so let's let's go over
it a little bit okay so because it's
interesting
okay let's go to Kusa
P mag this mod okay let's talk about
this for a while so I already talked for
uh 25 minutes okay so is there a simple
way to describe the difference between
URI and URL that's a good question
that confused me the fact for over 10
years let me explain that one okay
that's a big
hysteria among the tech geekers among
the hacker types among the you know
emacs every day Vim everyday veeam VI
emacs Unix Linux kernel this type of
people I despise and see coders you know
they they are they are they are holier
than thou you know they are on you know
Hacker News they are on GitHub you know
very popular typically they tell you
what to do python especially you know um
you know they they
they did so so backing let's say from
year 2000 let's say 1999 so the the
whole year 2000 the decade a lot of
these types for for lack of better name
I call them hacker types Elite hacker
types okay they are superior type you
know they are the type they always talk
about emac swim command line interface
you know they they will make fun that we
are ridicule Microsoft Word and hate
despite hate hatred deep hatred of
Microsoft every day these [ __ ] okay
I despise them these people for over a
decade you'll see this question coming
up often
when you mentioned you are oh no you you
are incorrect it should be you are I
okay why
so what's the technical difference
between URL and URI so I read that that
multiple times but every time I I don't
remember the details but basically in
general in general URI is just the more
generic generic
turn but more generic concept than URL
so URL stands for
Universal resource location locator okay
so basically it's a standard
standardized way
you know a syntax that specifies a
location in cyberspace okay basically
just a wet you know it can be a web page
it can be a local file uh yeah for
example that's also a URL but anyway
Universal resource locator location
locator okay you can look up Wikipedia
okay go do that
but URI is a universal resource
um the I stand for
um
Universal resource that I stand for
I I don't remember but basically it's
kind of the the it's kind of like a more
general idea okay
but okay so what my point is that
throughout the year 2000s this hacker
Elite Ed types will
repeat that all the time they will say
oh you are I you know you shouldn't say
UI this is the UI is correct okay so
after a while I followed them you know I
I'm also a nerd I'm a big one so I I
look at you know I read it a thousand
times so I think okay your eye is better
in fact you can see in my emac based
code
so you you go back to uh tml mod go to
the bottom so there's 5 000 lines of
code and now you list matching lines you
are I so you can see
some of my functions you know a few
years ago 10 years ago is using URI
but however the thing about this this
Ed hacker kind of jargon their concerned
their obsession is that
it's periodical you know it's a fad
today the Merlin gen and Zuma took over
with their JavaScript and Ruby and rust
lost have you do what do you think of
Ross rossly is the best language you
know the new generation they don't know
about this they don't care you know you
don't see this UI I mentioned anymore
it's just a [ __ ] damn URL okay it's
like XML is dead who cares about XML but
back then it's their XML everyday same
thing happens fat what can you do
so anyway my point here is that
you know the and God the the history the
w3c org you know the [ __ ] okay the you
know RFC for example you you know we
read our FC before in that generic use
you know based on rf's RFC three nine
something something you know sounds
Grand that's the hacker types today that
is forgotten that's not there's so many
other standards and HTML5 versus w3c
they fight you know there's a big war
you know so
you know back then they'll tell you you
know you if you don't listen to standard
you are a [ __ ] face this this Elite
hacker Fox Okay Unix philosophy
[ __ ] you know they
okay so that's enough rent okay so if
you want to know what's the difference
about UI or UI you know just Wikipedia
URI okay
so identifier that's right uniform oh no
it's not no they change your name you
it's not Universal it's uniform resource
identifier okay
so so let's look at history and blah
blah blah refinement and you are and by
the way this is also you are in
claim okay
[ __ ] them
you know I I used to be like like the
hackers and nerds you know I also pay
extreme attention I I read this a
thousand times you know before before
there's Wikipedia The the there was FAQ
then there's IFC you know
incomprehensible [ __ ]
anyway the point here is that it doesn't
really matter okay what did you know
whatever you call them it's just a
[ __ ] it's just a string okay it
doesn't really it's not that important
okay
and uh and you know remember you know
look at you know the the standard you
know this one for example this one you
are a generic pass URL this you know
this the past follows RFC 3986
you know sounding so Grand their [ __ ]
ass you know there is nothing wrong with
following standard of course standard
that's that's the purpose of standard so
we don't so we don't get into a
situation where you have your own you
you do your own way he does his own way
I do my own way it it's hell okay so
standard but what happens with this deed
hacker types you know these they they
think they know stuff they you know Unix
hackers Linux this type and and this and
Vim emac these types they forgot the you
know they don't have a general purpose
that they don't have a view of the whole
Humanity okay they don't know how things
work standards you know standard for
example this one now now it looks you
know look at this it just looks silly
today
then they they argue oh well because the
standard changes now
you know the standard artist human
created there's a lot of politics in war
so yeah sure follow standard but you
don't you don't want to be like obsessed
about it and and telling every other
people about you know you know so
anyway back then RFC is one of the Unix
idiots and see you know these type of
people they are sighted every day okay
but not today not not it haven't been so
for like 10 years okay so here is the
RFC 3986 okay
so anyway so that's uh that you know so
you know I thought you are you know so
to me I'm getting old I thought URI is
gonna take over you know as far as
terminology we should use UI but it you
know it's all back to UI who what the
[ __ ] is your eye nobody cares anymore
okay so you know again it's so we got
into lots of rent now so what is the
next thing we want to do okay so
yeah so okay so now excite HTML pass URL
now look at the naming now I now I'm
back to sticking with the naming choice
of URL not URI okay
idiot idiotic [ __ ]
[ __ ] these you know hackers
you know Java you know Java for example
in browsers the Dom the uh you know
thumb stand for document object model
that's another very complex
incomprehensible [ __ ] created by this
industrial code AS fax with Decades of
war and commercialization you know it's
it's a it's a huge mess okay anyway so
you see
here the term
document object model but this actually
came from the boom boom
browser object model because it's
actually you know this this object URL
is not part of the document HTML is part
of the browser so this
so this the you know they they their
function name is URL okay not UI or you
are n okay
so anyway so
so anyway so back to the emac this code
okay so this is so here's my code now
this is interesting I uh
I was going to explain some of the
details of the code back but I guess we
I ran it for 45 minutes uh much of the
hackers and stuff so
so today is not about
emac this technical details but anyway
it's interesting because
so for example let me show you these
parts
because
so you have a URL like that you have the
query string and you have the
fragmentation you know it's very
interesting because you know the API
design
is interesting that's one part the API
design I'll explain okay so API design
there's no Universal obvious Universal
way that's interesting which way you
want to go okay API design the other
part is the algorithm algorithm is also
quite interesting because you might
think that given a URL
you know let's open that so given you
you are you might think the whole thing
can be done with a regular expression
uh
yeah I think you know you you can do
that but that you know you're gonna have
a regular expression of
of of 20 lines you know it will be
extremely complex
um
and then you might think let's do
incremental passing you know we just
search for the you know different
separators at each step that doesn't
really work as well because for example
if you wanna pass the poor numbers
phone number and the domain name
you can't you cannot search for the
colon
character
because port number sometimes is omitted
so you don't have the colon
character but you do always have the
slash after port number so
if you want to incremental passing you
you know you search for the next slash
then what you get is the domain name and
port number then you know it's one thing
then your code needs to pass this string
to see if there's a port number in it so
okay so that's uh you know some of the
interesting part on the algorithm okay
then you have similar situation you know
about a query stream which can be
omitted and you have the hash
fragmentation which may also be omitted
also the the path the resource path may
also be omitted
so any of these can be augmented so you
have a common combinatorial kind of a
situation
okay so that's that's what um that's why
this is interesting from a algorithm
point of view what algorithm you're
gonna use to do this okay
then the design the API design is also
interesting for example let's say the
the last part the hashtag fragment
now so you have a key you know that
represents the hashtag should the value
include
the hash
uh character should it include it or not
you know I if I were to design it design
it I would say no but actually according
to how they do it
the you know JavaScript they include it
okay so for example you can see
uh you know here is the actual example
yeah so here you can see this is the
actual result so the hash you can see
it's magnify
you can see the hash includes the pound
sign and similarly for the search query
string they include the question mark in
in front Okay things like that but
however for port number they do not
include the colon
so you might say it's inconsistent in in
a sense so that's a that's some of the
interesting things about API design okay
I don't think this is a this is
absolutely the best way in my opinion
the you know you should not include the
hashtag in the
the hash value part and you should not
include the beginning question mark in
the query stream and also there's a
naming of things issue for example they
named the query string as such but
actually it should be named query stream
because that's that's not always search
you know that's the proper name is query
string Okay so
so in
you know we look at the JavaScript
browser URL object as a way to see how
they designed it but this is not the you
know the model you know this is not the
best way
not necessarily and it is not for sure I
know because it you know the browser
also is like hacking after 10 years 10
years you know 10 years basically they
stuck you cannot change it that's just
the way it is okay so but if I were to
redesign rewrite this again you know I
don't think those um you know it will
not be the same and also look at the
HTTP look at the protocol part HTTP they
include the colon at the end
in my opinion a better design should not
include the colon at the end but they do
you know
so that's a that's some of the
interesting part about about the API
design okay
so let's read the question and maybe
that's it okay so I'm I'm rambling isos
today 15 minutes already so we talked
for 45 minutes already uh so let's see
what else I want to cover so we covered
some of the details interesting things
and then
I want to put my code okay so my code to
my website so you guys can use it okay
now this this is part my size HTML
because I HTML mod by the way you have
to buy you have to pay okay pay me if
you like my stuff
pay me
I'll send it to you and it's open source
you can edit it
of course by open source you can that
also means you can sell it okay I sell
at 32 dollars you can sell it ten
dollars rob me that's the nature of Open
Source nothing I can do for 15 years
it's free but I don't get I don't get
the time I you know I get some but I'm
dying of hunger so today so you know not
so now you will pay me to get it
a pretty sad situation okay so anyway so
yeah pay me if you like my stuff okay so
so so it's part of HTML mod but um so I
can you know I can release this code
uh so I can just release this code and
put on my website so that's one thing to
do
uh and next thing next thing is actually
I want to some fix some other command
that requires the passing of HTML okay
let's do them both okay I hope 10 more
minutes okay let's read the questions
comments
the RFC folks have long lost their jobs
from Cisco's and other networking
companies
really I haven't followed exactly you
know the IFC
organization Community but but yeah they
changed you know after you know in the
past 30 years of or was it 40 you know
politics lots of politics and
commercialization they essentially
kind of control like today's Google
Facebook they control how the web Tech
and apple you know they they and you
know they begin the HTML5
which split from the standard w3c huge
argument and for like seven years they
don't this they don't agree so you you
have two HTML standards one is w3c one
is HTML5
mostly they agree but in details they
don't agree each one you know says their
standard is the standard okay
but about three years ago then they
finally they merged okay
so that's uh you know a lot of politics
for example
uh recently I updated so you can read
search for sorry history of web Tech
okay so you can see a lot history here
uh death of HTML friend said evolution
of the script tag okay there's lots of
lots of garbage you know in the past 20
years the JavaScript tag okay
uh you know like back then for example
you know I can talk endless about the
history because I lived through you know
I I I wrote my first HTML in 1996.
so I watched the birth
of HTML
and CSS
you know beginning in the HTML beginning
in 1992 all around a bit before but I
came late so
I watched the birth of HTML CSS
JavaScript
and XML you know actually it's another
big story okay and this this quote the
[ __ ] the most hateful [ __ ] that in
this this quote okay let me talk about
this quote be conservative in what you
send be liberal in what you accept this
this quote represents the [ __ ] in
the Computing industry basically all the
elite holier than thou programmers the
python coders you know they tell you
what to do they think they know better
than you
that this quote represent them this
quote did the damage in the in the
webtech industry for 20 years back in
1990s and up to about 2007. this quote
is ubiquitous everywhere every [ __ ]
hacker they will say they will sometimes
for the in their signature you know be
conservative in what you send be liberal
in what you accept you know for for
about 20 years
then people realized around the year
2000 people realize so that's a mistake
because with that quote every [ __ ]
Unix hacker Unix philosophy Linux
[ __ ] are citing this and they
realize this mistake what is a mistake
what what happens is that then you got
every web HTML they are invalid they are
just [ __ ] syntax soup invalid [ __ ] up
you know like like you know missing tags
uh matched tags everything garbage you
know you have
that because of this quote you should
say it says browsers you should try your
best to accept them so they created the
situation every like like for example
like the
maybe PHP or you know
so they create a situation where on all
the web page created you know uh
embedded HTML and all the commercialized
HTML applications for example
Dreamweaver or Microsoft Word or any
application that generates HTML for
example org mod you know they will
create invalid HTML and in fact strictly
speaking to this day to this [ __ ] day
so anyway this quote okay every [ __ ]
you know this Elite hackers including
many of you today you know I mean the
board is speaking you know you will see
there they're talking about a JavaScript
just how you should do this way or that
with [ __ ]
Okay so
after 20 years people realized
this is incorrect that's when XML
the vision the Utopia the vision of XML
began
okay and then then that that's another
whole story for a decade then the HTML5
suck heads you know this
this icon this this icon represent
everything that's wrong with the web
this is a Malayan gen New Generation
they came up HTML5 rocks [ __ ] them this
is a millennium and zumas they began
this is when they they they they they
overthrew the hacker types oh validation
is not important you see that you see
this icon
w3html 4.0 check mark that's called Web
badge that's ubiquitous on every one of
these emacs Rim Linux Unix types
philosophy [ __ ] webpage you know
proudly and you know this page you know
this html4 valid
these [ __ ] because you you know why
I'm angry because you look at you you
look at you now you look at them you
know the history of things it's just
idiotic City you know they think they
are doing so strict you know they think
they are
uh you know they creates misery in the
end what you have is misery misery okay
with today's JavaScript so bad you know
um situation
okay so so I rambled a lot so um so HTML
history so let me tell you about
um
yeah so this the the
Splinter the
Schism of
of
w3c and HTML5 begin here okay here what
the [ __ ] group
created by predominantly Apple and
Google
around 2006 okay what the [ __ ] group
versus w3c
political war they split because why
Apple you know w3c is the standard these
hacker types A Door obsess about you
know like
like upset obsessed with you know they
but then um
around 2007
these what the [ __ ] group
came up
they created HTML5
why why who who which [ __ ] came up
with that
Opera
Apple then pretty soon joined by Google
of course then Microsoft or the big
biggies okay why are they creating why
what do they want what do they want
because they are unsatisfied with XML
you know this this XML Revolution they
unsatisfied why because
they want money
is talking apple is creating iPhone
you know I I'm going to I'm going to
create iPhone where you can play games
that's what people want no we we don't
want to stick with whatever uh XML you
know extensibility whatever we want to
create our own Tech
that's the origin that's essentially the
basis of HTML5 you know they they want
to they don't want to follow your
standard uh you know it's a
the reason at heart Apple and Google why
is Google and of course Google Google is
trying to overthrow Microsoft Google is
trying to remember this is like 2000s
Google is trying to make the web to be
the thing not operating systems you know
not Microsoft Windows or Microsoft
Google wants the web to be their thing
Google Docs Google you know Maps Google
whatever Google web or everything they
want the browser to be the thing for
everything not operating system Google
sells them Google ads ads ads they want
fancy JavaScript you know that's that's
what that's when
HTML5 grew up begin okay they split they
disagreed
okay so here's a history okay
uh okay you know you know so and here
you can read the FAQ on the issue why do
you guys split which one is actually the
standard HTML specification you know
they disagree so H so the edge you know
the what the [ __ ] group of the Apple
Google and you know let's see your name
what working group okay you know they
explain oh well because
um you know why we split because well
our standard is still the standard you
know they basically then we believe in
something something something okay then
the wvc group says um well actually
those kids in town they are doing no
good because a standard should be
formally
you know uh validated you know
stuff like that
each one is actually just for money okay
money is talking money lots of money is
talking you know money and power
struggle okay but this hacker [ __ ]
[ __ ] those people who tell you
about you know these Unix you know the
sea Unix you know this python you know
this popular help the world people
usually white white boys you know they
pretty wealthy comfortable living well
to do [ __ ] okay
they are telling you what to do over the
past 20 30 years
okay so this this this
talk show turned out into a web history
event okay
okay so so be it
so now I want to Let's quickly now let's
quickly do uh create a page for it for
the site HTML pass okay so let's so now
it's
workflow demonstration time so you
you're gonna watch my workflow okay so
if you are interested in workflow watch
this so right now I want to create a new
page now the question is which directory
do you want to create it so I want to
create it so go here emacs tutorial home
page then go to
um
Psy Max packages Kasai Max commands go
there okay so I want to create a page on
the passing URL function here okay
somewhere so let's open this one okay so
copy that actually copy that go to emacs
block new section paste it link file
make a list okay copy paste okay and go
back to browser copy that actually go
back to browser and actually yeah so
delete so go open that page then go to
the top so you can see the emacs new
empty buffer okay open that copy the
file path close close Okay go here paste
it thinkify make a list okay now I want
make a clone of this page okay let's do
it so this is uh pause URL okay that's
the name of the new file I want
uh p p a r s e okay pass URL uh
and uh okay rename
[Music]
okay so now we want to say emac this
okay and uh
okay and okay that's a new title copy it
now go back here copy it copy the
content close open it create new paste
and call command to update the title do
it and go back here and uh
and delete the content here
okay and update the date
okay and showing browser new empty page
fantastic okay now close that close that
now select select because now this is
the power of PSI HTML mod okay now let's
describe function
uh and uh xhtml pass
uh enter Okay jump to the source code
copy the code
okay so I want to also copy the test
okay copy it close
okay now open the file
make a new emac Beast
code block paste it there show in
browser there it is you know that's a
code now back to emacs
syntax colored showing browser fantastic
so now you can see
you know you can you can get this
function pass URL
in images
for your own use
pay me okay support that's uh that's the
thing okay so now
uh head over now so now we want to so
let's write some introduction so usually
that's uh important because you know
this is part of from uh this this is the
experience of writing a Blog on the web
you know technically speaking
this page is about a function to pass
URL so and here's a code that's all you
need technically speaking but in
practice people usually want some kind
of like introduction
why why are you you know why I mean you
know why are you why do you have this
here you know they want to know what it
is even though it's fully documented
here but you need some kind of
introduction so so let's say here
it is
function that passes URL okay
so that
when people see that it makes it kind of
more
comfortable
from experience okay so there it is so
now you want to add this page a link to
the psy Max command okay do that let's
do that so copy the file path close it
and open this one and show in browser
now where do you want to add the link
okay the commands this is like a emac
disp utility so let's add it at the
bottom for now okay
transpose Matrix so paste it nigraphy
and do it
showing Bowser
go down
there it is Click fantastic okay now
close close okay
wait what did I just close yeah okay so
because now
this is my emacs blog so there's new
entry okay now you need to add it to RSS
okay so let's do that
so
call command
this command is some atom new entry so
the adds entry in my in the ISS okay so
close it show in browser then
what I have to do is just go to the
Powershell
and
sync to my server
and not async
okay then
you'll be there okay I'm gonna do that
later
okay so that's that so what else because
that showing browser talk show
yeah so this is so there's one more
thing
okay should I stop or should I continue
let's continue let's make this complete
we set out to do so so one more thing
here so what is this thing let me show
you okay so what what what are we doing
so here
so for example okay so for example
um
Star Search okay so let me show you
okay
so you go to study dot info and click on
the search so you can search let's say
um
emacs browser okay so you can see there
okay now you copy the URL copy it and go
back here and paste it
so you can see
you know it's got query stream
so this is why we are writing the pass
URL
now we want to open you know remember
this is still local file so that's why
you see the file colon size slash this
is local file so I want to open it so I
have a command
that lets me open any file path
but I
do it
it says file does not exist why because
of the query stream
so you see
so the function we just call this exam
open fire a cruiser okay so we need to
modify uh let's see copy
so open file at closer we need to modify
this command so that when it opens a
file path
it will when it sees question mark it
will remove those
part okay so that's one command this is
another command okay let me show you
another command that I need to modify so
that command is for example if you go to
this page
uh what is this image this view URL in
web browser yeah okay so
what is this
okay so this actually let's let's open
this view page okay so you copy the URL
you see it's already copied okay because
I'm using uh this key I mean this key
that basically that's Ctrl L control C
okay copy the URL now I want to open
that file by that you know by what I
just copied so one way to do it is paste
the file path then call the command open
file a cruiser to open it
but that's too many steps so I have
another key another command that simply
just open whatever is on the clipboard
so that you know if you watch the ping
ping window you'll see I'm gonna call it
now so
okay so you see it's opened and the
command is open file from clipboard so
the clipboard contains the file path you
just open whatever there you don't have
to you don't have to paste paste it
first then open it okay
so these so this command uh
this command also needs to be updated
because it will stuck if you have a
crash query string okay let's fix them
so let's just fix this one quickly okay
so let's uh describe function view the
source code jump to it open it so this
is part of software keys so here's a
function copy it new buffer paste it so
you can see it's 70 lines and let's save
it XX so today's date file name the
function name.el so let's save it as a
temporary
file so there okay so now we just want
to modify these to remove the query
string okay so what we do so we so I
already have a function written for that
so let's go to
describe key
Bam Bam Bam Bam that's the key for
activating site HTML mod okay open that
and now these matching lines uh type for
query string
q-u-e-q-u-e-r-y okay query string so you
can see there is already a function
saw remove URL query stream Okay so
we already have the function so let's we
need to call that copy it because okay
so we need to so before we open it we
need to remove the
okay so let's see where
so here's the input and input input so
what
am I doing good how are you guys
so I guess nobody is watching
we are almost 10 in six people not too
bad eight people
almost then comment and questions and
just say hi in the comments okay love to
see it
don't forget to donate
okay so we want to modify these okay so
modify the file path
so first of all the function doesn't
take anything then I mean there's no
argument okay so the argument all came
from
internally so input
so if there's a region
yeah so if there's a region grab the
region otherwise you know go to the
space and grab the line whatever okay so
now you have input two so input two
oh it brings the hook uh complicated so
input two so the easiest actually
is actually to do this okay so the
easiest is set
input two
you know we modify the input 2 by
by just doing that okay so let's uh
let's make it look better so that's the
easiest way
but I don't want to do that usually
because when you do this that means you
are mutating the variable
okay I am a functional programming
uh
Advocate you know I like function
program means programming so I don't
usually I don't want to do this but
but emac this is not a complete pure
functional programming language and this
way of mutating variable value is very
common okay so let's just let it be okay
this so now evaluate the buffer so we
okay now we go back to the link to the
file let's try to open that okay
so
um so if you look at the pink window so
I press the key bam bam bam it opens it
okay showing browser it opens correctly
you see the command I just scored is so
open file a cruiser remember it didn't
work before because it didn't work
before because you know you got this
question mark something query string now
it works okay try it again so put a
cruiser on the path and press the key it
opens the file okay so that's it for
today thank you guys for watching reopen
so that's it
Jaya is there a good intro course
game for better understanding regular
expression I came late to the stream
could explain some of the code please
okay that's it for today so you have to
watch the whole
today is lots of rent so that's it for
today
um
so uh so you are asking for a good
tutorial on regular expression okay so I
explained this a few times for example I
have
let me explain that what I have about
100 pages on regular expression in
different languages in JavaScript in
Wolfram language okay complete
uh actually you know so
I have tutorials on regular expression
in Wolfram language in closure in emac
with usually 10 pages for each language
usually so emac this regular expression
then you have Golan regular expression
you have JavaScript regular expression
lots of regular expression functions and
flags and syntax JavaScript you have
like 30 pages then you have per regular
expression you have python you know
python also 40 30 pages okay so regular
expression
ubiquitous your regulation is most
useful why do you need so many
documentation because for each language
you have regular expression functions
okay each programming language they
approach it differently so in JavaScript
you have
JavaScript is the most complex you have
regular expression objects then you have
methods then you have stream functions
methods that also do very good
expression you know fairly complex in
Python so anyway the point is like for
regular version expression you have you
need a lot of tutorials because first of
all you have a bunch of functions that
do regular Expressions some just return
true or false whether it matches or not
some finds the third first result okay
it doesn't change every it just find the
it Returns the index of the first
occurrence okay now some other function
you want to find all occurrences in a
stream so it returns a list or two power
or whatever okay all currencies now
another function you want to return not
occurrences but the captured groups okay
so you may capture one part of the
regular equation capture the date
another part captured you know a
person's age for example so it you want
to capture the group so it returns a
list of the groups you capture so
the point here is that you have many
different functions for the regular
expression okay
required for every language and these
functions some of them are maybe methods
you know depending on language you know
some of them are just part of part of
the syntax of the language for example
in Pearl you don't need to load a
library and you and and often it's not a
function it's just it's just the syntax
okay there's no function that to regular
expression is just part of the syntax
okay so anyway
you have different necessarily different
type of functions on radio expression
and for each language depending on
language some some of them is Joy or
just functions such as Wolfram language
okay some of them is like objects and
methods such as such as JavaScript some
of them is just pure syntax of the
language Pearl some of them python is
against object object okay
so that's regular expression functions
and language details about those
functions then you have regular
expression syntax okay regular
expression syntax which is one of the
most
complicated [ __ ] okay regular expression
syntax
okay so now you are looking at a
JavaScript and by the way they are not
universally same okay each language they
differ slightly different okay in
particular emac this regular expression
emac this for example I have you know 10
pages about regular expression
okay and also e in emacs the regular
expression is very different
um very different from the others also
the way it works is also very different
because in most other languages in all
other languages python Ruby JavaScript
rufan language when you do regular
expression you
are searching or matching a string okay
the string may be a long stream
in all these languages but in emacs
that's not the case when you are doing
regular expression you are actually
searching the buffer buffer is not a
string okay perfect is actually just
it's a different data type data
structure it's kind of like a glorified
string but it's not a string string is a
different thing in like this okay
you know string it are typically is
smaller but the buffer can be a thousand
megabytes
so in emacs you you when you call a
regular expression function for example
um you know here is the emac based on
regular expression functions you have
uh weight so here emac this okay so you
have research forward then you have
research backward this this is strange
because in all the languages you don't
have the backward thing only in emacs
you have to be regular expression search
backward you know so that why because
you are doing you are dealing with a
buffer so you have much much more
flexibility okay then you also have kind
of skip chart forward then you have a
version for just for regular expression
matching a string okay so then in emacs
here is how you deal with captured
groups or currencies and you know so
anyway
so back to regular expression so it's a
regular expression so we kind of covered
why is it complex okay it's not trivial
you know when I started to learn it in
about 1997 okay 1997 about 20 years ago
that's my first I started to learn
fairly complex you take I would say it
took me five more than five years to
eventually
get it get you know in lots of esoteric
details for example backtracking and
also the history of regular expression
as a that's another story history of
regular expression
because originally they came from the
study of automata they they came from
trying to find
the answer to the question of what
things are computable what things are
not computable I mean is it is it
possible something that can never be
computed okay that's that's theoretical
computer science that's where regular
expression came from regular you know in
fact it's not regular it's regular in
the sense of of certain
you know passing grammar okay that's our
engine that's a historical origin of
regular expression
which came from
passing uh you know passing a particular
type of programming language and the
context is basically about logic it's
about
when something can be answered you know
by computation okay so that's he's he's
that's the historical context of regular
expression but that's not
we know it for vast you know everyone
every programmer when they think of
regular experience they begin in Unix
okay in in 1980s when they think of
regular expression it's just a tool it's
a tool to match text to find emails or
dates you know to extract things from
string okay that so that is a practical
side of regular expression that's what
we know it for that's what we use it for
it's not about formal languages automata
about regular grammar you know it's not
about what is possible to compute that
that's that's the historical background
of regular expression Okay so
so in summary what I'm trying to say is
a regular expression is fairly complex
in many aspects that's why so it's not
easy to learn so it's normal if you feel
that you know oh my God regular
expression why is this complex it's
natural okay that's just how things are
okay that's it I talked for so long uh
so bye guys
yeah we finished you know we finished
all we completed what we want to do
today so so
today is full rant on the history of you
know web dev lots of history and mainly
about passing URL and these related
things in context
and lastly some talk
about regular expression okay bye guys