good morning good morning guys welcome
to another episode of star talk show
today is 2000
21st
2021 november 22nd
so today we are going to do
i'm not sure you know
today we are going to do a walk-in
session okay i'm just going to work on
my website and whatever i'm going to
basically coding okay lots of coding and
meanwhile i tried to
tell you
uh interesting things about emac lisp
about emacs images powershell from
language or javascript
so i love to see your comments if you
are here comments okay and tell me what
uh subject
matter you know related to what i'm
doing you know ask any questions or uh
such a thing
hello immortality okay let's begin so uh
so there are some of the things i want i
need to do so
why don't we do a uh emax workflow demo
first okay because there's something i
need to do okay let me show you so here
you are looking at my emacs screen
of course and on the pink window is all
my command cores and keystrokes for
example if i move cursor up and down or
eleven right by by word or by character
or i jump by paragraph you can see all
the command cores above on the pink
window for example i can delete these
several paragraphs and undo undo undo
you can see
the
let's turn on global high line you can
see
the command line i called the command
name i called and the keystroke so i'm
using
let me show you what i'm using i'm using
soft light keys okay
so uh if you haven't already go use it
fantastic emax key binding system soft
light keys
and there's a kind of intro video very
old i'm gonna i need to redo this this
is probably a year old video
uh stuff like keys okay
that's the key binding
uh efficient keybinding to work with
emacs and i'm using vorack keyboard
layout so you can you go to soft
flykey's website you can click on vorack
layout and it shows you the command
quality they are very clear comic player
comac dh workman and also supports neo
and others
neo uh some of the german layouts neo2
bop
uh and also car parks
layouts okay stuff like keys fantastic
it's on github
uh okay so emacs so first of all let's
go to to do so
i just call the command so yeah let me
so
again i'm going to do working on my
website and meanwhile i'm going to
explain
hope you hopefully giving you some tips
about
uh efficiency of using emacs and
and also my you know my packages so
first of all open the to-do file so this
is the file start to do on my website
you can see the url there
sorry.info and you
and you know like i have tons of to-do's
you know
uh
like go down go down you know the things
on my website you know 6 000 articles i
have to fix maintain and stuff so one of
the to do is you can so first of all let
me show you one of them for example this
one
this one is one of my website you can
see the ui out there and i want i need
to replace this
bitmap image by a interactive javascript
so
you know one of these days i'm gonna do
a youtube
talk show and uh you know live coding
this application javascript of two
letter diagrams in english
so replacing that bitmap so that's one
of the to do for example and several
others so
so right now what i'm going to do is
show you some workflow so i have for
example you can see
let's magnify okay you can see some of
the words are underlined with the red
uh
underline
so you can see you can let's see where
is you can see underline with red line
here
here okay now go back to the page search
for to do
and you can see that underline is caused
by let me let me just go to the top let
me show you a new one
so i type to do space and it
automatically become span
class to do
and i i give a date then something
something i need to do okay now show in
browser
you can see
we just added that and that is red
because of the class to do
so why do i so let me show you the css
okay so split the window go go to the
top open the css file search for to do
and you can see this line
is what's causing it to be read you know
underline so this is uh
to do so why do i have that because i
write blogs sometimes i write blogs
and uh it's not complete so i add these
you know i just i just type to do then
usually
oops
yeah let's do it again to do
usually
add a date
and
some notes
so and they are underlined in red so i
can
make them visually standing out so i can
see oh this is to do
but now
i have moved lots of these to do
you know in random places of my blog
into
into this one file so collect them
together
so since they are all here i no longer
needs i no longer needs the to do tag so
where is it so let's go back here so you
see
we i don't need the to-do tag anymore so
i want to remove them so how do i do
i just press a key so
do it you see
now let's do it on this one if you look
at the pink window you can see that
command is html tv tag pair it will
delete the whatever is a tag pair that
is under the cruiser position so my
cursor can be here do it you see undo or
i can my cursor can be at the at the end
of the tag do it you see undo or my
cursor can be in the middle do it undo
so let's demonstrate for example right
now
here is the image tag open it that's
this um
diagram image close it shrink the window
so i open it
enter to open it close it so if i want
to remove for example this figure
caption you see this
okay let's press the key to highlight
them you see figure caption tag
so that's what this
uh that's what this is a kind of
annotation for the image so if i don't
want this figure caption tag i can just
press a key you see
again they deleted it then i can press
that then go back to browser reload you
don't see that anymore so you see so
that is the so undo undo undo so
that command is the
uh
html dd tag pair okay
so if you like my uh html mod you can
buy it
so describe let's let's let's go to the
source code of html mod and this is one
of the most efficient way to jump to any
uh emac list package file location okay
so what you do is you call describe
function
i mean this you call meta x describe key
which is
ctrl h
uh k
then you press the key that activates
the function so in my case it's
space uh let's try it again describe key
space space m
h h for html mod m for march so space
ship space space
mh
that's the key to invoke some html mod
so i press describe key then press that
key then emac show me this uh
docs string then i can
press tab to jump to the file so
unsplit so we you see i'm right at the
command where the definition is defined
html mod so and you can press a key
direct jump okay this is a very
extremely convenient command press the
key direct jump to go to the directory
of this file is located with the cursor
on the file name you see so you can see
there it is style jump so that jump
by default there's no key in dire jump
so you you want to give it a key
uh if you are using stuff like keys then
it's just space
m okay
okay so this is the file go to the top
and here is and you can see the url open
it
and open it the command is uh again
three keys so
so that command is
open file at cursor
so now showing browser so that's a mod
if you like it buy it okay
thank you
that's open source
okay close it
so close it so i should i just showed
you you know the command to remove tags
so
so let me uh do it again so show in
browser so this is my to-do file
and in this file i want to remove all
those to do's for example here here okay
let's do it
so there so first so let's uh
interactive search okay search
to do okay
skip that skip that skip that skip that
okay this is the part i want because
it's got the class to do so
uh select that search
search backwards so this is the first
occurrence so search it
okay
delete it
search
delete search
next delete yes you see is do you see
what i'm doing okay so actually
um
[Music]
so you see what i'm saying
do you see what i'm doing so
let's make a backup so there is a
command i just made a backup of the
current file
uh by this key on the ping window now i
want to okay i made a backup now i want
to remove all these to do uh tag i don't
want to remove the content just the tag
like that okay but
but i just discovered a problem because
if you remove the tag there's no
containing tag i mean yeah so
when there's no con containing tag it
shows up kind of
like that kind of
uh
squeezed together with other parts so
anyway so
so anyway let's let's continue removing
removing these to do okay so
what i do is
query i mean interactive search then
type a quote
to do quote okay that's what i want to
find okay now enter to exit
exit it okay now try again search
right then i press a key to search the
next item you know by default you'll
search whatever you last searched so i'm
on it
press enter to get out of it
out of the i search mod then
call the command
start delete
tag pair okay because html dvd text okay
done now search again
press arrow for next
enter
to exit i search
then do it okay fantastic
now search again
right arrow for next enter to exit
delete the tag okay
so you see there are so
so that's what we need to do there are a
lot of repetitions now let's
let's do them in a way that's uh
faster okay
so let's do a macro so emax keyboard
macro so what i do is like
show you okay let me show you now watch
the pink window so
i press a key
key marker start macro okay now search
okay quote
to do
quote okay now enter
now
press the key to delete delete the tag
pair then
now
that's it okay that's it for the marker
now i want to end macro so
press the key
so
you got key marker in macro so i got one
marker recorded
now
i want to execute the macro okay we just
record it so
i do at least
you see it's actually done now it's just
you know now you just press three keys
it does the whole thing you see
and
i do this again you see
it happen again
and
i do this again you see the next
occurrence happen again so let me show
you an example so you see
now you can see there is a to do okay
right there is one right here
now let's put the cursor above it now
i'm going to call the marker okay by the
way the macro is the the name of the the
calling the last macro is
let me show you describe key
then press the key
so
the command i'm actually calling is
called last keyboard macro okay
so let me demonstrate so
again
i'm on this line so the next line we
need to delete is this to do right so
i'm above it so i'm just going to call
corelast keyboard macro by a key press
okay
now you you will see that this to do
will be removed okay so do it you see
now i'm gonna do this many times so you
see there's another occurrence now let
me show you another trick okay now i
want to highlight all these to do tags
by a color so what i do
call
highlight phrase okay highlight phrase
then
then just paste it okay to do
okay enter
highlight yellow okay
so now you can see
all these to do's are highlighted as i
scroll down you see
page down page down page down you see uh
you see lots of to-do's now let's go
back to top let's go back to
uh
let's go back to here so i'm gonna call
the keyboard marker okay
class keyboard micro do it
do it
okay that's so i just keep pressing that
and that will remove all these to do's
so that's a power of emacs keyboard
macro but it's actually a more
one level up
efficiency improvement okay let me show
you
any comments and questions hello alan
hey let me get my pens i need to spin my
pens to soothe my hands hello alan and
friends hello said taga muti
tagi muti
immortality great names you guys have
uh huang hero
okay
so today's
uh
working on
website
uh coding emacs workflow and lots of
other things
so if you have questions you know
related to programming tech
technology you know related to
programming uh
stuff uh
ask me okay
so i'm going to show you another way so
let me
of of improving the keyboard marker
improving efficiency okay so you see i
recorded a keyboard marker like i can
just call it code code code you see undo
and do undo undo okay but i'm gonna even
improve on that okay so what i do so
what i'm going to do is that
every time i call a keyboard marker
called keyboard marker that's three keys
because
i have you know this just anyway it's
three keys okay now i want to make it
what just one key one simple key okay
undo undo so what i do is i call the
emax command
um
let's see what's the command name
describe key
the command name is called repeat okay
simply simply the command name is simply
called repeat
that will repeat
my key press for the keyboard markup
okay so let me show you
so
coalesce keyboard macro done now i'm
gonna call the repeat command by a key
okay
do it you see
now it just did the core last keyboard
marker but now i just press one single
key to repeat the whole thing you see
now watch my for example watch my
keyboard
do it do it do it do it do it
hold down the
key it's done
so now
show in browser
you will see that all these to do red
under underline is gone you will not see
it we did it
and now
we can verify
to check if what we did you know
is it actually true that there's no more
to do tax okay so you what you do is
these matching lines
and by default you can see
in the um
you can see in the mini buffer by
default your search for the to do spam
tag okay just do it
then you say search one buffer no match
no match is found okay so
we have just
finished the task
buy
a keyboard marker and buy a repeat
command so okay so
go to the talk show page let's write
down what we did
okay so show in browser that's today's
talk show
delete this stream information
and let's say
and to do okay i mean keyboard marker
okay let me show you so
okay let's write down emax work
flow
efficiency
tip this is what we have just
demonstrated
so the first command is
that command keyboard microsoft macro
then
then we have this command
keyboard marco and markup then i
demonstrated
this command
core last keyboard macro okay so you
just call that and you repeat your
marker then we demonstrated
the repeat command itself okay
now look i press a key so okay so hold
on a second so
um
let's make a paragraph okay show in
browser
so you can see emacs workflow efficiency
tip tip
or this emacs command now i want to make
them syntax color because these are emax
func commands okay press the key
they become the code tag
go to the browser refresh you see we
demonstrated those and
now go to now in so i actually have a
emacs tutorial on keyboard marker so you
can read about it kind of a summary of
today's like
tips okay so
press a key to open bookmark
by keystroke so it asks me open bookmark
i just type
emacs
okay in fact actually i just type eb
okay so that opens my emacs blog
showing browser there it is now you go
to
practical emacs tutorial
then down somewhere here on the left
panel there is a e max marker okay so
where is it too many so just search in
browser
okay keyboard marker emax efficiency
keyboard click on that
so here is a
tutorial on keyboard marker which we
just demonstrated copy the url back to
emacs
close that paste it here
so that's a
that's a
path of url you see this is very
annoying file
colon slash slash slash and on windows
then you have c colon then slash
this is actually very annoying painful
because
depending on browser some browser when
you when you open a local file
it
requires you i mean
it requires you to have this file colon
slash slash slash
because
that part is actually part of the url
specification
so without that without the file colon
slash
this file path is not considered a url
you know which originally stands for
universal resource
locator
anyway so that's a kind of
some
in tech detail about
web technology so anyway
so i got this
path make a link so now it becomes a
relative link and also a list showing
browser so you got
a link to
this tutorial
about emacs keyboard marker so i tell
you all about it how to do and in fact
there are
you know there are a total of six also
articles on keyboard macro
so you can see a variety of actual real
world examples of using keyboard macro
to speed up your work
okay let's keep on macro now what about
repeat did i talk about repeat the
command
maybe not here completion hippie expand
uh repeat last prompt command okay so
there is
yeah so i explained the repeat here okay
let's copy it
let's
paste it here
make a link and list
combine the last two links
showing browser there it is okay that
completes one thing let's go back to to
do
that completes one thing of what i need
to do on my website
so
now let's see what you guys are saying
you guys are saying nothing
so i'm going to do the next task
let's see
so i've been talking for
30 minutes so i'm going to go uh do the
next task okay uh in fact actually
so this is start to
let's see let's actually go to talk show
notes
so if you guys see anything here let me
know what you want to do next i'm going
to do so today we just finished doing
that emacs workflow delete the to-do
text so let's move it
so this is my talk show topic notes so
let's open that
yeah so uh
to do
so there is it is
that line
delete it
and
go to today's talk show paste it there
okay now remove the li tag
and make it a whole list okay showing
browser
that's the main topic i mean that's the
first thing we did okay
now
what's next so
go back to the notes show in browser
yeah topic notes
no
no questions no answers no comments
so i'm going to do a next thing let's
see
question huang do you like to read 4chan
reddit or hacker news no i don't like to
read them and i almost never read them
4chan okay let me tell you okay so
what should i say uh you know they they
i don't read them
i think i think they rot
they wrought your brain
now this is coming from my you know 30
years experience as an adult now i'm 50
something in my early 50s so as a
nerd as a tech geeker as a programmer
you know in an industry
you know i'm not you know well yeah as a
programmer in the industry for 30 years
just like you guys like many of you guys
i read you know all the discussions
online you know even before you know
before the web there's um there's of
course this irc
there is uh news groups you know you you
younger people probably don't know what
the is news group but anyway so
this
let me give you a history okay a kind of
a
summary of the online discussion
technology in the past 30 years starting
from 1990s okay
so there's news groups
1990 1980 new this okay i'm just gonna
you know i'm not gonna be like formal
and whatever
you know
so anyway so there's news groups
uh there is then then there is a
compuserve
compuserve okay you you don't know what
is compu serve
okay basically it's a online service
okay back then this is even before the
internet before the you know before web
pages there's no web pages back then so
there's a compuserve where you
you buy a modem you you connect the
modem to your phone your you know your
not your cell phone cell phone wasn't
invented until 15 years later you
connect it to your you know uh
line
it's called lan land line you know from
you know
kind of hook them up more than
[Music]
okay let me
show you some of the history okay you
yeah so i'm getting old so
i can talk about history some history
so you go to okay talk show topics okay
you go to
but rather today i want to finish some
of the you know i want to do
work on my website not talking random
crap
you know when doing a talk show
like right now you know it's very fun
and usually people like it when i
started to talk like rent when i started
to get into a rant on unix and people
like it because it's dramatic or some
other kind of thing or on politics
because it doesn't require brand you
just enjoy the show you know
it's showtime america
but
all things considered just like reading
4chan reddit hacker news they provide
entertainment for a while but there's no
substance okay they don't they don't
they don't you know there's no substance
they don't last
so but anyway we digress so let me show
you some of the um
where is it
technology in the past 30 years okay
yeah since we talking about modem let me
just mention that
technology past and future let me show
you guys one thing okay
so these are you know my commentaries on
the technologies i've used and or love
you know this is my heartbeat watch i
bought in
1987 around there 250 dollars before you
before you guys whatever you know hobby
phone today so i bought this you know
uh
30 years ago 35 years ago so in my first
graphing calculator also my first
programming language hp 28
chess chinese chess abacus siri
you know
cortana
okay google you know this ai technology
okay anyway i want to show you yeah the
sound of obsolete technology so you know
you know so that you are seeing this is
this is a modem so in 1990s
you know this is a
14.4
kilobits modem
every every two years there's a new
modem modem coming out faster you know
so anyway i bought you know every two or
three years i bought the i bought the
latest one because you in order to
connect to the
you would you don't even call it
internet you know like i said compuserve
did i finish talking about that yeah
computer you know it's a service that
provides a good gateway to internet as
well as to the computer online servers
so besides computer there's also prodigy
and american online now the last one
probably a lot of you heard of or if you
haven't asked your dad you know as your
parents they probably have
you know these are online services
around 19 1900s you know so
okay let me finish one thing at the time
so and then we're gonna go back to look
at that um
that modem okay let me show you this
modem okay this is how it sounds like
you dial up
then you hear this sound
[Music]
okay now you are connected so that's
what this every time you connect to
internet that's what happens
okay so that's modem so
we're talking about modem you know so
i'm giving you a outline of the
technology of communication okay
especially online online uh
online discussion okay so
so there's irc there's the news group
okay you don't know what is the news
school but i'm not going to show it
anyway then this computer these services
prodigy aol online like you got mail you
know this this is also funny
you've got
mail
okay nokia is also a classic
uh then where's the okay windows boot up
sound okay
you've got mail okay that's the aol what
very popular because they spam every uh
mail
yeah so um
so you know all technology so
irc news groups aol
you know compuserve then you have then
you started to have web you know like
world wide web and the term is
cyberspace okay worldwide web considered
considered a cyberspace today you don't
you know nobody's called cyberspace it's
just the web okay but back then it was
the cyber space and all these links they
are called hyperlink okay not just link
it's a called hyperlink it's a new
technology
hyperlink
cyberspace hyperlink then you have then
okay so web began then you started you
started to have
mailing lists okay mailing list i don't
know if you guys know
email okay before all these you know use
you have email somewhere before so then
you have mailing list which is like
email but you
but a group of people altogether using
these
you know this this central servers where
you send email to it and all the people
subscribe to the mail will see it
then they can reply so it kind of
serves us a online forum
via email
so that's called mailing list okay so
so if you search for it there is a
wikipedia i'm pretty sure articles on it
yeah you know i think python
still have a mailing list
okay there it is mainly this wikipedia
okay that describes the history and and
so on then you have faq automatic you
know faq faq is popular since the news
groups news group days in the 1980s very
faq
is basically a collection compendium of
all the questions people you know of
certain topic
for example computer programming
how to play a piano how to buy a piano
how to buy a house what about
adult videos you know
adult entertainment industry what they
do how do you become an actor you know
how they how much they get paid uh list
of the phone stars that's all part of
the faq
you know how to do
uh how to do computational geometry how
to program in c language you know all
the frequently the most frequently
asked questions about c programming
language you know people want to know
you know how to
you know
so
those faqr compendium
or
compilation of all the past discussion
and experiences and their answers so
they are faq for all sort of
subjects for thousands of subjects on
news groups so piano playing poem
programming c language computational
geometry you know like also all sorts of
things mathematics um dynamical systems
you know lots of and many are uh very um
specialized in math or programming
especially those because most people go
online back then news groups they are
nerds you know
so you have faq so faq back then is kind
of analogous to today's wikipedia so
when you have a question something you
go to the faq of that subject you know
because all the people have
asked ask the questions and people
collect them you know
and format them into a nice uh
article
so faq
okay then you have new script then you
then you started to have the web then
you have the mailing list then you
started
started to have faq automatic what that
means is that
it's a perl script
placed on a website a web server
that
that allows you people to create faq in
a somewhat automatic way
you know because before
you know remember before it was mailing
list
and news groups
where
you know just like today's discord for
example we have the discord you know
today you are familiar with discord
right you go there a bunch of people you
are a regular there after a year or two
you have seen many
same questions popping up and the answer
so you start to compile them you know it
takes takes a lot of time you know you
are the
you start to you know collect all the
questions same questions and their
answers so people
can just read them you know without
asking again and again you know like
every three every few weeks
every
every few months we have a question
about
tienem the tank man of china every every
every month so that's a frequently asked
question so i have to compile and i have
to
you know give the answer
so um
so many so
so it's it's very tedious to create
those faqs so someone started to write a
perl script called faq omatic i'm not
sure if you we can still search find it
faq
or matic okay let's try to find kind of
old history
there it is faq automatic so this is
around
1997. okay there it is faq automatic
download sourceforge search sourceforge
is one of the earliest like today's
github you know like
like the
centralized collection of
open source software for sourceforge is
the very first around year 2000
okay so every qmatic began
which is a perl script that
that is placed on a server a website
that allows any people to just go there
and edit their red right there you know
without
one single
editor who works on you know maybe emacs
or or vi you know
do it
so you so every now everyone can just go
to this website faq automatic about
let's say about keyboard
then everyone can just edit it
okay so faq omatic is the father of wiki
okay now i'm telling you a history
this is a history okay
faq automatic is the forerunner of the
wiki concept like wikipedia
you know today we have wikipedia you see
you can anyone can go and edit it where
does it come from
it began
with the idea of
you know with the faq automatic
so
so then okay so then you have wikipedia
then
wikipedia began around year 2002 okay
before wikipedia so you have faq matic
then you also started to have instant
messages
so is instant messaging okay let's go to
wikipedia let's see what they say let's
see today today show yahoo
uh there it is so this is pidgin
you know they scum pg is a linux version
but that's not
shouldn't be here they should show
because if we are talking about history
of instant messaging the prominent ones
it's not pidgin pitching is just the you
know that's just the the push for open
source by the open source
heads you know they put it here
prominently a picture a buddy list on
pidgin but that's not the
in in terms of history pitching is
nowhere here okay shouldn't be on this
shouldn't have a screenshot prominent
screenshot here
instead you you should have um
you should have aol instant messenger
you know they are mentioned here
somewhere
uh
classic instrument this
computer what do they say did they say
gossip okay
i don't msn okay okay this is again open
source you know this is
you see this is this is propaganda okay
so they show this because it's open
source that you know they should they
are showing these application this this
is a linux you know like
i'm pretty sure it's a linux application
that they communicate to different
instant messengers you know
propaganda okay the real history of
instant messaging not not nothing about
it's not about these linux things okay
that's a
yeah you know you can find it okay so
this irc icq then then then um
then there is uh aol
instant messenger yahoo instant
messenger and uh microsoft instant
messenger okay because they are
they are widely used you know they are
used by almost everyone
you know they mention them somewhere but
i'm not gonna check okay so so you
started to have these instant messengers
then
then you start to have video you know
voice you know real time voice instant
messaging and also video you know that
so this is year
year 2000 you have to buy
you know webcam not like well today's
webcam you know
20 years technology but but back then
you also have webcam which is
pretty lousy compared to today of course
and you know lots of interruptions you
know the
you also require uh you know internet
bandwidth right
so instant instant messaging then you
started to have wikipedia then facebook
came up facebook is also a revolutionary
okay
even i think the mark zuckerberg is a
scum human animal is one of the biggest
scum of human animal it's a
you know i don't think he's a good
person he's a bad person
but facebook did
actually despite you know
mark zuckerberg being a scum
it has it actually did revolutionize
internet because for for this aspect
what is the aspect it is the first
revolution in internet where people
started to show their actual face okay
facebook
you know due to sub due to reasons
because facebook was a you know the
college you know in the elite college
dome which mark zuckerberg is one of the
scum you know they are rich you know
they want to show girls you know college
girls you know which one is more
you know compared to two girls
you know click which one is more
things like that or compared to
a cup things like that that's a origin
of facebook mark zuckerberg
but anyway facebook then it grew up it
grew it grew and grew it was back then
in harvard i think and it grew to other
colleges you know because zuckerberg so
he's
you know
he's a he's a scum but however he's a uh
entrepreneur that is true okay so he he
he pushed the idea to all the colleges
then he expanded to outside colleges so
it becomes a kind of widely used
uh website facebook and because of the
name facebook because the ranger is in
college you know you have the college
you know yearbook with faces so that's
how it's facebook
so
and
facebook is the
kind of the the the milestone
of internet because it is the one
that people started to actually show
their face online because before that
never okay
because of these hacker idiots they they
have a tendency they want to re
remain anonymous so facebook made the
actual
milestone revolutionary change one of
okay all these others are before it you
know so one of the revolution change
that is
people started to show actual face
online and
also
the people who use online who go online
who uses web is no longer just the
handful of nuts you know you started to
have actual
people like your mom you know
like your mom back in back then you know
they started to use
uh internet
so you have facebook
then the rest like i guess you know then
you have twitter and you have google you
have google google tried several you
know they then you have the social
justice
yeah
then the rest you know
okay so that's some of the history of uh
internet i digressed far
uh okay so what else
mono man says
so
a question about whether i'm going to
create a course on
udemy
i don't think so
because
you know so
yeah so create a course on udemy
no i'm not gonna do it udemy you know
udemy is one of those
startups shall we say you know they they
care about nothing except money they do
whatever
they can to maximize
the money they make just like just like
google twitter and so much others you
know and there are several of them udemy
you know for online course
they do whatever they can they they all
and they say nice things you know oh we
provided this service to help humanity
or whatever
but
the bottom line is they they don't care
about anything else they only care the
only
the yeah it's true to say the only thing
they care
is to make money from themselves
and as a consequence of that fact they
become corrupt in many
their decisions their choices their you
create account and then something
happened you know
every decision is
is based on you know making more money
for themselves just like twitter
facebook and all that
so they be they i don't know about udemy
itself i've heard you know controversies
lots of uh but i don't
so
i'm not going to use it because usually
you get okay
well it depends on you know you know
like
not for me because
if you are average person you know
let's say if you are average person then
you know about programming certain topic
of programming yeah sure you're gonna
create a video you know you see oh this
udemy so oh yeah i can make money with
it so you're gonna
create a nice tutorial you know lesson
one lesson two and uh
and go read udemy's rules or whatever
then you can publish there then you'll
make money and they will also make money
you know they take some percentage if
you are a normal person that's what you
do
and for a normal person you
only have one goal too
you have one and one single goal to make
money that's vast majority of whoever
doing things like udemy
you have one single goal you don't you
don't care about philosophy or what
history of internet you know all you
care is oh i know this programming
language i want to make money oh this
udemy i'm gonna make it nice and nice
you know no swearing and everything and
put it there so i can make money and
udemy can make money that's what you
that's what you want
for if you are the kind of average
people
that's not for me okay because it
doesn't work doesn't work you know even
if i need it it doesn't just
doesn't it it doesn't fit me it doesn't
work out
because
first of all i don't have a you know i'm
i'm i'm not you know i'm not
that type of person so
when i do videos you know tutorial i
don't
focus on you know one
nice
focus lesson like lesson one two three
four you know whatever
you know and you know i'm not into that
that you know at heart
so it doesn't work out
you know for me
then you have to follow the rules
whatever you know
then then they put up you know then they
put up you know uh
um
code of conduct you know that's
very offensive to me that is contrary to
my ethical principles i think only scum
do that so if one day you i don't know
they probably already did code of
conduct you know blah blah blah blah
blah blah
i i disagree that's offensive to me
that's a i believe that's a skunk you
know people on earth
you know they want to control they want
to
do things you know bad things
so
that's not for me
okay deus voice you seem quite hostile
to open source can you go over why or do
you have an article on that
i have 10 000 articles on that seriously
well maybe well not 10 000 but i have
like over 10 20 articles on that and in
the past two years i've talked about
that in depth
so many times you know this is
this is the faq this is a repeating
occurrence you know
like i can for example i can spend the
next hour to address your question i can
give my
i can try to give a coherent
uh criticism of open source why i'm not
why i'm not
into it why i think it's
evil you know i can do that but then by
tomorrow there's there's 10 000 people
gonna ask me the same thing because
that's exactly what i did you know in
the past two years so many videos giving
you a detailed account why open source
is so harmful
but that's the thing that's the thing
about code and propaganda
you know it's not just because you know
you actually put up a answer then people
are going to read it no propaganda is
that the way propaganda works is that
they
quote in propaganda is that they spread
to the massive number of people you know
it's like this
okay so that's my that's digression okay
now whether you believe in open source
whether you believe in what i say
whether you
believe i have my reasons against open
source if if you actually read it
it's good or not it's up to you okay so
but you know so in my opinion open
source is
it's not a bad idea but it turned out to
be super you know it's it's it became
extremely evil
perhaps analogous to communism the idea
of communism okay
now that's getting very complex uh
subject
okay that's it that's it for today maybe
i think um
okay so how long have i been talking uh
almost an hour so it's 10 more minutes
let's shut down okay
i wanted to
yeah maybe we can go back to some
technical stuff i wanted to do some of
these
but maybe that's it for today
refresh
so i need to redo site map and i'm going
to give a tutorial
and i need to write this emacs command
those are short and clean emacs commands
i can talk and do it live
and you can learn some emac bisp
and
yeah so one of the star talk show i'm
gonna talk about a complete tutorial on
the
syntax and operator
aspects of wufam language in comparison
to
lisp for example the lisp
symbolic expression very similar okay so
that's one of one of the days i'm gonna
do and this again i'm gonna rewrite this
live i'm gonna code this live in wufang
language and you can see the whole thing
rotate rotation of it dynamic rotation
this is mathematics this is called
stereographic projection
and
the jargon you want to look up is
raymond sphere and complex analysis you
know have to do with complex numbers and
and if you are into
physics relativity you know you need to
understand all these so i was thinking
so i did this like 20 years ago so i was
thinking 2006 okay i did this 2006 with
wufam language
um
and uh
you know i can you know it's been 15
years so wufam language has improved a
lot in different ways so i can redo this
live and i you know so
what you are seeing here is a
stereographic projection
meaning that you map a plane
whatever figures on a plane onto a
sphere
so that's what you are seeing here
and uh
yeah so i'm gonna do this live coding of
these
uh
yes and okay so that's it for today any
any
any last words
so open source to me it's a code okay of
course many of you are believe it you
know because that's because i'm
you know i'm part of the open source i'm
you know that's why you guys
find me interesting because that's been
i spent my whole life in the open source
community
more specifically unix linux unix linux
perl python apache
bash that's that's the technology i know
why because i that's what because i
don't like
i don't like big corporations such as
microsoft
apple is a different story you know but
apple tends to have extremely uh good
design but anyway i don't like big
corporations so so in many aspects and i
have the same mentality as many of you
or
nerds and hacker
mentality you know against big old
organization have kind of the conspiracy
minded you know looking for
you know
and uh not in mainstream so i like the
unix
you know i share a lot
uh mentality with the unix you know type
of people hacker types
but
the unix technology and open source in
general yes especially open source open
source is uh became a political it's one
of the worst
does the worst harm to computing
industry
so so bad you know i cannot you know
i keep talking about this i'm going to
swear
the most
severest
swear you know possible but um that's it
so so open source yeah so
open source uh and you know i think it's
a code
and uh
uh and uh you know for you guys you know
i cannot
um
change your mind you know usually you
know you you maybe you you might um
think about it but
not likely
okay bye guys
yeah source of conduct you know the
entire you know they changed the name
master you know git you know they
changed lots of things you know we're
starting to talk about that we get into
politics very fast
then google is gonna ban me you know so
why is google gonna ban me you know why
today we are in a situation where we
have to be i have to be very very
careful you know not not to mention
many of the you know like twitter social
justice things you know
if i talk about it
or gender oh my god i i said the
forbidden word you know
what's wrong what's going on i get like
why can't we talk about it if i do
google is gonna ban me you know google
is gonna say oh your your video is not
suitable for
google ads or they're gonna just ban
your account
you know happen so also so many
in to so many uh
people
why are we why do we have that such
situation i would impart blame it to
soap and open source okay you you asked
me why
part of it is very significant okay it's
not it's not separate very significant
part of the reason why this happened is
the open source phoneticism
okay it's a it's it's it's a trend it's
a heavy trend juggernaut you know the
classic word
i don't know if millennial
millennial generation or the zoomers
know know what that word means
juggernaut
it's like so juggernaut means you know
you should you can look up you know it's
like a
strong powerful coat you know that that
you know not
you know like a heavy train you cannot
stop it you know it just
it just run over whatever it creates
creates a wreck that's what i believe
that you know open source is part of it
and part of you know also free software
foundation they are connected
anyway
that's it for today
okay so i'm just gonna copy some and we
shut down in two minutes or so i'm just
gonna
instant messages we talked about
history of
online
communication tech
news
groups irc
instant messages
faq
oh
matt tick
wiki
wiki then you have wikipedia
so before there's faq somewhere
history of online online communication
tech news groups irc faq instance
then
the web
world wide web
cyber space
hyperlink this is around 1995 1994
the instant instant messages faq matic
more or less or in this uh sequence of
of technology wiki wikipedia
facebook
twitter
you know i might forget a few for
example there's myspace okay myspace
is before facebook
okay um
but i'm giving you the general online
facebook twitter then
then you know the rest okay
basically
this so this is up to 2010
show in browser
so what else we talked about close that
instant messaging gene close and faq
matic yeah okay this one this is the
very first one this is original okay
this
faq automatic written in pearl because i
was a great i was a per programmer for
four years working on the doing the dot
com this is the very first
uh faq
matic the father of wiki which is the
father of wikipedia
it it's a you know it's a script written
in perl as a online form that allows
anyone to start to write faq you know
like questions and answers
anyone can edit
and you remember this icon that you know
so this is very classic
so let's
copy that i'm amazed that this is still
here
so who wrote this i forgot who is the
person you know you want to know
you know sometimes it's interesting to
see
have what you know what have people been
doing so you see that link
so
kent.john.net i haven't gotten around to
looking up the virtual host directives
in apache yet so you just have to pick
your destination yourself
this is a now this guy is very old
how old is he
let's say
you know 50 something or 60 you know
you know maybe you know they usually
have a family
they don't you know
though they became managers they become
become the boss of some
big you know companies or whatever
so
this is back in like um
1997 also okay faq matic is a cgi based
system you know cgi if you don't know
cgi is the first technology
that allows you to have
dynamic information dynamic web pages
that you know
instead of static you know just
static web page dynamic web page where
you know so you can interact with it
like you can submit you can change
things you know you can
faq automatic so
so that is this guy okay i guess
uh copy that go here
paste paste his link okay
so actually i don't want to link
because when you have lots of links on
your website
then it became a maintenance hell
now what is this now this this is a
later thing faq automatic.net you know
this is what crap
because that mailing list okay we talked
about many english so yeah we forgot to
write about it instant messages
mailing list
okay
then ops the technologies let's post it
here
aol prodigy okay so there
you know i still have archive of my
compuserve
posts
back in from 1992 to 1994. back in i was
in college you know community college
and i was very into math
so on compuserve i joined you know
there's a math forum you know basically
a group like today's
you know in in disco you call it a
server you know like they have different
terminologies
of each technology you know on irc you
call it a room is called a channel on
instant messages a room is called a room
you know you enter a room you know
uh like a group of subject the topic of
that
discussion you know on instant messages
it's a room
on discord you have servers then each
server each one is called a channel you
know
idiotic it should be just called a room
okay
so uh
compuserve can be served so there is a
you know what what they call it i forgot
the room or whatever basically they have
a group they talk about math so i was
very much into math so i was there
posting a lot asking a lot of questions
and learning a lot of things
i still have archive of my computer
posts 30 years ago
close that repeat last command did we
copy that here yes close that
that's it thank you guys
pay me dominate me okay
html mod
okay
bye