good morning everyone good morning
everyone good morning everyone today we
are going to code wam language
Mathematica this thing animation of a
cycloid curve so you roll a circle with
a DOT on the rim of the circle then you
will Trace out this curve this curve is
called
cycloid uh you can find it by just
search for spal visual dictionary of
spal plan
curves then you scroll down cyclo then
you can see this animation so today we
are going to code this
animation uh let me show you my
keyboards and uh let's have a drink so
this is going to be slow if you are
watching this offline feel free to skip
around if you are watching it not live
so I'm having some drink red wine with P
pineapple juice I mean apple juice
and my keyboards glove
0 keyboard fantastic ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic all these I recommend
this is newly trackable and this is uh
Logitech g502 new 501 m501 I think so
and and again let me show you this this
is the most fan
keyboard called SW board s v a l b o a r
d if you search it you'll find it so I
will be using it so I just want to tell
you again and uh I will be using daily
okay s v a l b o a r d fantastic check
it out search for it okay so that is me
and now let's get to wolam language
coding serious coding okay if you have
questions comments ask okay uh okay
so wam language okay for those of you
new here let me just show you if you
search for EXA wolam Language tutorial
you'll find it the most high level
language than them
all and then you can click on download
this is where you can download the wolam
language engine so you can play with it
or you buy a raspberry pie
it comes bundled with it or just pay
move F and buy it I do recommend it okay
so that's how you download then you have
all these tutorials this tutorial my
tutorial on wfam language is for
programmers so if you are familiar
already with the language python Goan
PHP JavaScript or even c c you know or
you know or has Scout you can learn
programming wolf language
introduction print wolam language
version building help find function
that's
introductory uh sections then you have
how to comment code then you how to
print anything then you start to have
you know data types string how do you do
string and regular expression and then
other things such as number arithmetics
you know add plus
minus number input format and and uh
hexad decimal and arithmetics and then
Bing and if statements and conditional
and loop iteration and function how do
you define a function and so on and data
structure you know so w language I mean
c wolam Language tutorial okay that
we'll get you started down you can now
it's free for like four years okay so
begin coding so uh so let's see today's
talk show and uh what so that you know
so let me so this is what we coding okay
the
cycloid uh this curve is very
interesting
so maybe let me do some explanation
should I or should I directly
um yeah let me let me tell you why this
curve is interesting this curve is a
very famous curve if you search for
cycloid you'll find YouTube or other uh
information all over by in math
Departments of universities you'll find
lots of pages cycloid it's a very famous
uh curve and this curve is meant to
solve a problem so let's uh let's use
the pen to draw so let's see for example
if you have a uh wait uh you cannot draw
here so okay so I need
um wa where is
the yeah okay so you need the Microsoft
screen snip okay so let's let's just uh
snip
that okay so let me draw and show you so
you can
see okay anyway so if you have a line
straight line if you have a ball let's
say a small metal pallet you know a
small marble and if you drop it it'll
run down right so the question a very
famous question around 1800s I think or
was it 1700 so the one of the famous
question is that what kind of Curve will
let this Spore drop from point A to
point B point B is below point a the
fastest so you can have all kind of
Curves you can have this curve or you
can have like very sharp and then slowly
go to point B then or you can you know
you can have this way you know obviously
that way is slower so I mean so the
question is what's what is the curve
that will let a ball drop down purely by
gravity the
fastest okay and the answer turns out to
be a cycloid okay uh the answer turns
out to be a cycloid it's this curve so
this curve can be generated if you just
roll a circle put a dot on the rim of
circle or a wheel like a car or a
bicycle for example on bicycle today you
have lead you you can buy a lead light
Bol on the Ring of the bicycle so when
you write it it you know it kind of
Trace out this it Trace out exactly this
curve okay it's called
cycloid so so once you trace out this
curve then you just invert it so so this
curve you know um where is our drawing
so that you know so that basically looks
like that so that curve if you put a you
know marble on you know from one end to
the end that will that marble will roll
down the fastest okay so it was a famous
problem in 1800s I
think and uh and uh the solution is the
cycloid in fact you can look up
Wikipedia Wikipedia will tell
you uh in fact the the name of the
problem is called the bronstein or
something okay so cyclo by the way wolf
and research math word is not good okay
wolf and research math word is one uh is
not a very good reliable accurate
resource so whenever you want to read
about mathematics Wikipedia is better
okay so you know they showed this to you
know I did this so I did this you know
in
1970 uh
1997 or
96 but today Wikipedia has you know they
also have it so anyway so this so they
show the history you see so if you they
you know they they have an animation
showing different kind of curve which
one is the fastest you know so the this
black one is the cycloid and you can see
it uh arrives to the bottom the fastest
that's a solution so in order to solve
this problem is technically called
calculus of variations so you need to
use a lot calculus to uh in fact it's
Advanced calculus
okay so cycloid okay so that is the
story and uh what's the name name to
this problem let's see uh the cycl has
been called the Helen of geometers as
the Helen of
Troy oh I never heard of that huh
uh so it's called total Chrome or
something the problem so let me find
what is the name to the
problem let's just search for
Chrome yeah okay there it is
brist curve
so it says here the cycloid with the
cusps pointing upward is the curve of
fastest descent under uniform gravity
okay so you can click on that article
and you can see there's a dedicated
article for this problem history Gallos
problem 1638 oh so back to uh
1600 yeah 1696 is a solution more or
less Okay so cycl so today you know so I
have I wrote these packages to generate
those animations so here are here is a
package troid now troid is a special
case of cycloid so let's open it
okay so I was I need to I was going to
update this my uh wam language packages
but I thought it would be better if I
actually
just uh let's
let's
expand order okay so continue with
updated stting so what is troid okay so
let's see what is this oh this is the
troid okay so not this one we talked
about this one uh two weeks ago uh on my
YouTube this is the so-called spiral
graph okay
so you know not not this one okay so we
don't want the trco let's
see uh actually somewhere there let's
see what is this
one control shift left bracket okay so
that will expand
wait okay continue with the current
second uh select all control shift
expand all okay expand all
sales okay this is also not doing what
we want we have I have a cycloid page
okay so
yeah so originally I was going to update
those uh packages but I thought it's
going to be boring for you guys because
it's mostly just me working on those so
why don't I start from scratch and show
you how to generate this animation okay
let's begin let's just start to do
that uh comments and questions ask it
okay okay so we start to code wolam
language
um okay I'm using cly keys I'm using
emac fly keys and Vora keyboard layout
okay uh so this is and currently I'm
using uh s wam mod which allows you to
code wam language
in in emac okay close that we don't need
it okay so let's go
to so let me show you so what we're
going to do now is to show how do you
generate an animation in wolfen language
and then you can export it to varieties
of movie formats you can export it to
GIF and so on give or impa 4 or uh AV a
you know a
something
file so okay so how do you generate a
animation so what you the most fun
fundamentally what you have to do is you
create a graphics you create lots of
Graphics a sequence of Graphics that
forms an animation
okay
so okay so let's just do it okay
Graphics okay let me show you so graph
and uh let's say rectangle
okay
uh let's say yeah okay let's say
rectangle rectangle requires a parameter
that's the one corner of the rectangle
and the other corner of the rectangle
let's say
21 let's see how that works out okay I
think that's it now we have no idea what
are the coordinates so let's put a
coordinate
uh so
AIS
true shift enter okay so now we got the
idea of where the coordinate
lies okay now let's say I want
to create a sequence of this rectangle
go where they gets longer and longer
let's say okay so what we can do is use
a
table so table takes two arguments can
you guys see me yeah okay can you guys
can see it fantastic comments and
questions
okay so a table so first of all you need
so you just do like before you need a
graphics then the second argument is a
list uh not
not that so the second argument is a
list of variables X goes from let's say
one to5 in steps of 0 0.2 okay so now
the second point of the rectangle
instead of 22 one is going to be X and
one okay so this will generate a bunch
of uh Graphics a SE quence of Graphics
shift
enter so you go down so you can
see you know you know each one gets
longer and longer
okay so that's essentially an animation
already and you can export this but
before we export into a movie let's
let's make the plot range fixed so we
can actually see the rectangle changes
changes its
length so again this is the fundamentals
of creating a animation okay you all you
have to do is just generate each frame
then we're going to do this
cycle but you know but this is the
fundamental uh elements of how do you
create an animation in Wan language okay
so now we need to uh fix a plot range
let's say uh plot range I don't I don't
think it's here but let's just try it
here okay so plot range is an option to
the graphics so plot range takes you
know a list of two points so the first
point is 0 to0 and the second point is
let's
say x axis is five and y axis let's say
1.5 okay let's see shift
enter okay that doesn't work it doesn't
work
because because the plot range is not an
option of Graphics so if you understand
what I mean so let me show you copy
that paste it here so ENT let's let's
put it here so you can actually easier
to
understand so you have you know we have
a graphics function
then you know that's the then we are
giving it three
arguments rectangle which is a graphics
primitive you know exactly what you want
to draw and axis true is part of the is
an option for the graphics it tells you
that you know we want axis but plot
range is not you know this plot range is
not option of Graphics so we so that is
why you know you are getting this empty
things so what we need to do is you if
you want a plot range what you have to
do is you can um do
this uh let's
see PL range okay so how do I know well
I know because I've been coding wam
language for like 10 years so you can
find out by
options and uh
wait opt
options Graphics okay then it will tell
you all the options for the function
Graphics this applies to any function
every function okay so you can see plot
range is not here uh oh it
is oh okay so actually we got something
wrong my
mistake so why is it or empty
uh let's
see1 to
1 0 to five oh I think we got the pl
range PL range oh yeah obviously we are
saying so the first element the first
part of PL range is the x axis so it
should
be 0 to five okay then the Y AIS 0 to
two okay that should work do it there it
is you can see see now the you see the
rectangle increases length exactly
that's exactly what we
want so now we essentially got animation
well we got the list of images now we
just do that you know we just so we or
we or you you can do is uh list animate
okay so this function list animate we'll
take a
list of anything it will turn it into an
animation okay so we can just crl L to
copy the previous
input then shift
enter then we got uh fantastic animation
and interactive too let's make it cycle
backward and
forth so that's how you generate an
animation in summary you just create a
list of graphics and uh using the table
function very convenient and feed it to
this anime then if you want to export
this or you um that's very easy to into
a movie let's say let's export into a
gif so you just say
export okay then export you know this
table thing then uh well the first El
the first element of export is a file
name okay so let's give it a file name
the file name will be Test movie okay.
GI so if you have a file name extension
of GIF wam language will figure it out
it will expect that you want this format
to be GIF okay let's do it shift
enter okay it's done now where is it
it's in the documentation documents
folder okay so you go to the documents
folder there okay it is okay let's open
it fantastic a gift animation
fantastic then you can share this on
Twitter on whatever Instagram or
whatever uh Facebook or whatever uh it
also supports it supports lots of
formats like all possible formats
ever so let's uh well what so why don't
we try webp web webp is a new for format
from Google 10 years ago which supports
animation okay so go to the documents
folder there it is open it so it opens
in browser web P
format and you can also save it to MP4
okay so close this oh H we close that we
I don't want to close the whole browser
but anyway so let's do it again this
time MP4 four
okay shift enter to create
it okay MP4 takes a while so there it is
open
it there it
is MP4
movie
fantastic okay so that's the
fundamentals of how do you create an
animation there's lots of other ways too
uh but this is one one of the way
okay so now we just going to create this
all we have to do is just generate a
sequence of these images okay now this
will take some effort let's see I've
been talking for 20 minutes already okay
let's try to do
it uh okay so I'm going to do this in in
uh emac because it's much easier for me
to to code here so let's Okay so
let's generate a sequence of images of a
circle Rolling On A
Line a
point on the rim of
circle traces out a curve called
cycloid this is what we we'll do okay uh
that's a kind
of description okay
so okay so first of all we generate the
circle okay so
circle circle takes a center okay so the
circle takes a center so in each
animation we need to know this how the
circle moves okay so let's say XY and
the radius one okay so that's uh then we
rectangle this part we don't need X is
true uh plot range we need okay so plot
range is going to be let's see the
circle uh the circle of radius one let's
see okay so moving
from okay PL range so the x axis will be
let's say negative 1 to six okay the
height the y y axis will be let's say
negative
0.5
to 1.5 okay the radius going to be one
okay well if the radius is one you need
at least two okay so let's say the
height is 2.5 okay so we have these
Graphics you can
show you know you can show it you'll
show okay so well XY is not defined
right now so you can just say z z
okay uh and uh it's red so red means
something is wrong it's evaluated yeah
so wait why is
it c i r c l e did I spell it wrong
no uh let's see did I if was a parameter
wrong or what c i r c l e c i r c
e so here's a wolam documentation for
Circle why is
it c i r c l e what
what's going on let's see error
messages an improperly formatted option
was encounted oh I forgot the coma you
know you need a com you need a comma
after the circle
obviously okay comma there evaluate it
there it is we got the circle
okay okay so the circle so the XY is a
Center let's see so we got kind of one
frame where we also need to
draw
um so we kind of got the center we also
need to draw a DOT on the circle so okay
so let's a DOT how do you draw a DOT uh
is just a DOT okay and see um yeah you
can actually read the documentation
no no not DOT what is it Point okay so
actually it's a
point point is one of the graphics
primitive it will draw a point so here a
point on a
DOT okay so you know in the beginning
it's
um you know actually we don't know where
it is but okay we'll figure it out so so
the essence you see we already know what
is
the um where is that
got we know how to do this animation I
mean we know how to do
animation in terms of wolam language now
the problem we have at hand right now is
about the mathematics of it that is to
figure out where all the points points
and all the dots are in each frame okay
so you know this this these are just the
the the graphics so the main thing is
about the center of the circle and the
dot okay so the center of the circle is
actually pretty easy so let's
see so we need a parameter let's say t
that moves throughout
okay we need a parameter that moves
throughout then so as the parameter T
changes
the the Circle Center changes and that
dot position also changes so what is
this
uh you know this this is the parameter
okay so actually so this this is a
position of the dot okay
T okay T Min s t and Y is y minus cosine
T that is the position of the dot for
each frame with respect to T
okay
then okay then uh what is the center of
T
um I mean I mean what what is the center
of the circle
uh something simple so but I don't know
yet okay so but anyway let's try to code
this okay so the point is just the point
is that okay then then you need a table
okay
table two parameters okay the second
parameter is the variable the varying
variable so t goes from zero to two Pi I
suppose okay the first argument would be
this block okay so now we
got and uh and the center of the circle
we don't know what it is yet so let's
just say Z zero okay I mean let's just
get something going visually so we can
actually have some kind of progress okay
so okay you got all errors uh
uh t t goes from zero to 2 pi uh yeah
okay yeah obviously this is wrong
because a point just take a X and Y it
doesn't have extra coordinate one there
so you need to remove this
one do it okay more still error so what
is going on
uh let's see what is the
error an improperly formatted oh okay I
know
well so Graphics takes two arguments
right now you have 1 two 3 four so that
is incorrect I mean the first argument
is a graphics so in our case we have two
things one is a circle one is a point
each one is a graphics primitive but the
graphics function allows just one so
when you have more than one you need to
put them in a list okay so a list okay
like
that okay copy it let's do it here
select select select select
paste
and run it
[Music]
fantastic so we kind of see you see the
dots are moving that's a good sign so we
just yeah so zero T goes from 0 to 2 pi
in increment of one that's too big so we
add a steps let's say 0 point uh uh
let's say 0.2
okay evaluated fantastic I think we got
something okay so let's let's put more
steps so we can actually see 0.1
evaluate
it okay it kind of yeah it's going okay
yeah it's kind of is going so we can do
this
again by this animate like before okay
then copy the above
input run
it fantastic you see that dot is tracing
out a cycloid
next we need to figure out where is the
um where is the center of the circle
with respect to the parameter T okay
it's next step almost done so that's
just this this um
thing okay you know the last time I did
this is like 25 years ago so I don't
remember what it so now it's this is the
part you need to think about
trigonometry and
math uh
okay so
the well I mean we can I mean another
way is just like trial and error
so that that will never work out okay so
let's see the x axis let's just say t
for now okay then the the Y
AIS actually that makes sense the Y AIS
will
be uh what okay because the radius is
one okay so let's try that uh 0.1 steps
okay so cut paste and uh let's Lo Let's
Do List
animate just like before okay I mean
just like yeah so copy that go back to
wam language run
it
[Music]
fantastic our guess is correct blind
guess
even you see we got the circle going we
got that dot going so all we have to do
now is you need to have a trace of it
okay
so so stop this stop the is so in order
to have a trace you need not just one
point you need the list of points that's
easy
okay so let's uh whoops whoops uh so
let's
wait yeah so let me make this clear so
this is list of things okay now add a
comma and now you need the list of
points instead of that so so let's just
use table
again table that thing and uh a new
variable let's say x x goes
from yeah you need a list of table oh
yeah very easy so actually uh you should
be just T yeah actually you don't even
need uh
so right now we have some efficiency
considerations I'm doing this right now
in a very inefficient manner because if
we do this table here the computation is
repeated because for each frame you are
Computing the point then you are
Computing the same point you know
there's a repetition so but let's just
get it going so we uh you know
afterwards then we can think about a few
efficiency so so here T follows the same
parameter you know T from 0 to 2 pi in
increment of
0.1 again that's repeated code which is
not good you don't usually so but anyway
let's not worry about efficiency or
Elegance let's just get this animation
done which is one of the advantage of
wol language it allows you to do things
quickly like 10 times faster F than
python uh so you so here you want the
table of points uh that's right
so so actually uh wait so you want the
trace you see the trace of the
dots you don't want all dots at the same
time rather you want you know at each
time in moment you want just the back
you know the history of it
so so you don't want this entire thing I
mean you don't want from zero to 2 pi so
you want from zero to T actually so
let's change a variable here T becomes
x x
x x okay so here x is a variable X from
Z to t t is whatever the current
time so
yeah that actually I think that's it
copy it let's do
it
evaluate
beautiful
fantastic um you
know yeah so and so right now this
animation although
functionally is basically perfect but
you see we are missing in visual
elements
because because you can you know this
animation when you have a wheel rolling
you have you you need some kind of spoke
so that as humans we can visually tell
it's actually
turning
so in that case we create a line you
know we add another Graphics primitive a
line we want to draw a line
from where
from from the center of the circle
to to this this this uh Point
okay so actually a line okay I think
that's it let's just try
it stop this do
it
beautiful okay I think that's it um uh
yeah I can elaborate more and add color
for example this circle let's say
red um wait wait let's say Point let's
make the point red and uh let's make the
this
thing uh Pink okay let's say
pink okay so copy
that you know we start to decorate this
animation so it becomes more and more
beautiful and you know then we can
increase the length so it rolls you know
like this one okay but that's it
beautiful code you know we we don't want
to make it too
much okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching if you enjoy talk show
pay me okay pay me good night hey juang
my loow your Watcher so if you like my
stuff you can okay I need to this part
is Market
part where every YouTube you know takes
a minute to talk uh so I should as well
CU I need money to survive so you go to
cali. info where you arrive at my you
know technical website Kar code. info
then all the way down you'll see patreon
me PayPal and Amazon gift card me okay
use these links
because if you are in Japan or in German
you use Amazon gift card doesn't work it
need needs to be this one USA Amazon USA
or you can PayPal me patreon me you know
50 bucks 100 bucks pay it one shot okay
in you know I prefer instead of $5 a
month you know pay me one shot $50 $100
for a year thank you very much that's it
for
today yeah I think okay so here is
today's code Let's uh put it back syntax
correct showing browser so we have
today's code and the link to my website
so you can learn lots of these wondrous
mathematical
curves especially if you are young
people you know you are studying
engineering physics you know those are
great Fields you know also for you
programmers you
know um uh if you are studying calculus
trigonometry these things are great very
interesting and for programmers you know
programmers usually you know they don't
they don't do this they do you know they
do open GL and gaming you know the bit
map
Graphics extremely
complex uh you know so if you feel like
a change of things you know do visual
programming but instead of the gaming
and things you know you can try to do
this in wfam language or in your
favorite language okay thank you guys
bye why don't you use Linux that's a
trolling question because yesterday we
talked about it and we talked about that
a thousand
times bye guys