hello guys welcome to another episode of
talk show today we are going to do wolam
language at the end of code wolam
language
Mathematica the most advanced
programming language on Earth by far by
a magnitude better than hascar
closure rust C whatever Mathematica and
I would say better than
uh much better than maple and matlb and
so on so wolam language Advent of a code
from scratch I haven't read the problem
yet so it's a live coding hello guys if
you have questions uh say hi I mean I
mean if you have a questions post it
okay so so where am I I okay so you are
see me this is my keyboard glove 0 glove
0 fantastic ultimate hacking keyboard
too fantastic
and you haven't seen this yet SW B data
hand
fantastic that's my keyboard you can
search my YouTube you'll find review and
now let's begin the code let's so today
is pure
coding so let's begin okay so let's see
so uh check video check audio check
fantastic okay focused on coding okay if
you have coding questions you know wam
language so I'm using uh emac Sly keys
on the pink window is all the command
course live in real time and the
keystroke on the left I'm using vak
keyboard and I'm using cly
keys sarly keys okay so let's begin so
event Co Advent code let's read read the
problem so last time we you know Advent
Advent of code 2023 last time we did
finished day seven now let's do day
eight because it's been a while some
people want to see my coding you know
okay let's
read haunted was Wast land day eight
haunted Wasteland you are still riding a
camel across desert island when you spot
a sandstorm quickly approaching when you
turn to war the elf she disappears
before you your eyes to be fail she had
just finished warning you about ghosts
of a few minutes ago a few minutes ago
one of the Cam's purches is labeled
Maps sure enough it's full of documents
your personal input about how to
navigate the desert at least you are
pretty sure that's what they are one of
the document contains a list of Left
Right instructions and the rest of the
documents seems to describe some kind of
of network of labeled knots okay one of
the document is about left and right
instructions left and right
instructions and the rest is about some
kind of network n labeled kns now can
you can you guys read it yeah okay you
can see let's move it to the
right okay so it seems like you are
meant to use the Left Right instructions
to navigate the network okay perhaps if
you have the cam F follow the same
instructions you can escape the
haunted was
Wasteland after examining the maps for a
bit two knots stick out a AA and zzz you
feel like AAA is where you are now and
you have to follow the Left Right
instructions until you reach zzz okay so
you you want to go from a AA to zzz by
following this instruction this format
defines each nod of the network
individual in individually so a network
is like a in math Jon is a graph so a
graph you have vertices those are called
knots
okay the format defines each ND of the
network individually for example okay r
l a equals
to okay
[Music]
so okay so what does this mean a a a BBB
equals to this this okay so each line is
one
definition okay it's not clear what AAA
and BBB are starting with AAA you need
to look up the next element based on the
next Left Right instruction in your
input okay in this example start with
AAA and go
right by choosing the right element of
AAA
CCC okay how does that
follow by choosing the right element of
a AA which is CCC okay seems appears to
be okay so then l means to choose the
left element of CCC ZZ
Z okay by following the Left Right
instructions you read ZZ Z in two
steps okay so it seems it works like
this so each line you have a triplet
kind of so a a equals to BBB and CCC so
each nod on the left is a
not they and their value is a
pair one is called left and the other is
called right okay so a AA equals to you
know BBB and CCC BBB is left CCC is
right okay so you have several of such
lines and you are given the instruction
RL mean which means right and left okay
so you are at AAA so the right of AA is
CCC so you go to CCC then the next step
is left so the left of CCC is zzz then
that's how you arrive okay which is your
destination okay let's think about it so
you are given a left and right you know
a bunch of sequence of left and right
which means take the first element or
take the second element okay then so
given so you are you are you are given a
starting point as suppose the first one
so for each so you start there then
follow the instructions you take one of
the element then you look up where you
arrive uh then then you take the next
instruction right and that will give you
a notd then you look up that nod then
you can do the next instruction and so
on
okay
so of course you might not find zzz
right away if you run out of Left Right
instructions repeat the whole sequence
of instructions as necessary okay write
l r l means
so RL really
means right left right left and repeat
so okay the instruction can
repeat for example here is a situation
that takes six steps to reach Z okay so
left left right so a take the left is BB
okay BB take the left again is AA so we
are back to AA now the next is Right
which is BB so we are arriving at BB
again then then repeat left left right
so BB left is a AA then AA left is
BBB then BBB right is zzz okay so
there's a loop so let's let's absorb
this
information so this instruction you
follow you pick a you pick a element and
you look up the table again
uh and if in the end after you follow
the sequence of instructions if if you
did if the result is not
Z then you repeat the instruction
okay so one of the question is do you
stop when you reach Z even before the
instruction
finishes
probably okay yeah so the question is
starting at a AA follow the left right
instructions how many steps are required
to reach Z okay so during the
instruction each time you follow
instruction you have to increment a
count that's uh what it's asking how
many
steps okay to begin get your personal
input so let's get our personal input
but first of all let's get the toy
input so that so okay so show today's
talk show and today's uh so we're going
to code from language uh first of all
toy
input okay toy input is that uh
wait pre uh not
partial pre input and there's no input
pretext okay so that's your input and uh
we want to start wolam language okay
now now w language okay hold on a second
let me let me go show you so wam
language I already
started
um 3 + 4 you can
see shift enter to run it okay let's
magnify so there is wam language the wam
language notebook and I run it in
emac so let me let me show you guys
the
um wolam language index if you search
for wolam language in depth you'll find
my tutorial that will get you started uh
basically a comprehensive tutorial for
wolam language for
programmers assuming you already know
one language JavaScript Java c c or Ruby
or python or PHP or JavaScript you know
if you know one language programming
language this is suitable for
programmers okay it doesn't teach
mathematics no calculus no derivatives
no integral it's just for
programmers okay and uh you can download
wam Language by go here there's a link
wam download wam engine you so you can
now it's free okay so that's wam
language and what that and I have
actually I made like 50 videos or more
in the past two years okay so you can
watch
them uh and now what we want to do is uh
the what I'm using is I'm coding wam
language in emac so there
is there is uh let me show
you uh
so emac okay so F language video
tutorial where do I say emac search emx
yeah oh yeah there it is see alsoa mod
so there is this Emax
package uh close that oh yeah so uh let
me show you
okay for example uh anyway so anyway you
Goan mod emx you search it you'll find
it on GitHub it's free it's fantastic it
allows you to work uh uh W from language
in emac for example let's do
table okay table X let's
say X and
X
plus one okay run the current
line and you can see there is a
result so running wfam language in emx
okay but now we want to yeah we want to
solve this problem so first of all let's
put the input here so this is
instruction how you deal with it okay so
you can deal it with in two ways let's
see
uh input okay input that and this is a
look at table uh how do you want to
solve this this lookup table you you
want to turn it into a lookup table like
a dictionary hash table and uh so one
way do to do it is just manually edit it
into the wolam
language table
syntax the other way is actually pass it
so usually you need to pass it I mean I
mean you don't have to but because then
you're going to get your personal input
let's look at our personal input okay so
you got hundred of line lines copy all
okay okay let's let's copy it let's
create a new buffer save it so okay so
big instruction save it let's say XX
Advent of code input let's just say that
for now that's
today okay so
this is a v of code input so we got this
input
long so the input is going to just be a
string and this table needs to become a
Association table
okay uh yeah we need to do that so how
do you do that so which way we can
either pass it
or I don't want to pass it let's just
manipulate it edit it it into a wolf
language looks like a tree hello
hello okay am I doing good okay so we
got to do this fast because the Advent
of code is a trap like sometimes you
think you know it easily take two hours
not because of the problem it's just
because the coding in general takes a
lot of time uh okay so you you want to
turn this to Association table okay so
let's in wolam language Association
table is of this syntax
yeah this syntax okay so that's a
example that's a dictionary hash table
and in W language it's called
Association okay so you want to turn
this how do you look up so what you so
the left should be the key to look up
you need to look up hundreds of
times Okay so so basically you need a
function like this okay function oh my
God I haven't coded wam language I mean
I haven't Cod it
um
okay yeah so you need to code a you you
need to code the
function and uh you need to define a
function it will be like this okay look
up so how do
you okay
yeah so let's name this
function look up okay this function will
take two
things it will take two things X and Y A
is a not name Y is a
instruction
okay so takes two argument not an
instruction okay then will return one of
these okay so the lookup table so this
needs so we need to define a lookup
table
okay table okay we need to define a
table and
uh okay so the left is the key the right
is what okay it's just the first element
last element so the right side what data
structure should it be uh it can be just
the list right yeah okay so the way you
do that would be something like this
okay let's do
one um just for the for Just For
example uh and yeah so that would be the
syntax of one item okay easy enough
let's let's do it now
change that and we want to change
all parenthesis to curly
brais change parent now this is the
power of emx change
par change bracket pairs
okay change parent from parent
to uh to
trly what's the
name braces okay the American name
Braes there it is okay
then oh then
we add a comma to the end of each line
okay then yeah
so yeah
asso Association
that and uh that I think that's
it
okay double check if there's error so
there's no no no error so now there's
another question is
that so the input needs to be string or
symbol okay let the input be a string
because string is a universal format in
every language if you use symbols such
as in WF language or in
lisp then you have to deal with I mean
you have to it's it's um it's not
Universal I mean it may be um yeah
usually it's better if you just deal
with strings okay so let's so all this
needs to be strings okay let's show the
power of emac let's use a keyboard
markall so start recording move to the
right call a special command move to the
right move to the left do it again right
left do it again stop recording now
apply the last recording to all these
lines
fantastic okay this is a Association
now this is look up table
okay now we need to write this function
so now with that it's be very easy
so so now the not and instruction so
so so okay so we need to look up the
association how do you look up the
association so let's go
to wam Language tutorial in depth so
there is a data structure section
Association list there it is the create
Association length and the association
get value so what we can do it that way
let's do look up I prefer functional
approach so you can so that's the uh
that's the
parameters okay look up look up
Association name and key
so Association name is table and key is
not okay and uh what it if what does it
return look up key value so if key is
missing it returns that is it possible
for the key to be missing uh should not
you know again the advant of code never
specifies anything clearly so you don't
know you know it's a it's a trick like
when you actually run your input then
then there's a key doesn't exist or
something but in this
case it shouldn't be allowed yeah so we
assume the key always
exist right
because yeah so you yeah obviously
because you always just uh yeah you
should always you know any of these
right side value should be should
exist but again actually after all the
all the not names is Just A to Z Triple
A to Triple
Z okay so anyway look
up given a table name and given a key
name then after you get that then you
get a list of pairs like that then you
need to take left and right
so so okay so the if the input is
right that means last okay so how do you
do
that
uh why you know use pass combinators
what do you mean throwing a big giant
Jon pass combinators why you know use
pass combinators I heard of them code is
mostly passing problem
pass combinators what a fancy Jon you
you you can't even you know you don't
understand what what that that is do you
I don't know if you are
trolling I don't know what that is
myself but in it's intriguing past
combinators I dare say it's some
you made up
I mean I
mean the P combinator
Jon I think is 60%
the Advent of code is mostly
passing
problem that's also completely false
that's idiotic I think you are
trolling so anyway so look up table so
if the input is right you need to get
the last element if the input is L you
need to get the first element so what's
the easiest way to I mean the easiest
way the simply the Brest way is to do a
if statement you know if input equals to
L you know you do you take the last but
what's the let's say wolam language
pattern matching way is some kind of um
yeah I think it's simple it's just do if
let's not let's not get too fancy okay
so
if okay instead of instruction let's
name a step okay so if
step equals
to right then you do
uh then then you
do last last means take the last element
okay something like
that okay I think that you know that's
not worry about too much let's not worry
about too much anything else for now
let's just do
that okay I think we can run the code
let's see what happens so we got the
lookup function I'm pretty sure it's
correct we got the lookup table we got
the input so let's run it so so how do
you Rite
[Music]
you you you start with a AA and uh so
you
start so basically you will start with
like
that it's a starting step and
uh instruction so so you need to go
through this instruction which is a
string okay something like this okay
start at a
AA take one
step from
input if
result okay take one step from
input increment
counter okay so we need some kind of
counter okay this will be a bch to do if
you are going to do functional
programming because if we are going to
do functional programming this counter
thing will not be allowed and uh of
course it's possible to do but um but it
takes more thinking but let's let's
start with this okay take start at
AAA take one step from the input which
is a L or R incr counter okay an
increment counter then if result if if
result is zzz stop print counter that's
it okay if
not
else
repeat okay so so basically the whole
algorithm will be something like
that else
repeat okay so we got this is some kind
of
loop hello those problems are hard to
solve they are my nightmare but they are
a good practice to the for the brain
yeah so we already spend 30 minutes oh
God recently I started to have pain
again right here this is a chonic you
know it's been there like for by now six
years because I started I started I
typed so much in the in the past month
again so when I do this it it's
comforting you know it's right right
here and the reason is because for for
for 10 years I've been doing in
particular this finger to press the you
know anyway I'm going to not going to
talk about that because I talked about
that many times in the past and I have
like 10 blocks about that issue
repetitive string injury so anyway back
to the code
so you want you want to start to do a
loop okay start a take one step from
input increment
counter so first of all I don't like
this um this string input is not good
you want to turn a list of you want to
use the list instead because it's harder
it's harder to go through a string so
you want some kind of string to
list there is a function that turns us
string into a into a list of
of of
letters okay I don't remember what is
the
name you know actually I haven't been
coding wam language
for for two
weeks
what uh uh form string I
mean so anyway that so so we want to
turn a string into letters a list of
letters okay so that's one issue we can
worry about later it's not too critical
we can find it for
sure or the best way is actually so
let's go to string qu string string
Escape string functions get subst string
convert string there it is Comm string
two string string to number string to
list there it is string split oh
obviously oh
wait okay so let's try
that string
split by that okay run the current line
let's see there it is fantastic that's
what we
want so in fact the input can be just uh
let's yeah so we got the list of things
instead
okay so
now you want a loop so what is the loop
over I mean what what so basically the
the main thing you are looping over is
this input string the instruction left
right so you want to lbe it and it can
be cycled you know it can
be right and then and
until you want until you've reached Z
okay so what you can do is
that you so this is some kind of of
uh you know for each step you have to
check whether you reached Z or
not you know this guy is a bit is
taunting me about POS combinators but if
I do look up you know either it's going
to be a rent
or
uh you know can tell you what that is
pass a combinator is some esoteric stuff
okay oh there it is pass a
combinator but it's going to distract
our main thing about coding WF language
you know then it's going to you know
talking about that in POS combinator is
a high old function that accept several
passess as input and return a new
passess is
output uh okay so okay I can tell you
don't know about this thing okay
you don't know not a about this P
combinator am I sure 90% sure I don't
know even know who you are because the
people who understand that they won't be
watching my videos
okay uh okay let's go back to uh yeah
let's focus on
this this okay so now
so now we are we we want to Loop this
okay so we want to Loop this over this
list and uh stop only when we find it
equals to
Z okay let's think about this because
once we we we we we we found it then we
can easily code it and that's it so this
is a critical moment we don't even have
to test run our code so we we do a loop
until we find it so the easiest way I
mean the you know the most brandless
easiest way is to do a y Loop you know
that's imperative programming procedural
you know you you do a while loop so we
can we can write we can kind of write
that and mark up okay
while while
while test and do this okay so while the
test uh body so okay so while the test
is
um equals
to well the test
not equals
to uh but wait a minute how do you take
the element you see when you do a while
loop you you have to you have to take
the element one element from
the from that so if you do y loop
it's you then you need the index
so yeah okay then you can do a for Loop
okay I'm not going to do
that the best way is
to let's see fixed
point no fixed point is not what we
[Music]
want nest what about NE Nest nesting
recurse
recursion yeah if you do recursion
[Music]
or fold you can also do fold you know so
the problem is a bit tricky you know if
you use fold or reduce because one
because the thing is that this this this
input is allowed to repeat
okay
so so it's a bit tricky because if you
use you see you can use sare Loop or for
Loop but the tricky part is that you
don't simply o Loop over this input
because they will be allowed to
cycle
so basically you want to Loop over this
thing but in an infinite way and the the
the the the start point is on is is way
when when you reached Z
okay so the input is potentially you
know is is a is a variable
length so that means if you use while
loop or full
loop you cannot do it directly you have
to you know maybe use modular
arithmetics to cycle the index
okay however you can do a
recursion uh if you do recursion the
input oh God this is tricky
we we kind of like stuck on this
point there's nothing we can do other
than just solve this you know we have to
solve this point because once you know
what you want to do about this the
problem is
solved so the problem is how how what
kind of recursion or Loop you can you
want to
do okay this this is when I need to stop
talking and just think about this
problem okay so
so if you do a
recursion
fold fold is problematic fold and reduce
is problematic because you don't have a
fixed
input is that right that's right
otherwise you can use reduce
or fold but however the issue is that
you don't have the
fixed
input okay so you don't have a fixed
input
so you you don't have a fixed input so
that means
okay so you don't have fixed input so
that means reduce or fold is mostly
out Mo
mostly now let's look at uh fold let's
look at wolam documentation to see maybe
there's some options that allows you to
cycle over the list
input I don't think so okay yeah because
if you cycle over the list then it's
it's not really fold
anymore okay and
uh so yeah so the other option is to use
Nest Nest is when the function C itself
okay so you
can
so if you use Nest you have to have a
fixed number of times
which we cannot use because we do not
know when to stop I mean we only the the
condition is not the fixed number of
times therefore we can use Nest
while okay so next we'll call a function
recursively until a test we'll stop
it okay that we can
do call the function so the function
input will
be let's see Tes one
um so not in
Step yeah so it takes the function
should take two argument not in the
step uh and but so over here it takes
one argument so what you have to do is
that you have to make these two argument
into one like use a list instead okay
that can do that can be done so but next
while so you take these two arguments
not and the step and what does it return
it return turns a nod a new nod
right then step you take another element
from the step
instruction you call it again so you
see so the problem with nesting
recursion is that the input is not is
not
self-contained oh God it's
we got kind of you know some hot shot
here
okay we got a hot shot hot shot with
Japanese
name okay so let's uh focus on the
question we
God this is potentially a
problem I don't want to end up doing you
know not be able to finish
this okay
so yeah okay I want I want to finish
this so this this Rec
infinite so this input can be repeated
infinitely
and the problem is asking how many
steps oh
God so what you can do is that you make
this function so the function takes a
notd in
Step so instead of taking a knot in one
step it should
take a nod which is a AA to begin with
and instead of one step it just take the
whole that's right it just take the
whole sequence of
input then each time the
function so the function will return a
new
nod and a list of steps like minus one
right fantastic that's the that's a
better that that's a that's a that's a
solution so the function will so this
this way this function will be able to
recurse because it contains the
input so the function takes a notd and
the
steps okay and return yeah so this way
the function will be able to
recurse
now so that kind that solves the problem
you see we have I have
reached now I'm I'm addressing this hot
shot Japanese name guy okay now I want
everyone to see
this this hotot Japanese guy
my progr my programming skill has gone
into the sublime level you know like
Kung Fu like I don't like all sword
fighting you know the Western sword
fighting I don't even have to draw my S
thought s swords you know all the all
the happening is in in here you know
that's the state I have
reached so now we know the solution for
this function a recursive
solution we basically solved it already
Okay and however that's not purely
functional approach because you still
need to have a counter you need to have
a increment of a counter did we decare
it here you
see that's a counter is a global
variable so each time you update it
that's not good that's nonfunctional
programming is see functional
programming has many
advantages but of course you have to pay
for those
advantages
so that that is why many of the C Java
programmers they don't get it like like
why why do you have to go this way to do
function they they don't get it because
it's like there's extra step you have to
pay so for example in this
example by now you know this if you are
the Java you know C Shar or rust coder
maybe you already solved it with a
counter Global variable
but but but we don't want that okay so
the global variable counter can be
embedded into this recursive function
that's right so the recursive function
takes
three has has takes three arguments okay
the nod
the input
nod the sequence of steps
instruction and three the current
counter okay then it returns kind of the
same thing three values
okay that's
right that's right that's how we okay
let's code it
so the function will just take one
argument input okay now we we become so
Advanced
now so here's a new lookup
function let's let's document the
function takes one
arug of the form it's document so people
who watch my video can see what I'm
doing uh not
steps and
counter
okay and return the same thing
with
steps reduced by one
okay okay that's basically what the
function does okay so this lookup
function this shouldn't be called lookup
anymore so this is uh this is uh how do
you name this function this is not
the this is a
navigate
function xnav okay
navigate means a
navigator
fantastic okay the Navigator function
takes one argument of the form three
things and return the same thing with
steps reduced by one
okay and counter increased by one okay
okay that's uh that's
it okay the navigate function Navigator
function X
so so what do you want to do so what uh
what do you want to do okay so
what so let's write the module okay so
okay got
so what is the not steps counter not
steps counter not steps counter
okay let's just do it in the most
brainless way because now I want to
focus on finish the problem instead of
talking too
much so so not is that and uh steps
equals to steps equals
to yeah
that uh two okay and uh the last thing
is counter counter equals
to1 or just three okay so that gets the
elements so that's the local variable
then the body so what the body do is
that is that it looks up okay it looks
up and okay let's uh Cur
step
okay con step equals
to equals to con step equals to 2 and
the one okay take the uh yeah two the
second part and the first part is the
current step okay
now
if what uh what the if yeah now if
it's too many words current step okay
current
step if current step equals to R then
what you do if the current step equals
to r that means take the take the
second yeah let's say uh yeah okay well
let's say l
okay so if the current step equals to L
you take the first elent from the table
and yeah the the nod yeah the lookup
table that's right the
nod uh let's double check one two three
uh con step not if x table take the KN
uh if otherwise take the last okay okay
let's do it this way so clean up the
code clean up code are we done yeah
basically so this we don't need any
anymore this counter we don't need
anymore remove the imperative
okay
so so basically that is a function now
can we try to run this function yes
let's try it okay let's just test run
test run one time okay let's remove that
fold uh lookup table okay this is input
string lookup table
oh wait we got a problem
even with this recursive function
yeah we missed we missed this thing even
with this
function you know it doesn't it doesn't
do the cycle of the input yeah that's a
nasty issue you know one easy way is
like you just you know just Inc just
repeat this
as a first step repeat it 100 times like
like this is a hack just repeat it 1,000
times so so so you don't have to worry
about
it but yeah you know for example just
repeat you know just cycle you know just
repeat this input 1,000
times that's
probably you know depending on how
tricky they they do it that probably
work you can
even yeah but it's not it's a hack okay
so that's a hack so but what is the
proper way to do it you see so our
function
doesn't doesn't solve
that yeah our curent function doesn't
solve that problem
yeah
unless then you add
another
element
this original steps so you keep the
fourth argument that is the original
steps so that when when your steps
becomes empty then you just start over
taking taking from the original steps
right I think that's I think that can
work okay let me read the
comments I understand
G okay he's a Chinese guy hello
ni you know he you know he's probably a
Chinese guy who really appreciate
appreciate my work and I
just I just insulted him
okay uh okay God what is this so which
one is better like
Advantage uh well today I'm going to
focus on this on the wfam language
coding okay so I'm not going to answer
keyboard
questions what do you think about V your
studio
code stowman was right that's right
stowman was right how much does it cost
can you use switches with a low Force
okay I paid 500 tax included I used
the okay lots of keyboard talk talk
European company
okay back to the Advan
code yeah let's do it this way you know
you know I you know from my experience
you look at the Advan code all of them
are ugly they are ugly
you know so this way I'm doing pure
fun pure functional
programming okay let's just do it uh
okay so
counter yeah so here is several input so
let's add uh original
steps let's add a fourth
input I
mean okay kind of like that
now if
if yeah okay so actually so the function
needs to return kind of four things okay
so the function needs to return that's
the first thing it Returns the second
thing is steps so the steps is going to
be yeah we are coding extremely
inefficient
here this is extremely inefficient
code so steps need you need to drop one
so
can you be sure there is a element for
you to take
even actually you cannot be
sure yeah actually
so so we we so
because so when we call this nextest
while
function an
expression the function needs to
take okay the function is better written
in a different way in a pattern matching
way not not in this Lambda
way yeah it's much better if by yeah let
shall we yeah we should yeah okay let's
do
it so let's rewrite this function now
let's rewrite it in a pattern matching
way okay so because that's just much
better so Navigator so
uh so okay so I'm sorry I haven't run
any code this is all just working
um um because I'm familiar with the
language so I don't need to run you know
test like trial and error that's the
worst in programming is trial and
error thing like that's when you don't
know what's going on you trial and error
so for me I don't need to do that so we
have
nots we have steps this way so this is a
pattern this means a pattern of anything
and we give it a name not okay not steps
and uh then we
have
counter and we have orinal
steps kind of yeah and we have that's it
so we this function
takes
uh this function takes like one argument
in four arguments in one okay then then
give that then okay then we don't need
all this module
thing the current step thing we
need okay so we kind of need the module
the current step current step equals to
uh why why is this not colored
correctly oh my God coding is like
taking a long time it's already 1 hour
so
yeah so now it's much better now
steps
uh yeah so now we are using pattern
matching
so so it will return
you you will return also basically the
four things like that
[Music]
oh God this
is lots of tedious things to
do okay I need to finish this
okay this is two there's different ways
to do it okay so one way is like that
the other way is like that so when the
step is empty list then what you do is
you then you just do this okay this is
uh this is a
novelty uh other languages you wouldn't
know this is one particular feature of
wam language pattern maging okay so if
if so you avoid if statements you see
this is what happens when the steps is
empty
list if that is the case then you just
call the function again with this steps
be using the original steps right is is
that right yes okay so so that's one
that's one of the definition you need to
do so you need to Define that first that
particular pattern now
otherwise oh okay in that case yeah
since we are doing pattern matching
let's use to its fullest
potential so if the first item is zzz
that means we have arrived at the answer
okay then the steps this we don't care
whatever encounter we need this we don't
care what whatever okay so
if we got one of that the first argument
is zzz that means we that's it that's it
done
uh but what you want to do
uh counter plus one yeah right so if if
you get that then you just
return okay
uh wait do we actually need to do
this yeah just return itself that's
right
right if you get that then you just
return itself
okay so
then so then
yeah okay so let's use the full power of
pattern matching okay so now if that is
that now if this x
is
is R okay r
are zero or more stuff
then then what we do is
um that's right so yeah so here it needs
to be nod
Okay so
no let's try L first okay not L counter
y if it's that then
we
return that's right we need to return
this if lookup
table
okay look up table n first then
rest then counter
counter +
one then the Y is y is remain the
same okay very simple that's right so
Navigator not if it's l then look up
look
up rest is a list okay wait
uh yeah there then counter plus one that
okay then
also if that is
R then
we
last okay I think that I think
I think that's
it okay we kind of Define this pattern
matching
function am might make sense okay I
guess nobody's watching now everyone
went
home seven
H seven seven people ser trust
me okay
so okay so we we we got this pattern
matching work hello Scoopy noodle so we
got this pattern
matching code work and uh this this not
good so anyway we wrote this new
function
Navigator so it each time it takes a
let's review this time it takes a notd
a n is one of the one of this okay
then let's review so if it's
empty then you
call no original
steps if it's
empty do you increment the counter
no right so if yeah you increment a
counter only when you actually take one
of the
input
so that's right so you do
that yeah original
steps
okay uh and
then if it's Z
you need to stop
basically when it's Z just actually
let's see actually when it's Z just
return the
counter amazing that's
right that's right exactly so so we
don't need this
one when it's Z you simply return the
counter so this is a pattern matching
style of
coding
and okay then okay then if it's
that you return the look up you look up
the table with by the
not and
uh and L means get the first element
then here is the rest rest means zero or
more because they are three
underscores okay you go to The wolam
Language tutorial there is a section on
pattern
matching and uh you know basic
introduction then you have the pattern
syntax so triple
underline means any sequence of zero or
more blank nor sequence okay so here the
rest that will work
zero or more that's right yeah you know
I'm you know usually I don't code
pattern matching so I'm like 99% sure
but I'm not you know we need to test out
this
code uh so
counter
counter needs to be counter plus one
every time you take it that's right and
Y is original
original steps okay let's let's keep
using the name okay just so
that
okay
okay then
here here is kind of same so left
is first right is last okay
counter okay I kind of I think that's
it that's it I think that's it so this
one we wrote before kind of Lambda
style it's kind of messy let's remove
the Lambda style because if you use the
Lambda sty which is lisp all the lisps
lisp
closure uh then you're going to have
lots of if statements like if if
Expressions but pattern matching it
takes care of you know the ifs check for
you kind
of okay so that so we Define that
function this Navigator we can try to
run it one time okay we got the
Navigator so let's let's not do the
while so we can call the Navigator
function
the Navigator okay start with
AAA okay then the first step let's say
left just for
example Okay the third argument counter
zero okay the fourth argument uh is
original steps
okay let's
say okay
that okay if we run
this it should give us the
answer that's right it it should just
return a number okay it should just
return a number
that's assuming we didn't make any error
but that's not likely so shall we try it
yeah actually
run it okay
now what might happen is infinite
recursion then I have to quit
emac Okay so just in case let's start
Escape control control shift escape and
start the test manager okay run
it okay look up inverse inverse
something the argument Association that
that
that no is not valid okay we got a
syntax
error extra comma wam language doesn't
allow that okay R
again oh it
stopped
okay one step
BB wait what it should just
return one step okay so AAA and take the
left AA take the left is BBB
right that's right we only run it once
that's right perfect now let's try with
L uh with r
okay run
it so which one is it printing print
print the last line so it's printing
this line so if you run this line AA
take the right you return you got
CCC that's correct okay all you have to
do now is
is what your
nest
okay n this
function or fixed point this is even
more fancy
fix point will Nest a function until the
return value is always the
same
okay so actually we can try
that okay we don't even need this this
two we don't need anymore we can just
try
this save it
then okay fix Point code with one
argument two or more expected yes of
course we forgot to give the argument so
the argument will
be wait let's look up the documentation
for fix
Point function expression okay start
with the expression then applies F
repeated until the result no longer
changes okay so yeah
so the argument will
be there and uh actually this part will
be that like that that that that
okay and the max number let's say 10,000
so so in case we got into infinite
recursion
minute okay lucky we actually put the
check otherwise this is going
to be infinite cursion you
see
okay why is
that okay you see we got we we it
stopped
there
so okay we need to fix okay I know what
to do so instead of returning one single
number now if you're going to do this if
you want to call if you want use fixed
Point as a loop mechanism then your
function needs to always return the same
structure so in this line you cannot
have it just return a number you need to
return the same structure such as uh
such us like that okay so if
that
uh yeah
so that so you you know just
return return the same thing
right and you'll stop okay so
this
remove okay and in fact this one move to
the top because this is the most
specific
situation
okay yeah okay so I'm very glad I tried
this functional purely function fun
approach not just that but also pattern
matching so because this way it
showcases how wam language is very
different from all the hascar okamo by
the way okamo and hascar F sh they are
pattern matching is is very much
inferior than wolam language because
wolam language pattern matching is
symbolic
okay in okamo in hascal they are
matching
types so
that's kind of significantly different
because when you have symbolic pattern
matching that essentially means you are
just ter it's a term rewriting system
you know basically you just have bunch a
sequence of alphabets you define rules
how they change then you keep changing
them you know it's like purely
syntactical
manipulation meanwhile in hascal in
okamo in F job they their pattern
matching is kind of inferior because
first of all they don't have this nested
you know deeply nested you know like
almost like regular expression you know
they don't this is more powerful in than
regular expression because you can map
you know nesting
structures uh so
but I'm 199% sure in hascal or Cam they
don't have that then the other thing is
that they are matching data you know
they are matching types they are not
matching just you know uh syntax
okay so
anyway well first well we got to make
sure our code works correctly first okay
that I think that's um okay let's run it
let's run
it okay it worked two steps for the
first the toy input is that right
check he wait
six
what did did we forget to in increment
the counter yes we did you see uh
somewhere
what oh God I hope this doesn't run into
another hour or two just to debug this
okay quitting emx is highly dishonorable
okay
[Music]
so so we I hope we
don't stuck on this for like another
hour or so so we need to debug
okay why is this let's try three let's
see what happens the result should be
four okay something is
wrong why why is
this
no okay so we are missing missing a
possibility of match is that right
no we got left we got right
rest original
steps oh okay maybe I was
right okay two steps now of course you
might not find ZZ right away if you run
out of the Left Right repeat the whole
for example here is a situation oh okay
right so if you try this input string
then then the result will should be six
okay maybe thank you thank you sub have
subet
subet interesting name
uh okay
so okay so we got that so but uh but but
for this input why does it
um return no
for example if we run this input right
so if we run this
input okay we might be confused with
something so we if we run that
input um okay
yeah then what happens is
that so this does not match okay and
this does not match
match
okay and uh
this this
matches
right this line
match but why why uh why is a return
result no let's see
because this
sometimes uh sometimes you need
to
print oh indeed yeah because we forgot
to yeah we didn't print because of the
common and stuff okay so so this is
actually expected result that's right
returns four and become BB that's right
so now if
we that's right so
then what about let's try
R run
it okay it uh return CC that's correct
four that's correct okay that's
correct
now now we common this out and now we
run this fixed
point it returns two that's correct
uh but now if we change the input to be
this new
thing you know he says you know it says
we got this new
input
uh oh God we need to change that oh God
we need to pause that
yeah we can't we can do it okay let's do
it then
so what
is okay
okay so if the loop table is something
like that
okay okay this is two TDS we need to
write a function that pass this
input but but let's just try this okay
so if the input is llr and the table is
that
then the result is
six we almost done
let's pray to
God six
[Laughter]
fantastic now are we ready yes yes I'm
ready let's try the 1,000
input this
stupid days of cod of then of days of
then something something where is the
input that
1,000 lines of values where's the
we saved it
somewhere code oh yeah
what what is this okay this is a list of
Advent code we done before close it this
is s talk show today close it CL talk
show index and this is today's CL talk
show okay uh it's not here where is our
input we saved it
uh let's move this back and here I think
there it
is okay so are we ready to use this
input yes yes yes I'm ready okay copy it
let's do some surgery on this inputs to
make it into a wolam research syntax
okay
uh do that and
uh and
uh uh what okay now repeat
last okay do that and uh repeat last
complex
command change bracket pairs
fantastic and select that and boom boom
boom fantastic you see that's fantastic
and all you have to do is put the put a
square bracket and there remove the last
comma that's the the argument to
Association okay now cut cut close this
close this close this
pop this out then all we have to do
is okay then let's first of all put it
here okay all we have to do is this
input let's add another new input input
equals to these long lines
fantastic and now the lookup table
ladies and
gentlemen this
Association look up
table okay it's going to be this thing
and do put here go here paste go here e
uh that's
it okay that's a long input and here is
your lookup table how many lines 700
okay now ret shall
we uh
yes fantastic how many oh one it says
1,000 but it didn't you see 1,000 is our
limit so this is
incorrect so let's give it uh let's say
3,000 limit okay let's run
[Music]
it okay I think maybe our code is wrong
now 3,000 limit reached let's say
5,000 now 5,000 limit reached I think
our code is
incorrect now why is our code incorrect
I don't
know now could it be could it be that it
actually requires let's limit to 9,000
okay
okay 9,000
reached
hm how many how many lines of uh the
table how lots
of
what is the syntax
correct
God so what is it looking for
answer starting at a AA follow the Left
Right instructions how many steps are
required to reach
Z okay
so so why is it this's limit
to 2,000
okay run it
now let's carefully look at
this what could be wrong so
2,000 this means it ran for 2,000 times
and uh we are
at
ktk okay ktk is a current number
search for
ktk Okay ktk gets into that H so why so
I don't know why it's not working but
let's think about the problem so the
problem is that you have a bunch
of you have the
this each
nod so each you have these knots out
there and each knot
basically goes to two possible other
nods okay so each so this is a directed
graph you have a bunch of
knots of finite number of
nods and each nod has two arrows going
to
potentially two different knots is it
possible both of them go to the same
not it doesn't say but suppose I suppose
it's a
possibility so each knot goes to two
other knots
and and is it
possible that when you go to a new nod
that need this knot has no Arrow going
out at all that's also possible because
this data you know you don't know you
know it's possible there's one of these
thing on the on the right side for
example
dkq does it ever exist on the left yes
but it's possible it
doesn't and the input just never go re
you know go there so you know this is
the tricky part of adventive code so you
have a bunch of knots each
nod have
two arrows going to to two different
nods or the same nod but some not may
not have outgoing AR arrows at
all so what so what the what is the
situation so some knots may not have
outgoing at
all so anyway so this one bunch of knots
one of them is named a AA and one of
them is zzz
so so you are following this instruction
left right left right you know this
instruction
and
that that eventually reach
Z oh so you see now I'm trying to look
at the whole picture to see
how
so and so far
it's the complete picture is not clear
yet so you got you got this
graph this this is a directed graph for
sure now is it possible there's a ND
there's no arrow goes into
it
no because the input every arror on the
left you have an you know outgoing arrow
and uh and by definition every nods on
the right hand side always have some nod
going into it so in this graph directed
graph it's not possible to have a nod
that is not connected to anything
okay but it is possible to have a n that
doesn't go anywhere it doesn't go out at
all and but so the instruction is you
start from
AAA and each
time AAA will you know you follow this
instruction you know choose a
path so this is actually easier if you
kind of start to draw
diagrams can I do
that now this video is now 2 hours and
we are kind of like now digressing on
this
thing uh
but but let's just do it why not it's uh
uh this is advant of code is
always
uh uh so tedious to
do so basically you have not not not not
so each time there's two
arrows let's
say right right left let's name name one
two three
four five six 7even eight so each time
they
get let's say they have two arrows they
can point
to
any you know something like that this is
three
okay uh and
uh this is one one okay 1 2 3 4 five 6 7
78 okay seven let's say go
here let's say is it possible it goes to
itself yes very it's very
possible it's very possible it goes it
to yourself
itself okay so this this also needs to
go to one and
two and this needs to let's say both
goes to five and let's say it's
just let's say
that
okay okay what about two two goes to one
let's say and let's go to Five
okay so we are trying to see overall
what's going
on so you just travel you pick a path
until until you reach zzz so one of them
is named
zzz let's say this is a
AA right
so you you follow this instruction left
right left left right right and you just
travel
this this
graph until you reach
zzz H that's very interesting it becomes
more clear what's going on but however
what are some of the properties
like like what
exactly what what
exactly uh you
know so if you given this
instruction you can in fact start with
any
nod now is it possible if you start with
any nod you will never re Z yes
because some nod may not have outgoing
nod at outgoing arrows at all so you
know if you start at random KN you may
end up at a
nod that's not going
anywhere
or a knot that leads to a knot that
eventually goes
nowhere
or is it possible to have a
Loop yes obviously if if all the
aregoing arrows both
way you know it's it's possible
to yes it's very possible to get into a
loop that never goes
out so this
is indeed this problem is so is there a
shortcut is that like there is some like
trick what some insight some
equation that gives you give you the
answer I mean can we walk this
backwards so if you want walk it
backwards you start
with Z okay let's see let's search for
zzz okay so you see
this this KN will go to zzz okay only
one
no only this not leads to wait not that
this only this knot leads to zzz okay
but who leads to that knot and
see oh only this
one okay so by this way we can
actually trace the
result and only this one leads to that
okay so so far it's
linear oh okay now now we have
two path that leads to
that so anyway if you go
backwards then you run into a
backtracking
problem because if you go
backwards then essentially you want to
find an not that's a in fact you may
have many many different
path that leads to
AA so
many so suppose you found one of
them that may not
be you know that may not be
the it doesn't it doesn't relate to this
particular instruction
okay so all these thinking is kind of
useless so
far isn't it two steps look at the
previous
paragraph oh yeah that's so who who else
is watching I think nobody
know
five oh God don't end
up God I got I want to take a
break okay actually I got to take a
break yeah because I got to see my
wife
okay I take a
break audio let's turn off the
audio
e
e e
hello I'm
back okay we we got stuck on here very
annoying 3 hours so
far what uh 4 5 six 2 hours hours so
far yeah two
hours I guess I guess two hours is
actually kind of normal is unless you
are a speed coder into speed coding so
we analyze the
problem and uh it doesn't
give it doesn't give us any
insight so so how many people are
watching six so we analyze the
problem graph traversing it doesn't give
us any
insight so we go back to
code we go back to code is it possible
let's try 1,000 steps I mean 10,000
okay 10,000 steps 10,000
still no
answer uh let's say
20,000
steps there is the answer we just didn't
run enough steps what the wasted
wasted 40 minutes oh God okay we got the
answer
yeah let's go to Advent of code we got
an answer are you sure yes I'm sure 1156
submit that's the right answer
perfect we got
code one shot no trial and
error and worked and pure functional
programming okay let me do a
summarize
summarization so the problem is given a
list of string as input which consists
of right left right right left you know
a sequence
of instruction you know r o
l okay then you are given this table you
know the table is a dictionary and the
key is a a b b c c d and so
on okay so if you are starting at
BBB and you have you know each knot you
have two choices right or left so if you
are at BBB and if your step current step
is right you take the right side
otherwise you take the left side okay so
you repeat following each time you take
one string from the right left
sequence
until you reached you know you reached
Z then the problem asks you how many
steps it
took that is a problem
description so input there are two
inputs one is a sequence of steps and
the other is the lookup table okay so we
are given as our personal input each
person got a different input so the
personal input is you know this this
long string how many how many steps
let's count so in emac we do this count
Words so 269 characters
so and also by the way the the problem
says that if this
instruction after you reach the end if
you still have not found Z you repeat
this instruction okay so anyway we got
this uh initial you know got
269 steps instruction okay and we got
this table which is about
700 knots 700 knots okay and so our
solution obviously the solution is a
loop each time you take one of
these step and you look up the table and
see if the result is z if not you
repeat so the solution is just uh it's
pretty simple problem Loop
but so of course the difficult part is
to implement it it's always easy to talk
about the
algorithm so in to implement it you can
do you know you can do by for Loop the
easiest is just for Loop or while loop
if you do that
way you know you have to create the
index and you have to create a counter
you know the number of steps each time
you in increment the counter by one and
also you have to keep a state like
what's the current nod that's the
procedural programming imperative
programming you keep basically two
Global variables one is the number of
steps so far one is the current state
current current nod okay it's actually
easy to
implement procedural away but you got
you you you know but the floww of course
it's it's not you know the you got
Global variables usually in programming
you don't want that okay so I opted for
functional programming pure functional
programming
so and
so one thing is I do pure functional
programming no global variable no State
okay well the state is embedded within
the function so anyway functional
programming then the second thing that's
unusual from different languages is that
we used pattern matching so we Define
this Navigator function this Navigator
function documented over here that you
know it uses pattern matching so if the
if the input contains zzz so this is one
definition of a pattern so you see on
the left hand side you have a pattern so
if the pattern is this way and it begin
with
zzz you basically return this and that's
it that's basically you return that you
return Z basically you return the
argument itself no change okay now if
the in input pattern is an empty step
then basically you pass the original
step to
the to the to this to the instruction
steps because you know you because you
want to you know cycle this
instruction okay so that's this
definition a pattern so if you encounter
this pattern you just repeat the
original
steps you know you call the function
again you know with the original steps
as the new bunch of steps okay but
otherwise if
your pattern is like this where the
instruction is begin with L then that
means you do the lookup then you take
the first
element which is um you know the left
side you know the first
element okay so that's so that's this
section on the other hand if you begin
with I mean if your argument is
something
something right take the right part of
it then you you do look up and return
the last element and in either case you
remove one element from the instruction
you know for example this
if we got that you know the rest is zero
or more items so you remove one one of
them then and also you in increment the
counter okay so this
function every time this function
Navigator is called Cod it returns a
list of four things
always that's
important the structure the return
structure is always the same doesn't
matter what four items at least of four
items okay so that is our pattern
matching so then what we do is we uh now
this part is like the description of the
algorithm is that right yeah that's
that's kind of
right yeah so then what we do is we call
fix Point okay let's let me show um
let's show one of these you know as a
example call of our fun function okay
then what you do this is the main body
you know in C or Java you have the main
or go in the imperative languages you
have the M like like the entry point
which is CD by the
way so but anyway this is the main body
fixed point so what does fixed point do
is that it takes two arguments or three
optionally third argument so the first
argument is a function
it will call this function
repeatedly until the result no longer
changes okay so so this fixed point is a
functional programming approach to a
loop to one form of loop okay so you the
pass you pass the function and you pass
the initial value you want to initial
argument to the function so in this case
we start with the loop uh AAA no and
input zero counter and the original
input is the input in case it's used up
then you repeat the input okay and we
pass the optional
argument you know of
20,000 so that in case we have a error
in our code we don't get we don't go
into a infinite
Loop you see the advant of code you know
anyway so we we you know this is just
double check I mean this is
just just to be careful extra check so
we run the
code and we can see the result is that
okay so that I'm glad in two hours we
finished coding this I hope you guys
enjoyed
it
uh congratulations thank
you thank you and uh okay that's it for
today thank you
guys uh of course if you like my
stuff
consider PayPal me you know you go to
you go to kali. info kali. info and you
go all the way
down Amazon gift card patreon me or
payow me thank you
guys thank you bye
fantastic oh we we you see all this
entire while we didn't run it in the
wolam language notebook so we can copy
the whole thing actually let's run it in
wolam language copy it let let's make a
new one okay so
um let's remove all all the all the
comments okay remove all the comments
okay and
uh and
uh and uh so remove the comment so it's
all
clear okay copy go to w language select
all paste so it looks like that okay so
the input is
huge go down go down go down go down go
down go down okay and basically this
part you know here's here's the main
code okay
renette uh shift
enter so the result is
11567 that's the right an answer thank
you
bye okay now put the code back close
this put the code back code back to the
HTML syntax color it show in browser so
we got the code in wolam you know in the
site
so you guys can check it out and
uh okay bye guys