good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of kar talk show today we got we
are going to talk about a data hand a
fancy extremely fancy Batman device
keyboard okay data hand and uh data hand
and
uh La board and SW board that's a new
version of data hand i'm GNA show you in
a moment okay and so we talk about data
hand keyboard and we gonna talk about
emac I'm going to show you my
interesting commands and
package okay let's let's begin okay
let's switch to now that's my beautiful
face this
is this this is kis 360 keyboard okay
can you see it yes kesis 360 I recommend
it uh but when you buy get the linear
light switch okay so for kesis 360 you
should get the pink switch I believe so
remember linear switch and light 35 G
activation Force that's what I recommend
do not get the brown brown cherry Brown
switch is worst
okay okay so kesis 360 and this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard version
two okay and I'm going to show you my
keyboard blog and reviews so I have
video reviews on them uh you can check
them
out okay so uh keyboard okay so you know
just search for let me show you keyboard
s keyboard guide and you'll find all the
keyboard you ever wanted to know so the
re I recommend glove 80 I use for my
bedsite wireless I recommend kesis 3 60
I do not recommend kesis advantage to
now okay so and I recommend expose night
uh and I recommend ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic okay so all this I
recommend they gave me one so you know
so I help them sell sell and uh these
are my favorite things favorite my
favorite keyboard I have so many now
okay so this so
yeah so you can see my screen so we talk
about yeah so let's talk about so
keyboard okay s keyboard and you'll find
all that then let me talk about the
coding keyboards okay there it is Data
hand you know in the in the past 30
years we have varieties of coding
keyboard and coding keyboard systems for
example you have this you know what you
you guys may have heard of the stain no
machine so it's like actual real coding
unlike the typical keyboard control o
and you have to hold control first then
press the key then release that key then
release the control that [ __ ] up your
hand that's the
most that's one of the most I would say
the second most serious cause of
repetitive repetitive strain injury okay
hurting your hands
cord okay the
first cause is the key switches okay you
don't want rub but don't and you don't
want laptop keyboard such as apples you
type on it you get hand pen okay you're
going to your hand is you're going to
become a [ __ ] okay so go out buy a
mechanical keyboard okay that's one
first thing then then try to set up key
markers so you don't have to control all
Windows or Mac command stuff okay so
that's the normal coding which is not
real coding because this the order you
have to hold something and press another
one now the real coding keyboard such as
stal and several others this this photos
is by Emily who is a sto expert Emily uh
Emily is she she's this person fantastic
she this is Emily's battle Station 3
years ago okay so Emily so anyway so
she's the master of the
sto you know this is a real coding
keyboard like a piano you don't have to
hold this one first and and press that
and release that no such thing you just
press them together real coding keyboard
okay the major difference that's totally
entirely different beast from the normal
control old you know thing so this uh
coding keyboard sto most famous uh then
you actually have a piano system system
you know this researcher
she researched you know so you can
actually make a piano to do typing and
you can also code piano is also real Cod
uh then and Italian sto is based on
piano that's interesting in in Italy
their sto system is based on piano
keys okay then you have you know you
have quite few then you have this new
fancy keyboard they try to do St know so
there are there are quite a few version
of it uh Georgie unfortunately uh the
company they they kind of stopped you
know they they they are stopped at the
moment so you cannot buy them anymore so
anyway this are coding keyboard real
coding keyboard okay this is Extreme
case T Keys okay old old control
delete
okay then okay then so in the '90s 1990s
you have the bat keyboard bat coding
keyboard you know each one have a you
have to learn them so for example here's
a cheat sheet on how do you type
them uh so anyway there are quite a few
okay so you know invented in the past 30
years but then one of the most popular
famous is the data hand okay looks like
this okay so instead of pressing the
keys
down let's see if you are here say hi
okay hello
guys so you can see it yeah so instead
of pressing the key down you uh let's
see the Glorious photos Okay
you so it looks like that let's so you
move your fingers you know northward
Southward Eastward or Westward instead
for each finger so you have four ways
and you can also press it down so this
is how it operates so instead of just
pressing and you know you move your
fingers up and down or sideways or press
it down and also for the
thumb so this is data hand very
expensive I think it cost costs like
$2,000 back in
1990s but today with 3D printing we have
you know
uh you know so here's a data hand
featured in the in this movie great
movie contact
1997 you know they are trying to contact
aliens so you need fancy Batman
equipment in the movies so anyway so
today and here okay here is the data
hand manual I'm going to I'm going to
read it because there's new
uh data hand manual so you you can
see so here's a diagram for the keyboard
you know Asian
interface uh but oh there's this they
got foood pedals too and then you have
you know you have a section about how do
you actually type stuff on this
keyboard so you can see okay so you have
to learn it you know take a month or two
I
think but but okay but but so data hand
which went out of business you know
because very expensive and usually takes
learning so people don't want to learn
stuff so you have then you have 3D
printed version La board okay so this
came out
about 2019 3 years
ago okay so this is 3D printed version
you can do it yourself and
then let's see if they they GitHub is
still on now GitHub about a month ago
they started to require JavaScript
otherwise nothing
shows okay so this is a low board you
can you know you you you know if if you
are into uh do it yourself you are a
hobbyist engineer you can try to make it
yourself s okay 120 W per minute typing
demo oh 120 words per minute typing
demo I haven't seen this oh it's pretty
good let's
see
wow that's pretty
good
but okay it's not too fast 120 it's
pretty fast though okay so then okay so
let's so you have the law board
then then recently about last year you
have the SAR board which is a uh kind of
modification and the good news is that
they're going to sell this so you can
actually buy it
so so I I wrote a Blog you know about uh
two two years ago also and but now they
have updated a lot oh oh this is just
last year so let's go to their website
spile board I'm going to get one okay
the guy is very nice he's going to send
me one for review so I'm going to get
one and I'm going to start to learn it
and I'll tell you guys how it
goes uh looks now this is you know the
website has improved looks much better
than before
um yeah so this is the
news
fantastic
fantastic okay so that's about La board
SW board now they have a Discord I just
joined um and uh you know usually on
Discord you'll see a lot of beautiful
photos I haven't I haven't really looked
into them but anyway so there's a
Discord you can join you can probably
find their site but anyway the thing is
about this one is that you can just buy
$750 okay fairly expensive but if you
are really you know you have hand
problems you know this is a a
alternative okay and or you can buy the
kit and you build yourself self about
$300 okay
so so anyway that's
about the data hands vable so I'm going
to update I'm going to start to read it
and update my site and I'm going to have
a
review okay now let's talk about
emac okay let's read the comments and
talk about emac we are 16 minutes
in hello
the loyal fan hello oo
hello
zuu hello
Bernardo juang hello bra you have Browns
Browns no
good Kyle box black okay black I hate
blacks black is L is linear and heavy
it's you
know LR uh space alien Tempo what is
that can't wait to see the review on the
SW board okay fantastic now let's do
let's start to do uh emac okay so emac
so I have this package package that's
dedicated to working with files and
directory fantastic but okay let me
start to show
you uh okay let's drop into a directory
okay so first of all let let me show you
what uh what commands are there so s
diet mod is a mod you can buy you have
to pay me you have to buy it but it's
open source so once you get it all the
source code you you basically get the
source code and full documentation and
and and uh you know in the past 15 years
it's all free but I don't get money and
I become tax support every day spending
an hour to answer question so now you
pay me to get it
okay so I did a video long ago two three
four years ago oh my God this is a Asian
video so anyway I'm going to talk about
this uh what does this package do let me
just start to show you okay so you have
a bunch of image command let's go to so
let's go to a image
directory uh the pink window shows all
my keys and command course as I type
them so you can see the keys on the left
and the command name on the right
usually if you just search for the word
you'll find the source code for half of
them so anyway so let's demo some let's
show some images okay
uh okay so we have quite a few images
let's look at okay so Venom code Bor to
lat okay so example this one so this one
the image is here so let's say I want
this is a this is a jpeg okay so I can
press a key it opens in the default
image viewer on your
computer uh and uh and uh that is that
command
is open in EX in external app the source
code is on my website if you just search
it and it's also in sof Keys Sly Keys is
free you can download it okay the one my
most popular
it's a emac key binding
system okay so I talked about this many
times so clof like Keys you can look at
my website and uh you know if you are
emac users install it it'll save you
from typing control old meta stuff you
don't you basically you don't have to
you know 90% of them are read up and
there's a video this this one this video
is a nice demo so you know talking about
Sly keys so anyway I wanted to show you
so Sly keys so this image right so I
want let's say this so this is PNG I
want to convert it to jpeg okay so let's
uh see what commands are
available so here's a documentation for
S diet mod I mean the so you
have uh jpeg okay diet to jpeg okay T J
so t J there it is here's a new file you
see here's a JPEG version and here's a
PNG version okay jpeg
PNG so open it delete it we don't need
it so to jpeg convert to JPEG and what
else okay scale image let's try that uh
let's
try let's try some other picture okay we
tried that yesterday
reer okay let's try this um okay so this
is a big picture the file is here so
scale what's the
key tap s okay tap s and it asks me
scale percentage let's say 50% okay
done and
uh
refresh there it
is you see
previous scaled so you
see so you don't have to you know
typically if you are a v user or vs code
you drop to a
shell then you type image magic you know
uh Magic you know depending on
the depending if you are windows you
should the command is convert and
something something and scale and and 50
and you have to say percent and file
name you know that's typically what you
do or you do it in Powershell there it
is
Powershell you know so but but this
command allows you to just press a few
keys on emac okay so let's see did we
delete that yeah okay so scale image and
uh quite a few so you can convert to
jpeg convert JPEG to PNG you can
optimize PNG this is very important
because if you are blogger or if you
work you know in a company usually you
want to optim optimize PNG so I can do a
demo for example let's let's do a demo
so let's
copy let's make a screenshot
okay so here is my my screenshot and
let's go to that screenshot
directory okay so there it is open it so
that's the screenshot I just did now
let's make a backup so you can see the
original file size
128 kilobytes okay now I want to
optimize so I just press the key okay
optimizing it's done okay refresh now
you can see the size is significantly
smaller half half of the size open it
it's the same it's the same image okay
for example open it open
it uh you know the same image so okay so
let's drop that uh yeah okay that's
let's optimize PNG okay now again if if
you are in normally you would say up
tpng then file name and and blah blah
blah so this is much more
convenient and uh this show metad data
is also important this command show
metad data because you know if you are
using your phone you take a lot of
photos it may contain your location so
you can for example I want to see the
metad data in this image so I press a
key oh not that key this key so you can
see here is the meta data for for this
image so you can see the command I just
called diet show
metadata you see but so this is a
screenshot now if you are doing a
screenshot on Apple the Apple you know
they they they they put a whole ton of
meta info into your file like like like
this is like copyright Apple profile
color profile copyright Apple metadata
you know format something something lots
of you know if you do a screenshot with
Apple computer or iPhone you got lots of
metadata you usually don't want okay so
you can just also press a key you can
see it removes all the metadata
okay and and especially important if you
are uh photos of your private life okay
and you can also open an image in in
inscape SVG image or [ __ ] or CR or info
view or Ms pen let me show you okay so I
don't want that uh let's go to so what
is this let's go to um yeah so let's try
some some oh this beautiful wolam
language Mathematica this is uh this is
kind of Al you know uh algebraic
geometry so we want to do yeah okay open
in
qu open qu okay so if you are photo
professional this is uh convenient okay
let's open in
qu there it is so now you can qu or pain
or whatever let's try
my
some
thing let's change color okay uh not red
let's blue a n n o t a t i o n
annotation okay so open in qu let's open
let's change your
image uh let's see oh this is this is uh
Dion's desktop three three years ago
Dion has improved much uh let's see okay
Dion is the best programmer you know one
time we have a bet with Dion he coded
some P Python and I lost a
bit okay let's see what's some
interesting that's Emily picture of
Emily let's see this is Allen's drawing
okay this another beautiful geometry
wolam language we did a video of this
okay let's open in
[ __ ] [ __ ] is going to take sometime to
load thoughts on Evo
mod uh so question thought on Evo mod
Vim emulation in emac how does sly Keys
compare that's a frequently Asked
question uh howar flag Keys compare of
course it's Superior it's more more
efficient because the Vim Keys the Vim
or EVO mod their keys are historical you
know they cannot redesign but the Vim VI
is the reason you know the choice of the
keys is
historical uh half of it is pneumonic so
kind of you know but anyway it's a mess
so sfly Keys is from the ground up so
every key is
designed according to how frequently
some command are most used so you pick
in emac or any editor the top let's say
the top uh 50 about 50 or 30 that's the
most used frequently used command you
order them then you choose a key for
them so that's essentially the design of
sof
Keys okay now of course there's a
advantage of Vim or EVO mod that is it's
it has about 100 times more uses because
VI you know it's it's in every Linux and
Unix for the past 40 years history so
you have a lot users of
Vim so you can switch between emac and
Evo mod Vim emulation or VI so you can
you know that allows you to you know
that's an advantage of
the Evo mod okay but as far as technical
superiority Sly Keys is better you know
the situation is similar to for example
emac versus vs
code okay let's let's okay I'm
digressing but let's for example let's
go
to uh go to a talk show okay so wait did
I close it okay go to so let's see
today's talk show showing browser so you
can open VSS code okay so you open this
file in vs
code so vs code which one is better vs
code or emac of course if you spend the
time to study emac emx is far more
Superior now let me show you this you
know this is funny I showed this many
times so you can see my emx I've been
opening a lot images and stuff and the
emac is
is oh 278 megabyte memory it's using
quite a lot now but vs code I I only
just opened one file it's got 274
megabyte of
ram you know just one this single text
file no images so why is my emac um
using so much memory oh because I'm use
opening processes you know I'm opening
CR and [ __ ] and
stuff but usually it's like 60 60
megabyte okay so anyway in vs code it's
far more popular but if you have
actually spent the time to study the
editor emac is uh much more
um uh Advanced you know much more
efficient you know
stuff but you have the tradeoff
if you learn vs codee well which doesn't
take much time you can go anywhere you
can code you know and uh it's available
anywhere but if
you you know take the emac route you can
be more efficient you can be better
but but much less uh uses that's a
similar situation to Vim or EVO mod
versus stuff like Keys okay that's a bit
digression so do I want to kill qu no so
let's go back
to uh what we were doing
okay uh what we want to do okay so we
were talking about
images okay so yeah okay so here is did
we open in [ __ ] let's
see [ __ ] there it
is [ __ ] okay
uh credit license close yeah okay so in
game you can start to edit let's see
where's the
pen
pencil okay something
something uh anyway so actually this
pencil is not good you know game is no
good okay I recommend
qu if you want image edit I recommend qu
game is like uh no
good so anyway so you have the command
opening game opening qu and uh and uh
and bunch of others opening INF view
open opening Ms pen let's try
that Ms pen okay tab one there it is Ms
pen
instantaneous Ms pen is the most link of
of them
all uh
Ms
pent most
link okay so there it is and here this
is another wolam language stuff okay so
you have this command okay let me show
you some
other uh already 33
minutes
can you give me love advice my parents
keep asking about girlfriend but I never
had one uh That's a classic
problem that's the classic problem of
humanity not exactly a problem but it's
a it's it's it's this happens to every
every person since monkey men okay
because as humans
we we we are here to procreate okay we
want children
so that and you know that's not enough
so when you have children you you will
be happy I mean children is your goal
basically on a you know
average and but you also want
grandchildren so once you have children
your son or daughter they grew
up makes you a lot happy when they have
children too because you are spreading
your seed those who do not spread their
seed they die they die out so when you
have a children you have kind of a clone
of yourself okay your children have
children you kind have semic clone of
yourself so you spread your preferences
your likings your thinking your
philosophy your view of the world you
spread your
jeans if you do not want children like a
lot today you know or unable to have
children you die out okay your type your
kind of view of the word your preference
your philosophy dies out so after a
while after 100 years there are no
people there's no human like you
anymore so that is why it's not because
we want children it's only because those
who have a preference to have
children they survive those who don't
like to have children they die out okay
so
so basically every person on Earth will
have the preference to have children
most you know in general statistically
speaking so when your parents ask press
you to so what do you do when you have a
problem when your parents keep pressing
you
know you know they you know you know
they they they can't push you because
you know it's
a it's a love situation so you you just
have to this you just you just have to
deal with it as
you you know that's part of the life
process so uh I'm not sure not you know
what advice I can give you okay so back
to
the so let me I want to show you some
some interesting things okay so many
times you have a bunch of files for
example
um uh what is this
oh did I
delete wait okay actually it's
here so sometimes you have a bunch of
files you know let me show you a command
okay I got this inspiration from Apple
because I was using a Mac so for
example usually you have a bunch of file
and you want to let's say send send this
bunch to a friend you want to zip them
so on Apple you can select a bunch of
files and click bundle them so they will
create a folder and put these files in
that folder in one shot one command okay
this is a new command I haven't seen
that before
so without that command you you know you
manually create a new folder and uh then
name is something then you drag them to
you know it's multiple
steps but now on emac I can do that okay
so let me show you so let's see let me
Demo some command Okay so some emac
command this is part of soft keys so you
want to make a backup of these files
okay just do it you see the selected
files you have a backup now you select
all your backup files okay you see the
red ones those are backup files okay now
you can call a command this is a command
I just wrote okay wait did I where did I
go let's go back to
diet and okay let's do it again select
all backup files so you can see the
command is
uh okay it's not shown there but the
command is diet flag backup files okay
you select a bunch of files you want
then you call the
commanda bundle marked files okay do
it so it says file move to this new
folder so
refresh there it is uh
refresh
what oh okay so wait that's wrong okay
so let me do it again
because
uh okay I so let me Demo another command
this command will move a bunch of files
to The Parent Directory so let me do
it C unravel directory okay so wait
let's go up here so unselect them so I
want every file in this directory to to
move up so essentially undo the
directory so unravel directory okay do
it refresh you see the I just moved the
file back so you go the into this
directory it's empty
now and now I want to delete all empty
directories so
call delete let's see Calla list
empty okay so now it shows you uh it
shows you that this two D is
empty now I can call S delete
empty okay now refresh you see empty
directory are
again now you call list empty D now
there's no no empty D anymore so now I
Mark a bunch of files backup files okay
I want to put these files into a
directory okay now
call S bundle marked files do it okay
refresh so now open this so you see it
moves all the files there by a single
command so these are some of the command
I wrote uh in the past week also so you
also have list backup for
example so in emac you can list back by
simply pressing the
to key okay but however it doesn't do
subdirectories okay so if we go up uh
for example all the backup files are in
this directory
okay and uh let's make some more backup
okay backup them okay now if you
call if you in emx if you press the TAA
key it lists them in the current
directory but not
but not in but not the backup files in
in subd directories okay so you can call
Sar list emx
backup okay so now you see it shows all
backup files in any directory and sub
directory too and now you can
call delete delete back uh emx backup
okay s delete emx backup do it it asks
you do you want to delete these files
yes okay now open the directory you see
now it's empty close it now
call delete empty D okay so refresh that
one is G too so these are very con
convenient
uh commands so so you can do all this in
emac now if you don't know you know you
might say what what if you know I'm A
bash expert or I'm a Powershell expert
yeah you can do it in Powershell but
it's more cumbersome
because okay so we R to because then you
have to use regular expression to select
files and if you made a mistake you
delete your files you know in emac it's
visual so you can say I want this
one I want this one I want this one
things like that you know sometimes they
are they don't have a regular expression
pattern uh so for example I want this
one so now you
can um uh put them in a sub or delete
them and things like that visual that's
the thing about
emac okay so that's demo of this command
and and I think that's about it there's
quite a few more okay so open uh marked
um open in text edit that's for the
Mac change file lineing style you know
on Windows Mac and Unix they have
different line ending
style convert convert file coding system
you know so you have
utf8 UTF 16 things like that you can you
can
like select a bunch of files and convert
them then you can so these are file
related move file to
directory okay so this command is also
interesting move files to directory so I
can press a key and for example when you
have a lot
photos uh let's
see okay so for example if you have a
hug bunch of photos some of them let's
say let me open them okay let's open
them you know some of them belongs to
memes some of them belongs to
programming for example programming
category memes memes memes programming
category mathematics category so you
have lots of your photos or and you want
to S them you you want to categorize
them so this one goes to me memes for
example or HW show this one goes to
memes this one goes to code this one
goes to Meme and so on this one goes to
math and so on okay this one goes to uh
what is
this CPU okay this is about
CPU so you you want to categorize your
photos so over here you can just call
the command and it'll pop up a list of
directories and you can enter so you can
you can categorize as you browse for
example let's move this I don't want to
show it because I have some personal
data B basically you can just now press
a key and you'll pop up a list of
categories you want to put to that you
Des you create yourself you know
different
folders okay so that's what this move
file to the command
is okay and there's a miscellaneous open
python doc you know normally when we
code python for example let me show you
uh s talk show what is uh this is s talk
show January 8th okay track
ball uh let's see what is this page ex
talk show yeah this is today
so yeah so normally when you code python
this for
example
okay print so print three so this is
Python and uh right so suppose you want
to look up the documentation for
print
so you know usually you search the web I
I do I have a command no I don't have a
command for it
uh so anyway so usually you search the
web but
python has its own documentation so for
example let's open python doc so just
call open python doc okay so you see now
this is local so and let's
magnify so uh you don't have to so you
know let's see uh what's new I don't
want what's new Python tutorial you can
you
know you cannot magnify anyway
so that's what this command is about
okay open python doc you have to set up
the path to the documentation where you
installed it so pretty convenient okay
so I think that's about it for for the S
diet
mod and you can also empty trash let's
see do I have yeah I don't want to show
you I don't want to show
that okay so fantastic okay so that's it
for today oh and this one is interesting
diet show all
sub okay let's cancel that let's put it
back so here you have a directory and
you have subdirectories lots of files
200 files here and this sub subdirectory
400 files so you want to list all files
including Sub in D
okay because styed allows you to
visually you know Mark or move
so there's no building command in emx
but you can now call
S
show all subter okay
Enter so it shows you
know S Talk Show and then you see then
the image directories
files lots of them and then another
directory file so you can show
everything in one shot so you if you
have a lots lots of Nest it does so it
also shows
this these directories so you can so
very convenient okay I think that's it
for
today yeah on topic on this
command so that's start
di mod okay you can pay me to get
it so let's read the comments and that's
it for
today so Eric says I don't know much
about what you do but it looks difficult
is what you do difficult and how much
difficult is it
well uh so if you are a programmer you
would know what I'm talking about
otherwise if you use a computer of
course you do then you also know what
I'm talking about when I'm talking about
this keyboards you know this data
hand so yeah you know usually my channel
is not too
generic
hello
uh
so what are you doing is it from work or
is it just hobby well if you are a
programmer you know what I'm talking
about because you need to manipulate
files and stuff but if you are not
programmer uh this is not for you can
you give me a okay so one so how hard
would it be to add pen support to
emac uh do all the drawings on image
inside emac that's not recommended okay
emac is just a text
editor although it does lots of other
things but usually text based now if you
want to do drawing emac that's that's uh
that's not recommended you know I I bet
you are you a emac user because usually
that kind of question came from those
who don't know
emac okay another question about why
don't you like Linux o OS okay that's a
question I talked a thousand times in my
videos okay and Albert says hello sir
I'm here to ask something I'm very bad
in math one of the worst in my class and
still learning till the evening do you
think it's worth to study it if I Circ
at
math well math is a very kind of
specialized subject a lot people are not
good at
math so if you are not good at math
don't worry about it go into some other
thing uh so of course math field is
related to engineering and Sciences
hardcore Sciences engineering
mathematics so you know what they call
STEM which is a edotic brainwashing
jargon anyway so math is a hard Sciences
part of so if you are you know but so
depends on you what kind of person you
are uh
usually you know they are Engineers they
are you know physics they are chemist
they are biologist all these are
hardcore
Sciences they these people may not be
very good at math but however they are
still in a science you know engineering
type of people they can do and they can
be
successful math is kind of the more
extreme you know I'm pretty good at math
but I'm
not good at engineering you know it's a
bit different you know
so there are s you know for
mathematicians that's very specialized
so they are not good as programmers you
know most mathematicians they are not
good programmers you know and they are
you know so those people mathematician
they study math or logic you know logic
is another specialized area few days ago
we talked about type
Theory so
anyway your question you know if you if
you are not good in math do you have to
study it no so no math study engineering
if you can if you are not into
engineering that kind of then you
there's lots of way you can be a
businessman you can be a lawyer you can
be you know there's lots of other things
you can
do okay so you don't have to so my
recommendation is that if you are not
good at math don't worry about too much
you don't have to you know don't there's
lots of other choices in
life uh okay that's it for today thank
you guys for
watching okay you second so okay so
rodolph
says okay rodolph is another guy
uh I Circ at math still love it that
means you don't circuit
math okay that's it that's it for today
thank you guys for
watching now if you like my stuff you
find my stuff helpful and stuff pay me
okay it's only money that gets things go
around okay like the typical YouTubers
they all say this is a time to say
Please Subscribe and don't forget to
thumb up and subscribe push the
Bell [ __ ] you that's that's that's
that's that some marketing is good but
YouTube This Money scums made it into a
bad thing so anyway the point is if you
like my stuff pay me okay pay Pon Amazon
gift card or
PayPal bye
guys we shut down in one minute okay so
let me clean up close uh what I'm doing
here
so s flag Keys okay let's copy that
make a
link
close now this
is mod this already a link this is s
board I already have a
link this is La board okay I have a link
this is data hand manual I have a link
already on my website this is s homepage
s code
close s board okay so I'm going to
do a review in maybe in two months
because I need to learn it and stuff
bye