good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of
sound talk show today is 2000
21st and today is july
18th july 18th six o'clock
in the afternoon san francisco time if
you are not going to go to san francisco
you take the train
[Laughter]
okay today we are going to do emac lisp
fantastic lots of uh tons of things to
do with these fingers i'm going to
change the world
that's you guys i'm too old so
emac this today okay so looking look
look at this
lisp machine keyboard
you have control meta super hyper
shift symbol this machine keyboard okay
so we are going to do so show today's
page we are going to code some
emac bisp and live and then we are going
to
uh random okay so your comments is
appreciated
type your comments now now before we
begin let me check if i'm
alive check video check audio check
indeed i'm getting better at this game
so
so today we going to do let's
let's begin the show okay we're gonna do
emac list
and and look at my notes page
so you have uh so what is it we are
going to do so let me show you the page
here
in the browser and you can see emac this
to do so uh
reformat split element right split
element
yeah that that is the one
okay so i'm going to copy that
paste it here so you can see my
emacs command course on the pink window
on the left
okay right so we are going to write this
command
uh write this command
and join
element okay so you can see
right htm html
split element and html join element okay
so actually the join should go first
uh okay so we're gonna do
the join first i'm gonna show you what
what that is about for example
so you go to emacs blog so uh you you
questions posted okay comment so let's
pop out the chat
here so i can see who is talking
uh one last check is my video technology
working
i think so okay oh there's a comment
great
if he has a view doc okay view docs
sucks donkey ass i mentioned that before
and it's coded by a guy who lives in
japan i kind of know him
by mel uh
yeah view doc the emacs emacs mod that
allows you to view
pdf in emacs inside emacs
uh that sucks donkey s in fact i can
show you okay
uh hold hold on a second let me let's do
this first okay
so i want to continue let's get on with
the talk show and uh
talk about emacs view doc
uh view doc that
is view pdf in emacs okay
we're gonna talk about that but first of
all let me show you what i'm gonna do so
go to emacs blog let's do some emacs
this coding first you see we got a bunch
of lists
here uh and here's the source code you
can see beginning
with uh this one emacs less known tips
so i've been working on these pages
so we got a bunch of list items i what i
want to
do is join these two you see join these
two for example
how you gonna so basically i'm going to
delete
this end ul tag and beginning url tag
delete them
so if you show in browser you see now
they are like one list
but how do you normally do it for
example you can delete backward word
then then delete two extra characters
that's one way that's no good because
then you have these
dangling you know half-assed characters
left there you don't know if your
html you you want to keep your html
always well-formed okay you don't want
at any time if possible uh have your url
more phone
more formed url so another way so you
know one way is just dd backward word
that's no good uh another way is if for
example i press two key compact
those lines together then i press one
key to delete
that single line and this works
but it's still a manual job so i want
the command so i can just call the
command
so for example put the cursor here and
call the command
and you'll just uh do that okay so let's
let's start to write that okay so let's
um
let's hope we can finish this in 10
minutes then then we're gonna
continue talking about lots of
interesting things okay
so uh so yeah so begin so begin the lisp
code
begin it begin at the beginning
different
so we have a emac list so uh what is a
command name we want to write
uh html join elements
so you know i i might change the name
into html merge siblings
okay at this point it's important to
understand what's going on
because html syntax is a tree
okay comments questions html syntax is a
tree so let me show you
these fantastic let me let me let me do
this fantastic
okay so let's screen capture let me
show you the wonderful
the wonder of the pain computing
okay pan computing let me
show you okay so i got this pen and you
go buy it
you go buy it
it's a lot of cables so it's not
wireless so
so this is uh huiong cheap
and it's fantastic works truly great i
think it's
fifty dollars or sixty dollars or forty
something
so i'm gonna show you pain computing and
i'm gonna you know i'm going to explain
what's going on with the
um the html okay so
so so so yeah so
so i'm going to start to draw so
you see okay so html html here
html is a tree so normally you have a
tree right so you have a tree
here is a root and here's a nod and here
is
a children you know so
when you merge two elements basically
what happens
is that these two elements are siblings
brothers or sisters
so these two elements so so
you want them to become for example this
is a new tree
you want them to become so this becomes
one tree so these two become smudged
into
just one single children so
the proper name from a tree perspective
would be merged siblings merge siblings
above
or merge siblings down there's a
difference
you see because for example you
because html because the way the syntax
it's actually uh ordered so the
children's are actually ordered so this
is
one second children third children and
this is first children
second children so so again so this is
root okay r for root
okay r o o t okay
so let's cross out cross that out you
can you can i can use the eraser feature
fantastic
pen computing okay uh and and
okay so again we label one
two three now what is that one that is
that is two okay so basically the first
one disappeared
so if we do it this way then the command
the proper name of this command would be
merge sibling
too much to the next sibling
so you have two of them much to the
previous sibling or much to the next
sibling or much
much sibling above or much sibling below
so that depends on where your where your
cursor is at
so that's uh that's our pin computing
okay so let's save this
let's save this uh save it as a
screenshot okay
so now let's go back no that's it for
ping computing and now i'm going to show
you
where you go by that you go buy that for
my website of course
so some keyboard blog you go down
and so recently i've been updating lots
of these pain computing
um technologies they are fairly complex
because
unlike a mouse you know a mouse the
technology is very
pretty simple i mean there's just
basically one or two technology
you know before you have a ball okay i'm
not going to explain but before
uh the mouse you have a uh ball just
like a trackball okay so
so uh okay let's let's wonder about a
little bit
and they explain the history of the
mouse okay
so this is what a mouse looks like back
in the 1990s
you know that's what i use so optical
technology is actually a great fantastic
technology
you know with the ball you have to clean
it like
every few months you know it becomes you
know you open this up it's full of gum
gump and dust
and so they get they got they get clock
clocked
you know so this is before 1990s
then you have optical mouse and optical
mouse the best example the the first the
basic the first one
thank you microsoft microsoft invented
it
uh you know we don't remember microsoft
as the innovator but microsoft
invented the first kind of okay at least
they made the
most popular in teddy mouse okay not
this one this one is the later version
so let's turn on let's actually use my
pen i can
this you know on windows the pen is
actually a great
replacement for mouse so you see i can
swipe with the pen
you know so uh so
did i turn on the javascript yes okay so
let's
play this video yeah so here is a
microsoft
ad for the for the scroll wheel yeah
they also
kind of invented the swap wheel now the
the classic one of this mouse intel
anyway i
i don't know if i have a page but anyway
that's the you know
1997 in teddy mouse optical
and not just optical uh but also
scroll wheel fantastic uh invention okay
you need a square square wheel so so
then
so then you have optical which is uh
infrared then you have started to have
laser mouse so i have all details what's
the difference between
optical you know what's the difference
between laser and
optical sensor optical sensor usually
means infrared
but anyway so mouse technology is uh you
know there's not
that many variations and similarly for
trackball okay
so anyway you see these gaming mouse
they got two sensors you know they got
dark field [ __ ] dark field [ __ ] and
whatever [ __ ] this gamer idiots uh
so so you know mouse then
trackball is uh technology is pretty
much
the same then but however when it comes
to campaign computing the
the the technology is very diverse okay
you
have you know i cannot even explain it
com total completely different uh
technology for ex
example your phone you know your phone
you use your finger that's usually uh
capacitance okay
touch screen capacitance then then
this then you have the digital paper
okay digital paper that's a
different technology that's not
capacitance okay
then you have uh okay so there's a
problem with a
vivavi uh browser you cannot swipe to go
back so i have to
that's a problem okay so i have to click
on that little triangle that's
stupid vavaldi so anyway so if you use
uh so
anyway so the pen computing
technology are very diverse and totally
different so then you have
okay display paper display ink phone
thanks to emily emily who gave us
supply this photo and then you have
drawing tablet and joint have a
over the years different makers
different brand they have
different technologies you know so this
is what i'm using
you go buy this one right now okay go to
amazon
and i i get a dollar or two so uh
you know and so i i highly recommend
this
i don't draw but i do write notes you
know i do write notes a lot
so for example
for
example i am m and you can draw
math so you need to actually you need a
bigger
so you can do mathematics so this is x y
axis this is y axis and this is sine
and and this is cosine
and this is fourier analysis
okay so this is fantastic don't save
that and we have a tree and
yeah so the drawing the the pen
computing technology is very diverse
then you have these uh
okay so this kind of thing you know
i was fascinated because you have this
this kind of pen
are the cheapest pen they are called
inactive pen
inactive that means there's no battery
in it inactive so this
essentially they are just finger
emulators so you see this tip
and also the the most common tip
i i don't have it i have it somewhere
here
oh [ __ ] that where did i put it anyway
the
common tip is a rubber tip and usually
when you use that on
enough you know it's uh too much
friction okay
so anyway you have this kind of tip and
also you have this kind of
tip but anyway this type of pen is uh
basically finger emulator
they emulate the electricity um
conductiveness of the finger
and they are cheap you know one or five
dollars you get two or some things uh
many many on amazon okay but then you
have these
active pin so there's a battery in it
you can see your light
so they they are you know made most of
the all these are made in china
of course then this you know if you buy
apple pencil the official apple one or
the microsoft uh surface tablet you know
they they are hundred dollars
but these made in china twenty dollars
thirty dollars
this one turned out is this sucks donkey
ass okay so it's the worst crap
it broke literally in 44
days you know when you read amazon
reviews you see lots of comments
a lot of them you know you look at one
stars one one stars comments and lots of
them say
say oh this book in in three days
something and sometimes these wonder
are these people who you know are they
real
but act but this one actually broke 40
41 days you know
one one day i plugged it in the you know
the
light um what's the problem
the button uh the button to turn on no
longer works
yeah it just happened one day i and it's
not because i i didn't do anything to it
so this one sucks okay so so this type
is um
active pin there's a battery in it and
uh
so this you use um you know this one
you can use on server surface book or
apple so
this so how do i know how do you know
what
this one works on surface book or apple
because apple pen
pencil apple pencil and microsoft
surface pen
they are not compatible so because the
technology is different
so anyway so there's this type then then
you have the
um by the way if you are using a
microsoft surface tablet this one is the
best okay renaissance
uh thirty dollars cheap instead of one
hundred dollars the microsoft one okay
so so this uh so this
uh so so then then you have the drawing
tablet okay which
wacom is the most famous you know for
for
30 years or 20 years but today you have
a lot
okay so it's fantastic okay so you can
buy this and use on any computer okay
so let's uh copy that let's copy that
and then paste in a talk show let's see
talk show so we we haven't done
it so any comments so i love you you
inspired my emacs journey thank you
thank you um
okay so that's the digression let's go
back to emacs this is something i want
to talk about
i forgot i don't know so how long i've
been talking
30 minutes 20 20 minutes already okay
so so let's go back to uh
code okay so code where is my code
okay yeah so we were talking about
drawing elements drawing elements the
where is it yeah so you have to
understand the tree
what are you doing to the tree
okay so the proper name so there are
different kind of names
so so now let me talk about the naming
issue the naming issue of function
uh function names or variable names in
programming okay it's uh
it's part of linguistics for example
normally you can say join
text okay so for example for
for this command okay so for ex for this
command
uh let's show the pink window so for
this command for example let's go to
emacs bookmark so i want to
remove these you know url
tags right so this command you can call
it
you can call it join text okay
or you can say join elements okay
or you can say merge siblings okay
s i b l i n g s okay so
this much siblings this naming scheme
is from the perspective or treat of a
tree okay
while these two you know join tags
is this naming scheme is from the
perspective
of syntax manipulation okay
so which one is best uh um you know
depends
so i might change your name but let's
not worry about it now let's
keep coding okay so okay let's
let's start to code okay so uh let's put
the example here
uh so actually let's write the docs
stocks
stream so let's escape
the double quote okay i have a command
escape quotes okay so that's uh because
you have
called inside quote you need a backslash
okay
so johnny
uh let's see join elemental tag let's
say
tag because tag is from the syntax
perspective
while the elements is from kind of the
dom
perspective you see so we have several
naming schemes
different perspectives
naming naming of things
linguistic interest okay
and okay so that's what we were talking
about
so now let's just say join tax for now
okay
now but actually joint tax is kind of
ambiguous
because we talked about you see you can
when you want to merge two children you
can
you know you can merge below or above
you know because
by default the children's are actually
numbered so
you want to say join tags below or join
tags
above
uh
let's say above okay let's just say
let's let's now let's now focus on e-max
this coding
okay so let's see so so join
the current element to the
previous okay uh then
let's say below actually e-l-o-w
join tax joint tax joint tax
um yeah let's just say joint joint tax
okay
join the current elements with
the previous one okay
for
for example
so if your cursor is here for example
actually cat let's
do this dog for example
that becomes
that okay
that's what we are writing okay so
so first of all you want to find so we
start to code this command
so first of all you want to find uh
what what is your current
[ __ ] this is gonna take half an hour an
hour
all this talking i mean starting to code
now is going to take an hour so first of
all
you so our cursor is here you want to
find
the current tag name
you know so now now we run into a user
interface
design issue so
one way to do it is you tell the user to
place a cursor
on the tag inside the tag then when you
call the command
you'll you know join them the other way
is to put the cursor between
these uh sibling elements
so which way is the proper it probably
should be between
okay
okay so uh actually
ah this is going to take 20 min 30
minutes at least
this is going to take 30 minutes
so any comments any any should should i
continue should i continue um
you know i i should i think
so first thing first thing you want to
find out what is the tag you are trying
to merge
okay first job
first find out what's
the tag you want to merge okay
so let's let's start coding okay search
for word
search for word for left bracket
okay then so let's declare two positions
p1 p2 search for search backward
actually
search backward okay search backward for
for left bracket okay
then
then um then get the tag name so
actually i have a command for that
uh so let's let's look at my command
because i have already written the
command
so let's go to html mod
let's go to this source code and let's
list this matching list
matching lines so these are all defense
and so here is the function we want you
see
so get tag name okay so get tag name
so let's jump to it so here is the
function
uh the function returns the tag name
yeah so
get tag name so search backward
okay search backward forward char
forward
chart one so that the cursor is inside
the tag
then call
so actually so forward char
um position to the left okay actually we
don't need to forward char
so okay so we need to it takes one
argument
the argument is point okay
you know search backward we'll put the
kuza
on the left of that character by the way
the the character is going to be your
i-beam so
e-max cruiser is actually between
characters it's not on the character so
so search search backward
then call then then we need a variable
tag name okay so
set tag name to be
that okay prettify the code
okay so so we got the tag name
so let's see so we got the tag name then
then we need to find out is it beginning
or end tag
uh i don't like let's not get too
complex let's just
get a draft version working okay let's
just get a prototype working
because i'm in a talk show i cannot
think too much
let's just get a prototype walking so
so we so we first
move here and we get a tag name
and and make sure that that should be
your ending tag okay
so so this matching functions
uh is ending tag
i have a command that tells me
is opening tag okay so here
so this command is opening tag
html is opening tag and what
uh tag begin position so what um
what argument does it take return true
if current tag is opening tag
self closing text such as hr
br also returns true this function
assumes your cursor is inside the tag
tag position is the position to the left
of yeah okay so so why don't we set
p1 equals to point so we can say
p1 here and then
we give the argument p1
okay is open tag p
set
okay so we know
this is open tag okay so this is uh open
or closed
we are trying to check you know whether
that is open or closed
it should be your closed so this should
be false
if it's open tag
um
let's rename that okay above above is
open text so we are trying to check this
tag okay
so if that is a open tag error
okay
let's just say tag problem
so arrow tag is not closing tag so you
see
we expect this tag to be a closing tag
so so otherwise continue
then we search forward twice
okay so let's i mean i just want to
get the prototype going so
search forward search forward
then search forward that
okay so we were
we were on
cruiser is currently here then
can you see because it's going here we
so you want to search forward
okay so we need another point p0
now p0 is the original position
of the cursor okay set p0
point okay p0 is the original position
of the cursor
now go to char p0
so we return the cursor to to
two here between the text okay so go to
char
point zero then search for word for that
okay for for the greatest
sign then our cursor should be
here okay and
and then search forward um
search forward for that okay
search for all that backward char
backward child move cursor backward by
one
okay then then
then our cursor is
is here then we want to check is
on okay
below so so let's rename the
above is open let me let me show you
okay he's
open tag above
okay now we need another variable is
open tag below
below means below the cursor okay so
set is open tag below
so we are trying to double check
if this
tag is a open tag okay
it should be true because otherwise it's
arrow
so it's open tag below how do you know
uh well you you call this function okay
okay so so then if that
is also true then we are ready to go
okay then we just want to
delete the tag then delete the yield
attack okay
okay
uh said open yeah his tag is is open tag
below okay
so is the tag open
below okay so is it true so
so if
it's true that that's good otherwise
it's a user error okay
uh okay so
okay tag above
so let's change name okay let's let's
let's change name above below let's
change
above to before
there there and let's change the name
below to after
fuzzing on semantics
do it do it
do it okay wait
why is it three times let's say
it's open tag before oh yeah so we
need to rename yeah so now
okay now is is open tag after
is that true i mean that's a variable
okay
now you check if
is open tag after okay that's that's
ambiguous
okay let's forget about renaming that's
not
so it's open tag after so if it's true
then that's good otherwise it's
error okay so it's true so what else
what do we do
then we now
delete the
tag below yeah
so
search for what
okay p1 p2
p3 p4 let's name the tag this way okay
so you see the tag we are concerned
about
is these four i mean these two tags with
each tag has a beginning and end
position
so i'm going to name these four
positions
like these okay so here's p1 p2
then p3 p4 okay the cursor position is
p0
okay so let's rename rename
our variables okay shrink p1 p2
p3 p4 okay so
so the first one is p1 that's right
okay so so so the first one is p1
then p2
then okay then search forward
that okay
then you have p2 then
go to char p0 which is a cruiser
position
then search forward
that okay
then set p4
okay then search backward
that then set
p3 point fantastic
okay so we got p1 p2 p3 p4
again let me remind you guys the tags we
are concerned is
mostly just these two and we need these
four positions p1 p2
and p4 and p3 okay
so we first of all get the point
positions properly then we
then we do the code okay so so we don't
we no longer need this
is open tag after so is open tag
before so actually we don't need
is open tag before p1
that checks the p1 is
open tag that's that checks p2
he's open tag before he's open tag after
okay wait that's p3 okay
so
so if
so you need all okay all statement
it's open tag before
true
and or
is open tag after
so either one of these conditions is an
error okay
so here is a statement to check
the open tag before
okay this is probably confusing but uh
but if you are coding you know you know
what i mean
so if either one of these case is true
is it's open tag after
then it's an error okay user error
okay there it is
otherwise it's we are good to go so
so now we delete the tag okay
yeah so so so so so actually let me let
me do this way it's
simpler okay let's do this simpler
if let's not if when
okay when
okay so this is what we want okay that
and
okay so actually it's pretty fine okay
so this is a good error checking
now if everything is good now we start
to
do things okay we start to do
things here
now we start to delete the tag okay so
how do you do
you first of all you go to you want to
delete the bottom
tag first delete this one first
so p3 and p4 okay so it's easy
delete region
posit position 3 position 4 okay
then delete region position 1
position 2 fantastic oh jesus
we did this faster than i thought
possible
okay okay here's our code
okay now you know the documentation is a
little bit
verbose but it's necessary you need to
have
examples because it's quite confusing
with the opening tag and closing tag you
know
but uh but i think that's it that's it
let's think okay i think that's that's
right so evaluate the buffer
so now we have the function we can
actually try it now okay i forgot to
show the pink window
so actually we can try it now so let's
go to
uh emacs blog so let's work on this
okay so you can see we're gonna work on
them on those first so first of all
put the cursor here
call it meta x okay you cannot see it so
let me put it here okay call it
paste size html join text
do it oh it worked
you see you see so let's see undo
you see you see the difference and we do
undo
redo and do we do fantastic
one shot coding no trial and error
that is kind of my style you spend one
year to study the problem then you just
call it one shot
okay so but you see it leaves lots of
spaces so let's try another one okay so
you see this
element this list and this one you see
now we want to delete merge these two
you know so i can call this command
sidechain html join text do it
it did it but however there's you know
it leaves empty space
you know we can add some cleanup codes
so so that you
automatically remove the empty space but
let's leave it okay
so let's leave it so actually let's
continue coding our code do it
do it do it do it
so merge all these beasts okay now
no okay so there's one more here do it
okay now compact the spaces let's
manually
fix the empty lines okay
then show in browser you see now it's
very compact before each one is a
an ordered list now it's just one
unordered
list with all the items
okay fantastic we did we did this we did
this guys
finished now copy the entire code
delete it go to talk show
go to this talk show here's the emacs
code
paste it there show in browser okay
now it shows like garbage because we did
not escape
the greater than n less than equal sign
but
let's do it now let's make that
you know you see you see it adds these
uh html
entities you know very complex
you know entities html entities is a
escape mechanism
but now if we show in browser it's
fantastic you know you see
it now it's even colored okay
that completes today's main topic
and actually we did it pretty fast so
you know
and we rambled about other things so
that's one thing well we did it okay so
anything else
am i still talking are you guys still
watching five people
six people okay six people and uh let's
check
obs audio check video check
okay i'm done with this this code let's
talk about something else
random okay
five people watching oh yeah so dark
view so you want to know about dark view
emacs dark view it sucks
okay just don't don't use it basically
it sucks
uh let me explain okay so so hold on a
second let me clean up here
where are we so we got a talk show we
got
uh we talked about drawing tablets uh
technology
let's let's let's put the code at the
bottom okay
so okay yeah so we talked about
showing browser we talked about drawing
tablet technology
we talked about mouse technologies
okay copy it
mouse technology
tech why is it not
expanding [ __ ]
okay now you see we have a situation you
see we need to merge
this unordered list into one
unordered list so we can just call our
command you see
what i want to do is you see i want to
merge delete these two so i
call out command x html join text
fantastic
oh there's one more okay uh
okay now you know so this
command join html tags tags is going to
be part of
html mod
okay so so let's talk about dark view
okay
who is asking didn't
conclude okay dylan
conkling okay so
so yeah so so dark view let me show you
my page okay you go to
emacs tutorial emacs tutorial go to
emacs tutorial
search for pdf uh
search for wait what what search for
view okay
type vi ew okay so you have view image
file
uh you know you can view images inside
html
and even gif okay let me show you this
is funny okay this is
microsoft clipper in vim
you can also view gif animations in
emacs
you know why don't we show you uh so we
open this page
search for gif for example so
here is uh for example let's magnify
so you can you can see here is the file
vi creepy assistant okay you can open
the file
you know that's a file and
but
you can show it to i believe you can
show
animation so describe mod
i forgot what's the you can go frame by
frame
you know increase speed decrease speed
transform reset
image whatever you know the one of the
issue is
in e-max is although it can do lots of
things but you have to figure out
so image increase speed so what is the
command to make it animate
i don't know you know i don't so in in
general you know
so basically the doc view or image
viewer in emacs is that something
occasionally casually if you want to
casually view an
image in imax this is fantastic for
example
you're looking at you're looking at a
image directory so every one of these is
images for example i can
open it and and actually i customized my
keys
so that i press right arrow you see the
next image in the directory
so you can use emacs as an image browser
fantastic can you do that in actually
you can do that in vs code as well
yeah and this is uh svg okay that's why
okay uh [ __ ]
svg funked it up so here's the svg file
so anyway so
you know you can view images in emacs
okay
but you actually you can do it in in vs
code too so let's call the command
vs code open console opening vs code
so let's see what happens there it is
okay close this one yeah
so there's your image okay so in vs code
the thing about vs code is that you
don't have to think you know you just do
it
in emacs you have to this you know years
of trouble to figure out
you know how to do this or that so in vs
code you can actually go to the
directory just by clicking that
uh wait let's click on that
and i don't use emacs i don't use uh vs
code so i don't
no but anyway you can just uh what is
the source control
new file open new folder okay so you can
actually
open the new folder and
open this folder okay let's just say
select folder
do you trust the authors of the files in
this folder
yes why are you asking code provides
feature that may automatically
execute files in this folder what no i
don't have search code
yeah trust orders shut the [ __ ] up okay
so you can see
here is the image directory so now you
can just uh
press use the arrow key and hold and and
and
or you can click you know to go to you
know
so you can also use vs code as an image
browser
so but anyway you want to know about pdf
so in this image directory do we have
any pdf
no okay so i need to go to another
um by the way you can also
view them as thumbnails okay let's
you know call meta x terms okay let me
show you
meta x thumbs in emacs okay
so show it yeah
type plus to display more images
what yeah okay it's not working yeah
that's a problem with emacs you have to
figure it out
okay so anyway let's let's show pdf okay
so let's close that
close that close that um
yeah i didn't talk about opening pdf
files because it
really it sucks so bad so i didn't
include that in my tutorial i don't
think so
i may have wrote about it i don't
remember
so let's go to my keyboard directory
okay
so you can see keyboard block then let's
go to
uh let's go to a image directory let's
see
yeah so image directory and there is
[Music]
some
you know so here's images okay so now
let's
view this in microsoft um you know
the folder explorer
and hold down control
v l
extra large icons okay so you can see
all these are images and some of them
are pdf for example this one
the bray browser okay let's double click
so it opens
in bray browser so it's a pdf now let's
try
to open this in emacs okay
so copy the file path
shrink the window back to emacs
open that file path okay which is this
one
right so search for pdf
there is the file okay
cl shows xpm layout you know this is the
inventor the creator of the
mechanical typewriter about 200 or 300
years ago
so he wrote something so let's open it
there it is okay
you know actually you know you are not
seeing the pdf because actually because
in my configuration i turn it off
because every time you open pdf it
takes a long time for emacs because what
emacs is doing is is it is
it is trying to convert the pdf to an
image file
then display those image file which is
uh
idiotic you know if you really think
about it that's a
extreme idiocy if you are any company
and if you claim oh our products support
viewing
pdf but actually what you do is that you
you turn you convert that pdf to an
image and display that
your company will cease to exist right
away
okay the customer is gonna say go [ __ ]
yourself you [ __ ]
that's but but in emacs that's okay oh
yeah the free
freedom you know that this is what
happens that you know the
you know because emacs is a code so when
people see this situation they don't
they don't feel it's bad they think oh
fantastic emacs and even
display pdf okay let me show you this
let's
uh let's actually view the pdf so
so what you do to view it i turned it
off myself in my config okay so but
to view it you say meta x um
view doc okay stupid command names okay
uh dark view
wait do we have a dark
dark view mod okay there it is
dock view mod okay let's try it
do it
type cc to toggle between editing or
viewing the document why is it not
showing
yeah maybe because i'm on windows
wait wait this is still fundamental mod
okay so
actually wait
uh it says stock view but why is it
uh what what is stock view mod okay so
actually let's
describe function let's see dark view
mod
is an auto auto loaded interactive
compatible
major mod in dark view buffers hello
braveheart
so guys comment
dylan so dylan do you have a question
about dark view
i mean what do you like you don't know
how to use it or
what is it uh you want me to talk about
so you say stock view mod is an emax
document viewer
it displays pdf ps which is postscript
uh and dvi files you know those are 30
years old stuff
very few people use those these days
uh and you know you see it says here as
png images
so it converts pdf to png first okay
so let's see dark view i want to get it
to show pdf
that but how do how but um i don't know
on windows is um
so so so dylan are you still here
dark view mod why is it not
i don't know why is it not showing
the pdf
describe function
tank view mod image
next line
okay dark view first page let's try that
command
wrong argument type this p t
yeah okay let's go to
you know let me try actually to get this
to work
okay so let's go to my exhaust settings
okay
search for dark
dark view okay yeah
uh let's search for pdf okay pdf
so by the way yesterday i we did a uh
anac says you you don't have a clue
about dark view
yeah but didn't is asking the question i
don't know if data is still here or not
so pdf okay so let's look at pdf
run current file okay i don't care about
that
let's see
so where is uh
so okay so let's go to my other innate
directory search for pdf
there it is you see here is my setting
that turns it off
here okay so you see this line
open p open pdf files in hex
mod because i don't want it to start to
convert the pdf into images
it slows you down and it freezes emacs
so if we uncomment out this line now
which file is this emacs init
file association okay so let's say we
comment that out
actually yeah okay so let's say we
let's do this okay hold on a second
instead of comment out let's just say
pdf
let's say dark view mod okay i have a
brief
annoying okay let's
evaluate that and let's go back to the
pdf
file
where is the pdf file [ __ ]
so let's go to keyboard go down
go to the image file path
so there it is the file let's open it
okay
dark view mod
cc type cc to toggle between editing or
viewing dog
cc cc
it's not doing nothing
anyways uh so do i still want to try
that
let's let's try to get this to work okay
so actually so let's
try comment this comment this out
okay now quit emacs relaunch
so i just removed my config file to
prevent
viewing pdf as a you know a
doc view so now here is a pdf file so
you can see
let's open it open max
dock view mod yeah i don't know i don't
know why it's not working on windows and
i'm not gonna you know it's it's not
good okay
but if you know instead you want to do
this instead okay so let's start
let's start casa command mod so you can
see all my commands so i just call
command open
in
and wait the command is just open
you know opening external app okay so
here's a command you can see
then it opens in whatever whatever the
default app to open
to view the pdf which is much better you
see this is the real pdf viewer
in a browser actually you know in these
days
since about five five or ten years ago
every browser
can view pdf every browser becomes a pdf
viewer
and the way they do that is that
actually the browsers
use contains javascript code
so the pdf viewer is actually written in
javascript code in the browser
i do i think i remember seeing the code
actually so
you know i can actually show the source
code you know if you just look into the
browser's directory
so every browser you know chrome and
also
you know well
firefox also firefox uh
both of them you know any chromebase or
firefox or or even microsoft edge before
chrome
[ __ ] or blink uh before the blink engine
they they all can view pdf
you know they have a javascript code
okay so that's it for that
okay thank you guys for watching now
support my work
okay pay me paypal or patreon or
whatever you know give
gift card or whatever amazon gift card
buy my emacs tutorial
okay that's it bye guys