good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today September
3rd
Tuesday
2 o'clock p.m.
San Francisco time
and
good morning Beth Lemieux
so Bethany says today the topics is
coming free to be number 10 functional
programming style ok do I have that here
ok right on time yes
bathroom you the
non-mainstream
so function programming style
ok
functional programming style what took
what to cover about that topic
ok style my style okay yeah there's
quite a lot to say about that
functional programming style and my
particular
take on functional programming style I
have to think I have to think about like
what to cover though because
of hand
yeah so we can talk about
about that topic programming style in
general maybe
so so who else is here so where is
Neutron bathroom you I got five people
watching good morning everyone coming
and typing in the chat say hi so I try
to be not
stutter or Rambo too much and focus on a
topic I don't know Haskell really okay I
don't know has gone either but we don't
need to know Haskell to do functional
programming
ESCO ESCO is the new kid in town and
every
every hotshot is like oh you if you
don't know Haskell then you are not good
program you know that's fashion that's
like pearl pearl in per days you know it
it's a trend but Haskell is actually a
pretty old language good morning good
morning
Cody Oh Paris
cameo Claudio is my longest fan
Thank You Claudio
for coming and crow do I need to send
you my Emacs tutorial update I haven't
been I have
how many have not been regularly sending
it out you know so I'm going to send
that out
so Claudia what's up so oh my god I need
to cough
this is bad I need to learn how to mute
then I can hack the hell out of it then
her a second time
okay I'm back so crow do
no problem thanks so Claudia so what
what do you do are you a professor or
you are programmer right I know I am
pretty sure you are programming are you
also professor or something and
you are in where you're Germany or Spain
so anyway we need to talk about
functional programming
yeah so styles and program is now is I
need to think about like things I need
to say I want to say
do nothing this is a Firefox bug so by
the way limited mission D so I have this
Firefox plug-in what this plug-in does
is remove duplicate tabs for example
typically I work in Emacs let me start
saw start command log mod okay so you
can see my
Emacs commands on the Left window and
let's move these down
Oh
Claudio is spacing Spain so what time is
it in Spain so let's see 3
11 o'clock p.m. around there
so he gonna talk about yeah so Haskell
is actually a pretty old language you
know because I been reading the
frequently asked questions of functional
programming and functional programming
languages a new scoop back in 1998 you
know even before 1998 you know before so
so before you don't have Wikipedia
Wikipedia began in 2002 you know and
that just it it began 2002 or three then
it's not good until you know at least
five years later it becomes better and
better actually but in 2003 there's
nothing it copies my website yeah you
know how did how did I learn about
Wikipedia the first time
because back then I I look at all the
people linking to my site you know you
have logs you know I haven't been
dealing with Apache logs for four five
five seven years anyway back then that
you know you'd be check my log I have
analysis of my log okay let me show you
language let me show you my articles
about that
one language to rule them all
to rule them all
now this is about
let's see we can find it yeah too many
articles there
one language to do them all or what
language to use for Find and Replace
okay this is a long article
yeah so you see back to shell bag
after you learned Perl you you are a
master of Perl and you also learn Python
and
but it turns out you know they they are
situations you just go back to shell bag
shell you know a UNIX shell bag because
I analyze the situation I think you know
it actually
I
you know it's
okay let me write let me talk about this
good morning iris so so you see so back
ok anyway
keep on track of what I'm talking about
so hold on a second functional
programming style ok and program is
style in general ok find something to
talk about that and
Apache logs ok and
one language to do them all and
has cow yeah Haskell the h of Haskell
old you know
ESCA new scoops
news new scoops
FAQ
functional programming ok that that's
that some of the topics we are talking
about so Apache dogs so yeah so back
back then yeah the the first time I'd
found Wikipedia so
first time found Wikipedia
so I the first time I found Wikipedia
because it links to my website so what
website is this one this is the most
popular back then on my website this
project a special plan especially a
visual dictionary of special plane
curves this is this is the most popular
page of my web page from 1997 to
you know back then you don't have that
many internet so Wikipedia copied my
conic sections well yeah they copy and
they say oh you're sauce sauce you know
they rephrase you know things like that
that's that's the first time I found
about Wikipedia so that's one thing say
and this you know this is a
visual dictionary of special plane
curves math very interesting so if you
are you know if you are studying
calculus if you are into math this is
worth checking out although it's it
haven't been updated for over ten years
one of my plans to replace all these by
JavaScript right now it's not you see
these in animations it's in gif I
convert you know before that it was in
QuickTime QuickTime is a pause video
technology were the first video
technology that that made video popular
is from Apple you know that the
technology called QuickTime so QuickTime
is the most popular video technology
from 1990s to mm you know mm throughout
not today today's you know so Apple
created QuickTime so this this is
creating you know so I generate
generated this animation back in 1995
but you know video technologies such
that you have the format of the file a
kind of meta wrapper container format
then you have what's called codec codec
is a
specific way to
encode animation so you have different
codecs and they have different
properties some for example these kind
of images that's you know
computer-generated just figures you know
plain figures and stuff there is one
codec that's best for these you know
meaning smallest size and the most
clarity no fuzziness no segregation so
that's one codec and there's other for
example today you have MP MP 4 you have
you have several you know and browsers
doesn't support you know Apple Safari
support one chrome support is this that
Firefox support you know things like
that so anyway and this code I was using
is
deprecated so long ago because this is
created in 1995 so about five years ago
I converted all these QuickTime movies
to
give animation so that's why the you
know that's what you see these are gif
animations so you can see these are
generating a lisp you know you know what
it is a lisp you know the mathematical
details is extremely interesting I'm not
going to go over it but you might check
it out if you are into math and you can
see from these animations there are
several ways to what they say construct
a lisp
put in put it in another way this is how
you can actually draw as a draftsman you
know you can actually draw it is
correctly accurately how can you draw
that basically they rely on mathematical
properties of the lisp and this
animation you can see how it is
generated if you actually look at it you
know study yet you know just look at it
and think for five minutes you will see
how to actually create a you disp
so that's and this here is another one
that it that is why all these curves are
extremely interesting you know for this
one this this one is called
Archimedes trommel okay this mechanism
where you have a power sliding on two
different bars this mechanism is called
Archimedes trommel and
it's a engineering mechanical
engineering device so for example it
converts
rectilinear motion to circular motion
okay
and and so if you have this uh
committees Tremmel and you put a point
on the bar and you you you know you go
about sliding at that point will trace
out a lisp
so again this this this is true because
you know the fundamentally because the
properties of the lisp there are so many
properties hi you know extremely
interesting and for for example this one
shows that
this one for example you can oh
there are so many if you see here is
another way to generate a lisp now when
you look at this Elise ellipses pictures
you might think oh they are just say
oval shape nuts not so you know see in
math everything is very precise you
don't just draw an oval and co-ed Elise
you know for it to be this
it has to follow very definite
formulas you know it's not any shape
like although it's just it is well for
example another way to put it is that
Elise is the result of these formulas or
equations
for example this this is the most
popular this is algebra equation but you
also have parametric formula this one
you know B sine T then y equals to P
sine T and X equals 2x equals to B X
equals two cosine P cosine T and y
equals to a sine T that's how you
generate a lisp by a this is called
parametric equation or parametric
formula
so anyway that's that's this animation
so also if you have a cylinder and you
just slice slice it that shape you know
that shape is actually a lisp you know
this is very interesting and also and
there
there is a paradox
I'm not sure I should go into explaining
that so we are digressing should I let
me know okay oh oh let's go back because
we have several levels we already went
into different topics
so so that's that's some of the
interesting math things is that so
that's my website oh we were talking
about codec quicktime movie formats so
let's write it down
quick time
apples apples quick time
that made video
digital video popular
okay and
video
has contained formats and
codec
you know codec codec is extremely
complex you know at one time I looked
into like 10 years ago I studied all the
codecs not not in detail I mean I just
studied what are the format's are there
its and they change all the time that's
one of the technology that that changes
every every three years every five years
the new ones coming in replacing the old
one the new ones are much better and
stuff
okay guys guys comments okay comment and
okay codec so we were talking about
let's get back to our topic okay so
let's copy that released so we talked
about that
let's previous page previous page
previous page oh I want to go to
so what was the topic before I post
QuickTime yeah the first time I found
Wikipedia it's because
they linked to my conic sections page
and okay about Wikipedia you know I so
how did I find out who link to my
website because there's Apache logs so
you know I've been you doing Apache logs
for over ten years and
then you got this article let me show
you what that is about
so close that show in browser and one
language to rule them all so when you so
what happened with this sharp shout back
you know of code is that you have you
know you use
so you have a patch log what Apache log
is just lines each is a hit he so-called
hit meanings someone get a fire or image
or a CSS file any of that it's a hit so
for example in this page this page page
is got the text file the HTML file
that's that's one hit then it's got HTTP
it's got CSS for example let me show you
so this is the source code you can see
here is a CSS file you can open the CSS
file that CSS file so if you visit this
page
the Apache log will log you know this
file path the this file path it will
also log the CSS
file path because you know it is send it
to your browser but that's it for this
page because there's no images but
otherwise if you have images then that's
also another
log entry so when you visit a page
usually they are 10 or 20 you know hits
lines in Apache log so typically in a
day you have millions of you know lines
so when you want to do statistics I mean
I mean you want to find out who visited
your site things like that
you can you know you have to analyze all
each you know process the log so what
one way to do that that very basic you
know Pumas ways to use UNIX UNIX to
shellbacks so you cut the file you grab
it then you grab grab something else
then grab something else that's not
there then save it to a file so let me
show you this line ok that's a typical
UNIX stuff
so let's go back here so guys comments
okay comment so iris Kashia says you can
show the requests opening developer
tools in a browser oh
right yeah and okay I see what you mean
but that's not for the server I mean I
cannot use that to see who this is my
website
but
but yeah I think I know what you mean
but I mean if you are studying HTTP
protocol you can see you know the
request headers and stuff in in a
browser console I have a tutorial on
that of course yeah why not let me show
it
okay so this this would be JavaScript
you go to so by my tutorials you know
I'm telling you guys oh you guys and all
the people watching out there you know
that's I got the information here so
here's JavaScript in depth Dom
for example there's a article on cookies
what does cookie means you know cookie
is one of the worst technology major one
of the biggest hack and
the biggest hack hack that won't die
it's it's been 25 years now and it's
easy it's extremely inefficient it's
very bad but it's kind of just keep
going on it 1-1 tie so here's a
technical details about cookie and HTTP
protocol headers
so let me type that
javascript in depth not close that okay
that's too big some more larger and make
this spash okay you see this is
bash code okay I mean I mean I mean this
is Emacs stuff so I can color it then
also vinca fire showing browser
so you see that and we want to we want
to talk about
-
well
cookie Oh HDTV protocols okay that that
is here so
that's that's that's
tutorial on HTTP protocols and and you
can see how to use the browser to get
the response header and request header
and so on okay so back to the shell
thing you know
one language to route your demo so I got
this shout thing you can see in browser
you see
so you you know you can a file you grab
for two hundred two hundred means
success you know the the file transfer
is success so you only grab those lines
then you grab forget because some other
request is like what's the other one
post you don't want that you add you
know you just want people who visit your
site you don't want people who try to
forms you know the theater for most
stuff so you get you get forget then you
grab - V - capital e to theater out
these things these things are parts you
know Scott's gedcom
yahoo.com
google.com but you know MSM calm this is
old you know this you can see those
names MSM yahoo those are
in 2008 so okay so in this this this
share to bag is in 2008
you know so you saw to see history you
know Scott Scott net.com I don't know I
forgot what that is but that's some of
the you know such engine parts so you
feel future out parts then you save into
a fire okay then
then what do you do then then you take
that file
okay for example this line what does
this does listen I do so you take the
input file you cut cut is a tool that
you want to only get a column so you
want to get the sixth column then you
sorted then you remove duplicate then
you sort it again
then save it okay so so the result is
all agents agencies a idiotic jargon
from these hacker types what does agent
mean agent mean just browser okay
they do but you have to call agent
otherwise you are idiot okay you have to
it's like a man hackers you have to
otherwise everyone say oh that guy is a
idiot [ __ ] idiot see this program
hacker types UNIX so agents very bad
terminology what the worst jargon okay
when you know so there's a question what
is a good jargon that's the science you
know you say let's say you approach that
topic from a scientific perspective so
what are the properties of jargon you
want it to be communicative you want to
be not a pig you want to be easy to
understand you know communicative you
know and and you want to show this
better than long things like that how
you judge your jargon
so for example a jargon a pig jargon
like agents you know is a jargon such
that when I mention the word if you
don't you wouldn't understand it unless
you've studied it you know but on the
other hand if I say browser
then you understand it right away anyone
you know understand right wait then
that's a good jargon of course there are
other things for example people would
you know the these hacker types they
will say oh but agent has more
generic broad meaning that those are
idiots okay
I'm not going to go into the jargons
what what what makes a great job in the
science of jargons the science of
communication the science of Newton the
neuroscience of human recognition like
recognitions abilities you know that
that's a science that's actually a
branch of science you know how you
perceive how you learn you know that
that's the thing so I have a
section about jargons this this section
jargons of software industry when
programmers use joggins such as kit did
a cyclic graph has common ad htdp idiom
potency this home homeo iconicity they
don't know what which side is mouth
which side is ass that's programmers
that's the hacker types the UNIX
philosophy type of people they love that
they always use this idiotic a pig
doesn't make sense joggins you know
there's a there's also a criteria like
when does a jargon I mean we talked
about a little bit about what makes a
jargon good okay what are good jargon so
what are bad this is critical because in
science for example rocket science you
have tons of jargons early math but you
know you need to have char guns that
people in this you know that you have
good properties things like that just
just like programming code syntax you
know they are there's a science to it
not exact science but there is you know
aspect it's not
whatever you say you know it's no it's
not whatever sounds good or whatever is
fun you know the great quirk UNIX Fox so
anyway that's about the science of
jargons then there's another aspect
about for example what makes a jargon
popular this is related to what makes
something go viral you know everyone is
interested in that today you know later
down on Twitter social social networks
in the marketing departments from Google
you know they all want to know what
makes something go viral because
because because
that benefits you when you become famous
that benefits you so
so so what makes so back to the jargon
so what there's this a thing you can say
what makes a
jargon popular among these UNIX hacker
these hacker types you know those people
who love UNIX philosophy you know Linux
you know these hacker types what makes
it
popular there's one
that is if the chief if whatever the
jargon the word is is hard to understand
and has some kind of a pun
that makes it popular okay that that
that is one of the things for example I
can give you so many examples Monad okay
clue what does Kuno stand for Kuno is
not Unix oh it's a recursive acronym
post the fact you know the English in
literature there's no such [ __ ] thing
but the programmer idiots the glue you
know and a lot you know they they they
create invented this this concept of
recursive acronym so whenever they say
they expand grew they all say oh by the
way that's a recursive acronym and all
the the idiots or the hacker idiots oh
my god that's so deep it doesn't exist
it's just created by these people hacker
idiots monad no there's so many okay so
I got actually I got this year list
comprehension lambda ripple crochet
Corrine tail recursion a synchronous
okay a synchronous is not exactly that
that that thing but anyway so tell
recursion then what are the others
yeah basically the the the top those so
each one I I actually explained them
what they mean and what and why ain't
that so jargons is a big is a great
topic in property speaking is part of
linguistics when you studied linguistics
with respect to communication
you know there is a big thing about
joggins and and also many other jargons
regular expression lexical what does
lexical mean it's very
there has many meanings and least space
has hygienic marker and the jargon data
by type often times very confusing
because datatype
my hand is a structure it's a data
structure on the other hand it's one of
the type of a programming language
you know so it can mean both things you
know depending on the context but
usually you get confused usually
usually you know you know typically
usually you don't want the jargon that
means many things when you when you need
a concept that needs a name you don't
want it you don't want to pick a word
that has many meanings
usually okay the the the unique meaning
is the best you know for example then
you have object okay object is the
ubiquitous jargon every language has got
object okay
so that's an example where a word has
10,000 meanings you know that's not a
good jargon but but object also
for example I have this article the
meaning of object in computer languages
the object in Java
means one thing okay in fact the Java
language do not have the
technically do not have the concept of
object now now correct me if I'm wrong
if you are a Java programmer for 10
years I think you know I'm pretty sure
that Java language actually there is no
technical definition of object you know
there is technique you know like we are
talking about the language SPECT
so what is there there is reference okay
but there is no object and there is
anyway I mean I mean ambit may be
incorrect but anyway so I forgot you
know what I wrote there so in Python
class object means entirely different
thing than then then the Java okay then
most interestingly in JavaScript it
means something else entirely do I have
a JavaScript here
JavaScript yeah JavaScript object so
what services javascript object but
basically it's a hash table okay it's
like a dictionary with inheritance
mechanism it's entirely different from
Python or Java and this also you know if
you Emax this not manual okay he also
has lisp object you know they'll say
object object this this this and this
object is again entirely different from
all the others what is this object this
object is basically a binary blob that
is when you have list code you run it
whether interpreter or compiler you
would rewrite that that block that code
expression becomes the object okay any
any expression it just becomes this
object so so in this object is is simply
just whatever that is become compiled
you know it's just a you can think of it
as a binary blob it's with whatever unit
of expression that has been compiled
then you just call it object it has
nothing to do with all P you know or
classes or inheritance nothing
everything is object every expression
becomes object okay that's least object
and not you know in C language also has
object I don't know C so someone when I
was talking about these someone wrote to
me and this guy I trust I talked about
him before he's a old Asian Emacs user
Nick o'clock if you search net his name
and such my name you will find I talk
about him I've talked about him on video
before but anyway he's a expert master C
programmer he called I I think this is
public information because we talked on
Google+ so he works for Oracle in UK he
lives in UK and he's the expert he's
he's one of the great expert I respect
so whenever he says something I listen
and learn things anyway so so he
explains what is object in C
so anyway that that's about object the
jargon so we're talking about
we're talking about several digression
same things recursive digression so
we're talking about software jargons of
software industry and now let's go back
to one level up we are talking about
these shellbacks
this shellbacks
okay this way you Paul River in shows
yeah even you point linked to my website
I
think I think maybe I did I link to my
website oh oh I forgot I don't remember
the details Oh in stumbo you know do you
guys remember stumble
guys do you guys remember you remember
Stumbo Stumbo is this website it's kind
of like Reddit not not that great a
there's one another one before that it's
a link bookmark it basically it's a
website where you put all your bookmarks
there
Stumbo a pound yes that's a stumper
that's so I love you you know so I think
they are still around right I haven't
seen that website for ten years over ten
years I haven't visited so a lot people
you know Stumbo a pound a link to my
website but there's another one before
stumble upon there's a link you know
they closed down they know this they so
to to Yahoo I think then Yahoo [ __ ] it
up then he shut it down then the
original guys spotted back but it never
become popular I don't think so
do you guys remember this is around 2004
you know early 2000s yeah there's a
popular web site that gathered you know
this is like good you go there and put
your interesting a
book book most books mas there [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] are us wait link are us
deserving a bit pair link link like they
delirious there it is tedious
you know this is an era where people use
clever domain names I believe it's fair
like this they mean type it again
DL and
first okay the
u.s. something like that so DL i o
u dot s something like that okay so
let's let's search see what we find Oh
delicious okay I
got mixed up with T devious
let's go T devious
the icy IOUs okay now you need to put
the dart in proper places
delicious you said he suggests that
okay I hate this AT&T my
my internet provider they
okay let's go to
something go to DuckDuckGo and paste
here so Claudio do you have a question
for me or anything because you know
like if you have any questions for me
then we I can't say it now
because I don't know much about you but
I do know you for a long time on I think
on Twitter or
email
so okay i we actually so we digressed so
much that we did not begin to talk about
programming styles well I think Bethel
mu is still happy about that that's okay
so
so we
yeah so anyway so back to this so what
about these shellbacks oh I started to
do these to process my Apache log and
this is this way it turns out very
convenient very convenient but then I
start to wonder you see here's the
question you see because in my mind back
ill even disrespect 2008 back then even
then you know we programmers have a
thought that we want you know the best
language you know one language to rule
them all and I've been programming Perl
for over four years you know from to
1998 and so on and I saw so I know per
well and my opinion back then was that
Perl should replace all these [ __ ]
UNIX packages you know the shower oak
grab you know replace them all I could
remove them from Linux from from UNIX
okay didn't expect then you see us a
UNIX you don't say Linux okay so we move
them all these shell back tools you know
because you don't need it pearl pearl
replace them and you know you have one
single language more powerful a more
coherent okay that's that was my thought
you know but every time you know the
Linux people these UNIX for us of people
every decision when there is a decision
everything they do they don't agree with
one I have okay they don't like that
they don't they don't do that
so
so so anyway did that never happened
also there's so many history in the
shell becomes ash because in order for
Linux to start up quickly uni -
my roommate is back or something
anyway so my thinking was you know so I
started to write these shellbacks to
process my Apache log and but ice I
wonder you know so I suddenly I wonder
why am I writing all these lines of you
know idiotic shout grab stuff long
battle I why can't I just you know what
happens to the idea like that you know
since I am proponent you know pearl I
know so well why not write the whole
thing in pearl because usually we
program us you know those of us who like
languages a lot we have the idea you
know we just want one generic language
you know what what's the best generic
purpose language and so I think I
thought about this issue it you know it
turns out doing this is actually the
best way you know just line by line to
get what I want this is this is actually
the best way but you see but why not
convert it to Perl I can of course I can
but it's gonna be exactly just like the
shell because you don't write a some
kind of a library or functions you don't
do that you actually just you want the
line by line kind of thing you know each
one just do one thing so if yes I can
convert this whole you know lines to
Perl but but it's basically just just
this imperil in power crow thing that's
all you know it's it's line by line so
that's so that's here I found that
interesting that's
so cold claudio says you know what's
your prefer best generic programming
language
well i
right now for industrial coding that
that probably would be :
so : yeah i talked about that a few
times in my videos
let's see well let's see let's just
quickly show that language tutorials
yeah : for indoors industrial coding
okay but otherwise my favorite language
is still Mathematica so go lines here
otherwise my favorite language is
mathematica these glorious beautiful
hyperbolic this is so called hyperbolic
a darker
darker Hedra yeah hyperbolic donna
hydron okay this is a mathematical logo
for Mathematica version
2 and it's my favorite Mathematica logo
this is back in 1995 or so and by the
way there's a quote from rich Hickey the
creator of closure he says every
developer should buy a copy of
Mathematica because it will expand your
mind
that is that's that is how great
Mathematica is
so this is my favorite language it's a
symbolic
computer algebra system with symbolic
pattern matching and essentially it's a
lisp it's kind of you know some people
say the least and right okay you know
why mention this I hate so much of the
list phonetics because every way because
they have a good language but they don't
you know the modern whispers let's say
since 1990 so the this you know it's a
big thing I fight with a lisp up with
these phonetics they call me a troll and
every every way that Lisp is good good
for they don't understand it you know
they don't get it don't get that least
this phonetics [ __ ]
especially the common business I so much
despise the common dispersed I mean
well that's that's that's a lot you know
to talk about this anyway goal and I did
a video to last week ten ten days ago at
least several of them good ones pretty
good ones so if you guys like to check
it out
oh
my Mathematica tutorial actually I don't
really have that much I mean I don't
really have Mathematica tutorial what I
have instead is some kind of
essay you know on the fly one or two you
know fry you you know you could learn
something from it but it's not it's not
like a coherent tutorial to get deep
into Mathematica I don't have I don't
have that
yeah so
so you you you you have Mathematica you
use Mathematica right
so we got digressed so much let's so so
let's finish that so this article we
finished talking about you know the
about the question about the paradox of
one language to rule them all
now let's back to let's go back to the
meaning the meaning of object in
programming languages jargons of
software industry HTTP protocol get
cookies set cookies and the shell and
visual dictionary was special plane
curves
one language to rule them or yeah and
okay Apple QuickTime okay and
Pesce okay has cow has cow is a old
language because back in 1998 you
don't have Wikipedia so you have what's
called new scoops new scoop is kind of
like forum you know like a reddit you go
there talk to people new scoop and the
mailing lists and and
they are allow the info there are so
much great info because for example
there's a new scope for functional
programming and then you have this thing
called FAQ okay which stands for
frequently asked questions back then FAQ
is is like today's Wikipedia like today
every time you have a question you go to
Wikipedia back then everything is FAQ
there are hundreds or maybe thousands of
FAQ you if you search every FAQ archive
new scoop FAQ archive you can still find
them
new scoop FAQ archive or just search for
Wikipedia then you'll find things you do
tell you what it is about so
here is this yeah this website is old
it's like at least 15 years old use
Usenet FAQ archive so you have tons
these are fa Q's these are created by
people you know like like us we go there
because some some questions like which
which one what for example what are
functional what functional programming
languages are out there you know people
want to know you know so people who
started to you know I know something I
say Oh Mathematica then someone say oh
there's a scar then someone say their
screen you know
you know so eventually you got the
answer proper correct answer and then
people start to archive it so all these
are the code so that's why they are
called frequently asked questions they
are created by people typically experts
those are fantastic and the subject
matter ranges from programming languages
you know for example there's one
functional programming let's try to
search it
functional programming
the idea is okay the odd [ __ ] [ __ ] the
art of UNIX programming that's from ESR
so okay it should be on the first page
it's not showing up you know the because
this gets old they fit right and
supposing a bit rod and you don't you
are not sure for example if you are not
sure if you click on something that's
actually the original because there's a
lot you see I have I have ads turned off
let's try
let's try if they have ads you know
they've maybe they are ad ridden yeah
well there is ad there it is
anyway the
instant you see this search is not FAQ
anymore it goes to on the other websites
money money is talking here hey I pay
you hundred dollars a
week you put my things here
[ __ ] and [ __ ] open source open source
made this happen
anyway so there's anyway there is a
functional programming FAQ ok and
25 years ago so Haskell is pretty old it
only became popular in 2008 or so ok
this new generation of programmers they
think they think that's the best
anyway
Haskell
so back to so that's
one language to them or so
so we are getting
we are getting back to our engine or
topic Apache logs ok programming style
ok maybe we can start to talk we can
begin talking about programming styles
and function ok it's the house right now
let's see it's already 15 minutes ok let
me read the comments and it's
okay so Gus iris iris Garcia says how
can you hate eunuchs that much and use
Mac OS X OS X which is Linux under the
hood that is an FAQ there are two parts
of it the first part is how can you hate
UNIX so much in the Mac okay
it's it's intertwined two questions okay
one question is about me so why do I use
Mac basically what do I use Mac the
other question
that's embedded in that sentence is Mac
OS X is a UNIX okay let me tell you that
is a myth that that that is one of the
UNIX philosophy UNIX people are nervous
because you see this is common this is
frequently
seen behavior okay folks okay let's see
you know it is so common I have essays
about this I have tens of essays about
this because UNIX people for example
when they when they see Mac for example
if you are open source okay if you have
a free software foundation phonetic then
Oh Mac is no good no don't never use a
Mac but meanwhile you are also typically
a UNIX lover lynyrd Linux lover right
then when you see a Mac oh yeah Linux is
so great UNIX successes is so secure is
the most powerful even even the Apple
Mac they put Unix in
in a Mac you know even a Mac adopted
UNIX you see it's a it's kind of like
biased because that you know let me for
example they make in contrast let me say
another thing x11 okay
let me find the article let me see what
how can I find the Allah cop
sorry x11
let's see
how to ex how to start x11 that's that's
one of the esoteric UNIX [ __ ]
okay so let's see sorry
UNIX pestilence
okay let me let me give you a contrast
to the Oh Mac OS is great because even
the Mac's adopted UNIX okay so here the
UNIX pestilence you know this is a very
famous book back in 1990s very famous
it's but you know UNIX haters book okay
you have to read it you know anyway so
this book they criticize UNIX in many
ways and the UNIX haters book there's
one chapter called x11
by written by Tom Hopkins okay let's see
if I can find it x11
okay so not there let's see
okay let me just say it you know so
there's a chapter on x11 and you know
another thing Santa a UNIX has problem
Santa on PS you know the the the the the
the process PS to hell especially also
eras and it truncates your lines the
[ __ ] trunk Adrian eyes silently
because UNIX that that's what UNIX
people do you know yeah UNIX philosophy
kiss keep it simple so if the line is
too long it's just just silently cut it
off after 80 characters [ __ ] UNIX and
that's part of the UNIX philosophy
so everything you you you you if you
have a file name that's more than 200
characters you know then you tie it then
you and ha you your line scan your name
is truncated that's UNIX that's the
traditional unix for over ten years it's
been 20 years is like that fact the UNIX
and I have detailed documentation on all
these all these I just mentioned you
know the
truncating of tar the truncating of
lines on PS on Solaris especially and
extremely [ __ ] up the option argument
syntax for PS you know for example PS
bsd unix you do PSA eww yes
it's like it's like part of my muscle
memory now even I haven't typed it for
20 years PSA u WX w WX okay let's answer
so there's UNIX you type that too to get
all the processes
you know including root and stuff I
forgot exactly but anyway that's what
you type
hp-ux or the the AT&T UNIX you do PS -
EF okay
and what what about Linux they merged
okay you see you see the this one you
don't have you don't put the - but this
one you do but only nerds today they are
merged so you try to do man PS okay
actually we can do it here
magnify let's see man PS okay
you see you can start to read it but
actually let's do it in Emacs because we
do we live in Emacs so
PS okay there it is PS you know PS
ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba you know the these
synapses synopsis my ass this
incomprehensible nobody read it synopsis
okay so description the PS utility
displays a header line followed by lines
can any information about all of your
processes I have control in terminals
then look at this paragraph a different
set of processes can be selected for
display by using any combination of - a
- G capital G lowercase G - PT as stuff
okay so this this is actually BST wait
yeah this is VST let's see
yeah this is this is PSD
PS okay this is not the Linux PS if you
are Linux marks type it you know PS you
know man PS you they start to explain
the merge you know or the
you know the the BSD and AT&T UNIX
command options it's like convoluted
incomprehensible [ __ ] that's UNIX that's
this this is this is the beauty of UNIX
philosophy does it do it one thing well
no
every tool does it does describe to grab
well no does find you know the fact
finding X actor do they do anything well
no because if they do one thing well
then you you don't need the grab - are
what would you need are for because if
you know going into the directory you
don't need it because you should use
grab with a combination of find you know
let's do one thing well you combine them
but most of the time every tool every
single Bay almost every single one of
the UNIX
command I [ __ ] they do not do one thing
well in fact
they cannot something you cannot simply
cannot do even when it's typical needed
that's and that is why in UNIX then you
have the new versions you know the BSD
versions the AT&T version well the the
the reason they are BSD and AT&T because
there's a commercial split you know any
anyway then you have the glue versions
you know TV which is usually entirely
different from the PSD okay because
Google version they try to improve it
then the new people start to invent you
know - -
you know for example you can start Emacs
by - - no - in it yeah I think that's
that's right you know you can history
you know you know you know free software
foundation they started - they created
invented the - - notation the the the
reason is that that so that it's more
readable okay anyway it's it's an entire
mess because then when you have - -
then some options has - - version some
doesn't and then some all yeah so so as
opposed to every every - - - - option
has a corresponding one - option if
that's the way then simpler because you
know but that's not the case well anyway
so and and of course the Gleaners people
that the bsd the many branches the set
of the unix can they disagree so they
they don't follow that you know they you
know they for example in leanness the
the guy who created Lena says you know
they have a article on programming style
you know see for the nino linux kernel
they say
you know about programming style first
thing is to get a copy of the new
C coding style
and
and take a lighter and burn it
that's what Lena's said
do you guys remember yeah
let's let's try to search that that's
fun Lena's C programming C style guide
okay let's see
let's see if we can still find that you
know the the social justice has taken
over and you know things or things may
change they are not what they used to be
so let's see why there's such for burn
there it is okay first off I would
suggest printing out a copy of the new
coding standards and not read it burn
them is a great symbolic gesture okay
these hacker types you know they
disagree
this is written by Lina's Lina's Lina's
yeah he he is one of the you know
mouthy chat you know when one of the
talkative
dramatic programmers but I I like I
think he's a good guy okay now his stuff
doesn't interest me you know he's a he
rather typical of the UNIX type people
you know they like C they like C++ they
like the kernel stuff they like to talk
about memories you know references
pointers you know they like they like
those things on the other hand they
never ever talk about for example
symbolic computation proof systems
correctness you know the the the
theoretical computer science they didn't
they never talk about those things he
did and and math they never they never
tell you something about Matthew C so
the here here is a different style of
you know
personality kind of the style of
programmers but these are the main UNIX
type I I despise them
but dinners you know but but I respect I
like his personality you know he he is
famous for you know swearing all the
time
abrasive I like him [ __ ] those people
who doesn't support him
anyway so that's that's
Lena's you know on on the programming
style so
okay so that's another tangent so back
then so let's go back to the previous
topic we were talking about unix options
and we were talking about
okay once I didn't write it down I
forgot what what became that topic
actually so I need to read I guess I
need to read comments
so hold on a second how long I've been
talking okay so let me take a break
read the comments and
so why are we talking about options oh
yeah okay so that's because PS PS the
big flame war ma'am here's okay
ma'am PS and UNIX philosophy okay oh
yeah I remember
UNIX philosophy we need to finish this
topic this is critical UNIX philosophy
you know the Mac OS thing okay so let's
go back to this page okay UNIX
philosophy I mean the UNIX pestilence
okay so there is this book I mean so I
created so there are many problems of
UNIX right I criticize you know I and
you know they they call me a troll I've
been fighting with them for over ten
years mostly in 2000's and so every time
when you criticize UNIX for example in
this book now there is a famous chapter
about X 11 which is the worst technology
the worst hack in the universe in a
history of programming what what is the
was hack x11
written by dong Hopkins okay UNIX
pestilence quote quotations let me see
if I can find it
x11
okay I actually wrote about it here so
it let me read it when UNIX problem is
described for example in a UNIX haters
handbook then the Unix Linux phonetics
reaction are often like this
well that's not Unix that's x11 okay oh
that's not Unix it's just the file
system you should switch to a better
file system okay oh oh that's not Unix
that's shell nobody is forcing you to
use tcsh okay use zsh okay these are the
typical UNIX people UNIX fill in
phonetics their reactions when when some
part of UNIX is criticized okay then
another one you idiot the problem you
described is tar just change tube note
ah okay there another way well good
point but that's not Unix set forth it's
the mark ternal the mach kernel okay so
you see so what is unix that is the
question you see when peoples you know
when unix when when linux unix phonetics
they see mac they they are thinking
ottoman automatically is oh you necks is
so great even Apple have to adopt it
okay that's but when when when UNIX is
criticized
trying to pinpoint a good example that
contrast that
you know so so anyway so I guess you get
a point you know when when when people
criticize x11 you know all these tar or
this shell or bash they say oh that's
not Unix that's not Linux okay Nina UNIX
is a kernel okay then there's a distinct
distinction distinguish this
distinction between the kernel and
whatever UNIX two bags on top file
systems you know the shell the x11
windows systems you know then they say
although those not not unique you know
eunuch said oh you know things like that
so you know this happens not just to
UNIX people I mean as I talked before it
happens to everyone your biases your
whatever you like you know you tend to
do that unconsciously that's that's
that's a critical thing unconsciously
you know when you see a Mac oh yeah even
Mac Apple has to adapt Unix well when
you see you know when you read this book
I've seen you know I've talked to you
know UNIX argue with them for over ten
years you know like sometimes you read a
blog and after you you know used you
know Linux phonics phonetics UNIX
phonetics they read this they blog about
Oh today I came across this book and
they then they you know like they write
a blog then they say oh yeah but that's
all correct but actually you know many
things in x11 today has improved so and
also by the way x11 is not Unix you know
they honestly you know
you know that's the opinion
so now it's not all UNIX then and then
you go to slash of you know slash
slash start hacking use reddit you know
the UNIX forums name then you say Oh
unique UNIX is the greatest because x11
it because it's got X 11 X 11 is the the
system that
you know the windowing system that you
know they got slogans I forgot what but
it's supposed to be a network based you
know that window greatest
OS agnostic
windowing system crap you know it's the
worst hack in universe yeah you guys
should read that article okay don't
don't Hopkins he's got it on his website
dumb hop Kings
he's he started to follow me me on
Twitter a few months ago but I know him
I have wrote emails with him ten years
ago long longer than that oh yeah so he
started to put his this thirty years old
article on medium so you should check it
out X the X Windows disaster yeah that's
a title and today you know it's been
thirty years now thirty even more more
than thirty years well in anyway since
Nina Linux came up it's been thirty
years and today as you know the Linux
people they are all trying to replace
exterior but now people understand how
sucky x11 is but they are trying to
replace it but they can't because it's a
whole package of you know compatibility
you can just
replace it's a problem it's a problem
thirty years ago it's a [ __ ] me it's a
[ __ ] problem thirty years ago but the
link Linux phonetics is a UNIX file and
phonetics you know the UNIX philosophy
[ __ ] if they think it's a greatest thing
since sliced bread
let's so that's that's my UNIX hatred
that's how deep because that's how deep
I hate the UNIX the the you know the
UNIX philosophy fact there's no basis
scientific basis whatsoever it is just a
code
it's a pure is a code
so okay so now I
read the comments in that that's it for
today I think I
don't know if I did good or bad you know
it's all rant and that's kind of part of
saw talk show so maybe that's on the
spot you like it or maybe you don't
so SEMA says it's it is it better to
call it dysfunctions many times or
should the output go into a VAR
using that inside non-interactive
functions
but that depends I guess
in general it's better to put into a bar
you don't want to call function many
times yeah because that's much much
slower much much slower maybe I don't
know exactly how much but let's say
maybe 5 times 10 times stole yeah if you
can if its proper you know if you have a
choice like you you're not sure just put
everything into a bar save it as a bar
then to whatever don't don't call a
function many times
so iris ace but multiple browser can use
the same agent
how do you mean yeah you know sometimes
I'm ranting and framing so it's not you
don't don't take it for granted so you
know some technical details but in
general my my stance my opinion on
charges
you know I stand by that you know you
shouldn't co-agent you there's no reason
there's no good reason just go ahead
browser okay like typical the argument
against that is that oh but browser but
some agents are not browser but because
these are that email you know some other
things so form or whatever yeah but
people understand okay just say oh
browser
the browsing app just say browsing app
okay
that is you see that that's a that's
communicated people understand you say
agent you know agent
you don't know what don't know what the
[ __ ] is agent you know youyou mean FBI
agent but precisely you know why people
love the agent jargon so much you know
from these hacker types precisely
because it's difficult to understand
that is the reason that is precisely
reason then it becomes so more than more
hacker type so you know college student
who think they are hotshot they we'll
use that face because you know it's a
part of human communication it's a
behavior you know they use it because
use it signifies that you are in group
that you have you know read stuff you
know you signifies to whoever you argue
it you know that's how community grows
you know that's that's part of humanity
once you realize that you know but you
also you know
anyway
so you have to speak Latin to understand
jargons I would imagine there is an en
island in Chinese either
English equal sign what do you mean I
don't know what you mean
so entry entry says good morning entry
can you make a video about OD emotion
Dodgers no I don't know nothing about it
you know I'm usually I usually I'm the
guy who don't know nothing about
JavaScript framework or libraries
you know I tend to but I know the
JavaScript language or the Dom very well
but I don't know about all these
libraries
high-resolution real-time spectrum
analyzer oh that seems very interesting
and useful you know and every time I try
to learn them it's a headache because
then you know the MPM okay yeah yeah for
example for example this this looks
interesting to me so I try to you know
use it although yet first step is NPM
then you know you don't you try to
install I downloaded that and then this
library actually download a hundred
other libraries [ __ ] I don't want that
immediately I don't you know I don't
it's a problem I don't want to use it
ever that's okay you know JavaScript
frameworks disturb you Java JavaScript
communities like that you download the
thing it download literally I'm not not
exaggerating some some of them many of
them download 100 other libraries and
some of these libraries are lines for
example there is the library of one
function five lines to trim stream
this is a space of JavaScript script
community
they have reasons of course but in
general my opinion of them is no good
so entry says a logarithmic frequency
spectrum analyzer made in JavaScript
yeah it's interesting
yeah I don't know anything about it and
also I don't actually know much about
the math of
spectrum you know analysis that don't
know much about that
petia Padilla says what do I each day D
now I'm living with roommates and they
work in restaurants and sometimes they
bring me Chinese food and they cook you
know they are Chinese from Thai from
China okay they are not programmers or
in some sense they are illiterate so
when you talk about programming you have
to understand that did they have no idea
what did they don't know what is Google
okay okay they don't even they don't you
know they made they have heard of oh
this Google is some company that's
that's all is because like typically the
programmers we we don't get we don't
understand
the degree the level of how average
person like don't know what you are
talking about like they do they don't
know there's a distinction of why five
and and the phone network like like we
program us know right you know phone is
wrong you know Wi-Fi is Wi-Fi that is
different I mean you don't even have to
know the technical details so these you
know they are different but they don't
they don't they don't get you know they
kind of and not you know they don't get
they don't you know and you try to
explain to them it's impossible you know
it's like it's like trying to tell your
mom to use emacs okay
you know you don't even begin you don't
even begin so they you know so they have
to eat Chinese there's sometimes cook
and they cook for me and
otherwise I eat bread and milk typically
like like the video I've shown famous
video like seven years ago
so bathroom you made a claim about a
kitten
what's the context
pajama ever laughing too much I forgot
the content the context okay so don't
remember the name
delicious yes not really I enjoy hearing
your talk okay
about everything Andres is such P 5000
dodges yeah okay I don't know anything
about it why is coding so why are we
talking about that about curves think of
something like that
so entry says why is coding trained why
the coding train didn't make a
logarithmic frequency analyzer on p5.js
I
don't know
Kody haces what's your preferred best
general programming language okay that's
Golan in Mathematica I need to check out
my thinking okay so
how can you hate UNIX okay iris I I gave
my aki-nee on that
you know so I argue with UNIX people a
lot and for me it's no big deal I mean I
don't you know it's not it's friendly
argument okay but I do realize something
I don't either have noticed some people
they don't take it that way they you
know yeah some of these UNIX people they
don't take it that way
you know for to me it's like okay you
present your opinion like these people
you know these hacker types on you know
on forums you know they are not you know
they are not you you know they maybe you
think they are oh they you know I swear
all the time they don't swear you know
sometimes you see a new scoop they say
how can it possible this is new scoop
this is all the scientists and the
engineers gather to discuss in
subproblems how could you you know
sometime comes in and swear and like you
know like sorry you know this is like
out of the out of the is crossing a line
no it's not causing like go [ __ ]
themselves you look at the way they talk
they flame each other all the time in
swearing to you know for example Python
versus Perl or you know this person
versus you know whatever they [ __ ] go
cutting throat each other with each
other all the time then then you come up
with someone saying
you know this is a forum where
scientists engineers gather to solve
problems how idiotic cannot be I
don't do that you know so this I usually
do this in new school in any public
forums I never ever do it on a
private or meaning is some kind of more
private private face I don't do that for
example on Agnew Emacs death
mailing list okay that's that's the
place where all the Emacs they've
gathered they talk every day you know
about Emacs death and I've been there
you know two or three times maybe three
times total in total
you know I know what you a lot of people
are thinking oh you are trying to you
know go there to throw nothing like that
I don't [ __ ] do that I don't like the
trance concept of the TRO I don't like
you know I'm rather you know as many of
you know me kind of like foam foam Oh
like I find it even annoying like
sometimes people start to anyway I don't
I don't throw okay I don't like that
concept you know but I do but of course
I know I'm swimming and I'm being
dramatic often and why do I do that
because I [ __ ] hate this these
hypocrites do the UNIX philosophy or
this or this you know hypocrite you know
I [ __ ] hate them so like like the
Richard Stallman said fighting fire with
fire that's his way what did you know
what is that that is the GPL that's his
philosophy you know why do you create a
copy you know copyright copyleft you
know a license what you needed you know
if you are really for the good of
humanity just put it on the open public
domain that's the law that that's a
legal jargon public domain where anyone
must be published code anyone can take
it without attribution or to whatever
with it public domain that's great of
humanity if you are a great you know a I
think a person you do that and you get
no credit whatsoever whatever you know
it's like donation you know when Google
Big Shot or some Microsoft Bo gate they
donate but the then the building is
named after them because you need the
name you need a name and yeah also it's
a taxing same something you have they
have reasons you know to donate but
typically it's true when you donate you
want your name there because you know
that's that's part of that you know
that's part of the human thing but if
you want to argue about that you know
about this being good the felon
philosophy you know the best thing to do
donate anonymously you know that you
know you have a 1 million you want to
donate you know just just throw your
money out nobody knows who you about you
that that's that if you want to argue
that is the best thing so same thing
likewise if you want you know for free
software put your code in the public
domain without your name just just you
know you can do that
that's not what people doing this today
you have on github or this major you
know project it's hard to find a name
you know like they have a generic name
for this you know even for example match
it magic the very popular Emacs package
for for doing get ok
so match it you know so in terms of
others almost all projects for example
the audio motion let's see audio motion
did is say who who created it
ok so there's a licensed by by this guy
okay so anyway typically you go to this
github you okay yeah this guy actually
has his name but typically you go to the
so pencils you don't find the name but
is it true that they are truly anonymous
you know truly good for Humanity no they
you know that you don't find them is
kind of like like the convention the
tactic you know but actually they are so
eager in their resume in elsewhere you
know in some other way they are eager to
say oh by the way I'm the author of
magic okay this happens across every
major project
but by the way magic I like the guy who
created magic the the maintainer for the
past you know five or ten years I know
him on Twitter sometimes we had the
exchange I think he's a good guy so
yeah the you know he's on Twitter and so
on the he's a maintainer of magic
so actually we should stop it's like
what is this
okay so yeah so that's it
one more question also if you have
posted then that's it
how can you hate UNIX yeah so math dot
log ten
okay I think is more about units
philosophy archetypes
I don't think mac OS would be based on
Linux you know Mac is not Unix in every
way you know it's hell you know you
could say the only thing UNIX is the
mach kernel and well yeah okay so you
have the shell back you know it's like
what how you define Unix okay actually I
wrote a poem
I need to show this one this is this is
important
UNIX pestilence okay to do okay so when
Mac OS come out it's a big topic because
everyone Mac Apple itself has
advertisement about open source you know
they like they they have a giant ad I
have it somewhere here okay let me show
you so that's the topic I want to show
you they have a big idea at
advertisement you know basically say
something we are UNIX the the most solid
foundation in industry
you know they sell to these to you guys
you know who
Linux pants you know UNIX fans back then
and meanwhile you see it is you see
there's a conflict of interest on one
hand you are like for a free software
foundation or open source you are very
much you know
phonetic okay on the other hand use you
love Unix Linux okay but Apple they are
not in your free software they are not
open source so you know you know but but
then they are UNIX so that you have this
you know conflict it's like there's a
candy you know whether you want to eat
it every time you eat it you get a shock
you know that's what happens anyway so I
was trying to find Mac OS okay so Mac OS
let me show you the article yeah there
it is Mac OS 10 you know when it came
out you know there's okay so I wrote a
poem I was fighting with the Mac
fanatics okay this is another thing so
you you have open source phonetics free
software phonetics you know Foss then
you have the UNIX phonetics away or Unix
Linux then you have the Mac phonetics
you see this different camp of peoples
you know they don't agree with each
other but sometimes they intertwine you
know so I was fighting with the Mac
phonetics so what are Mac phonetics you
know you you probably know you know you
have some opinions for your own
perspectives about the Mac phonetic
these people you know they always have
the the latest Apple product you know
expensive they are typically well-to-do
you know they have money they can buy
things fighting with this Mac phonetics
so I wrote a poem back in 2002 when Mac
Mac OSX came up so there it is Apple OS
X one of those you next beauty and
beasts new UNIX complex I love Apple o X
I hate all Unix now with OS X
love-hate amis the sea of phonetics
Eunice's and open source beavis and
butthead making all the noises
think different us voices clamoring all
over places beauty and unix
marries in peace in my dream OS there is
no unix beauty and elegance without
phonetics
so anyway so that's that's my poem about
you know fighting with the Mac OS
there's a Apple ad I'd like to show you
I don't know if I linked here
so there is a essay on the question is
my Mac OS X Unix you know that's a big
you know dramatic topic everyone you
know this yeah and there's also you know
clickbait articles from this website you
know they do they are or talking about
this is mac OS unix because you know
it's a one of the critical question all
the unix phonetics need to know they
need to know is mac OS consider the unix
you know is it
there it is apples add back in 2002 this
is you know taking the UNIX phonetics
you know
since all other since other UNIX boxes
to dev know okay you know if you are you
know and and you know this is Mac OS X
in 2002
you know this is running what is this oh
three windows grab us on top
you know so Apple you know is trying to
get you open saucepans to you know take
you over to a poor land
okay that's that and that's that's about
it for today
hey thank you guys for watching
see you guys if you like my stuff donate
PayPal patreon stuff oh my I'm on on my
website you can you know click find it
so
bye
check okay I'm just a knife