hello welcome to another episode of sun
talk show
so today we are going to do
um
very fun stuff okay so we I'm we are
going to code emac Beast python
JavaScript Golan and fan language we are
going to code a find and replace program
okay so given a directory you know 1000
files we're gonna test on uh 2000 files
also let's say one thousand files and do
find replace so multiple pairs of find
replace so you want to find for example
all uh all the world lists to something
else to python
find replace okay so we're gonna write a
script in all these languages to find
replace and we are going to compare
their speed
okay now I suspect I suspect
Golan will be the fastest the second
fastest will maybe uh emac beast that's
what I suspect emac Beast for finding
replays will be faster than python
JavaScript
and wufan language
okay and go might be faster
uh okay so that's what we are going to
do okay so this is gonna be fun it's
probably gonna be more than one hour uh
90 minutes maybe so let's let's begin
and let's try to do it fast okay
okay let me uh Focus let me uh let's do
this because I wanted to do this for a
long time find replace which language is
the best now emac now wolf fan language
is probably the easiest okay once you
know Wolfram language
the the but the most flexible and and
powerful and easy to code
the most flexible and Powerful for text
processing would be emac bisp okay
and go
go language here will be the will be the
most cumbersome because you have to
convert string type to to a slice of
um
uh
to a slice of uh
what's what they call
um
run okay to a slice of your own data
type basically which basically means
Unicode characters so that means
basically a array where each element is
the Unicode character so you have to
convert the string to that data type
and the reason for that is that string
in Golan is just a sequence of bytes
and immutable but because you are doing
fine replace so you need them to be
mutable because otherwise it's going to
be extremely slow every time you do a
fine and replace it's gonna recreate the
entire string so you don't want that you
want to convert in in Gola and you want
to convert the string into a array of
characters Unicode characters so
and in utf-8 and so it's going to be
very for each character it may be one
byte or two two uh four bytes
so it's not the most tedious okay Golan
let's hope we can do we can finish this
okay if you have comments and questions
uh posted okay uh be relevant and also
um also if you are watching offline you
know you might want to play at the
Double speed or something so because
this is gonna be a long one
so find replays so first of all let's go
to Let's uh find uh let's go to the um
the text the directory we want to find
so we are going to use emac list menu so
emac this manual you just go search
online you'll find it uh in a download
downloadables zip file uh ZIP file
version okay so it's gonna be
um
1000 Pages emac lisp so let's copy the
directory here okay so let's uh I hope
to do this quickly we can time time them
and compare the speed
okay so first
um
and when you do now one of the things
critical in this comparison speak
comparison is that find and replace not
just fine not just web because
if you just want to do grab there is no
mutability involved you don't need to
change anything
in that case the the fastest is the
code uh silver or something you know
there's several um
several uh new web utilities like Unix
web okay so let me find my uh
so I'm just going to go slowly uh
leisurely okay
so crap let's search for grab rip grab
okay rip grab is the fastest so you know
I have several articles you can learn
about rip grab
rib grab has a fat fatal flaw that is
this guy refused to make his program
into a finely place you know he just
want to search he don't want to because
he think you know according to him he
says that it's too complex to do it
right I think he's just chickening out
Andrew gallon you know a great
programmer but he's
chickening out on a task with some kind
of obsession with some kind of extreme
excuse saying that oh once you have once
you want to do you know find and replace
then it's gonna be too big a pop too big
a problem too big a project too big a
complexity complexity to make it right
so I think he's chicken chickening out
but in terms if all you need to do is
just fine then rip grab is the fastest
okay there are also several others in
the past 10 years Arc silver and and so
on so
actually we did uh you know I looked
into rip grip in depth and I think I uh
also did the video on that
um anyway find replaces my thing because
that's uh because my website you know
7000 HTML Pages all manually written
like like you see every day when I'm
doing live stream so since they are
directly in HTML so
I have two for example this topic box
that topic box exists on every page
you know
and for example let's open let's open
another page okay so for example let's
randomly open this one what is this a
text file okay so HTML
so you see this panel
navigation panel exists on every page so
that
so when I want to change something in
the navigation panel I have to to find
and replace on a thousand Pages or
usually a few hundred pages
so that is why find replace is critical
for the way for my system for my web dev
system
uh you might be thinking so why don't
you use some kind of JavaScript or
variable you know I tried them all they
are not good you you want them to be
static so you want them to be oh you can
paste it on template if you base it on
template you know some some of you use
org mod some of you use the
hide the Jackal and whatever there there
are two very popular you know if you
want the static website if you use a
static website generator
then your source code is going to be
some kind of markup or markdown you know
like Oak mod you can also use markdown
you know then you have to generate the
page so so the page is gonna be very
easy to read you know without all these
tags but however every time you you have
the extra step of generating the page
and you also have other complexities for
example
um you have quite a few complexities
because then your template
is not as powerful and flexible
as compared to Raw HTML because raw HTML
and CSS you can control it in any way
you want for example here is a here's my
CSS file I can reformat them I can
control them like you know but if you
based on template system every time you
want a new tag or something you have to
kind of create a new new template for
that anyway so the point is that when
you use a static website generator
so-called
uh used to be called content management
okay website content manage management
manager there are like so many in the
past 20 years you know they come and go
and each generation just knew a few so
today
the most popular is uh let me try to
find it
static website
okay at this rate we're gonna uh this is
gonna be uh like two hours okay so let's
see this these are all crap you know
these are all ad
uh field spam website you know they they
pounce on the most common questions or
each one of these idiots they are not
really there to answer your question
they are there to they they are usually
hired cheap writers by commercial
entities or spammers so that they their
results you know they have search engine
SEO and whatever you know they have a
team doing that so their results come up
on top and typically their answer is the
was the most worthless you know
what is a static site generator Cloud
fair or Cloud Fair also doing that
okay so let's look at a few okay
typically this website you know using
the latest framework they think they
look pretty and they usually have a
spammy irrelevant you know image so that
for people who don't know anything about
anything they can say oh oh computers
with static website generator you know
but if you want just if you just want
quick answers usually they they tell you
okay so what is a static website
generator in 2023 oh they are quick to
change the day to look
so
SEO
uh okay so let's let's there are a few
okay so yeah usually they are filled
with Spam or you know oh and building
SEO functionality what the crap
static website versus Dynamic size so
where are they Jacob okay
that's one of the most popular okay
let's copy it
so that's one of the most popular and
there's another one
Janko is one of the popular and uh and
what is the um
Jesus this like content Management
Systems okay that's what it used to be
called in 2000s
uh
what's a jam stack I have no idea what's
uh okay mark down
okay Jacko and another one I know I
heard of you know all the Geeks all the
Nerds telling me so why don't you use
Hugo idiotic okay
I would claim my system is faster when
you want to write anything any page it's
faster than them it's more flexible and
more powerful what what I mean by faster
meaning
less number of keystrokes right in the
same page
in my system
you know you need less number of
keystrokes for example all the H3 H1 you
know I can
for example uh
something okay
one two three
four four key presses gets you that and
if you want that to change that to H2
one two three three key presses and you
can see the command uh you see there so
the cost of using sound system is that
you you really have to know that in
depth or the HTML you know and all the
CSS and you have to also be a master of
emacs and you have to also have you know
I'm using the HTML mod user so so
yeah so you have to you know learn all
this stuff
that is the cost just like emacs you
know for typical programmer you can use
vs code you can start to code right away
but if you want the Earth mode
efficiency Emax or Vim is better however
you have to spend one year to master it
first so that's a trade-off in a similar
way
the way you know I create you know 7000
HTML pages on study.info and kosari.org
over the past
25 years since 1997 that's my first web
page and
sunny.org started in year 2000 exactly
so I mean so they are originally they
are written in Microsoft Word
you know character by character tag by
tag you know of course I also mastered
Microsoft Word so I have a I have lots
of macros you know but in Microsoft Word
that's the beginning 1997 okay
the event so in by 1999 I started to use
emacs exclusively for all text editing
so after 20 years you know I started to
learn email between 2006 so now I have a
system you know a complete system
so and you know I that's why I I would
say it's faster more efficient more
powerful more flexible than than any of
these any of this jacob or um Hugo okay
okay that's a giant digression but um
let's let's start it to code this today
okay so let me just mention Jacob and
Hugo okay
here okay turn now turn off this uh
garbage website spam websites okay now
so first step is to
um
so we want to do the find replace on
this directory so we need to um
and see no copy paste new blog
when will you be on Lex Friedman's pack
podcast next reading
next treatment is a phony
you know the classic jargon for Lex
Friedman is phony or careerless
opportunist that's what Lex Friedman
fake you know he he he pretend you know
he always say nice things like the Dalai
Lama you know oh Humanity we must be the
most peaceful the love is the key to the
whole Humanity you know uh equipped like
that makes Friedman but phony you know
he's there whatever he do is this he's
he's got one goal so that he became more
popular and more uh makes more money
that's that's the only thing he
interested in you know anyway so but
today the Malaysian Zuma jargon for that
is squifter okay
laughs
Okay so
and let's let's focus on this okay uh
yeah this is gonna be a big task and I
already talked for 20 minutes
so here is a milk
milk and banana
Lex Friedman you know it is you know
watching his video the the way he
watching him the face the facial
expression the way he talks the the
style is offensive offensive deeply
offensive you know a bunch of fake
things and he doesn't you know he's an
idiot he's got low IQ he doesn't know
what he's talking about
uh you know and just
and and and the most critical I mean the
most important is the fake phony
he's got only one goal to make himself
popular more money that's what that what
he that's what he is
and here's a coffee and milk
so let's let's focus let's get back to
this um
so we are going to write a fine replace
uh script
in in multiple languages and first of
all we need to prepare a directory for
this find replace okay so let's uh let's
prepare a directory
okay so let's just go to so close that
okay so let's go in here let's create a
directory XX let's just name it that
okay
and we want to copy the entire emac list
manual to this directory we we need to
do this multiple times even uh yeah so
okay so please so for example I want to
copy this file path okay so you know
that's how it's done and let's just use
um
okay let's
hit Powershell
okay so Powershell
Superior then bash then the 30 years
Unix bash package
um
okay that's the syntax recursive
actually
recursive okay uh copy because One
Directory to a destination okay
[Music]
so and uh what's the current directory
here
okay so and let's replace that by
okay let's see so let's
do Powershell so we're gonna Powershell
okay and uh copy CP is 80s to copy item
so you can either use CP so let's try it
okay
cancel
paste
oh yeah so we missed uh this part needs
to be a directory
okay copy
cancel paste do it
okay done
pump it back drop into the directory
open that refresh there it is emac piece
Okay so
copy that directory close close
okay so here is the directory we want to
work on
uh
okay
so we're gonna write so first of all
let's write a emac bisp okay so because
my audience is mostly emacs users and
you know they Trust
you guys trust me on my emac base okay
so let's let me show you how it is done
I I have it already written for example
let me show you and let's just do it
okay so for example let's open that
let's say I want to change all
um
all words files okay you see that word
files I want to change them all to this
magnify a little bit
you see the the word files okay so I
just call this command press press uh
let's show the Ping window okay watch
the pink window you can see the command
name
do it you see starfine replace text okay
paste files I want to replace that
string by what you want to replace by
let's say something random that okay
enter and which directory this directory
enter
what HTML I mean what pattern for the
file regular expression dot HTML okay
minimum the depth okay starting at zero
okay maximum the depth so this is a nice
feature to have so you can specify a
range of directory depth
because this is important if you want to
to find and replace in HTML
sometimes you want to focus on a
specific directory level depth because
otherwise your relative links will all
be wrong okay so anyway so max the depth
99 right changes to file let's say yes
fixed case in search yes fixed case in
replacement yes backup makeup backup yes
okay is
going there it is okay
so they are 10 000 files you know so you
can you can scroll you can press the
arrow key you know and you can open the
file so you can see this world has
changed from file to that you see
so this this command I'm calling it's in
it's this one sapphire and replace text
and it's in the package because I find
okay if you want it it's open source but
you have to pay okay support me because
I've been you know doing open source for
15 years and nobody gives a but
instead you become tech support
you spend one hour every day to ask
people's questions to answer people's
questions
so this this command is already there
and there's also
uh there's also a regular expression
version
and so
here is a source code go to the top and
you can go through this home page
so if you like it support me go there
pay it I'll send it to you okay so this
is one of the most useful you know
and the code is 700 lines okay close
close Okay so we demonstrated
find and replace of this package because
I find which includes a nice you know
user interface you can jump to it you
know things like that
by the way of course if you are emacs
user emacs also have that feature but
it's not it's not as good uh I mean
that's why after several years
eventually I developed my own package
emacs you know also has that
okay
so we have done that and now refresh the
directory you can see all the backup you
know you know it automatically
automatically makes a backup you know oh
so that word does not appear in every
file so you see only some of them Scot
backup so
okay copy the directory close we also
want the command to um
to
to delete that directory okay so let's
let's let's uh add here
Powershell
um
I am
RM is the short name early Alias for
remove items so uh so we can do recurse
again
okay let's try to let's see let's open
it so it's a directory close it and run
this Powershell command okay
okay instantaneous let's look at open
it's not even there so
open you see it removed them okay that's
good
uh uh let's just say RM okay so that way
it's more familiar to
the Unix heads
okay so we got the script to remove and
copy
yeah so
um and now we need to do copy again so
this is gonna take a long time uh to
code this okay so now let's try to open
it
okay fantastic they are all pristine now
now
let me write a script to um
to do find replace in emacs okay so let
me show you how to do that
so emag these
of all files in our directory
okay that's our documentation
how we how do we want to do this let's
do this in uh not as a function but just
as a script so that we can run it in
Shell okay
so and for this purposes let's hard code
the directory path
because we
um because we are trying to test the
speed
what what is this oh this is today's
talk show
what
uh wait we screwed up something wait 2
000 yeah this is today's talk show so we
put that
uh we put
oh emacs block wrong place okay
copy copy copy copy we can select you
know progressively select more stuff
yeah we didn't screw up my emacs block
okay close now paste them here
foreign
browser
fantastic so here we got our Powershell
now next step is to
um
yeah so
let's see yeah okay yeah so remember we
need the directory so let's copy that
input okay so this is emacs you don't
have the equal sign you use set queue to
set the input directory and the input
directory is going to be
um
that
okay
so for now
the next thing to do is for each file we
open them
okay
and what's the best way to so you need
to Traverse a directory so what is the
best way look up emac this basics
so now you go to practical emac disp
and uh file in buffer section you have
walk directory okay let's see which one
we want to use directory files
uh return at least some names of files
in directory
and then we also have list directory and
or subter
okay and we have a custom function to
filter directory by depth level okay
uh in the in this case we just need the
flat okay directory files that's all we
need
close that okay so we need to do
something something like that okay
directory files input directory are
optional so let's look at the
describe function let's look at the
documentation
for match no sort count okay uh return a
list of names
for optional arguments four is the near
return the absolute file name
yes we want the absolute file name okay
true
if match is the Neo mentioned only found
in Susan directory part
okay that's basically filter by the file
name
okay we don't care
matches the Neo okay so you have Neo
and no sword is useful if you plan to
show the result yourself
okay no sword is true okay
there is a new Option it's missing in my
uh it's missing in my Emax
tutorial huh a new Option count
if count is the Neo and the natural
number the function will return count
number file names okay we don't care
okay so anything else
has anyone ever tried applying soft fly
keys in Vim there is there is a
someone wrote a Vim package
seven years ago seven or even ten ten
years ago
you can find it in fact I have a link in
my website there someone wrote a
Vim package that emulates the keystrokes
in Ergo emacs okay Ogo Emax is a Emax
package that's the predest predested
president that's that's the previous
version of that's the beginning that's a
before soft like Keys okay but it's not
model
so but the key choices are the mapping
two commands are similar so over emacs
then I created PSI emacs
and someone wrote a Vim packaged package
based on Google emacs keys so
but you know actually I've been thinking
of creating sucks like he's in vim and
in vs code in particular vs code so the
idea is that because something like his
is you know that's my original Vision
because it's a
you know uh editing key map system
that is not just useful in emacs but can
be in any editor or IDE vs code veeam in
fam language so that was my original uh
Vision I just never get to do it it
takes time so
um
yeah you can do it yourself but there
are quite a few people trying to do that
you know they
that's the that's the nature of emacs
user you know and hackers and and you
know like someone create a package you
know and you think it's good but you
don't want to use it because you because
you want to add your own touch that
becomes your own you know then you can
say this is my
like we will have been using the meal or
something
you know they're trying to then they
copy
the my design
which is a bit annoying because
well that's the nature of Open Source
you know because if I have the power I
would patent it just like apple
Microsoft you know that's that's the
actual way to get it
to to grow my to to have my to have
money so I don't die and also to expand
it to the world you know because because
open source is just
crap
so directory files input Okay so
so okay so now
file list
equals that okay in fact we can run this
okay run
show the pink window run
oh
something is wrong just two files
what is the
wait
why is it just two files
oh
that's right yeah actually the directory
you want is Elis okay
run it
there it is a thousand files okay
now you have a list of files
now you want to open each one so how do
you do that
you can do it by
there are many ways but but you have to
be careful because emacs
you don't want syntax coloring you know
every time you open a file emacs calls
the major mod and do the order syntax
coloring that's very slow you know so if
you are writing script you don't want to
call find file okay you want to do
something else
and here is a tip to how to do that
open file so let's see
read file there it is okay and actually
we also need write file okay so let's
look at read file so this this is a
great idiom
to
quickly if you want to write a script to
process files this is the way you don't
want to call find file
then it invokes syntax coloring it also
invokes Undo You Know recording undo and
redo so every time you do something
emacs recorder and do in the background
super and slows down slows you down
tremendously and bye bye bye bye five
times this at least okay and also every
time you open file then one bunch of
um
hooks
gets cold gets cold cold
because for example the Highlight
current line that will also happen when
you if you use find file because emacs
is just like
real interactive so you don't want that
so you want to do it this way okay
so so this is a function you know
um where you just basically all you want
to do is create a temp buffer then
insert insert the file content by the
path okay that's that's
that this is the best idiom to open the
file and do something okay
do something okay so so open the file do
something so here
here is the find replace you want to do
then you want to apply this function to
this bunch of files okay so what you
want to do is you say
map car
and uh
the function name will be just that
okay my process file and the sequence
will be
X-File list okay so
we use map C because you don't care
about the output otherwise you so map C
is like JavaScript for each okay if you
want the output then you have to say map
car okay
okay and it's magnifying Okay so
but now we're gonna focus on this uh
process file okay so you once you insert
the contents into a temp buffer
then you want to
go to Cha coin Amendment
okay go to chart one point movement is
one okay uh what
okay you go to the beginning and uh
okay let's now let's think about
what text we uh we want to find and
replace
it needs to be
we are going to make this decision for
also the code in Golan in JavaScript in
Python you know so let's let's
um
let's write out
text that
appears that we want to to find and
replace okay let's say
okay so let's say
something
to something else okay and what are
those something let's let's let's go
look at the the emacs manual let's see
what kind of things we want
okay uh
so this word happens in every um
okay let's say let's say previous to
uh p
something
okay so let's find some other word
so there's the word Lambda that's that
also happens frequently
let's say we want it to be
um
let's just say random character for now
okay
then
yeah we want to do multiple pairs that's
important let's see right okay let's say
two that's a let's say that okay that's
a very common word
that to
that
okay
let's make this
okay suppose that's what we want to
replace
find replace pairs let's let's do one
more okay
function okay function is a frequently
used word
yeah wait let's try something else uh
let's say number okay
okay so let's say these are the find
replace pairs
okay
and showing browser
Okay so
okay so yeah let's copy that
yeah let's do it okay
okay let's go back to the emac Beast
code okay so now we have a bunch of
um
find replace pairs those okay
uh what to do here's what to do go to
chart one
while
and we want to use regular expression or
not
uh let's see
let's say no okay because I want to test
find replace focusing on on the speed of
find and replace
so I don't want to use regular
expression because if if we use regular
expression then that will involve the
speed of regular expression in different
languages
you know in Golan in JavaScript in
Google timeline
you know it
you know there you know each language is
regular expression will be will have a
different performance characteristics
but for the purpose for our purpose I
just want to see the speed of find and
replace because if we focus on that I
believe emac this will be possibly
faster than all these
okay maybe except go
okay so we don't want regular expression
so we we end and we are going to hard
code we are going to hard code this find
replace pairs okay
um
okay the first pair is search for word
that optional bound Neo no Arrow
about Neo no error true Count we don't
care
replace match okay replace match by
that
okay fixed case yes literal yes string
Neo so we expression we don't care okay
now this is how you do find replace okay
so you have multiple pairs now all you
have to do is just um
let's let's make it
just make it four copies okay
uh and here will be
that
okay so let's bring this to this
Lambda
becomes that
okay and none
becomes
that
okay so here is our complete code this
script will do find revised
are you sure yes I'm certain
oh
that's right
are you sure this is correct yes I'm
certain this is correct
okay so
um
now
pop this back
search for fail oh
yeah we remove we moved it okay so cut
pose
and uh
paste the code here okay syntax code
showing browser
so here is the emac this code
and now we need to
put this code into a script so that we
can run it on the terminal and we can
call Powershell measure to measure the
time it takes
so let's do that so we need to prepare
we need to create several um
yeah okay let's do that
okay let's go to the directory go up one
directory so we're gonna have several
files here new file this is emac this
uh
okay so there is a emac list version
find replace
okay let's let's double check Okay so
I think it will work
okay
oh God I'm getting getting tired
Expos yes exposes the keyboard hello
change through
Okay so
so let's open a Powershell
now
Powershell
the power of shall power shall
okay so we can run
now what's what is the syntax let's see
uh where is my Emax okay emacs 28
fantastic okay so I can just run e Max
and what is the I believe it's script
okay
I believe that's that okay but uh let's
double check I need to double check
so go back to emacs tutorial
second let's go back to talk show
keep
um
keep the links we talked about copy
paste
because
cop copy
oh wait we forgot to write file oh yeah
so we forgot to write files so
yeah we didn't write files so
correction okay opening it again we
forgot to write file
Okay so
open it go here here's the directory
here's a find replace copy the fire path
close close
uh and put it here okay
that's the emac be fine and replace okay
we need to modify it because make a
backup because we forgot to write file
okay once so once you
you made all these find replace
uh let's let's make it one line okay
thank you
Okay so
so now you need to write to file okay so
what you do
right region that's that's right
and no backup that's right
so
um
we we want to write to file only if some
replacement happened okay we don't want
to rectifier when there is no
replacement
because that way he'll be inefficient
okay so uh
so which which way uh to do it is the
best way
uh my back oh God I need to walk for 10
minutes
or five minutes
open read possibly right okay here is an
idiom I have already yeah so when file
changed P so you just said that
so when file changed p
how do you
okay so we need the let
okay Neil
uh how do I do this efficiently
because we can say
that you know set it to true but however
if you do this every time
it finds a new occurrence your your
set the variable so it's redundant
uh so how do you do that
oh God this is gonna be two hours and I
don't think we can do all these
languages
you know we're gonna do several
okay anyway let's just uh go slowly my
usual face
Okay so
so you want to
so let's so there's a variable in emacs
called buffer modified
okay there is a function that returns
true if the buffer is modified
since it its file was last read or saved
so this does not apply because
our buffer is a temperature it's not
associated with the file
so this does not apply this buffer
modified Okay so
yeah let's look at the buffer functions
this is a new feature in Emax 28 By the
way
which is fantastic it's it lets you
easily see all the functions
related to some topic
but for Life p
okay buffer name window buffer okay I
don't think there is a function that
both a size no
Okay so
no
so how we want to do this so we cannot
use both from other modified okay
so
God
you know one way
so if you are doing this another way you
know one way to do this is that
like this let me show you okay
so
in one way is that
you go to chart you search forward
then
if search for what is true then
you
that means you found it then you do the
replace match
then you set the change to P okay
so
and we can change this if to when okay
so once you do that once One Step then
you do this uh
then you do a while loop on the same
thing
and now this time you don't need to do
that okay so this is one step
but then you're gonna repeat it for one
two three you know for each one of them
so that certainly works okay so this
works
so this time you don't have to go to a
chart you just say that
yeah but it's more code
so he's
um Okay so
foreign
so if we are going to do this then then
we are going to copy this code
replace each one of these fine replace
by
this movables code
so
which does the job but you have lots of
repeated text like right now so another
way so to make these
condense the code you can turn this
bunch of find and replace pairs into a
list
then you just map over the list
and
painful the
okay let's really think about for each
one of these
so previous yeah so you either do that
you know
that
verses
anyone watching how many people oh
eight people have been popular
so anyone any comments oh God I need to
take a break okay that's that's just um
let's just
I suppose let's just go to the painful
way and then let's get this to finish
okay
double check one more time okay go to
char then find when this happens you do
the replace and you set the change to
true then you do a while loop
okay yeah that should work uh and but
before we do anything let's just write
the file now okay
just write the file so write a file
so
when
file changed when if the file changed
right region
okay right region point mean Point Max
file name is gonna be F path
and optional append no
visit no
log name no
must be new no I don't know what that is
must be new let's look up describe
function
must be new
it must be new is
neither Neo or Excel that means ask for
confirmation okay we don't care
okay so let's just do this for now okay
formatting issues okay
make a backup
okay that's it
now that is the emag please find replace
file close it close it now
what we need to do is to find out how do
you call the script
uh emac script what what is the syntax
okay
where is it here
so uh so you go here run emac Scripts
repetitive string injury right here
hurts right now
typing too much
okay so here is how you run it exactly
dash dash script to dash the glue
convention
uh script really Max like batch with
load set to path okay yeah
okay so let's run that
do it
oh it actually prints the output what
the
suppose it worked okay
file error what
debugger entered least Sparrow file
error opening input file permission D
denied
oh did we get uh
insert file contents
file error
enter this area debugger entered this
area of file error opening input file
permission denied
and C uses sucks sorry info emacs
oh
we got the input directory incorrect
yeah that's
yeah
oh did we screw up our code yes we
did it shouldn't be need should not be
in this directory this is my Emax
directory
it should be in talk show Jesus
okay emergency fix
okay did I screw up my
Emax
okay emacs manual did I screw up here no
okay good
now let's open that
search for XX
open that
okay
copy that new buff new frame
new buffer save it paste it
okay this is critical you don't want to
lose that
then
all these directory is delete
okay that's right
all these directories
go up DD the entire XX let's double
check
we don't want to make any errors here
okay
delete XX yes or no yes recursive yes
permission denied because
probably because on Windows you know you
have to close you see that's why
on Windows you have to close
or the open fire thing
okay refresh delete yes deletion done
okay
now let's clean up our error here
now this path is wrong because that
okay info okay close that
no
we got we got out directories wrong so
go to talk show
search for XX no it doesn't exist make a
new directory press
X
okay
refresh open it empty that's good copy
the file path
close
so this is the file pass it should be
Okay so
Okay so go through it
copy the emac this code new buffer paste
save it XE visp
dot e l okay
drop to the directory there it is make
the backup
open double check correct okay
close close okay now let's be very
careful here open
copy the final path close
so the lisp file is here okay
delete that and we need to fix our
Powershell
okay so yeah
yeah that's not the right directory so
yeah we got it wrong here
so the directory should be
that okay
not that okay and the remove because
okay hold on second open it
okay so it should be easy
I'm gonna be very careful here
so this removes the E this
directory which doesn't exist now and
here we copy it
okay so let's copy it
go to the directory well not here so
open it
okay now
now paste
copy all the emac Beast menu or two
layer
okay then
refresh there it is
open it yeah
okay
because it
copy the file path
open it
yeah because okay
pop it back
now let's fix some of these
that
don't need that
now that we need
showing browser
okay
yeah
so now
so I actually
um
so now we we do that uh
We Run The emac this code script
Okay so
check yeah
okay now we need to get the path correct
okay open the emac based script get the
path correct
so the path will be
okay so let's
right
that's right input directory okay
okay that is the file okay now
open the new Powershell
uh
there it is
let's double check
yeah
double check our code
yeah yeah
comments any comments okay let's run it
do it
oh I hope it's not Arrow
debugger error open your input file
permission denied
instincts
why permission denied
oh and
we forgot and okay that's one Arrow we
also forgot one thing
because you see now it's trying to
insert fire contents of this path
and this path is dot dot that means go
up one directory
so we need to fix this
uh
file list directory files
we need to we needed to say match okay
because we don't want
the Unix dot dot
Unix you know that's the
one of the damage of Unix to the
Computing industry because you see Let
Me Explain If you
you know if you don't get it yet
directory files
given a file path it should list all
files in that directory right but
however
in the emac this case it also returns
dot dot
the Unix the Unix
why should it return dot dot so I mean
so this essentially
this like typically you don't want uh
hello uh uh thank you
so uh let me uh read the comments in a
bit okay so
that's a problem okay so the Unix this
this is a Unix damage to the Computing
industry
so in in this case to fix it we want uh
matches the Neo mentioned only file
names whose non-directory part matches
the rejects okay so this part will be a
Rejects
HTML let's just say that that should
work okay
so that fixed this part but however
there is also
there is still debugger entered file
error opening input filed permission
denied
what do you mean permission denied
I can see why is permission denied
so let's see the comments your command
because I open file Yakuza has saved me
a lot of key codes thank you
it's
banana and milk
I know I don't understand why the
permission
of
oh you see maybe it's because of this
yeah because of the dot dot that is why
but if you know because the of the dot
dot
it's trying to go up one directory that
is why
it's trying to do something to the XX
path
you know you're trying to do something
to this directory but even that I don't
understand why is it permission denied
because this directory is your
um
anyway
let's try again you should um
you should work let's copy the
let's copy the EVS file in case it
overrides it okay doing it
oh fantastic
now
pretty fresh let's open Evie's file
let's check let's open
um
you see it worked you see there there it
is
one replacement
and what's the other
so that underscore so
there underscore these matching lines
there it is you know great it worked
then there is that
these matching lines
one occurrence
and there is that number
underscore
so it didn't wait
so it didn't happen in this file okay so
it worked okay our e-mac this script
works now we just have to time it let's
try it
you know there's a problem because you
know right now we can just time it yeah
let me show you
but this time is fake
because you already did the replacement
so when you run the script again
it doesn't
um
it doesn't actually do any find replace
so that's why you have to close
close
showing browser that is why you have to
run this Powershell script
yeah let's let's do it
and it's yeah it's
run them separately
do it what happened
again
do it okay
do it
okay
now if you open that drop to a directory
open that now look now you see they are
back to their original okay
now we can try to render
name in the same window okay
okay instead
so we want to run this script
so this will be full path okay
that
and in fact it's dangerous to have the
script here so I don't want the script
in the XX directory I want to move up
One Directory so let's do split go up
one directory go here
capital r to move
yes okay so we move that file there okay
now it's good
now make a backup
okay so we got the file there
open it this is still good
because
refresh because
now that should be that okay copy it
paste
do it
why is it uh
the measure doesn't measure time
I mean why is it zero
okay let's close that
so now you can see we have a bunch of
Powershell scripts to do our stuff
uh but the major command is returning
zero
because
oh major time that's right
and you know so let's I forgot what's
the Powershell command so let's go to
Powershell
I have a tutorial
check out my tutorial okay so it's good
so how do you test speed of things
let's search for Speed
okay
I believe there's a measure time so
new tab help measure
measure command
yeah
so what you want is the measure command
okay measure command measure the time it
takes to run script script blocks in
commands Okay
how do you uh God
I didn't prepare these
so let's see if I have an example how do
you use this
uh
search for a major command this
directory HTML fixed case in search now
okay that's not there
let's go to to do
and search that
that directory HTML fixed case now
between surrounding text yes
so yeah so here is the power power shell
in one of my to do
the documentation
measure command so
example so okay so you have to do it
that way
okay
okay so I think I
know because
Powershell so we need to do measures so
the command is actually
something like that
okay let's try it
there it is
milliseconds
total days and that Jesus
total milliseconds okay
291.
now if you run it twice it's going to be
much faster because if we are load all
the files in memory
270 let's do it big but
280 okay
300 okay let's do again 279 okay
but if we
if we run the command to remove the
directory
now you see now we remove the directory
and we copy the whole over
okay now we actually do the find replace
fresh now it will actually find those
string and replace to it
so it takes a while now because it needs
to write the file you see
four thousand um
milliseconds so this is
MIDI
five seconds basically
total seconds yeah total seconds five
seconds
now but now if you read running again
first of all the files are in memory
secondly there's no string to replace
so it becomes
zero seconds
okay so but anyway we successfully
did
um
timing of the e-mac this find replace
okay
so today's talk show we successfully did
the timing of emac we find replace in
the code is here oh actually
we need to modify more of these
uh yeah we need to
because okay so we are almost dead Okay
so let's revisit the emac this code you
see
you see we need to modify
wait did we oh actually this is not the
right file
the right file is the
here okay open it
wait
open it oh what
doesn't exist what
e x e d dot El
what
wait
copy the file path go here
remove those paste here what's the
difference
oh yeah right we changed the path that's
right
so
open it copy it
close it and back to the emac this
okay select all replace it
okay this is our new code
so and we also we actually need to do
replace each one of these line by this
block
edsc
okay let's do it then
okay let's let's just do it the idiotic
way
so that
paste by that
okay next
Lambda
by
lamp
okay and number
by
num something
okay so this is our full code
copy
put it back
and
actually
DD dead
because we don't want repetition open
this
make a backup
segregor paste
okay so here is a full code let's double
check
time previously
tight tight
the Lambda
full code
save and back up and close
and we can now run this again
remove the order directory
copy it
run and time the e-max find replace
command
five seconds that's right
and right now again
zero seconds
oh one second this time
do it again
okay so this changes matters let's see
oh because each time you see each time
that becomes that but it still contains
that
so there is more change to do that's
that's a good that's actually a good
thing good test
that solved the problem I had before
because of the loading files into memory
so okay so the speed of this script
is basically 1.7
seconds okay it's emac this
okay
so we have done the emac this code now
you guys watching okay answer
um what's the next language shall we do
python or JavaScript or Golan or Wolfram
lamb pick one
okay
now you guys are here still
eight people okay
please tell me which one of the language
we should do next
and maybe that's it for today
you know I was hoping for Golan because
Golan would be
uh
kind of most interesting goal line would
be would be faster
but for the others I'm not sure but
anyway pick one which one you are
interested
okay so we're going to take a break
be right back five minutes
mathematical rat
rat from
from you know I know where you're from
but
that's an interesting choice so let's do
Wolfram language okay but I'm gonna take
a break five minutes
okay okay guys so
yeah I'm Gonna Take a Walk In Smoke
fantastic okay
so next yeah fantastic
smoke
and see how many let's see
that's good
so I'll be back in five minutes
I basically sit here all day and night
encoding and
do research
on programming languages yeah
ah
we'll be back
foreign
okay I'm back
and back and
let's do
let's do wolfam language then
okay wufan language it's pretty simple
so
I have already a script written in fact
you know if you I have already written
Gola and Python 3
in Pearl find replace
and the regular expression version of
Golan in Python and oh here is wufam
land it's already here but it's
um
you can find it on my website it's just
just search for example Language
tutorial
then you go all the way down
you'll find a
move from script
uh here script to find replace text in a
directory
so here is how you do it in Wolfram
language
and you can find my goal and script for
find replace it's here it's all linked
at the bottom
each script have different features such
as whether you want to write to file and
whether you want to make a backup
and the regular expression for the final
path
and with a you know backup or write to
file and what's a backup file name
so each one have different features so
here's Golan
here is python
okay so I wrote these all these in past
20 years
then there is Pearl
the pro is my earliest one 20 years ago
in
on 2000
around year two thousand two thousand
yeah year two thousand so here's a pro
script it has more features per script
uh so then there's emacs
um
okay here this one is how to how to do
it in emacs without using Microsoft find
script
so I mean you can do this interactively
but anyhow we have showed how do you
write it in emac this was a script
as uh oh yeah so here is the
here's my package because I'll find
replace in pure emac this and using
emacs regular expression not the Unix
grab regular expression because they are
different
and here's a video I did before so then
yeah so uh so now let's go to from
script okay I already have it here so
copy this close it close it
because it now go to the directory go to
XX
new buffer paste and save it save this
as X
move from land okay
go from LAN
Dot
WL okay
okay save it
there it is oh it shouldn't be here it
should be one directory up so yeah so
let's move it
there it is open it fantastic okay
close this okay
so find replace now we need to modify
the input directory
and make backup so that we don't
um so so that they are like kind of the
same
doing the same thing okay so input
directory will be that
make backup that we we want to remove
that okay remove that the depth Infinity
actually the depth should be just
uh one
final name uh file name extension that
okay so let's modify this Wolfram script
Okay so
input make backup
let me down we don't
remove it
we want to remove it because
um
what
yeah
we want to remove it because otherwise
the checking will make it slower
so if backup is true
something something
uh do you do that we don't care
so to do that
okay
the depth the depth is going to be
uh
one okay
so let's look at the documentation for
scan
scan in Wolfram language is like
JavaScript for each and the emac Beast
map C okay they are the same thing
turn on JavaScript
and the level spec let's see what is the
syntax yeah so level one through n
ible n Only so yeah so that is correct
so the depth we don't need anymore
file name extension we need and let's
hard code it
okay
here you can use the glove pattern
instead of very good expression
okay let's double check the code
find replace pairs okay here is already
a list so we copy the pairs we want to
to find replace okay so there are four
pairs there
Okay so
one two three four all right
okay the first one is
previous
change it to that
okay
that
change it to that
Lambda
number
change it to that okay
okay
so that's the payus okay and process
file is a function
takes
um
module is a local variables like lisp
slit
comments okay comments
so uh
content restream okay
so
content happened only
one time so
content here can be just
inline so we don't even need that
and here is the right string
okay this is wrong
I mean it's not wrong but it's
inefficient because
even if there's no replacement you are
still writing to file
you don't want to do that because
writing two file is very very slow
okay so
um God
so if we want to fix it that's gonna be
you know we do string replace here
we want to know if it's true or false
yeah in wolfen language it's gonna be
super slow it's gonna be much slower
okay but also
read stream file path that Returns the
file content as a string then you call
with string replace
and you
here's the find replace pairs
okay so hold on a second the back here
this part is uh what is this
the history now that's uh no date that's
basically backup
yeah that's the backup we are we are
adding a date we don't want that
so this part can be just that we don't
need block block is like a local declare
a local constants I mean well no decree
a local
Dynamic variables
[Music]
okay so the code is actually just this
okay so module actually you don't need
the Cody's just like that
you see in wolfan language is much
simpler
but
there's a efficiency problem now so when
you do find replace you if there is a
change you must
record it
if there's a change you write to file if
there's no change don't write to file
but
it would be hard
to
to code these
end in a efficient way because
you know like how do you tell if the
file contains a string
you know you can you can create a
variable you know if you found a string
then you do the replace if you found a
string record it that there's a stream
found then you do find replace
then you save the file however if you do
that
you see when you check if the string is
already there
that takes some time
then you do the replacement
basically you are repeating the process
so that's inefficient
so you want a way to not repeat the
process
and I do not know
how to do that
let's look up the
because because the string replays
simply return a new stream
it does not tell you
uh you know it does not tell you whether
there is actually some change let's see
replace a string expression s s by 8 by
SP whenever it appears in string yeah so
it doesn't tell you it actually did the
replacement or not I mean it occurred
I could not not so
yeah so in wufan language this is gonna
just going to be super slow
but let's do it okay this is just yeah
so
it's no point oh fam language is a loser
here in terms of speed but in terms the
the the time it takes to code is minimal
okay
you know it's one single line you can
you know you can put this function
in here so it's just one single line you
know it takes one minute to call this
but
compared to all the other languages it's
more slow
okay so actually this will do so
scan
so for each file name
something HTML in the input directory
first level you apply the function
process file to all of them okay so
that's the Wolfram script now let's run
the Wolfram script okay so copy the file
path
foreign
close it and of course the emac this
close that
and we want to yeah learn the Wolfram
language script which is
uh so here's a script and uh let's run
it so to run it you do this
so move from
okay so you need to run that UFM script
uh actually let's pop this out so we can
easily see the Powershell syntax
so Wolfram script
and here is the script
and that's not the right syntax so how
do you run Wolfram script
so let's go to my Wolfram Language
tutorial
okay
and at the bottom there is how do you
learn Wolfram script
okay
so you can either do it in code or file
so this is the way Dash file okay
close that
Dash file okay that should be that
should be it
let's try it okay
let's hope always good
is that correct
yeah let's just run it
seven seconds
let's see what was emacs Emax was five
seconds you see
emac these five seconds
who from language 7.
because there is an inefficiency because
it's
um
because it's trying to
save every file but now let's do it
fresh okay I mean let's do it again
now the second time is one second much
less than e-max
I'm actually surprised
wow
now let's let's look at the directory
let's see what
did it actually change stuff let's open
search for that
you see it changed three times you see
that something something you see
so it worked okay but now let's do fresh
okay let's remove
all the directories
copy it over
okay
close it
reopen
search for that
you see now it's uh you know it doesn't
example it's you know
yeah so you see
so now it's fresh
close it
now
let's run the Wolfram script
do it
one second
what
Jesus
this is faster than immaculous
I cannot no I cannot believe it
let's open let's double check
no something is wrong
search for that
okay there is a bug I think
yeah this whole family language it
impressive yeah but there's a bug okay
no there's something wrong
run it
one second but it doesn't change the
file
you see open it
you see that
you know if we go to for example let's
look at what the string we changed
you know
that becomes that
these matching lines
you know it didn't change
so
I think so there's a bug actually
there's a serious bug in wolfam language
I have noticed before
is that the bug is that once you read
once the Wolfram language reads a file
somehow it keeps the file in memory
so
you know when you are doing the street
stream it actually doesn't
read the file string you know the file
path
fresh it actually just use whatever it's
in your memory some for some reason I
can I haven't figured out
so if you know so right now it's
actually not doing anything
because it considered the file it's
already whatever
um something is wrong
yeah okay that's a failure in Wolfram
language that's pretty bad some
something is wrong I cannot figure out
um
maybe you know
something is wrong
somehow it keeps the files in memory
it shouldn't happen because if each time
we are running you know if I'm script
fresh
so
so yeah that's the problem so
and I won't be able to fix it right now
because this happened to me before I
don't know
it take it will take me
half an hour or an hour to find out
exactly what's going on okay
yeah but you know but it's about it's a
it's a very obvious bug
you know it's not actually changing
files
you know we can we can run this code
here
you know it says finished
but but if you open this directory open
it
you see it's not changed
open it you see
so if we
remove it okay let's see what happens
now the directory is
refresh empty
you see now the directory is empty
now if you run the Wolfram script you
should
return an error let's see what happens
you see it doesn't return error it just
it kept the files in memory
this this is a major bug I'm gonna you
know I I need to tell the Wolfram
research people
because last time I spent you know at
least 10 minutes 20 minutes I can't
figure out what's going on okay that's a
that's too bad wolf and wolfam is a
failure Wolfram script
okay so I think that's it for today we
should have
um should we turn another should we do
another language
so let me know you know
and uh otherwise that's it
I think that's it it's been two hours
okay so today at least we did the demo
of the emac this
again
copy it
and now let's run the Emax
should be five seconds
emacs trustworthy
you know six seconds when the second
time it will be two seconds yeah
German says when you run the Wolfram
script it has to launch the kernel every
time I thought so
that you know that's what I haven't
figured out maybe because if it
relaunched the kernel then obviously it
should work
but somehow it's keeping things in
memory
you know apparently somehow it's keeping
things in memory that's why
you have this cash issue
and the cash issue it shouldn't happen
because
the code
you know we are actually reading the
file there's no you know if you read the
documentation for read stream
you know you give it a file path
if it Returns the file content as a
stream
it does not mention anything about cash
you know but apparently he behaves as if
it's reading a cache you know
so I have to look into I don't know
what's going on I shouldn't you know
so I I so let's see the kernel is it is
is the kernel still running it shouldn't
okay so do we have any
uh so
but the first test seven second was
valid yes
yes the the yes that that is absolutely
valid and we verified it actually
changed things
but you see now it's a problem because
how do you even get it to
remove the cache because Wolfram is
Kernel is not running I don't think so
is there a way to search
tasks
you know this Microsoft idiotic
process manager
you know if you look at uh by name let's
see details users
startup
details yeah so can you magnify this
window no the funking idiotic Microsoft
you know Microsoft Windows is sucks in
every way
because you have this
ease of access this allows you to change
globally your text size but doesn't work
in many of the applications
so here you look at Wolfram
w
uh you know I don't see any Wolfram
kernel process
however if we run
the Wolfram script I think you will see
it
yeah if we run it and look at over here
I think we should see wolfam let's go
here
okay
run it
it's too fast well
let's try this again
run it
okay let's we need to refresh faster
update speed High
okay
order by CPU
done it
and it's too fast
doing it
let's put a timer here sleep
the easier asleep
uh easier a pause
okay let's see what is the documentation
pause for at least n seconds let's say
pause five
that way we don't know okay now back to
the
shell
okay where's the um
process manager
okay
now when it you'll pause for five
seconds so we can look at the Wolfram
kernel
the fact
okay it passed we can see
but uh
let's pause for 10 seconds
20 seconds okay
run it
all right
there it is there it is you see two of
them
wolfram.exe that's a kernel there it is
now it's gone okay
so you see so Wolfram kernel was there
now it's good
now it's 21 seconds that's correct
because we delayed for 20 seconds but
so I think
somehow
wolfam language the kernel
saves a copy as a cache somewhere in a
wolf and engine directory so we have to
look into that
let's run it again okay run it
and let's see CPU
memory
you cannot enlarge this
okay this is not useless
let's delay let's dedate it to 60
seconds
let's say 200 seconds okay
doing it
and now we have time to look up wolfam
language here
is it
oh
the the found is too small for me
so do you guys see it I don't see it
now let's go to details you see in
details you can see those two processes
there
process one eight one two four
okay now let's go
back to process now
they don't show process number
do I make sense guys
foreign
Ty
okay
but wufam where is Wolfram
instead of default task manager just use
process exp yeah but that requires
download right
I'm aware of that but I was trying to
avoid complexities
okay let's try it one more time
uh oh actually this is still running
it's still running
details yeah it's still there
process one eight one two four
but how do we show the process number
God and this is English PID
there
PID
it doesn't show up here oh
what
so there's some new interesting
discovery
that now it's done you see now it's done
now you see now you don't see it anymore
so but let's try to change it to five
minutes
run it
okay so you can see the process number
here
with um dot exe one zero four two four
and move from script one three nine
seven two
okay one zero four
two four now back to processes
PID
one zero four two four
one zero four
it's not here
the Wolfram kernel process is not listed
listed in the processes
one zero four nine two let's try let's
check again details
one zero four two four
okay one zero four two four
so it's not showing up
in the process ah
you know
so now the Wolfram language complexity
now trying to debug it now it becomes
Windows complexity why is the process
not showing this in this idiotic
Windows
now I haven't used the process
you see there
one two four two four
that's a Wolfram kernel process
but not showing up in the
task manager
what the idiotic
so apparently some processes you can
hide it or something
and even the Wolfram script is not
showing here
so what if we do something computational
X
expensive
should should the CPU show up here
I don't know so anyway
what happens if I'm running a notebook
okay let's try that okay so let's start
notebook
and let's kill the move from
oh God is it safe to kill now you see
the Wolfram notebook shows up desktop
kernel kernel
uh uh and uh
I'm pretty sure it show up here too
and there you see the Wolfram desktop
shows
but not when you do Wolfram script
also settings idiotic Windows okay so
let's open the new notebook okay move
from notebook
first of all we need to stop the
okay we canceled it let's see make sure
it's canceled yeah we'll find kernel the
old one is good
now it's uh we have the notebook desktop
who from kernel.exe and Wolfram kernel
two of them
okay let's
close let's make sure we don't
um
I mean I want to make sure everything is
fresh okay
uh what
so Windows key let's start with um
notebook
okay so you can see
when it starts it launches two kernels
open a new notebook
now
type something
evaluate
okay you can see
it still launches two kernels Okay so
okay now
let's copy our code
let's remove the pause
okay and it's coming out of the past
copy the whole
put it here okay that's our code
and go back here
it's
click click up remove the whole
directory
copy it
okay now let's run
let's put a timing
okay
run it
what
zero no what
zero
zero seconds right
did it actually change anything
search for that
it doesn't
you see it didn't change anything
running it again
okay something wrong with the Wolfram
script
I don't yeah this is the same thing same
thing I don't understand
it worked the first time right did it
let's change let's try to change
something let's change the
to all depth
unit
it's instantaneous
meanwhile it didn't do actually do
anything close
the open
these matching lines that it didn't do
anything okay
well the script is running this
processes are all attached to a window
in a non-detailed view
okay you might be right okay so you are
saying the wufan process might be under
Powershell Maybe
you know the when we are
when we were running in Powershell
so where is the Powershell
yeah so before
okay let's try again okay now let's
this this is very oh oh okay here's the
problem
that
is a problem because you are using the
tear that I that's one of the problem at
least okay let's fix it
so typically you want in you know in
Wolfram language
it won't Auto expand
okay so that's a script
so first of all
turn off don't save
turn off over
quite Warframe language completely
okay now
let's
see the Powershell
okay now let's watch the Powershell part
see if the Wolfram kernel shows up there
okay now first of all remove everything
recopy the directory
now
blend this Wolfram script okay
run it
okay let's see there it is okay it
showed up in Powershell do you see
fantastic
six seconds
okay let's try it again
do it
three seconds let's run again it should
be three seconds
fantastic
so now let's open the file to double
check if I actually changed things
open it
uh yes it changed except that it got
this um
End of Line
screwed up let's lease the matching
lines that you see
so it worked
okay so in emacs it was five seconds the
first time so Wolfram language is six
seconds
so every subsequent time you run it
it's three seconds
okay if every subsequent time you run it
it's three seconds we'll find language
works
now let's try again emacs
remove everything
copy it
run Emax
emac script the first time is six
seconds okay
subsequent run
it's two seconds okay run again
two seconds okay now let's do it over
again with Wolfram language
remove everything
copy it
will fam language
six seconds
same thing as emacs
okay
now subsequent run
three seconds much slower
than emacs
yeah the reason is that because that's
that's not the flaw of wufam language
well I mean the reason is slower so for
subsequent run is because we
we didn't check what's changed so it's
actually saving every file it opens it
resaves them and that is a huge
cost making it so so
anyway so we did so that's it for today
um we
we you know we made some progress about
this issue about which language is fast
uh so
so what's what we need to do next is to
to for example fix the Wolfram code so
that it will only save the file when
there is a change
okay I'm not I don't know how to do it
efficiently
because if you check it then you know
you are basically trying to find the
string again so I don't know how to do
it efficiently in wufan language
but wow in emac this it's easy
what about in Golan
um
oh okay so in emac this the way we do it
is that we just
yeah we first of all we do a search on
each of the fine stream
if that occurs then we
we make we Market you know it's changed
so we can do the same thing in Wolfram
language
you know we can do the same thing in
Wolfram Language by
by instead of you know calling replace
string
we just say search string you know find
the first occurrence so if it's found
then we call the replace string yeah
that can work
so if we do that then the wufam language
will be comparable I mean our code will
be comparable to the emac list version
then
we can properly do the timing again
and one more thing
for the timing you know I think we
should
you know instead of 1000 files we should
we should concatenate all these files
into one single file
so that way we can focus on the speed of
find and replace string and you know
write out one single file instead of you
know
instead of getting distracted by the
time for writing each file and the time
for passing the directory
yeah and when we if we do that then I
think emac this has a chance to beat to
be faster than all these all these other
languages
because of the emacs buffer data type
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching the time reduction is because
the cache memory all the time launched
in a kernel
oh the time reduction is not because of
any any of that it happens in emac this
too the time reduction happens is
because
uh because you know we are doing these
four Replacements you know it doesn't
matter which language
you see so the first time you run it you
have four pairs to replace but once you
do that
you no longer have the stream previous
you no longer have the string Lambda you
no longer have the stream number
but only this string you know that
becomes that something so
so that's why there's a Time reduction
okay and and there's another issue that
is the time to read the file because
that is a huge you know
because whenever because I do find
replace on thousands of files almost
every day you know for the past 20 years
and the biggest time the bottleneck in
time is loading the file
so
so if you do you know grab is same thing
for the grab especially for grab you
know if you do grab for the first time
it might take 30 seconds but the second
time is you know one second or something
because all the files are in memory
um so anyway so
two so
two summary two two these again next
time is that we need to uh fix the
wuframe code so that it will only save
the file when there's a change
and the algorithm will be basically the
same we do we did with the emac this
okay
then after that is done then we need to
concatenate all these files into one
single giant file you know maybe two uh
three Mega five megabytes you know one
huge file then we do the comparison okay
so that's next time thank you guys for
watching
uh bye guys okay
uh if you like my stuff you know if you
enjoyed my show pay pay me okay PayPal
PayPal Amazon gift card or
or you can buy my emac this tutorial or
uh
JavaScript tutorial okay
okay bye guys
long time no see rat we should we we
should do some video chat you know join
this code
is called sometimes we do uh voice party
so