Hello guys, good evening, good morning,
good evening. Welcome to another episode
of Kadog Show. We are going to code Emac
this pure Emac this coding. Okay. Uh
that's all we're going to do today. And
uh so uh this thing we did, okay, emac
coding. I'm going to create basically
for about 10,000 HTML pages. go through
each one of them and find any thumbnail
tag image tag. For example, let's go to
uh ergonomic keyboard index. So, showing
browser. So, you can see this is my blog
about keyboards. So, you got lots of
thumbnails. Now, each thumbnail, so
that's one example. Open it. So, that's
a thumbnail. Each the HTML markup for
the thumbnail. There is no width and
height. You see? So my job is to add
them. So I'm going to go through 10,00
HTML files, open them, find any image
links that doesn't have width and
height, and add width and height. So
basically that's what I'm going to do.
Okay. So uh uh but effect. So anyway, so
this is probably boring. It's just my
work. It's just going to uh my work
session. Okay. So keyboard block. So uh
we um so let me uh tell you about um uh
let's go to start talk show. Okay talk
show. So um search for width and height.
Uh yeah so let's say so that's the
previous talk show. Let's search for
that.
Yeah. So the reason we want to do that
is because of the uh HTML cumulative
layout shift. We don't want that. Okay.
Anyway, last so last episode episode 787
about two months ago in May we did a
talk show about this but I started to
talk for one hour about other things
about why am I doing this? So but so if
you are uh if you feel bored you can go
watch that one. Okay. Episode 787. So,
copy that. Close that. Go to today's
talk show.
Uh, today's talk show. Search, search,
search, search, search, search, search.
So, that one. Open it. That's one. And
paste the related link uh up here. So,
go to the bottom, paste, and copy the
current file path. Paste linky them
both. Make a list. Then press press
press
make a topic box. So this is about emac
lisp. Okay. So let's add a title. So
this this is about
emacis coding add width and height
height to image to to HTML image
thumbnail.
Okay. Uh image thumbnail
markup.
Okay. So, showing browser. Okay. Go back
now. Go to the top. You want to delete
live stream. Delete that. Delete that
to-do and delete that date. Showing
browser. So, that is clean. Okay. So,
and here is the topic box.
Now, we want to add the topic box to the
previous talk show on this page too. So,
so you go to the topic box. So, you
press press.
You can see the command on on the pink
window which I talked about in many of
my videos. Okay, showing browser. So if
you are here, say hi. Okay, love to see
your comments. Uh let's see. Pop this
out
again. So this is just me Emacs list
coding. Okay, boring text processing.
Okay, so uh okay. So let's see today's
talk show. Okay, so yeah. Okay, so let's
start to do it. Okay. So, um,
showing browser. Uh, so showing browser
back. Close. Showing browser. So, this
is the keyboard. Let's, uh, go to here.
Okay. Do it yourself keyboard. Uh, close
it. Close it. Go to talk show. Open
today's talk show and go to the top and
show this page. do it yourself keyboard
because we can see the thumbnail right
away. We don't have to scroll. Okay. So
now now I have a command. So uh so open
that page search thumb. So here is a
example of a
uh of a uh thumbnail. Okay. Link. So
here is the href
link and here is the image link. Okay.
That's uh that's that's the uh
what's the name? Uh tactile keyboard.
That is a tactile keyboard.
Uh very good. By a guy I met in keyboard
meetup by a guy. This guy who is also a
eac coder. His name is um
Matt Adri. Oh, I haven't heard of him
for many years by now. So this is 10
years ago, 2015. Matt Adareth, he be he
he he, you know, he designed this
keyboard based on Kinesis and you know
called Dactile.
So and I in in 2017 I met him in
keyboard meetup in San Francisco or
somewhere here. So and I tried it. It's
great. Okay. So anyway, so this so this
guy Yeah. So um
so he's a EMAC list coder. He's also a
wolfam language Mathematica coder. In
fact he's uh he's a very uh excellent
wam language
expert coder. Okay. Yeah. Coder and
expert. Wuam language. Uh because I've
seen some of his code. He compete I I
you know he compete in the wuam language
code competition like that test for
speed or uh the shortest code and things
like that
very powerful wuam language okay so that
guy so he created actile so anyway we
but we you know I'm going just going to
do the thumbnail so here's a thumbnail
so so uh let me just work on it because
if I talk it's not going to I can talk
you know I'm going I talk about this for
one hour and I didn't get anything done.
So, let me just do it. Okay.
So, uh extract URL. So, here is a URL I
want. Uh so, call a command to
start
icon linky. That's a command. You do
that and that becomes icon. So, you can
show in browser. So, you can see now we
got three copies. So undo
redo. So icon linkify.
So by default it's space space MI. Okay
remember that. Now let's go to the
source code. Okay. This is part of my uh
my uh personalized command. So in this
command it creates so you see this
command takes two
uh links. So uh let me And
yeah so and do so you see you have two
file path then space
MI then it became
uh this like linked icon. Okay. So it
begin so so which is a uh ul a list of
of one item
an older list of one item and this item
contains a link and the link contains
the image. So that's what makes this
icon link. Okay. So undo. So this the
two file path one is a file path one is
the image path. Okay. Open it. So you
see so when you call it space space MI
you see yeah you see it does not add the
width and height it used to but I take
it out because I found you know the so
many width and height very annoying so I
decided you know just remove them
because these uh thumbnail images very
tiny they load very fast so you don't
need them to you know I want a more
clean smaller efficient
file, right? But turns out that's not
good idea because because there's no way
for the browser the browser has to still
load every image in order to find out
the width and height. And I thought I
thought that you know with CSS you can
uh you don't need the width and height
anymore because you can specify width
and height, max height. So you don't
need it. But actually
if you want each of the images or the
icon link to have different height then
it is necessary for each of the image to
contain the width and height. So I do
want each of the icon files to have
different height you see because some of
them are naturally taller. Therefore
I actually need to uh have the width and
height. Okay, I going to stop my alarm
clock.
That's my alarm clock. It beeps every 30
uh minutes to uh remind me to get up and
walk.
Okay. So now let me check um
Okay, hold on a second.
Okay. So, so yeah, I need to do this.
So, let's go back here. Go back to
Emacs. So, um yeah. So, icon linkify.
Okay. So, yeah. So, you press press
press wrong key. Press press press
press. There it is. There it is. And it
didn't add the image link because I took
it out uh several years ago. Now I Let's
So let's let's first of all fix this
command
because I wanted to have the image
within height. What?
What the
there. Okay. So um so okay copy that new
buffer paste it here and oh my god the
font is huge today's date and the
command name thenel
okay so that is we going to work on make
them underscore the link low line make
uh rename the file name so that it's
[snorts] connected not space so and now
add t uf F uh TUTF okay the lexical
binding cookie and UTF8 encoding
declaration that's a EMAC convention so
now you got this so we uh what we going
to do is we modify this code okay given
two lines of file path make them into a
link with image uh used to create links
with image thumbnail that's right first
line should be a HTML file path second
line should be a image file path. Okay,
for example, that becomes that. Okay,
correct. Is it correct still? Because
sometimes I modified my code and I
haven't updated the documentation which
is a common problem. Okay, so uh flow
excel. Yeah, so I think that's right.
Okay, so next cursor should be on the
second line. Okay, this is annoying part
I want it to change because you
you know you should make it so that curs
doesn't matter can be on any line the
program will figure it out but that is
actually some somewhat problematic to
code okay so anyway let's see uh I want
to add uh the image file uh width and
height okay so where is the code doing
that the image so search for img
so there is file if file exist image
path then something something
okay so here is the issue you see oh god
so this is not so easy to fix because it
inserts a hard-coded format
then with the uh arguments for the file
path
okay so uh
So, so it's not just quick modification.
In order to fix this, you need to uh
I mean you can't use this code because
this code does not allow you to simply
add width and height. You need to you
know like find
find width and height here. for example,
then when you insert, you need two more
parameters for width and height. Oh,
actually you can do that. So you all you
have to do is let's see you see this is
uh this is the C gave us this
problem this this this string format
cryptic incomprehensible and you
know percent s you know that
[snorts] with uh the c gave it
gave us this
so anyway uh yeah so we can add actually
so let's just let's just quickly uh get
it to work Okay. Paste. Paste. And this
will be width. Okay. And uh another
dollar sign percent dollar sign. That's
a width. And uh height. Uh what? Not
that not that not that
Which key? This key. No,
this key. Yeah. Okay. This that key for
completion. Okay. height is another
percent s okay s for string actually
uh this should be uh uh it's going to be
numbers it's going to be integers so
integers is um
is it d or n stupid format okay
let's look up format documentation uh I
saw the comment nice haircut thank you
hello
SCP where you from I forgot in you are
in USA right it it you know it's uh it's
a problem that um like when you when you
do live stream you have many people you
forgot but
thank you for coming by anyway so let's
see um what we want to do um hi
hasa
okay so anyway format so what is d is uh
d means produce a a signed number in
decimal.
Uh what is it?
Yeah. Normally, so in EMAC, it's a bit
odd.
Why don't they have like um
showing browser? Okay, let's go here. F5
is undefined showing browser. So, EMAC
this tutorial. Fantastic. So, you want
to go to this basics. That's right. And
you want to go to string and you want to
go to format string. That's my si in my
this tutorial. Okay. Or you think all
the things you ever wanted to know. So
for integer just use D. Okay. So format
number or two decimal. Yeah. So we got
so close that. So you got width and
height. you know that that you know I
for 30 years I pronounced it hate until
when I started to do live stream five
years ago and Allan told me
with and height with and hate. I don't
say no it should be height was idiotic
English you know h ei h ei cannot
possibly be height hate is better okay
anyway so so you got two numbers so you
need so you need here okay so let's
let's uh edit so let me show you okay
let a local variable x width okay uh x
Hate
I hate Unix C fuckets.
Okay, delete that. Pasted it. Prettify
the code. Fantastic. Find width and
height. That's right. And and you need
code to uh set the width and height.
Okay. So this this format value you see
you see now this is the first argument.
the second argument then this is the
third argument let's say you see you
need to so this is first the c
gave us is this this first second
um
1 2 3 4 5 so they the width and height
should be um
here okay so x width and x
predefine Right. Fantastic. And
beautiful. And here you just need to set
within. Hey, how do you do that? I have
a command for it.
South California. South California. I
see. So, what do you do? Uh what what do
you do? Like do you code for a living or
what do you do ACP? Are you a or are you
a student?
So, width and height. So, yeah. So you
need a command to get the width and
height. Yeah, I have I have such a
command. In fact, I have a command you
can get. So uh emac search image with uh
there get image size. Okay.
So actually so you can see right there
go there go to this URL and you will
find the code. Uh in fact there are
several versions. one calls the external
command image magic which is actually
there are five versions also let me
explain okay so um so so so go to Emacs
blog create a new section paste the link
linkify it make a list showing browser
Emacs blog so there it is okay open it
and let me tell you okay so the uh one
version used the Max building sips
command sips.
That's a very nice command line tool on
the Mac by default Mac OS. Okay. So you
don't need image magic. Image magic is
hugely mega bloated. It's like several
gigabytes now. Like when you download
image magic it today it also installs a
text recognition AI engine like
[laughter] several gigabytes. It also
install a whole bunch whole established
you know the mega font suite like entire
thing dealing with fonts because I
suppose because it has to recognize text
so it you know image magic you know it's
like holy bloated
and uh anyway so on the Mac you should
use sips it's it's built in on the Mac
okay on the windows you can also have
one. So this one is dependent. This one
calls image magic cause the shell
command magic. Okay, this one use uh
cause image magic to do it. They return
so they all these functions they take a
file path of a image they return a um
two numbers. Okay. So but what's the
format list? Okay, they return a list of
two items, right? like for a while I was
use uh returning cons or for a while I
was returning vectors
anyway so several versions so this one
uh use image magic okay then there's one
this one use powershell so if you are on
windows this this is like native
powershell building you don't have to
install um any uh packages okay but but
this one is sucks powershell getting the
image width and height is very slow this
uh this powershell okay but apparently
there's no other way so you know like
imagine you know all you want is the
image file size I mean the dimension
width and height turns out it's not so
simple like
uh god so okay then this one for Linux
on Linux you can do it by uh what was
the the file command okay you all you
have to do is just call the file command
okay Then there is eacisp native
version. So you don't need any external
commands. You can do it purely in
eacisp. However, I discovered a bug to
to this day today is not resolved. Okay.
Because I noticed like when you have PNG
files or uh or whatever I I think I
documented the bug somewhere here. Emacs
bug. Emac this get image width and
height. Okay. 2024. So when you have a
image, let's see, do I have an example?
Yeah, PNG, it returns if you use Emacs
way, it returns
and 129 for this image width and height.
Okay, but that's incorrect. If you use
image magic, you know, it returned 205
117. You see? So this you know but it
they are still proportional but it's not
the the the return value does not agree
with image magic.
Okay. So here's a sample image. You see,
so I've I found this bug to to this day.
I'm not sure what's going on
because um because
you see because then I asked AI, you
know, it it it turns out, you know, like
when you have an image, the width and
height of the image, depending on the
image format, usually it's in a header
like uh section. I mean
so the header section will tell you
what's the width and height but the
actual image may act is the has a real
you know depending on the length of the
data has the real width and height
you know so for some image format so in
other words some image format has a
header in a field in in the file that
says you know the width and height
however that is not the reliable way you
know It's it's just a convenient tag.
But the actual the real length
the 100% reliable is actually the length
of data data something like that. Okay.
So it this depends on the image
depending on whether it's a PNG or JPEG
or TIFF or whatever. So this issue is
very complicated you know. So I was
trying to find out you know
why you know is emac this wrong or what
is the actual correct width and height
for this image image it's not that easy
okay well for this this specific image
this PNG it might be easy but anyway it
involves
you know looking at the binary and the
specification and I don't know those you
know so I'm not familiar with those
the C coders would know the C C++ plus
Rust type of coders. They, you know,
this would be uh easy for them.
But anyway, so here, you know, there you
go. There's the the bug about using
Emacs to get the image width and height.
Okay. So and I had some you know I've
been I I wrote this function like 10
years you know been diggling about this
function uh 10 years so many versions
since uh since what's the date since
since like 15 years ago okay but where
is my um
2015 okay yeah but even before that 2017
2015.
Anyway,
so then I also explored you know is it
easier if you just call a Python code
like you can write the you know you can
write the code yourself. This is how you
can do you can do that in Python. So the
EMAC command Emacs command will call
this Python command. The Python command
will you know do it. Would that be
faster if you than image magic you know
so on and also you can have a Goland
command to do it. So this is how you do
it in Goland uh and then how you do that
in PowerShell you see. So I explored
quite a lot ways anyway. So
okay so what do you want to do? So uh so
let's get let's look at the source code.
Uh
uh not yeah let's get the source code
EIP ut okay
so let's see
so you can see you got all these
versions
hold on a Okay.
So, which one do I want to use? Um,
Jesus. Do I have still have this bug?
Oh, it's annoying because you see
ideally you just want to use the emac
dispersion. You don't want dependencies.
It might be a little uh slower, you
know, a fraction of a second, but you
know, but then you discover this bug.
Does does it still happen? Jesus.
Uh yeah. So that's annoying. Okay. So,
let's um
Okay. So, let's go Em EMAC blog. So,
what is this?
No, not that. You want to check the bug.
Okay.
Also, you want to rename this uh this
page name. you want to add width and
height there
so it's easier to search or more
convenient for SEO because I have a
command that search on my website but
they search by title you see so you
don't have if you just type width and
height it won't find those commands you
have to type size
then you you'll find the command you see
so yeah so you need to rename okay so
let's do Okay, that's you know
uh let's this this is uh so yeah so let
me just rename them
Python get image size
width
height
>> [clears throat]
>> It's
tech industry. Three
learning Emacs little by little. Cool.
Uh
let's make them all lower case. Okay.
Copy to my click uh to my register.
Let's do it. So I wrote this command.
You can you can see the um I don't know
if you can see the name that will rename
all my all my links. Okay. So yeah. So
all these are occurrences. Done. Good.
Let's magnify. Okay. Then do this. Get
image size.
do it.
So that's the Golan version. Close. In
PowerShell version, get image size.
Paste. Oh, I forgot. You see, you see
you need this little script
because that indicates it's my personal
code.
You see this little unic code script
icon? So, showing browser go to the
bottom. So, you see
we got that for PowerShell but not for
the Python. Um, yeah, let's add it.
Do that.
That will rename all links in my 13,000
HTML files. So do that again too.
So this is goland.
Okay. Fantastic. Now lastly for the Emac
disp and also remember we stopped using
uh
we stopped using uh
capital letters because I changed the
style in how you name titles. So now
it's all lower case
before it's like get image size show in
browser. So go to the bottom. There it
is. That's better. Okay.
So, Python Goland get width and height.
Okay. And PowerShell get image size
within height and emac this. So, we want
to go to this bug. Copy.
Close it and linkify it there. And go to
this here. Search for PNG.
search for it.
So this is a file
and so
extract the file name paste it here.
Let's see what we have.
So
so the command code is HTML image path
to figure tag. Okay. So
describe function that that's another
command. Uh describe function that.
Okay. Then go to the source code.
And so you see this code adds width and
height.
You see I'm not doing a good tutorial.
I'm like just randomly doing my stuff.
But if you wanted uh like more solid
tutorial, you can watch my past videos
of coding interactive commands. Like
there are hundreds of them, over hundred
of them. So anyway, so here is another
command that that adds the entire
figure tag. Okay, figure and image and
figure caption. Okay. So the part that
what are we doing? So
okay. So it's calling this command image
path to image tag.
Okay. Then we can use that.
Okay. So describe function
go to the source code open it there and
uh so it you see it adds this image tag
width and height and what function does
it use?
So let's see image file P is a image
file then uh then something something.
[snorts]
So there is the width and height. So
let's see. Copy that. Copy.
So you see we can just steal this
snippet. Very nice. You see it's already
actually inserting the whole thing for
you. Very localized. You see how great
compact you know how modular my code
are. [laughter]
So now you go back to um So now you go
back to the code you want to edit. Okay.
Um
not that yes here. Not that here. Okay.
So you just so let Okay, that's what you
want.
Okay, so
and
set them
insert them and delete that. Okay,
prettyify the code. So here's how you
set them.
So you you got so we are calling this
get image file size
and insert them.
So we don't want that code. So because
this one is this one actually get you
the old text. It do some processing and
returns a old text alternative text
based on the image file name. We don't
we don't need it because here we just
want to say thumbnail. Okay. So, but
anyway, the point is to get the width
and height which we have. Okay. D that
uh Okay. Uh and oh, it's a string. So,
you see it's it's a string. So, this
function
returns a pair of string I suppose. So
describe function to go to the source
code
there returns a list width height of
image size. The elements are strings.
Fun in very interesting because when you
design this function you have the you
know you have the issue whether you want
to return numbers or string.
Idea you know usually you want to return
numbers because the image with are
numbers you know. So because when you
have numbers it's much easier to
manipulate. Numbers are like kind
[snorts] of internal format. They don't
cost much as opposed to string. String
cost things because for string you have
to
uh kind of create memory for it. Okay.
So anyway so so then and then you have
to clean up you know the string like in
in turn string you know. Anyway,
so normally for numbers you just want
numbers. You want number type. But in
this case, no because the because the
external command you call usually they
return strings, right? I mean there's no
way to return number. So so if you want
them to be numbers, you have to convert
the string to number. But once you got
numbers eventually you need to be a
string ultimately or like usually
because whenever you get image size
ultimately
you either want to display those on your
screen to tell you you know the width
and height or or insert in a text you
know so ultimately you want them to be
strings. So if you if your function
return a number
like you have to convert a string to
number then back to string. So so I
think it's better to have you know the
it the function return them as strings.
Okay I used to you know I they used to
return uh numbers in my code. I went
back and forth so for over like 15
years. Anyway, so this this function
[sighs]
what are we doing? So this function
depends on the system type. Okay, so if
it's on Windows, it's called image magic
because the PowerShell is like too slow.
On on if it's on the Mac, it calls the
you know the max building sips function
command line. If on Linux it just calls
the file util. So all in fantas
fantastic except the Windows The
Windows the PowerShell is really bad.
Okay. So that's what my code does. Okay.
So Okay. So get image size. Okay. For
now leave it.
Close that. Okay. But did we fix now? Um
so is it is it fixed? I think I think so
actually.
So let's clean up one more time. Eval
the code I actually so I think we are
done. We fixed our
HTML icon linkify with lots of talk.
Okay. So
are we done? Okay.
Um
yeah we can try it. Okay. So, space
space MI.
Fantastic. Can you see the width and
height? And it 327 and 191. It matches
the width and height in file name. Open
it. Wait.
Open it. Fantastic. Okay.
So, now we got that. So, showing
browser. So you see now what we do so
now okay hold on a second so what we
have now we can so now let's remove the
duplicate okay so
remove that remove that back to the
original
page okay now you see all these does
they don't have a width and height we
can fix it by recording a macro
Um,
so how we going to do that? So, okay.
So, let's see. Okay, let me show you.
Okay,
now watch the pink window because it
will show my command names I call and
the keystrokes I type.
Press press
start recording. Marco search
L I
uh wait type uh mistake okay let's start
again
start recording Marco search L I then a
h ef okay then you want to
uh actually search for image
Okay. So wait.
So we ser we searched that press
tab
R to extract the URL.
Then back back
paste
forward
delete. Okay. Then space space M I then
tap D.
Fantastic and beautiful.
So is that right? Yeah. Okay. Now stop
the macro recording
which is that that that. Okay. So we
have recorded our marco. Now we can call
the marco again. So the ne when we call
again we'll fix this line and add the
width and height. Okay. So let's try
press.
Fantastic. Can you see that there
showing browser to make sure it's still
good? Yeah. Mhm.
So now press so we do it again. It'll
fix that. So, okay press. Now, first of
all, make a backup of this file. Now,
press press. Now,
it's done. Now, let's call repeat last
command. So, press press.
Okay, that's a repeat last command. So,
we can I just press one key or do it. Do
it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do
it. Do it.
it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Okay.
This is going to never ends. So, there's
actually lots of actually I can hold on
the key.
Okay. Warning animation. Yeah. So,
Okay. Something is not correct. So now
and do
and do and do and do and do
and do and do. What did I do? Oh, we
went into the Oh
Yeah. So this whole part is Oh Jesus.
Okay. We went too far. So it
we need to fix this. This is a
navigation bar. It went wrong.
Yeah. So in fact we can delete the
entire navigation bar
and copy it from somewhere else. So go
to ergonomic keyboard.
Search for nav. Okay. Cut. Undo. Close.
paste. So now we fixed the nav bar. But
now let's look at the uh did we fix them
all? Looks like yes. You see they all
have width and height.
Now show in browser. Fantastic. So we
added width and height to all
um all of them here. Okay.
Now because I have 1,000, you know,
10,000 HTML files. So I don't want to do
this manually even with a key marker.
Uh yeah. So you want to write the e Emac
this code to process it.
Yeah. But but anyway, there are some
pages I want to update right away. For
example, let's go to Kasali info.
You see this uh there's lots of that I
can fix right now so that when people
this is one of the most frequently
viewed page because that's my homepage
of.info.
So whenever people view this you know
this the cumulative shift.
So let's fix that. Okay. So let's search
for image.
So you can see there's width and height
but there is oh oh I did add width and
height to some of them.
Uh search for
search for image source.
Oh no. You [clears throat] see there's
no width and height here. Okay. So let's
let's try to use our marco. Um no the
marco is not good because let's redo the
macro. Okay. So record
search for
img space src equal. Okay. Stop. Now
go to into the
file path.
Press this key to select the file path.
Copy it.
Now
move to the beginning of the bracket.
Paste the link.
Um
and um and move to the end. Delete it.
Then you want to call the image uh uh
tag. Okay. I forgot what's the command
name.
>> [sighs]
>> uh casa image. Okay. So then meta x
cas
html
path
to image tag tab ei. That's right.
Anyway, so now do it.
Fantastic.
Okay. Now you want to go back. Now
search back. Now actually um
let's say
you see I want the old name to be
thumbnail. I don't want that, you know.
So
what's the best way to do this? Okay.
So, okay. So,
go do that. Search a L T
equal. Enter. Go into it. Select the
thing.
Delete. Then type
thumbnail.
Good. Okay. Now
stop Marco. Fantastic.
Now when we call Marco again, it will
fix this one. This one. Okay.
Okay. You got a problem because this one
is SVG. Now SVG file is a text file. SVG
file is a
XML. SVG file is XML which is a text
file. Okay. Now, so but for SVG file, so
you don't have the width and height like
a normal bitmapped image. However,
depending on the specific SVG file,
sometimes you do. So, it depends on uh
for example, this one, you got the width
386.75177.
You see? So, it gets complicated. So,
then now you got a floating point for
width and height. you you know then you
need to remove the
uh the decimal part. So anyway so I'm
not sure what will happen. I forgot you
know I've wrote so many code to deal
with this. I think the I forgot what my
particular command do but let's try it.
Okay so called the keyboard macro.
Okay so it added nicely the 387. Okay,
it added nicely
and uh wait but it did not change this
old you see
wait why didn't it not
why did it not change this part to
thumbnail I don't know
it should
let's see let's try next okay press
address.
It did not change the thumbnail. What?
That's not what we want. Okay. So, press
press.
All right. Press press press press.
That's no good. I want I want it to be
thumbnail. Okay. Uh
so let's record again.
Uh but this time
I know tab EI. Okay, that command is tab
EI.
Okay, let's see.
Start recording. Wait, let's just copy
uh
let's see what we have
did that. Let's just say
put that to register. Okay, now
start recording.
Search for
image src equals to stop. go into it,
get the file path, copy
then
um
then go to the beginning, paste,
go to the end, delete.
Then
tap EI. That's right. Then
go to the beginning again. Search alt
equal.
Oh, Typed the wrong thing.
Uh, that's not good.
I typed the wrong thing. Okay.
So, let's do we need to do this again.
Okay. So,
so let's say this one. Okay. Well, let's
skip the SVG. Those are SVG.
So, let's God, all these are SVG.
Search for JPEG. So, let's try this one.
Okay, that's mathematics.
So start recording. Wait,
what? Wait.
Start recording.
Search that img space src equals to
stop. Go in.
Press press. Select the path. Copy.
No,
no, this one already has the width and
height.
Anyway, um I think you know, so I think
I'm going to write, you know,
uh Emac this script to do this.
Okay. So, anything else? I think that's
it for today.
See, four people watching.
Oh, is there some
Okay, that's it for today. Yeah, you
know, if I do this offline, it'll be
much faster. It'll be like, you know,
doing the same thing,
uh, doing online would be like five
times slower, more than five times
slower. I mean,
if I go into a rant, it's like 10 times
slower. But if you if I did not go into
a rant, um, doing online is like five or
10 times slower.
because because if I do this offline I
don't have to talk you know like
everything
you know so this is like accessing
memory like when you work on a computer
accessing so you have three storage
areas you you want you can retrieve
information like the the one of them is
your hard disk
you know that's hard disk okay the other
one is your RAM your memory like I have
like you know 16 gigabyte of RAM
>> [snorts]
>> uh performance memory you know
but the then the another one is the
internal cache like the CPU the GPU the
CPU they got cache like cache one cache
2 something very complicated okay like
L1 cache L2 cache L3 cache
so basically each level like the memory
is a magnitude faster than disk.
I forgot 100 times faster or something.
The then the cash is 100 times faster
than than your RAM. Okay, let's ask AI
for some fun. So, let's just ask AI for
some fun.
How much faster is L1 cache versus RAM?
L1 cache is roughly 50 to 100 times
faster than RAM. L1 hits in about 1 to
four CPU cycles under a nancond on a
modern chip while RAM takes 60 to 100
cycles or around 50 to 100 nonds. That
gap is why missing the cash hurts so
much.
How faster how much faster is RAM
compared to flash drive?
>> RAM is roughly 100 to a thousand times
faster than flash storage. Random reads
from RAM take around 50 to 100 nonds
while flash SSDs take 10 to 100
microsconds. That's 100 times to 1,000
times slower depending on the workload.
Sequential speeds look closer on paper,
but for real world random access, RAM
wins by a huge margin.
How much faster is flash SSD versus
spinning drive?
SSDs are roughly 50 to 100 times faster
than spinning hard drives for random
access. A spinning drive takes 5 to 10
milliseconds for a random read, while an
SSD does it in 50 to 100 microsconds.
That about 100 times faster. Sequential
speeds are closer, but for everyday use
with lots of small files, SSDs feel
dramatically snappier.
>> Exactly. So, thank you. Thank you, Eve.
You're very welcome. Glad I could help.
>> So you see
uh L1 cache is like 100 times faster
than RAM and RAM is like 100 times or
thousand times faster than flash drive
and flash drive is 100 times faster than
the solid spinning drive. So in the same
way, your brain is like a thousand times
faster than when you have to speak
things out.
Uh so you're in the motherboard and sit
next to the CPU. That's right. It's not
I mean it's like like you know uh you
mean the RAM, right? L1 cache uh
learning Emacs little by little. Yeah.
From tech industry. Okay. So L1 cache L2
cache in general are for CPU operations
purpose is different than RAM.
Yeah.
Okay. So that's it today. Hello uh Mo.
Um that's thank you for watching. Thank
you guys. Bye.
Bye.