good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of exotic show today is 2019
December 12th Thursday 11 o'clock
37 minutes San Francisco time I forgot I
had a video scheduled like an hour ago
now in 30 in 30 minutes ago and so thank
you guys for coming and today we have
several topics to talk about
okay the YouTube is not receiving enough
video to maintain Smooth Streaming or
such videos we experienced what what
okay hold on a second let me technical
issues okay in my life okay what studio
mod okay so for some reason my oak Mick
Oaks is not working anyway today we have
several topics Oh am i alive guys am i
here am i here so
Ohama ohio Cosima's ooh okay i don't
know what that does that what does that
mean I think I can approve it right so
today we have several topics to talk
about we're gonna talk about the elvish
language linguistics and we are going to
talk about Japanese input systems
continue from yesterday so you guys I'm
alive great I'm not okay do cardio
cardio by the way are you on discord
join my discord club okay
you can find the link on my website just
go to saudi dot info join the discord
club if you are not there already i
don't know who you are
well anyway so today we're gonna talk
about Japanese input systems Japanese
language Japanese key keyboard layouts
that's a fascinating topic oh and we are
going to talk talk about the elves the
language of the elves so today's the
subject matter is the subject matter is
linguistics the language of human
animals and grape juice to good life so
you know you don't know how hard it is
being a woman looking the way I do and
[Laughter]
oh where is my energy drink that is
necessary a necessary condition what oh
okay
energy drink the juice of life ban
sugar-free okay always drink sugar-free
never never drink sugared water
okay never not have C no Coke no nothing
like that no no no no sugar okay I don't
know about mall as loon areas is ruin
areas here green areas is into mall as
he's talking about mall ass every day in
Canada you know Canada is famous for
maple syrup are we talking about having
so scripts okay that topic about the the
love thing I cannot I cannot fathom why
people would use this okay let's talk
about this for five minutes okay so so
you people are talking about this thing
the labs so apparently this guy this is
the fitting famous youtuber of the Linux
lineage you know the heat so he he is a
handsome guy and he does Linux YouTube
videos repealed okay based based okay so
he is this guy Luke Smith Luke Smith oh
I can remember is his pretty face okay
ah no JavaScript so let's turn on
JavaScript and let's try it again
so Luke Smith of popular YouTube who
does Linux related stuff not just Linux
is because it's not he is kind of the
you know hacker type okay so oh he has a
Twitter account as well so let's go so
his YouTube let's go to his YouTube so
there is this guy there exists this guy
whose name is Luke Smith he does
bunky oh he walks a Bunge is that really
bunkies again gaming company right funky
new updates love developers whatever
destiny destiny des game okay so that's
a gaming company so apparently he works
at Bunge or something like that he's
associated with Bunge and and okay so
his profile photo his darkness pitch
darkness that's that's the
representation of him and let's look at
his YouTube Oh YouTube you need to turn
on JavaScript otherwise no candy for you
basic rotation basic rationale for using
lobs so Allen says bootstrap arc install
with sensible defaults and when then
customize from there and Allen says Adam
proclaims that is the basic rationale
for using lobs okay Ron page look Smith
does not work at Bunge oh okay so this
is not the Duke Smith we want okay so I
thought so because he doesn't he doesn't
look like game developer so this is Luke
Smith the real one not the blue peer one
the rapier one this is the this is the
real Luke Smith okay so he does videos
typically touching on Linux you know the
the the hacker culture that is a proper
wait he's you know among the hacker
culture did talk about that kind of like
me okay and as far as I know he's into
UNIX philosophies okay he's my rock
enemy when it comes to philosophy anyway
he so I was I've watched like three
three or four of his videos they are
good you know I am too old to keep
watching this kind of thing so anyway so
he created this this this script
cage bash shell script that is supposed
what you know what an ugly what an
ugly
Lago I wouldn't use it okay so anyway he
created this script called lobs that is
supposed to you know let me read it okay
so let's magnify that magnify so he says
lobs is an efficient shell script that
will install a fully featured tiling
window manager based system on any our
clinic space system without any of the
routing of manual post install processes
in configurations configurations okay so
it's it's the it's a windows manager
easy for our clinics crap i wouldn't use
it i mean i cannot fathom why would
anyone na well economy in a sense of
philosophically you know philosophy
because he's into UNIX philosophy that
kind of thing and he created this script
I will never use and will never touch I
cannot fathom today's Linux people
especially you and the crash hacker you
know cachaca is this nerd guy in our
community where is it programming okay
crash hacker I don't know where's crash
hacker
what's your youtube name show up guys so
anyway crash hack he's also using it
apparently so crash hacker is a hacker
he is right now in Japan now all this is
public information okay he's in Japan
and doing his doing artificial
intelligence in the subfield of image
recognition facial recognition you know
things like that so he's you know he
puts he possess the input he you know he
has a machine that's a supercomputer you
know one day if you last week he showed
a computer you know that's 126 CPUs
something like that
than Emily and then he ran now is seen
you know he's doing research apparently
and in Japan he's doing you know image
you know artificial intelligence image
recognition kind of research so he's
working with supercomputers apparently
and he also is like oh yeah I you know
loves is a great thing hi I cannot
fathom I cannot I cannot understand
so this script you know you if you wanna
us use Linux if you want use our clinics
especially our clinics which is more
kind of advanced more geeky more nerdy
Linux okay just diving get your hand
dirty you know tell you you know yeah
yeah so you want to install the tiling
windows manager which is kind of the
nerdy thing you know hiding I oh I want
Linux but not just that I don't want
women to I want I want the the advanced
our clinics and I want adding windows
manager you dive into it and spend hours
to fix the config that's that that's the
purpose that is the goal that is the
gist of these things you know that's you
be play with it you learn you you know
you you you you let you go through the
hard process of learning you know the
config tiny managers how to set up so
that is how I take it you know that's
how I see it you know and when I see
this it's like ridiculous I cannot
understand so why like there are people
using that I cannot understand but
according to you guys you know according
to add and you know crash hacker
apparently so it's the reason seems to
be like well yeah you know so our
clinics is the better Linux and the
window manager is a better system
therefore we want to use it but this you
know this patch script just helped us
you know to install it it easily then we
can config you know they can't diving or
something yeah I don't I don't get it
okay that's not my
things that I think you know from what I
see this is not hackers to hacker do not
do these okay it may be times change you
know this in 1990s nobody would do this
you know you don't you don't download
someone else's smash script so that it
helps you makes it easier for you to
install the window managers you know
that's you don't do that if you are
hacker I mean are you a hacker or not
are you interested in to the hackers
subculture you know that you don't do
this then if you are if you are such a
people which most of many of you guys
are you don't do this okay nobody would
do this but perhaps times changed you
know I'm getting old and the new
generations of halves times changed so I
don't know so that is about that that is
my conclusion of our lives
Finch okay Finch agrees with me okay
okay I do have one agreement okay great
I'm not too old yet so Alan says is
hacker community gatekeepers I don't I
don't know and I use Windows so okay so
let's see what's a comment so we cannot
talk about I think we're gonna talk
about so anything anything about this
that you know anything about this that's
interesting so what does slavs install
okay so yeah you know I would you know
and at least okay that's not my thing I
mean you cannot you won't use a Kleenex
you dive in you you study you go through
the pain the every details of the pain
that is the point okay you know like
they say no pain no gain but you could
argue well you know this makes it easier
you just install it first then you start
to play with it yeah that works too this
is not you know this is not really
important you know if you want to do it
that way that's fine
okay so that that is about that okay
this will actually let me copy that lob
start XYZ Oh interesting domain now you
have a domain X Y Z so let's go to
Kassar talks on talk show open it
and paste the link here so that so that
on a second so we we wrote this Emacs
command command let's make use of it
so Sabich font okay sorry bigger font
Global enter every buffer every window
now has bigger font
great so now we go here and where we
post it here so this is lobs LARPs okay
okay show in browser okay that's that
then back to Emacs go over here let's
cook sauce start command not mod so on
this window you see all my Emacs
commands my neighbor is making great
noises apparently there is a excavator
that's digging the road or something
every day there is a problem where is it
wait what huh LOB's showing browser why
is it not okay so I paste it in a wrong
place
what's going on oh man okay so I need to
go to main here so show in browser
there it is slops okay so this window
needs to move down it needs to move down
according to the saw workflow of using
the mouse auto click ok so in Firefox is
over here the labs that's our first
topic and the other topic I want to do
is so today I was doing so so so guys
let me know you know if you prefer to
talk about the Japanese input system
Japanese writing system Japanese input
system and Japanese keep
layouts those are related topics let me
know type it we're gonna cover that okay
back type it right now that's one thing
oh we're gonna talk about the elf the
language of the elves okay that's the
other topic the language of the elves so
what about the language of the elves let
me show you okay so okay yeah my my my
moving windows you know that my moving
windows is a is a weakness
okay of my system where i could set of
key but I just didn't
so I was studying let me show you okay
the elves the language of the elves so I
was looking at the keyboard so case our
keyboards some keyboard and I was
working on the oboe ducks keyboard let
me show you the picture okay over Docs
again let me know okay you wanna see
talking about elfs language or the
Japanese input system type it okay
actually we are starting to talk about
the elf language so I got a new picture
today from one you know one of the
people you know in in this code so this
guy is oh I didn't know yeah fun track
so he he this is his keyboard ago Docs
and look at the key caps what language
is it I was wondering and I was looking
at my periodic passage we don't want
that banned key codes indeed I was
looking at okay so let me get this let's
not let me go to Unicode so I was
looking at my my unicode documentation
and I was trying to identify what
language is it now it's not Japanese and
it's not
Ethiopia it's not you know I don't know
what it is I don't know what language it
is and it's not Arabia for example so I
asked people and people answered you
know people got gaming gave me the
answer apparently that's elvish language
that's the language of the elves where
is it you know Emily answered and Emily
told me it's the language of the elves
you know you guys have talked a lot I
haven't been reading them because I was
busy I was pissed busy studying about
the elf language in the past two hours
and tango ah yes correct so Finch knew
okay so let me read the comments ok so
anyways also I learned so it's elvish so
I started to look up on the elvish
language it turns out it's one gigantic
complexity one gigantic artificial
complexity why because the elf language
okay we have two pictures let's show
let's show some glory of these pictures
the elf language okay that's one of them
two of them let's see we can so this oh
there is one so we can see we have two
ago ducks with the elf elvish language
on the keycaps it's look it looks cool
you know it's yeah although it's not it
would not be the one I would choose
I mean if I were to choose some sort of
firing or cool language for keycaps I
would not choose this one
another popular alternative is runes
okay actually I close the windows so
anyway so here is another look so these
two key caps the you can you know you
can check out the letter arrangement
they are pretty much the same okay so
for example look at the top row on the
left okay and you can also look
go back to look at the top row on the
left it's pretty much the same except on
this one you have some kind you have
words you know you actually have words I
suppose that means tab I suppose that
means caps lock you know things like
that I suppose that means shift you know
so over there on the left and on the
right as well so they actually have some
phrases words of the elvish language and
but on this one they don't have that
they just use you know they just say
they just use English so anyway that's
the that's the pictures so I started to
look into then it turns out the elf
language is one complete artificial
complexity now this you are looking at
is the lineage of the elf language from
Wikipedia
so elf language you know of course it's
a constructed language and in other in
other words it's fake fake language fake
okay fake news fake and it's created by
this Lord of the Ring Toki ungai now
this token guy is famous among nerds
I know of probably many of you we all
like get et like oh my god Oh Toki no
yeah you got straight hours reading it
so Tokyo language nerds
amis Aichi woofle week hey hey I think I
know you I think I know you somewhere
you are at least a max user right
massage week or you being on you being
on my youtube channel before he's always
or something like one or the other or
both
anyway so the elf language okay answer
okay anyway so the Alpha language so the
Lord of the Rings the dystopian guy who
wrote Lord of the Rings and he so he
created in in you know a lot of rings is
three thick volumes why was young like
when I was you know 22 I was trying to
read it because I heard
I heard you know all the guys people you
know this is back in 1991 in 1991 at
that time you don't have internet okay
you know you have a life there is no
internet so it might be your life you
don't you don't know how it works
so back in 1991 I heard well that that's
when I was like 22 I heard there is Lord
of the Rings it's one of the great
classic novel you know in the rearm of
science fiction or some kind of fantasy
fantasy fiction and I am very much into
reading so I read a lot classics so
that's I want to read that because I you
know because I read you know this is one
of the best and so I bought actually I
bought all the all of them Lord of the
Rings and The Hobbit or was it just the
Hobbit anyway so Lord of the Rings there
are three volumes of it okay this is a
novel printed and then the Hobbit is
another novel it's supposed to be the
prelude to the Lord of the Rings so you
have the Hobbit then you have three
volumes of the Lord of the Rings now
supposedly if you want to read them you
just read a good morning part is what
here somewhere hey hey but so lot of
greens you supposed to just read them
but the Hobbit although it's a tree dude
some people say it's kind of boring so
you might you know it's not necessary
that you read The Hobbit before the Lord
of the Rings so you could just go ahead
and read The Lord of greens so anyone of
you have you guys read it the Lord of
the Rings or any of you are fan okay I'm
gonna read the comments pretty soon okay
Lord of the Rings okay so you can read
them so I started to read The Hobbit
because I tends to be systematic I want
to read from the beginning every word
you know back then I have this habit I
told a
few times in my video I want to read
every page every word you know in
sequencing order so I started to read
The Hobbit but I didn't get far and
somehow I find it boring or something I
didn't get far so I end up so Alan so
you have read The Lord of the Rings all
the three volumes this was packing
graduate school days
oh okay so graduate school so you went
to so you have a degree like you I mean
a graduate degree you have masters or a
PhD yes love the series okay Freddy also
read it I guess so anyway so I started
to read The Hobbit it didn't go far so
hey I just never read it you know I just
never read it then until in 2002 also
the movie Hollywood started to pump out
the Lord of the Rings movies and I
watched them
I've watched I think the first three so
okay so I watched the first three you
know a lot of rings and turns out I
don't really like it okay you know I
watch the movies you know I know all the
notes you know they are quite this is
this Lord of the Rings thing is
significant among the hacker culture
okay yeah I know quite a few you know
big nerds and small nuts they are all
into it for example the Eric Raymond ESR
guy who wrote the cathedral and the
bazaar and who you know wrote many UNIX
programs in early days and you know yes
ah he's pretty famous pretty in famous
so he also of course he's a big fan in
fact he has written
I forgot what he has written some
linguistic or linguistics or something I
mean he's he's very into it and he
talked about that anyway so and he he
and by the way Eric s es ah he is uh
he's a great writer okay I don't like
the guy I don't like his opinions I
don't like his
UNIX philosophy I don't like his idiotic
hackers logo you know guys remember
hacker logo he created that so that he
can become more famous and sometimes I
see on Twitter or elsewhere I see people
using my logo and I was like stop it you
know hacker logo yeah so he created this
this thing okay the glider it's a this
thing this thing came from 1 2 3 1 2 3 4
5 5 dots this thing came from here's a
guy okay he is a bad picture of him but
that's a picture very popular so this
logo came from the game of life which is
artificial which is called cellular
automata it's one instance of cellular
automata which is entirely fascinating
subject also computer science
anyway that's digression but anyway he
created the hacker logo okay so ESR so
what I'm saying is that he's very much
into geez what are these these are wrong
okay so I guess okay so I guess the new
generation is kind of replacing this you
don't even find the popular hacker logo
anymore you know it should be just like
that it should be just like this okay
but you don't find much pictures I'm
afraid some point is gonna pop out
because I have the I have the censorship
censorship turned off anyway so lord of
the rings it's a big thing of my notes
but I actually never read it and the way
I read when I read the movement and when
I watch the movie it turns out I don't
like it that much
yeah you know I didn't like it that much
for reasons for whatever reasons I don't
know but however on the other hand when
I watched when I learned the what is the
name of that show do you guys can you
guys such you know
the recent the last episode ended half a
year ago the what's the name of that
show Kim of the Thrones when I learned
about Game of Thrones about two years
ago I started to look I don't have a TV
I don't have Netflix or whatever I don't
have nothing but I watch I can watch
clips on YouTube and I can read
Wikipedia I can also read you know the
Wikipedia wiki you know wiki for the
game of thongs this tremendous amount of
information so anyway when I learned
about the game of Thrones I find it
fascinating okay I find it I'm like
fantastic I spent hours reading about
Game of Thrones
you know geeking about Game of Thrones
and also watching all the clips on
YouTube so in fact I almost know the
entirety of the story of The Game of
Thrones so that's in contrast in
contrast although these two epic this -
our epic game of Thrones and Lord of the
Rings
they are epic and they are in the same
similar fantasy era you know but it
turns out I don't like the Lord of the
Rings at all but I do like very much
Game of Thrones and what is the reason
and well I haven't really actually
thought about what is a logical reason
you take you know ten minutes to think
about that but anyway anyway so get a
load of rings where are we talking about
load of rings because in load of rings
there are different different races one
of them is elves elves Emoto and elves
they have languages you know it turns
out this guy Tolkien who wrote log roll
up means he you know he's a scholar he's
what what do you see I forgot but he's
right you know not just a writer but
he's also a scholar linguist link
linguist you know he study I think he
was a professor I forgot but he in you
know when writing Lord of the Rings he
created a entire you know it's an epic
story so it's you know you cover
hundreds of years or thousands of years
like history you have an entire
fictional history and universe then you
have different you have languages used
in by different races then among them is
elves elves in a race that is Emoto and
beautiful and they so they have you know
this so they have languages elves
languages but it's not just one okay
it's not just one like the Star Trek
idiotic idiotic ringa Linga okay you
have a Klingon language and nerd so
nerds log into it but this lo de RINs
this elf language do you have an entire
history family of the of the elfs
language not obvious just one of the
language he's got other languages
complexity you know entire
artificial complexity so we are looking
at the family of a of languages so in
the beginning you have primitive
Queanbeyan okay that's that's a
prototype of the of language and then
you evolve to comment out elder Ian and
other in then coming out of and evolved
into so then you have the Queen Nia
tailoring sim varying not Orion you know
it's like this this kind of group of
languages they are like real life
history of languages it's a mess but
however these are entirely artificial
you know he just created hey he just
created the whole thing himself
nerds creating artificial complexity and
you go to Wikipedia you can see you
there are tons of articles and neat
gritty details like how they evolved
what what race are they what time you
know this epic from Lord of the Rings
what time you know the great March or
whatever and okay so so you have of
languages and I you know I only read
about one hour
before you know just one hour before and
it turns out they so what what yeah so
you see I was looking at it because I
wanted to know what what caps key caps
are used you know what language is this
so I started to read about Alvin and you
go to Olivia so there's a lot of
information okay so let me not try let
me try to summarize what's going on so
in the end so Alvin so in my one hour
reading about Alvin apparently there are
two main elvish dialects okay
one is Quenya this one Quenya and the
other one is Centurion that's as far as
I know I haven't I haven't completed my
reading of this so anyway this is
getting esoteric so let's let's just let
me let me get to the point okay so elf
elf language let's go to Wikipedia let
me show you some of the interesting
things elvish language okay you click
there so apparently not just opium but
many others have created or try to
create a language of the elves
so in Wikipedia they show a list of some
of them and then you click on the elvish
language of the token then you arrive on
this page which is which is a kind of a
summary of the elf languages in token
universe then you can see all the
different ones
the common element you know but anyway
you go to Kenya and you go to cinterion
I don't know if I pronounce them
correctly but then but basically the
writing system okay let me tell you
about the writing system you see that
that is what you see on the oviducts
keyboard that there okay so and you know
so we are talking about the writing
system of the what wait time timeline of
order yeah I don't I don't care about
the timeline of order so anyway so this
is Alvin okay so it
school down you know they show you
consonants this is a full linguistic
article phonology consonants more foam
form or muffle phenomics what the
moon Amex and alle phony palatial
clusters labial clusters guttural
glottal clusters simple ab
simplification of clusters vows so
anyway I want to get to the writing
system like what alphabet do they use
okay this is you know so here okay so
here a writing system of the Quenya
elvis training system so so okay so
anyway so
so this Quenya language the rating
system is this this thing called penguia
okay here penguin
so the crania the Quenya which is one
tire leg of the elf language they they a
writing system uses this Quenya penguia
alphabet
you know the tango our script it looks
like that so I was reading about this a
little bit it doesn't appear to me okay
it's it does not appear to me for some
reason I did I don't I just it doesn't
then the cinterion which is another
branch of the elf language then we can
see you know basically they have at
least two writing systems now let me try
to find out the other one so that is
this here no they didn't they also use
penguia okay but anyway the other
writing system is based on rooms runic
okay so it's not on this page I forgot
where which page but innocent let me
show you the runic script so let's go to
Unicode actually let's go to say Unicode
Kesari eunuch
and let's imagine evolving so how many
people asked your watching let's see
general much much liberties let's see
eleven people okay we talked up for 40
minutes we're gonna shut down maybe ten
more minutes okay so you go through my
Unicode such Unicode rune and you you
will arrive on this page sorry
Unicode run so this is run and what is
run run is kind of ancient it began it
looks like that okay and in fact I have
a JavaScript technology you see I'm also
interested to know this script so you
have learn script you have penguia
script then you have JavaScript I'm also
a script for example oh you need to turn
on JavaScript god no now let's select
for example now we are typing JavaScript
ok typing spelled wrong typ ing
JavaScript in real time and it is
translated or actually transcript it
into the runic script fantastic okay go
there use it okay promote my website
okay so let's go paste the link in my
unicode face link here so we can see we
have a topic we talked about we talked
about so so there it is okay so we were
talking about actually we were talking
about elvish script
and tang war and the ogle docks okay and
oh go ducks keyboard so aintry show okay
show in browser so we talked about a go
ducks keyboard elf elf elf elvish not
elf fish no no that's not right
II let's just say elf language stupid
English stupid English elf language okay
in penguin King was script okay
ting Gua script then okay so so we are
talking about a load and the load of the
Rings and and and the Lord of the Rings
okay and okay so so in elf language
there's a big family and among them the
two big ones is is is crane Quenya and
the other one big one is sin sin Darion
okay and the writing system they use the
script is tin wah but however there is
another one they it's it's it's they use
one based on rune ruining script you
know this guy Toki and he just started
to modify this run characters and but
that that one the runic script based one
for the elf language did not go far so
it's it is the tengwar
tink war that went far and most most
nerds geeks love this because why I can
tell you why okay this is psychology
analysis of human psychology
because if you have a new language based
on rune okay
rune is a old language I mean in doing
is used in studying in year 1,500 I mean
year 152 about year 1500 you know it's
not really that ancient you know it's
like okay so anyway so you have the run
script and the Tokyo guy tried to modify
it a little bit so it still looks
similar so that's no fun
you know you already we already have
runs you just modified a little bit
that's no fun so nuts
it doesn't attract nerds now but however
when Nazi tengwar this this holy cow
this is alien holy cow look we have
never seen this before thinkwe then
there's a they becomes a magnet there's
attraction that that is why you see on
the Ergo docs keyboard is so Tangra but
by the way there's also you learned
look at this keyboard okay so this is
ultimate hacking the ultimate among or
hacking this is one this one is called
the ultimate ultimate hacking keyboard
which I possess right over there I
showed a few times in my video so anyway
this one is you know it's using the run
key caps okay so as versus you know
drunky caps versus the where's my gogo
dogs versus the oh god ah the the the
Tengu are the elf elvish key caps which
which guys you know which would you use
that is the question which one do you
think is more like beautiful or what
what do you guys think okay so now I'm
going to read so that I think that
concludes my talk about this elf elvish
language that's that's about that and I
think that's it for today as well
so let me read okay so let me read the
comments okay let's go through the
comments and we shut down in maybe five
minutes or so let's see anything
interesting we need to go to Google okay
so so that's it for today
let's take five more minutes and talk
random stuff and let's see so magnify we
I need I need I cannot see anymore you
get old you cannot see anymore I need to
magnify super super giant font okay now
that's better so so let's read from the
beginning I have some time so the left
one so bar says the left one is better
so the the Bart prefers the tengwar
script in bar says I don't like
staggered keys I don't know why so many
wannabe yoga
staggered yeah that's well yeah that's
true but that's a different issue though
what could have made eunuchs better
what could that's that's a complex
question I mean what could made eunuchs
better I mean how how do I answer that
it's a big question so I'm gonna check
out the comments okay take a sip to
health
so Daniel Anglo is has been gambling at
the casino oh no just playing poker okay
passion stole script okay so more less
Mona's monads bootstrap bootstrap arc
install with sensible defaults okay
wrong page Luke Smith okay so got that
minimalism
oh so Luke Smith is into minimalism I
see the UNIX philosophy so that's a
whole point of our clinics okay so by
the way I use PS PWM now what is PS PWM
another esoteric tightening system PS
PWM oh there it is
PS PWM are our clinics okay it says
there is apparently a Wikipedia entry
meaning it's not it's not a small player
it Oh someone deleted the Wikipedia game
ok b SP w BS pwm is a tiling window
manager that represents windows Asli let
us the leaves of a full binary tree
[Laughter]
turning windows manager that represents
windows as the leaves of a full binary
tree why what do you like what what you
gonna do with that it only responds to X
events and the messages he receives on a
dedicated socket okay it's a problem
that what doesn't handle okay whatever
whatever show a picture okay show a
screenshot no screenshot this is typical
of this in this nerd idiots knots no
screenshot okay oh my god it's got three
three thousand stars
show me a picture you see this Linux
idiots show a picture I don't
care about your tree you idiot okay so
what did it jump to somewhere let's see
so it's hacker community gatekeepers I
use Windows I use I have no hacker is
gaping the truck trying manager okay
using a Robson is like Safra keys for
your whole OS no I don't think so
it's useless garbage that nobody needs
that doesn't fix any problem
laughs fry OS fancy so Italian window
manager for Microsoft Oh really fancy
zones that's what having window manager
for Microsoft I haven't heard of that ok
year windows on the desktop watch some
move window without having windows ok
does anyone know that the UCI yeah that
is a problem I mean that is you in when
you see my move my windows you you'll
see oh oh God SAS system is the worst
you know why ok I have two V's I tell
you two things about that
one is that because I have Mouse auto
click you see I don't click I showed
this many times in my video you see I
don't click auto click is just fantastic
ok actually so let me adjust this so
like you can actually see how you can
actually see so there is my oh wait so
actually I need to show you the windows
as well so you can see my hand I'm not
you see I'm holding the mouse like that
ok I put a movie here it just it just
auto clicks you know I can move to this
tab ok I can move to auto click that's
what
oh oh you might go a Hoover Creek okay
it's Auto click the it goes by several
different names stupid names for example
they usually call it trail on the Mac
for example they it's called trail
because it's supposed to be for the
disabled drill meaning you know it's
supposed actually it's supposed to be
used in a tracking system like so when
you are staring at somewhere for more
than let's say one second then it does a
click so that's what is suppose I think
originally what is supposed to be trail
okay so you on a Mac you go to
accessibility then then you go to it's
it's a bit then you go to keyboard okay
then accessibility keyboard then you can
see this enable accessibility keyboard
yeah there yes
what tray out there you see you see that
button that says tray options exactly
this is a part you see the name trail
jail so why would they call it trail why
don't you just stupid you know just
called Auto Creek that's what it is
Auto quick well suppose I suppose or
internally it's designed for you know
eye trackers or something so when you
your eyes are trailing at the point then
it makes a quick something like that
okay so it's called trail on Linux now
but I have articles about that okay this
is fantastic I mean this training is you
never act like you don't have to click
anymore it's really fantastic
especially if you are using a trackball
so let me show you a sorry Otto Creek
so I have article on how to Mac on Linux
on Windows by the way I'm in Windows 10
apparently they removed this feature at
least from the GUI so you can no longer
turn this song we are the GUI but
however the feature is still there you
have to go into some kind of wake waist
okay so I have this article is for Mac
and I have articles for Windows there
okay and and for Linux now I don't have
an article for Windows now because
Windows they remove that feature in
Windows 10 it used to be you know in
Windows Vista or 7 or something so
anyway so on Linux is so I have articles
so this is our Mac you can just go and
you know it's this is great I would
recommend it but however we want its you
it will take some use too because you'll
get frustrated for the first week my
history of using this is you know I
tried it some seven years ago and I
didn't like it after a few days I think
this is like I don't want to click and
you just clicked by mistake you know
that happens
often so I stopped but after a few
months you know because I'm obsessive
about this user interface and so I I
thought about it then I thought maybe I
should try it again then that that then
I stuck you know I insist
in this stuck so I've been using this
Auto click for seven years now on Linux
on Windows in our Mac okay so this Auto
Creek and on Linux it's a bit complex
because on Linux you have two things you
have first first of all the auto race of
Windows you know the idiotic vinick's
you know the first of all so they have
two things because due to their window
manager system because well do 2x11 okay
in other words it's the technology the
way it is implemented that that effect
how how it is exposed to the user in
other words but anyway on linux you have
two concepts one is the auto auto race
of Windows that means if you move a
mouse over window you're automatically
automatically come up again there are
two options either you want it
automatically to come up or you don't
have to have them pop up but instead you
have focus you know yeah another idiocy
of the Linux in x11 Linux you have the
concept called focus which means for
example my mouse right now my window is
the browser but however you see my Emacs
window is behind it but however I can
make it I can make my Emacs window
focused without pinning it to the front
that's that's what this focus means so
when a window is focused that means
whenever you type something it goes
through that window so that's that's
what X 11 is the idiocy this I'm trying
to not swear okay this UNIX this came
from UNIX okay so you have this so
anyway so
so our linux x11 the GUI system you have
auto race you can set it to auto race or
or autofocus don't use auto focus okay
don't do that just use auto race but
however the auto race does not actually
do quick you see it's different from
auto click because for example if I'm if
I'm on Linux if I raise my move my mouse
to this tab it will not make it
you will not click you see even if you
have auto race on because the purpose of
auto race is just about the windows you
know the windowing system but however on
Linux you do have auto race that's
another thing that's again that's called
rail ok
so Hoover Creek okay so you go to this
article so this is the Linux trail just
like the Mac it actually does a quick
whenever the kusa stops moving it does a
quick so on Linux if you want auto click
you you know you type these commands to
turn it on then you want to turn off the
auto race because then because it
becomes redundant you know so anyway
that's the story on Linux you can try
you can go and try it and I would say
this is this auto racing it works great
with a mouse but it was works fantastic
with a trackball so if you have not
already pay me okay you go to my website
go to the track board go to a keyboard
then you see my keyboard reviews and
always it not anyway so you go to track
boss I have lots of reviews of yeah ok
so anyway I have lots of reviews of
track polls you go there and buy it
because the auto race this auto click or
auto race wait
works fantastically with trackball so
let me copy this thing actually let me
just paste it here and we are almost
done I haven't read of sorry I haven't
I forgot the comments okay so so we are
almost done
two two three three more minutes okay
copy mouse Hoover click paste here back
to browser close it copy that min
extinct in here and make and go to the
browser and back to here because that
who a mouse to windows copy it close it
back to Emacs actually back to Emacs
face it here ok and back I don't want to
go back here I want to back to this
browser and what is this ok this close
and BS ok let's copy yeah
ok so let's we talked about that give
them a link okay so so notes will be
happy ok we then we have the list then
we have the run we already have run here
I think I'd forgotten I need to do
cleanup afterwards then sad sad Aryan ok
we already have linked that so that
Middle Earth
that's Middle Earth Luke Smith did I
linked to his page and I forgot and it's
for the link ok and close that and so
this this is Alan's config ok so anyway
anyway so let's go - yeah let's finish
reading the comments and we are done
so a picture shows more than a thousand
words
Alan says hiding window manager easily
key mapping apps easy key mapping apps
put one full screen app on each tag
press super something or however you
have things set up and the jump between
apps in high speed
select window is a discrete event well
anyway anyway so what one of the problem
with my setup is the track you know I
was trying to explain that because
because I have auto click so when I want
to drag this window okay I cannot simply
just move it here there and start to
drag because because because it's going
to do a quick that's why you often see
me trying to drag and it failed and I
try it again you know that's why but
usually in my workflow I I set up the
window position in size I never change
it never change
you just didn't doesn't change except I
have one key to fullscreen it toggle you
know so for any any window one key to
toggle it so once I say that window I
don't I don't change the size and stuff
so let's see what all the swirly stuff
comments okay let's read okay I think
maybe too many comments how long have I
been
oh one hour already okay we almost done
two minutes
okay so actually Alan said Japanese
let's talk about Japanese tomorrow
probably let's talk about Japanese
tomorrow telling me so you are correct
Alan you got tired of installing okay so
Finch says he used to invent his own
programming languages yeah I have to
fight to keep my channel like enthusiasm
greetings greetings pot have you heard
of have you heard a browser called next
browser
oh you I think you asked before right I
haven't heard of it
next browser what is it
okay so which let's go here next rather
be productive on the Internet jump
headings okay would let's show
JavaScript because maybe it's not
working
download start on github Quick Start
manual so jumpy exactly okay these are
features be quicker switch tabs to no
tree history loose nothing no well go
mouse this no idiot people duct tape so
what what's a what's a deal I mean what
what engine is it using and it's I
suppose it's open source
this this is gonna go nowhere I can tell
you right now it's gonna go nowhere by
next year
you will you will hear nothing of it
that's my opinion
that's my well that's my impression okay
by next year you will hear nothing of it
now I'm actually I'm trying to find out
what what is I mean what engine is it
what what is its roots who wrote it
what engine what browser engine it uses
so any anyone comments on that so anyway
I don't think this is I mean if my
opinion is this is gonna go nowhere it's
it's a nerd thing you know perhaps many
nodes we just find I mean we'll find
this it is exciting and tell every
everyone else to use it but by next year
you'll be completely that dead buried
that's what I think
okay so that's it bye guys
oh great school okay
and the Hobbit is intended Oh Hobbit is
intended as children's book oh I didn't
know that translation so if there is a
translation made by Israel fighter
pilots well in Egypt while in Egyptian
captivity already
laughs logo homesteading and no sphere
the cathedral in basa that tower
programming languages nice reads no not
to me I read that the you know I'm a
nerd back in 1998 okay I read lots of
his things the cathedral and the bazaar
I read it twice and you know anyway
there was when I was younger right today
I don't you know I think he's crap he's
his opinion is this crap his books are
crap the cathedral in bazaar crap the
tower programming crap it's a the tower
program is the crap of crap it's a
worthless I don't even have to read
it ok I can tell you since by the way
sincerely that's what I believe the
tower programming so let's put it this
way more scientifically the Tao of
programming my evaluation of that book
is that in history of humanity that
study that book is it's it's it's it's
how can I describe it so that it's how
can I describe its worth in a precise
manner we thought with respect to human
you know evaluation books so basically
it's a crap ok gee it's not even worth
meeting it's well a lot of books are not
worth meeting at all and this that one
that our programming just just by the
name of it and also knowing yessir
and I think it's not just not worth
knowing I mean is this crap ok and
Cathedral and bazaar he's also crap
entire you know it's a it's a
coat it's a lie it's a fake fake fake
news fake garbage ok the philosophy
of garbage
the Cathedral in Gaza however that book
does have value that book has historical
value like in history many things
happens you know including philosophies
even some of them are bad ones but it
did has a it did have a great impact on
society even even if it's bad ones
for example Hitler okay or some of some
other bad guys okay so Cathedral in
Basel in my opinion it's a one of the
worthless book but it does have a he
stopped historical quarter and how do
you say a value historically because
that is a very popular book that that
book helped make that that book helped
the popular with the popularization of
open source movement okay that's my
opinion about that about yes our stuff
how long so ok so that's it let's see
okay I probably skipped some comments
I'm in a rush to say goodbye for no
reason actually we can talk forever
Weyland I don't know about wait wait and
that's you know Weyland is a Oh God the
I cannot help but start to flame UNIX
the entire of UNIX Weyland you know
why why does wait in the Weiland exists
because X 11 is the worst crap possible
and the the the the the UNIX people have
been wanted to replace x11 for 20 years
good morning Matt so actually I think
it's good time to shut down I mean you
know it's no good because my videos are
too long so I started to ramp Rambo
inside to go into so many other
directions so thank you guys for
watching
support me if you like my stuff okay go
to my website solid our info you can see
you can buy my Emacs tutorial my
JavaScript tutorial in depth ok my other
other things you know in patreon in
Amazon ok bye guys now wait where is the
end stream ok so end stream so shrink
shrink shrink shrink and stream the end
of matrix