good morning good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
show today September 24th 2019 Tuesday 9
o'clock a.m. 10 after 9 a.m. San
Francisco time and I just woke up 10
minutes ago
I'm trying to keep a schedule now so
every day is going to be 9 o'clock in
the morning for this week this week
everyday 9 o'clock in the morning is the
start time of talk show let's check if
I'm alive yes indeed and nobody is here
yet and I think I'll you know I'll be
back in in five minutes and I just wake
up and like I have
I'm not awake yet my eyes are not open
yet so I'm drinking five minutes okay if
I mean it's O
so guys pull something post questions so
either I come back in five minutes or we
start right now you know you you post
some questions and we can start right
now or I come back in five minutes and
we have no you know pick a topic so okay
pick a topic be right back in five
minutes okay so 9:15 okay 9 3 9:15 a.m.
San Francisco time okay guys so pick a
topic and we'll start then let me show
you this screen okay yeah so
okay guys I'm back no topic yet no
topics yet so I'm thinking we gonna talk
about
I'm gonna give you a introduction to how
compiler works so introduction to how
compiler works if you like that just
type it okay now type a topic okay
type of topic or we can talk about how
compiler works otherwise I'm just going
to start random how compiler works for B
for how compiler works for beginners oh
I'm just going to show you random good
morning sir key mean it's a great topic
how compari walks okay let's talk about
that okay let's just start on that topic
impromptu were you from Sochi I haven't
seen before so okay how compiler works
max the rater good morning max Reiter
max radar you are from Russia right okay
so how come very walks so let's go - how
come - Pilar walks let's to go to
language tutorials and let's move this
here and let's move this here and from
search search in vain search is also
from Russia um max Reiter is from Tacoma
Washington where is the comma
question 10 state right so how
comparator works and see if I have it
some somewhere here
okay let's see how comparable so this is
going to be a introduction to how
compiler works parsing and compiling
this is not technical I'm just going to
give you a overview how the whole thing
works along the way you'll learn about
about grammar
you know programming language grammar
and also some theoretical computer
science because when you start to talk
up about compilers there is a lot
periodical computer science very
interesting stuff you start to learn
about automata regular expression that
that is our engine of regular expression
it's part of passing and ok let me find
that let me find the article first
keyboard talk show
should be here no okay so let's find the
article first programming language
tutorial index hacker coat hacker coats
how compiler works there it is okay hold
on one second
you
okay Maxo radar says interpreters in
language like CT TCL is nothing more
than function functions there is no fast
AST okay so you you already knows about
it because I do not fully understand it
now ast stand for abstract syntax tree
conceptually you know I understand what
it is it's a tree you know it's a tree
of those structures but but have you
ever written a compiler or I have not so
I don't really understand how how easy
it is
anyway so then okay so let me just begin
the introduction how comparable so
compiler you know what is compiler
compiler is for example let's start a
Python let's say Python code
okay so Python so open a new shell let's
say print let's say Python 3 ok Python 3
and start a new shell new buffer 1 plus
3 that's Python code doing it and we got
for now so the compilers job is to they
have to look at the code ok I haven't
been coding Python for of wire so let's
say x equals to 3 plus 4 then print x
Genet the result is 7 so when a compiler
first of all you have to read in the
source code so this is the source code
you have to read it in you have to pass
it then after you pass it then you have
to turn that into a into the machine
language into the
into the machine language so that the
CPU can actually run it then then you
execute the machine code then they need
output seven stack languages like forth
okay
I can talk about that but the comparator
topic will probably just take over taken
an hour
so anyway so so compiler so there are
two steps to come you know first of all
compiler is is a program that takes a
source code so let's write it down so
maybe if we write it down then we have
more organized topics for the show
compilers okay compiler is in the source
code and output another code typically
typically assembly language upon another
code in another language okay it's so
easy basically translate one language to
the other but typically typically the
output is assembly language now assembly
language is almost is the lowest
language for the machine to read okay
we're gonna do we're gonna explain that
so okay so so comparator is reading
reading a source code and output another
language code typically that language
code is assembly language assembly
language is the language for them for
the machine to read what does that mean
exactly for the machine to read we
cannot talk about that so what does
assembly language mean what does it mean
to say for the machine to read okay for
the machine to read because human
languages include programming languages
high-level languages such as Python it's
read by human you know you understand
what this means x equals to 3 plus 4 and
you understand what print means is
typically it's based on English but what
does a machine what does machine
understand what does the machine read
okay you can you see you can think of a
machine as abacus okay this is the most
basic understanding of a machine abacus
have you guys seen a single abacus let's
just search for abacus ABAC us okay and
that's such folks are the abacus I have
a page written about abacus so let's
look at images what is this
why you know why why are these pages you
know those photos are me but I have not
I don't have this page on my website so
why are they showing or this abacuses
picture I don't know but if you go to my
ok so wait so such images here and we
don't want images here so abacus sorry
so this page so here is an abacus
you know abacus they are basically just
stones on a string you can manipulate
you can push the beads up or down okay
that's how tally how you tally how you
count you know it's it's almost like
it's like a counting machine so you push
a bead up then that means one to you so
typically how this work is that you know
you start here so this is this if you
push this red bead up then that means
one if you push push two beads up that
means two so you got one two three four
then four five you you push the top row
down so that's five so if you have this
push down and the bottom one pushed up
that means six so in this column you
have a total you know the maximum is
nice so if you want ten you push the bit
to the left of it up
so that's abacus so this is a machine so
abacus is one is one of the most easy to
understand machine now algorithm is all
about machines you see what algorithm
means now this is important this is the
definition of algorithm what algorithm
means is that algorithm is the recipe
it's a written typically written down
recipe that that tells that that is a
step by step instruction to some machine
okay there's a ways of machine involved
when you talk about algorithm implicitly
it means a machine ok this is important
what is what is algorithm okay
algorithm is a step by step instruction
that is a written step by step ins
instruction that instruct machine to do
something okay
now when you talk about algorithm
important this is a thing we usually
forgot when we talk about a algorithm it
always a or w8y s involves a machine
okay so for example just in your daily
life when we program Python JavaScript C
or whatever Java language there's always
a machine involved you see in this
machine this machine is typically you
know modern computer machine the CPU
whatever chip it is Apple you know our
Intel chips on different chips they are
actually different machines so compiler
reading the language source code and
check out these typically assembly
language for that particular CPU so you
can also for example you can read a
compiler so that compiler reads a Python
code and output instructions for these
abacus you know like assembly language
for the abacus so depending on what
machine the assembly the language will
be different so what is assembly
language assembly language is a is
basically instructions to control the
machine for example we have a abacus
here and what are the instructions the
instructions are for example move
to the move to the column one
push push the beads up or down
that's instruction or move to the left
column of the current column pushed
beads up or down
that's instruction so you can you know
imagine we have these abacus then we
have what's called instruction set
instruction set a set of instructions
the instructions includes you know
moving moving let's say moving a robotic
arm you know to a column and push feeds
that that's the instructions and that
makes up the assembly language so
assembly language is kind of the it's
kind of the low-level language that
controls the machine okay as assembly
language is a low-level language that
that that executes instructions of the
machine
abacus is a example of a machine now
there are many other machines for
example CPU is a machine and you know
modern computers such as CPU CPU or your
calculators or what are the chips in
your microwave
those are all machines and those
machines are very very very complex it's
hard to understand but but in principle
they are just like abacus you have a
instruction set every machine has a
instruction set okay so so back to the
compiler compiler is a program that
takes a source code in a particular
language and output to a machine
language okay and now the now usually
there is a some distinctions about
compilers and interpreter you know
computer science scientists call them
interpreter so what's the difference
compiler so remember compiler takes an
input source code output to an another
language so from from higher basically
usually from higher level language to
another language now in JavaScript for
example we have many so called trans
trans transpilers but they are just
compilers okay transpired they are
basically just compilers in principle
bye-bye-bye principle for example
javascript many for example a typescript
typescript taking a source code of
typescript source code and output
javascript code you know that that's
typescript compiler then your browser
takes the JavaScript code compile it and
output the machine code
you know the browser that's that's
that's the browser's job you have a
JavaScript compiler in
so so compiler takes a language source
code and output another language
language code typically low level and
and another thing is about there's a
word interpreter so with the difference
typically between compilers and
interpreters is that compilers reads the
entire source code and output another
language code now interpreter typically
based typically they just take one line
or a few lines of code for example when
I run this Python you know Python
interpreter takes this source code and
output a machine code and run it like
right away run it typically compiler do
not run it that's not compilers job but
when you talk about interpreter that's
part of the part of the process so
that's a minor difference of between
compilers and interpreters for example
but you know the differences are
basically become less invested a for
example in : so here is a Python code
let's copy it so python code let's go
back here and let's make another goal
and code so goal and so let's go to
golan and let's print let's say variable
x 3 plus 4 okay and print
x okay garnett 7 you see so in :
this is : compiler but actually also
function as a interpreter so you know
instead of output a another source code
it actually and it happened under
another language code but it runs it
directly so the colon compiler is both a
interpreter or in compiler so that's a
kind of the semantic differences between
compiler and interpreter
okay so so let's summarize hey am i
doing good
I think I'm let's see okay 27 minutes we
are kind of too slow let's see the
comment good morning Kathy there does
not have to be a machine to have an
algorithm you cried you know there needs
to be a machine so this is this is where
importance of culture comes in
now remember compiler always involves
the machine always well yeah I mean you
you know you might say there does not
need to be machine for example you cried
algorithm LCD LCD is this common
denominator algorithm qualifies as
software algorithm yes but compiler Oh
algorithm always involves a machine
because so so what what is algorithm for
for example 1 plus 3 what is a machine
where is a machine when you do one plus
three or suppose you you want to sort a
bunch of numbers so 0 1 2 5 okay you
have 5 numbers 1 2 3 4 5 and they are
randomized you want to sort them where
is the machine the machine is a virtual
math machine the machine is math you
know that is the machine because without
machine you don't have algorithms
because remember if you look up a
definition of algorithm algorithm the
definition is basically going to be step
by step instruction to do something to
do something you cannot do something if
you have you if you do not have
something to do with you know if you are
cooking you have a recipe you need you
know ingredients you need to cook where
you need the stove you need a fire
that's machine so so this is kind of
this is kind of in importance yeah so so
when you talk about math
you know math scenes things for example
psy sign three sine cosine you know
trigonometry or any function x squared
okay x squared x squared if X is 2 then
the result is 4 where is the Machine
okay
in math you don't think of a machine
because it's just a function but when
you actually want to tell the computer
or someone to actually do it how do you
get two to four you start to need a
machine you need a machine it's not you
know you need a machine and this in this
case the machine is kind of a virtual
math thing
so anyway compilers interpreters
algorithms and the recipe now let's talk
about recipe let's talk about languages
languages for a moment so remember
compilers reading a language and output
another language now what are languages
languages is a writing system that of
instructions basically instructions you
know just like human languages in
English French Chinese Japanese you have
different languages same thing for
programming languages so so Python Ruby
pearl Java you know they are they are
basically instructions okay they are you
know they have precise meaning and
instructions the low-level instructions
machine is kind of like abacus you know
we talked about instructions where like
move move you know move this card on
these speeds up by one or you know move
over here and move another bits up or
down those are instructions so and also
another thing about CPU is that you know
you you might have heard of instruction
set in a CPU like Intel i5 you know chip
or something each CPU today they have a
instruction set
instruction set is a collection of
basically instructions or commands that
tells the CPU what to do so so put the
whole thing together when you run a
Python code on my Mac on this particular
model of Mac you know it has a CPU
inside Intel fiber whatever it has an
instruction set so the compiler reads
the Python code output you know up put a
machine language this machine language
is feed to the CPU this machine language
you know is represent is basically
instruction sets you know tell the CP
what to do then as if he runs it so
that's about compilers that that's the
overview of a compiler so okay so I
think I'm getting too slow back down so
so let's let's read about it's so
comparison interpreter interpreter is
just like a compiler except that they
also run a code okay so you have
assembly language assembly language is a
low-level language that still makes
sense to human okay so here is an
example of assembly language now
assembly language typically have three
items like each line is just three items
for example this move a 661 H means load
al with 97 decimal ok so that's an
example of a assembly language so source
code of assembly language is just like
that you know basic basically three one
instruction for lie now what are those
instructions basically they are like you
know put this number in this face or
read read a number from that place
things like that that's assembly
language and what is a machine language
machine language is lower level than
assembly machine language is a set of
instructions
X
it directly by CPU what it looks like a
machine language just looks like a bunch
of zero and once it is all just 0 1 0 1
0 0 1 1 once you know like that
ok so let's keep that so compiler ok
let's talk about the structure of
compiler so I thought about our learning
assembly but I don't know what can I do
with it it can do anything for me any
software does you see any software you
run through a compiler that that becomes
machine code you know so it it basically
just lower-level it does anything
software does every software basically
every software had you know eventually
our modern computers they become machine
code whenever you runs you know any
language assembly or whatever they
become by compilers they eventually
become machine code you know a bunch a
bunch of 0 and once y 0 1 y Y a bunch of
0 ones because that's that's what that's
what the CPU reads you know because CPU
we are using electronic computers you
also have non electronic computers like
such as like quantum computers and DNA
computers you know biological computers
they don't use the electronics you know
they are not electricity but for our
computers they are electronics and
typically they are they are just they
are 0 and ones because electricity is
either only or off that's how it works
so that that is why machine language
machine code is just 0 a bunch of 0 and
ones so but remember machine code a same
assembly language or higher level
language like Python Java they are kind
of the same I mean they are just the
same they are just in different
languages like Chinese English you know
version Python Ruby Java JavaScript C
they are high level
which language languages we understand
but the machine language
assembly and machine code machine
languages so they are you know they are
they are they are kind of the same the
only difference is that machine language
is unreadable to us to humans because
they are too low-level and we have
showed an example of assembly you know
it's just things like that like like
read this number from this registry and
read that number from that registry and
add them together so that's assembly
language so you can see actually see
some examples of other assembly
languages so here is Wikipedia you can
see some examples of assembly language
see so here is a example of what is is
assembly language
yeah here's some example assembly
language it's look at this what is is
each line is basically one single
instruction the things on the right side
are comments these are the comments
anyway I don't know I don't know same B
language so actually we are going to
slow to so because there are a lot of
things so okay so we know what is a
compiler we know what's an interpreter
we know what's the assembly language we
know what's a machine code so far all
the other things that's important
because that's you know we talk about
algorithms what it means exactly you
know and we so let me repeat algorri
algorithm is a step by step instruction
written down written down in some
language that's what algorithm is so
algorithm so you can have you know so
algorithm always implies the machine and
in turn it always implies with a
particular language one or more
languages because because algorithm is a
step by step instruction and it's not
verbal it has to be written down
typically we assume it's written down so
you know we have a recipe you know and
when it's written down it must be in
some language so it cut out you know be
your language and and the language is
basically instruction set so that means
it has to work with the machine it has a
machine somewhere so that's what
algorithm now now let's talk about
comparators now when you compile like
today's goal and JavaScript stuff they
have they have two steps in basically
they have analysis and synthesis
analysis analysis step is basically you
read the source code you understand what
the source code means exactly and you
generate a tree let's see if I have that
: so anyway so here is the source code
for example this is a Mac B's you know
eMac these compilers they have to read
this source code and generate then you
read this source code then you output
typically you are putting what's called
ast that sent for abstract syntax tree
not just that more like more information
in that but but basically we you you
read a source code you output in a
format in a more logical format okay
then the second step of compiler is is
synthesis or general code generation so
the second step reads the output of the
of the you know of the ast then it tries
to convert it into the target language
maybe it's assembly language maybe it's
a machine language or maybe it's another
language for example many many compilers
today they compile for example : 2
JavaScript or Java Script to see you
know Lisp to see you know like there you
are converting languages so two steps
one step is basically just reading the
source code read it understand it I put
some output in a format that's easier to
understand then the second step is to
read that format and output to whatever
target language machine language or
whatever so so here is the two steps in
more detail so the first part here so so
strange you start with a source code
stream then this part the first part of
compilers job is called passing so you
so you pass it passing has three steps
lexical analysis tokens syntactic
analysis okay anyway that's passing then
you generate a pass tree yeah
you are put a pass tree then the the
second step generating code that's that
task is called is typically called
compiling so you take the pass tree and
you are put to your target language okay
so hold on a second
you
it's - its kind of - so and and I just
woke up and woke up and we got night
people watching so actually we get we
beginning we we are - so so let's I want
to jump to some interesting parts that
if that is the grammar formal grammar
and formal grammar bacchus no form and
and context-free grammar because these
are high level stuff I'm a much
interested in those things and this also
you know interesting stuff so let's talk
about that so okay okay so so let me let
me try to cover them so so compilers
remember there are two two stages of
compiling the first part is usually
called parsing that is you read the
source code you output to a format that
you understand it you read the source
code you you know really in a source
code is not easy for example here's a
eMac this code so you know how do you
begin to read it you know that's that's
the job of compact the deposits though
you let's for example let's say this
line so this line said something then
something something you know you you
actually you you have to write a program
that reads each character you read this
character the neck next character next
character and so on you this is every
every compiler every parcel does this
you have to read character by character
then you have to so how do you do it I
mean like we if we are doing this from
scratch how do you do it you have to you
know you
that's a passage op you read each
character by character then you use
grammar to understand it we will talk
about that then you find out the output
a format with so compiler has two stages
parsing and code generation okay
parsing is when
when you read the source code and
outputting a format you understand then
then the cogeneration takes that format
and output to another language okay so
the interesting thing is how do you pass
like like how do you pass so let's so
let's see what we have here
Mexico analysis mexicana analysis
non-deterministic finite automata and
deterministic finite automata okay stuff
stuff syntax and doing okay so there is
a lot to it so okay so let's talk about
passing passing you know so I'm just
going give I'm just giving you a
overview how this works in theory kind
of a theoretical overview I don't know
the stuff in detail so that's one of the
things I'm trying to learn let's see
what we have here comments
miksa Reiter says the concept of
assembly syntax is easy it's all the
machine level details that are difficult
search e search he says there are nice
games by Zack tronics tis 100 Suns
engine io x XR punks if you want to get
the feel of assembly programming or some
way
good morning Bartholomew who is shaving
their head in a background oh it's a you
know they are loaning among people are
lonely anymore Pass is breaking up the
stream of syntax into keywords by by by
use of case statement yes parsing you
know before so for example this is a map
this language you have to pass it so
pass it actually essentially passing
essentially means understanding the code
but where do we begin like we don't I
mean how do you start to so this is a
hard task so let's go back to the for
example : okay
so showing browser so we have Python
code here we have : code here you so
like suppose you you have this task to
do you need to write a program to pass
it where do you begin
you basically you have to read each
character but then then what so you know
so this is actually so this is a
tremendously difficult task this is
actually a very difficult task and so to
do passing actually so so this involves
first of all so this passing involves
under the understanding or language you
know because each language is different
so that means a language that comes the
concept of grammar each language needs
to have a grammar
competitive phrase okay so let's see
pausing phrase okay so passing phrase
they have passing passing can be breakin
broken down into three steps lexical
analysis syntactic analysis semantic
analysis
okay I'm so lexical analysis is the
first step of parsing it takes a input
string and lexical grammar and then
breaks the input string into a sequence
of seeing tactical units each is called
a lexeme or token okay so
yes max max the raters said it max
Laredo is great so max Raider is telling
us passing is breaking up passing is
breaking up the stream by syntax in to
key words by use of a case statement and
passing has to go character by character
to break up the syntax into tokens it
uses PMF as a rule set to do this
exactly I'm kind of stuck I don't know
where am I going with this
actually I should know this I should
know this better so so that would be
more fluid but the problem is not big
that's not problem because because I
mean sometimes even something I know I
got stuck I like I got stuck because I
don't know I I lost track of what's
interesting things I want to say about
it passing so anyway so this is so
passing you have to you know when you
pass a language you have you have so
many different languages and you know
the difference between Python goal and
Ruby that's all the differences in
languages so first of all you need to
have a grammar for a language because
for example in Python you know you can
easily have syntax 0 for example you
cannot say for example if you to put you
if you put the two things in the same
line that will not work that will not
work but how do you know it will not
work as a human you know well you need a
line here but you have to tell the
machine that's what that's the thing
because compiler compiles don't ask you
oh you know you you have to so that's
part of the parsing part of the
compiling you know passing a code then
you generate a new code so that's part
of the
you know the algorithm jobs so so the
the pasa have to know about all the
rules so here comes the concept of
grammar so for every language you need
to have a grammar grammar means means
basically a rules that machine can
understand that specifies you know which
syntax is correct which syntax is not
correct
okay so so parsing is actually fairly
very complicated in fact that's a
foundation that's kind of the foundation
of computer science and it is also the
most critical part practical computer
science you know especially in in your
early days like today we don't think
about compilers or passing at all like
if you are a web dev you know you you
almost never in your life in today's
programming you have to work with
compilers you have to like you don't
even have to understand what exactly
compilers do you can be a software
engineer you know for for 10 years 20
years without understanding even basics
of compilers because you don't need to
because it's already written you have
you know you have Python comparators you
have Ruby compilers you have every
compilers but you know you have to begin
somewhere but somebody has to write a
compiler you know something you know
it's you know and compiling tools so
today if you want to create a new
language then you need to write a
compiler so compiler like we mentioned
before there are many it's very complex
you have to read the source code you
have to understand grammar you know
grandma is very complex
actually there is a entire you can learn
you know you can spend a few years about
parsing itself about grammar and and
grandma is a topic that's very
theoretical computer science I mean you
can study grammar in your entire life it
because it connects to the
radical computer science and computer be
dirty and things like that
and yeah so the whole topic is very
interesting for example we talked about
machine language so Turing machine for
example that's a machine language and
lambda calculus lambda calculus for
example that is a programming language
and they much they have to do with
theoretical computing but they are much
they are also related to what we are
talking about here like lots of it so so
we we so whatever what what I was
talking so so parsing what was I'm
talking so parsing so let's let's talk
about parsing okay so come on in Boyer
okay so we so you have to submit you so
you have to so every language
programming language so yeah we were
talking about relations to theoretical
computer science about Turing machine to
machine as a specific machine and lambda
calculus can be considered as a specific
programming language that is written
down form of instructions and so let's
let's talk about grandma okay so in
order to in order to pass yeah so yeah
so we were talking about the how they
how compilers relate to three original
computer science and how today most
programmers you don't have to know
anything about compilers at all to work
in software you know 14 or 20 years but
some people have to do that yeah so back
to if you are creating your own language
like today there are so many new
languages there's a name there's a name
there's a crystal crystal that you know
that basically that's like you know
there are so many new languages has
called a
and others so in order to have a
programming language you know if you are
going to create your own programming
language or Lisp you have to have a
grammar grammar so what is a grammar
okay yeah so so you have to have a
grammar
because without how do you how do you
begin to pass you know this you know you
cannot verbally explain to the computer
you know what what is your code so you
have to have a grammar grammar is a
specification of the languages syntax
now you how is that done that's so
complex for example how can you possibly
tell you know imagine imagine we have we
have a Python code right here right we
have a Python code look it looks us it
it to us it looks very simple you know
the x equals to 3 plus 4
you know how it's so simple you know you
cannot be simpler then you say print
parentheses something but the thing is
you have to you have to you have to
explain this to a machine so that is a
grammar so how do you understand how how
how is grandma so let me explain how
grammar is and and how it works yeah did
yeah so okay so let's explain how
grandma is every every state every
programming language needs a grammar and
so grandma we have so let's talk about
this Backus no form okay focus
Backus no form so for more grandma for
more grandma is almost always written in
a notation called Backus no form or
variant of shortened us B and F okay
Backus no form is a notation used to
specify the grammar of a computer
languages okay for example let's say we
have a language for audition for example
3 plus 4 or 6 plus 2 are both valid
source code yeah so let's begin simple
now let's forget about x equals through
something let's forget
prints something let's just focus let's
say you are creating a new language and
let's say the entirety of the whole
language the syntax is every line must
be this form okay
a plus B okay every line is in that form
so and what is a and B a and B must be
characters like 1 2 9 0 to 9 okay
that's suppose that is your language now
if you add a space here then it's
incorrect
you know it's invalid invalid syntax for
example so suppose this is your language
you know very easy to understand so then
you so for that language then you
specify the the grammar for that
language looks like this okay it looks
like this so you have s arrow sign
number number that's one line by itself
then each number can be one of zero to
nine okay so this this this is actually
the full specification for for your
language you know so what
okay so actually we need to go to detail
about this
actually I am now I am not good you know
this I'm not good I'm not good is kiski
doing this topic yeah yeah I need much I
need to be much more familiar to do this
better
yeah yeah yeah I think okay I kind of
failed here I think that's we already
talked about for one hour I wanted to go
to so many interesting things here but
it's I'm not ready to do it I don't I
don't think so because then because yeah
I'm not I don't know this subject too
well and this is my first time trying to
explain it and you know you you know you
should be able to be able to at some
point you know like for example I can't
explain JavaScript well you know eMac
this because I know it's so well but not
so much with this because this this
topic you know there are so many
interesting things I want to talk about
but right now pick because I haven't
done this and also because I don't know
this too well be so that I cannot I
cannot just like have so many things in
my mind I want to tell you like every
time I act a few sentences I have to
read it then so it's not good so I think
that's you know what we I'm not doing
doing good today for this subject
okay so that's I think that's a good
point
and I'm trying to I I tried to yeah I'm
trying i I made it I'm trying to like
it's it's almost like I'm trying to
explain to ten years old kids so I
should go faster much faster there'll be
much better so okay let me try that okay
so so anyway so so this is this is one
example of bacchus no form okay at least
you know that okay this is an actual
example like if you actually look at
programming language grammar for example
if you go to yeah let this go some
practical things let me just talk about
what I know
okay Python Python documentation you
know for example we here we see a
practical example of grammar
specification okay so if you go to
Python and actually this is practical
because because when you you know a lot
of you are Python programmers and you
have to read documentation every day and
often you will see these okay stupid
Python you need Java wait let's just go
to the dog come on
go to the doc what's going on with this
quick
stupid Python okay here's the Python
documentation okay you if you are a
Python programmer you are probably
you've seen this a thousand times so now
you go to language reference weight
language reference okay that's what
Python calls it but if you go to
language reference then you we are now
okay so this is why this is important
okay we were talking about compilers in
Bacchus no foam so aside from even if
you do not write compilers in your whole
life all this information are very
useful because once you understand you
know the the outline of how compare
compiler works what what does it
involves you know the Bacchus know from
the parsing the code generation the you
know the grammar specification then in
real life you understand many of the
terms used in for example Python
documentation for example you see
lexical analysis now lexical analysis
just means like passing like you read
you read the source code you are trying
to understand what they mean by by the
grammar you see so in Python doc you
know so use you see lexical analysis you
see hold on a second so they you know
you say spied on program is read by a
passer input to the parcel is a stream
of tokens token just means what is a
token okay token means for example let's
say let's go back to Python let's go to
token token is basically just means a
word okay
for example let's for example this X is
a token X is a token equal sign is a
token three and four they are tokens
plus I is a token the print the forward
print is a token the left parenthesis is
a token X is token again and right
parenthesis is token now that's that's
Python now in :
package is a
the whole world mean is a token the the
turbo quote for string is a token
okay that's a token so curly bracket is
a token so you see that's what polka
means so token means is a token is kind
of the the smallest unit of a thing in a
programming language source code so
that's what toca means so the first
stage of passing you know you read the
source code character by character and
then you you want to break them into a
sequence of tokens so so for example if
if I'm trying to write a parser for :
then the first step I will have package
you know I'll have a sequence of tokens
that will be packaged main import then
this whole thing will be a string or
token or sometimes you know three tokens
like legs like the double quote then fmt
I think the whole thing is our token
anyway then function main then
parentheses that's a token you know
that's the first step of passing you
break down the source code you know a
sequence of characters into top sequence
of tokens and this is this is called
tokenization you know this is part of
the compiler process token so anyway so
you you back go back to you know read
the Python documentation so you have
line structure logical lines physical
eyes comments increasing declarations
and stuff okay so that's a practical
thing about pausing and okay it looks
like I'm lost again so token
tokenization then then okay let's let's
see gramma
okay so let me go to like this go back
to Python documentation and wise
whitespace between
other tokens identifiers and keywords
let's see so there it is okay here is an
example of grammar this is you know this
is the Bacchus no forum we are talking
about so a grandma you know you have
actually we need to explain what Packers
no-foam is exactly we haven't done that
yet it's you know it's extremely
interesting well anyway I think we're
gonna stop on this because I am NOT
doing good here it's extremely
interesting because because there's so
much I want to talk about that because
because I want to talk about I want to
talk about the arrangin of regular
expression I want to talk about the
hierarchy of grandmas you know and what
it means for what what does it mean to
be a context-free language anyway so I
and you know it's to these sometimes
again in the future when when do I know
better
okay so dingo Thank You dingo and thank
you max the Reiter PMF is a pattern
matching so it often uses case statement
to match rules exactly so so BNF so max
Reiter you know you have experience you
you know you have you ever ever written
a parser or compiler looks like you know
you know the stuff so max Laredo says
PMF is a is like pattern matching so it
often uses case statements to match
rules is exactly you know if you know
PPA you know the parsing is extremely
interesting I mean wait hold on hold on
about passing so parsing let me talk
about this parsing is reading a source
code and output you know reading a
source code and outputting a format you
understand once you analyze the source
code you know like tokens
tokens after you got the tokens sequence
of tokens then you try then you follow
the grammar then you generate a tree
okay basic basically that's passing but
but before you talk about passing these
things about grammar
now that's that's about theoretical
computer science this is about formal
language because because you see here we
see an example of a grandma so what does
it mean what does it mean so a grandma
is basically okay it's basically many
lines and each line is a basically a you
can think of it think of it as a fine
replaced rule so think of these as you
know replace whenever you see the the
word number you can replace it to zero
okay that's example oh this is one rule
okay
so a grammar is a set of rules okay each
row is kind of like find replacement
like like strain find replacement you
find a word and you can be it this rule
says every time you see number what you
can be placed by zero and so on for you
know
so that's grammar for example in Python
here we see the same thing so it says
every time you see the word string
literal you can replace it by you know
by by okay here they the grammar becomes
more complex but basically it means you
can replace it by either a short string
or a long stream and possibly with
string prefix okay that's one rule so
what does short string means you know we
can find it so short string you see here
this line so short string every time you
see short string you can replace it by
by either a single quote then far
by short string item one or zero or more
of it then followed by another single
quote okay
let's magnify okay so so here here's a
rule so that's one of the rule oh you
know all these so so that's an example
of Grandma so each line is a rule and
each line is a rule it's basically a
replacement rule on the left hand side
whenever you see something like that you
can replace you know it's your choice
you can every you can choose which rule
to apply so you begin with a informal
grandma you begin with okay okay
informal grammar in the back of snow for
me informal grandma so again let me
summarize a grammar is a bunch of yours
each rule tip are typically just one
line
so yeah and and each row is basically
find and replacement now there is one
rule that's special you call it the
starting rule so you have the starting
rule this is a this role must be applied
first always the first first rule so
this is how you generate a language so
grandma you know grandma is the grammar
of a language it also generates a
language so so basically this grammar
means you begin with something with s
whenever you see s you can replace it by
a number plus number okay so but this is
a beginning so so to China so given a
grammar you can generate languages like
like all possible source code of the
language so so in this Grandma you start
with s you know just just a character s
then you replace it by number and number
then every time you see number you can
replace it by a digit so that's that's
our language there so in a similar way
the Python grandma there so what what
what is pythons first rule you know
there's a first rule let's see
string literal anyway so that's that's
that's about part of it that's about
grandma so so dingo says think of the
basic esteem so pretty crazy how fast
you can pick up the basics of cassava
kiss despise the ketosis being pure the
ergonomic let's submit it to the madness
so you are using it now bow your says
weeaboo I think that's it for today so
I'm yeah so that is it what this is this
is a botched topic maybe we can talk
about it next next time abacus oh yeah
these are interesting abacus is you know
I like to think of when I think about
theoretical computer science
I don't like Turing machines it's CVI I
like to think think in terms of abacus
like whenever you encounter some strange
ideas in programming languages you know
or something or compiling or something I
like to think I'd like to you know I
like to understand by to be able if I am
able to break the whole things down you
know all the way down to to abacus like
imagine if I have an abacus how does the
whole thing works you know it's
explaining the whole thing in terms of
the abacus in terms you know like down
to the lowest level of moving bits on
the abacus then I understand the concept
so so for example you can understand you
can stop for example you can understand
Korean recursion you know try you know
you might try curry recursion or sorting
you know what does a sort me or
ASCII code you know what is a C code or
Unicode code point you know yeah you
know try to explain all of them down to
abacus because because this is logical
you know this is a logical bit because
like when we talk about like many things
today are so abstract like when you work
with Python you never think of a machine
you know when you program Python you
never think of CPU or anything but but
actually that's what actually what's
going on so if you can you know so if
you try to think of abacus try to think
of everything in terms of abacus then
you understand it well like so so I
think that's it for today so let me just
read the comments and how can I agree
map how can I be map control aid to be
home across all programs like a Mac same
with control F control Yi you can do
that but that's that's that's you'd okay
pasyati ad bus Basquiat says how can i
remap control a to be home you mean a
home key or the home command
you I don't think that's what you want
to do I mean you know that's
okay there are several questions there
are several questions I'm kind of still
either been watching fourth okay they
let me tell you about fourth okay wait
wait actually let me finish let me talk
finish about the question the sirens are
running the mean the mean image so
passed yet passed here says how can you
map control a to be home of course all
programs
like in Mac same with control F control
II so I you say are you saying there's a
siren running is some car security
alarms it's very annoying very annoying
in modern society
so basically bust yet I think you are
what you want is is that you want Emacs
keybinding or cross every program on the
Mac that's I think that's what you want
you already have that by the way in on a
Mac for example something ok ok some
thing in the water
ok now let me press ctrl-a you see it
moves the Cuusoo all the way to the
beginning I press ctrl F you see it
moves character forward control B moves
it backward so on the Mac by default in
many text applications you you already
have that feature for example let's go
to the URL field
let's press ctrl-a there you go control
f you see control B so you already have
that on the Mac I don't I don't
recommend using those keys by the way
those keys whack your fingers that they
give you you know you're gonna see a
doctor if you do that often
so Boyer says there's
there's no need for you to learn stuff
like his if you are already a master of
evil mod yeah but if you really really
really want to be more efficient then
then you might check Sophocles so max
Reiter okay so you read books about
compiler okay so the rule in baf our
recursive for example number number is
itself a rule that contains number rule
yeah so he's a dragon book a good start
to learn compilers yeah I read you know
so in my articles how compare us work
okay so I have lots of notes but those
all these notes or these notes are just
for myself they are not polished in any
way I mean this a whole are doing it you
know when you when you study passes like
I said you know I'm more interested in
theoretical computing theory Racal
computer science especially formal
languages so when you start to talk
about grandma's BNF there's a lot huge
amount of theoretical computer science
going on and passes for example passes
passes formal grammar
okay formal grammar you have
classification of languages according to
their complexity of the grammar and you
have lots of you know technical jargons
for Grandma you have linear grammar
regular grammar context-free grammar
yeah that's those are the things I like
to talk about you know then you have
analytic grammar you have lexical
grammar you have because if grandma you
have ambiguous grammar you know
ambiguous grammar is very interesting
because when you study this then there's
a lot of interesting theoretical
computer science it's because it's like
in a word in a sense it's a puzzle you
try to solve this puzzle
yes or no like like you you have you
have to answer yes or no you know only
one answer is correct things like that
and here is another example of a grammar
and this yeah so you know this grammar
and
passing is very very interesting so then
you have parsing expression grammar now
the parsing expression grammar is pretty
new it's only amended in the past Oh
early 70s I think it's as I was thinking
it's 90s
parsing expression grammar so formal
grammar and passes or passes is you know
passes are techniques to takes
techniques to passing programming
language like we talked about before you
know when you have a source code when
you have a programming language you have
a grammar
okay then you need to write a compiler
for it meaning that you have to pass the
source code so in order to do that that
means you have to write a program you
know but then then there's a lot of
problems how do you do it you know
that's an algorithm that's called those
those programs are called parser so
there are so many techniques about
passing you know so these are algorithms
for parsing and there are many different
types of passes parsing techniques so
this there's an entire book written
about passing about all these techniques
of parsing which one is better which one
you know there are characteristics you
know so let me show you some of the
actually books about interesting books
so dragon books dragon book is book is
the most famous yeah I recommended I
would actually you know so the latest
version is this one but I like this
cover much better this is the classic in
1990s I read like three three quarters
of it so here's a table of contents
contents of that book yeah so you so you
can read this book you know you can
actually buy early version that
bye-bye this version okay it's from 1986
how much
okay buy used $14 okay yeah now these
days the books become so expensive the
latest edition is $130 but you can buy a
used one for $14 and there are other
books you know today there are other
compiler books so you can read that book
this book does this book is small
practical oriented so if you really
actually want to write a compiler you
can read this book but but today there
are a lot of tutorials out there you
know you can actually if you really want
to write a compiler you can actually you
don't necessarily need to read a book
they are a lot of information
you know tutorials and so on and passing
so they this now this book is the most
this is the classic most famous and most
popular book on passing now this this
book is basically like the Bible or
passing so it talks about everything
that is known to humanity about passing
okay so this book is written by this guy
dick one actually I emailed him a couple
of times you know he and okay so and
there's a version online free there's a
early edition free in PDF so you can
download and read it so I recommend that
you go to like do I have the PDF here I
think I do have the PDF here so yeah
book website so you go here
that's his website so yeah so you just
remember the name dick one okay that's
his name passing you know such for
passing you will find his name so this
book I highly recommended it's it's long
though
I mean this is the whole book the entire
book is about passing so it's very very
very technical and kind of boring so but
but if but if that's the topic you want
to know this is the book almost yet this
is the book
okay so yeah good morning Pablo so I
think that's it for today so okay next
time yeah should be I don't know when
you know this is a topic I want to
finish I need to I want to be able to
write a compiler I want to write my own
language you know create them my own
language you know even at all you want
sometimes you know in the future in the
near future so this is one thing that
you know that is my to do it's a and I
haven't done it for like two years so I
need to get on this so so maybe next
time you know why I'm doing you know
when you know when I know this stuff
then we talk about that next time so
thank you guys for coming that's it for
today so I'm going to start to do a
video every day now o'clock in the
morning so now your clock just like just
like today every every day for this week
so that is my schedule that is a lot of
people want to ask me a schedule so that
is my schedule now your clock California
time every day for this week okay any
more comments questions posted and I
think I'll answer the whole question so
that's it for today thank you guys for
coming
good morning weeaboo okay thanks bye