good morning everyone
good morning
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
video check audio check and today we are
going to do powershell
the microsoft monad the microsoft
open source
scripting language
powershot
why i love powershell powershell is a
magnitude better than bash hello cpa
um and so today
i'm going to code i'm going to demo a
powershell script maybe explain
something
um
about it okay so this script
will
change
let me show you okay so let's see let's
go to keyboard
uh
let's go to my keyboard blog so you can
see all the keyboard i'm using kinesis
advantage 2 right here this one
that's that one and ultimate hacking
keyboard that's this one you go buy it
okay just go to xlii keyboard
guide you'll find my blog okay so let's
go let me show you okay so let's go to
keyboard let's go to one of the um
images so let me show you what i'm gonna
do with powershell so you see all these
files lots of files
there are 600 files over here so open
them in
uh in microsoft
explorer folder viewer
so on the ping window you can see all
the commands of course i make for
example i just called start show in
desktop that's how this you know in
emacs direct
press key
and it goes to desktop so this here you
are seeing all the image files
okay so tons of image files let's open
it you know
fantastic keyboards apple keyboards
classic
uh ancient you know this is one thousand
keys stock trader broker keyboard
uh this is you know th this is the um
you know this is the keyboard maker
what's your name
das keyboard yeah that's they are trying
to get into gamers pens
uh this is in taiwan the key keyboard so
you know basically lots of images so
happy hacking so let's
so what i want to do so when over the
you know 30 years
when you have downloaded tons of phone
images you know
10 000 1 million of pawn image files
there are many duplicates
okay so you want to remove the duplicate
hello
cortes powershell number one
so you know you have 10 000 million
images
now they are duplicate for example these
two for example let me show you okay so
this is a smaller size uh
yeah they
they are not arranged by date or
something but anyway so you can see many
duplicate in this case they are smaller
size but sometimes they are exact
same image
so you have a million image files you
want to remove the duplicate image files
that's when this powershell script
comes alive
powershell script so the idea is that
this script will
change the file name to a hash
to a hash basically a number okay to a
hash so if they
if two files are identical they will
have the same hash key
so that can indicate they are duplicate
you know exact same file so
when that happens you can delete it so
you can remove duplicate
okay so
i didn't prepare for this talk show but
in you know like
20 years ago i wrote a perl script that
does that exactly so let me show you
guys can i show you um
i need to go to my uh get sweep repo
let's see
script okay so let's see
uh
perl you know some some of these
files you are looking at they are 30
years old you know like okay
occasionally i run into my unix learning
notes
taken around 1998
so anyway where am i okay so duplicate
there it is delete duplicate files okay
so
so there it is you see the file per
duplicate file so
this code still runs we can try it okay
so this is a perl code
written in
2005 written in 2003
and what this
script does so there are
200 lines 200 lines plus you know i
separated into libraries back then i was
a pearl expert so plus 200 lines there
and plus 100 lines so
400 lines okay 500 lines per code this
code will find
you know given a medium files you will
find duplicate
and and
and uh you can give it a parameter and
it will remove them it will show you
which one are duplicate then you can
give a parameter to remove them we
should demonstrate this okay
and then the powershell is alternative
solution you know so how do you how how
do you do this you know what's the
algorithm what you do is that you for
each file first of all you get their
their file size okay file size
then you order them so you have one
million let's say just 1000 1000 files
ordered by file size
now if the file size are different
obviously the files are different
but when the file size are the same
then you have to compare whether the two
files are the same sometimes two files
there are different image files but they
have the exact same number of bytes file
size so when you have two files let's
have the same size then you
you want to check if they the two files
are exactly the same how do you do that
well in unix
uh you know the classic unix or linux
you know you linux youngsters so you
have the compare
command okay i'm on windows so i don't
have that command i don't think so so
let's go to powershell let's see
um
let's let's let's make this so this is
you see my way of work so that i just
move my mouse to the top and
i'll get to my powershell
terminal
bottom is
emax
on the right side is
firefox and here on the top right corner
is discord
and on the left you know so you operate
you don't i don't have to click i don't
have to do old
old tab you know the idiotic old type
uh
so again
turn off that
citrix celtic orthodox hello benjamin
hello
so powershell okay so powershell and
delete duplicate image files of one
million images so on unix linux you can
use the classic command cmp so i don't
think i have cmp
uh cmp yeah it's not only oh
what
where is that from
cmp you know i
let me just talk random okay hello alan
long time no see
so cnp so where is that from uh
i don't know so let's go to powershell
so let's focus on powershell today
i'm going over okay so i'm um
so powershell
right now
gcm let me tell you what gcm is gcm is
get command
so you can see here's a command name
full name get command gcm
is a alias of get command for example
you can see
alias
gcm
okay so you know and g so what's what's
this so get command is
analogous to the unix linux which
which command you know it tells you
where the file is located where the
command is uh
the
full path of the command
so you can type gcm
and
cmp
to see where is whether you have the
command cmp
cmp is compare you know in unix linux it
returns it doesn't return any output
when the two files are exactly the same
now another way is stiff okay uh hello
hello ellen korean number one thank you
so another command in unix stiff linux
is stiff okay that can also
uh tell you if two files are exactly the
same but diff is usually used for text
files
so let's see gcm i don't think i have
div compare uh
yeah i don't have diff
i don't have unix stiff installed the
diff you see is the edius to compare
object which is a power shell comlet you
know a powershell command but
technically it's called comlet so you
have uh you see what is the comlet
you know so i have this powershell
tutorial you go read it and learn it
okay powershell is a magnitude better
than bash
pau xiao is a wiping out of
30 years of
unix
shell baggage that's bash and z shell
and tc shell and and so on oh sure okay
and you want to know why i think that
way
go to this page why i love powershell i
give you detail i can i can talk about
it if you guys want you know if we have
people
with technical interests
i can explain why powershell is the
magnitude
not just a little better but it's it's
better in every way powershell better
than bash the bash unix crap unix is the
worst possible on earth you know
one of the worst technology you know let
me give you just one one example coming
off top of my head okay
unix
you know when you have a file name you
know i'm rambling over but when you have
a file name let's go to it and show you
okay so you see so i got three files
here when you have a file name
on windows you can go to properties
and you have the file creation date you
see unix
windows sucks in many ways you see the
tiny font it's impossible to enlarge
this window it's called model when
anyway
um it's impossible to enlarge the font
you know
so when you are getting old you cannot
see it doesn't matter if you magnify the
font size
it won't magnify here so anyway so
on windows when you have a file you have
the create date recorded okay part of
the file so you can always know
when is the file created you know let's
say you wrote a note you know 10 years
ago you forgot what date when did i
write that oh
create date file creation date okay
windows
on the mac same thing mac is superior
design when it comes to user interface
when it comes comes to
usability mac is supre superior supreme
for the past 30 years basically this the
scene haven't changed between the these
operating systems so mac
as far as operating system user
interface
goes
macintosh apple is supreme to this day
okay
so anyway file creation date on the mac
you also have file creation date but on
unix and on linux you don't have that
you unix unix
unix idiot and linux
they don't know you know you you you
talk to the unix
min you know they've been assisted me
for 10 years
they heard they hear what you say oh you
are wrong c time c time d you know
whatever crap dribble
unix let me tell you one more time okay
let's
uh you know set this into your brain
on unix and linux
and bsd2 bsd freebsd netbsd you know
cqr you know open bsd whatever dragon
bsd
on all these unix systems
the file creation
date is not recorded okay get that
remember that
you know remove that you can you can
talk to you can talk to your eunuchs uh
you know
gurus
right now or linux gurus they don't know
they have no idea they they insist they
will insist
how do i know because i've been fighting
with them for 20 years
yeah
uh starting around 1998 okay they insist
it creates it
you know you can find the
file creation date it doesn't okay go
look around you'll find the answer
you'll find the true answer you know in
our at first you will be you will be
fooled by these dribbles by the unix
and linux phonetics
they don't they don't know they they
just think oh eunuchs is the god that
the idiots
okay so let me get back to my point
on unix linux systems
file you don't have file creation date
you you will not know when is the file
created because it's not there because
the unix idiots and they see
they never you know when it comes to
design they never thought of they never
thought of
they they don't they don't know what
design means
you know what they know is hack
that's what they know that's what they
love get it to work hack fast we are
fast we are c fast
it's a unit unix
okay so creation file creation date you
know this is the main um issue on my
mind you know for 20 years because i
always i've been fighting with the unix
and they always you know
they're just wrong
so they so
let me say this again
file creation date which is a very
useful information you need to know when
is the file created on unix it's not
it's not there it's never recorded okay
so
so okay i'm starting to rent i got you
know starting to get angry so anyway so
back to what i was saying so um
so come so diff so on unix you have diff
you have compare okay that compares
whether um two files are the same
and uh what
okay so let me let me get back to what
am i talking about so
ah god i'm getting over
uh
so let's let's just let's get back to
demo demo of this powershell script okay
so
uh remi
rename file by hash okay so how do you
compare two files are the same so one
way is to use stiff or use the
cmp command
or another way is to you know once you
know once you find two files have the
same size file size is the first easiest
way easiest filter so once you got two
files that's the same size so you can
use compare or you can use stiff to see
to check if they are identical
and by the way let me not get into um
hard link
that's another
unix idiocy you know unix file systems
has the hard link concept that's another
extreme idiocy
so anyway
so why why am i mentioning it because
when you have a hard link that's that's
actually identical file you know it's
the same file but use but have a
different presentation on you know any
anyway so comparative okay another way
to compare
to check
if two files are identical is to
uh compute a hash key so let me explain
what is a hash key okay hash key
basic is you know from a practical point
of view is that when you have a file or
a bunch of binary digits you know
basically your number or
you know when you have a file
you can
hash key is a function hash function it
can take the file as an input and output
a string basically a sequence sequence
of
uh
of alphabets okay
and this sequence alphabet will be
unique to that file so
so in theory
if two files have the same hash key
then that means the two files are
identical okay so that's
that's what this powershell script is
doing so let me show you some powershell
okay so
i'm go going all over the place okay
so let's see let's so so let's um
so okay so here is the powershell script
and i'm using xa powershell mod you see
so this is powershell in emacs you know
uh powershot subpowershot mod you can
find
on my website and pay me to get it
okay you search for some powershell mod
there it is
okay that's uh you know for emacs so you
can you can efficiently code powershell
in emacs
um
so for example let me show you the
okay duh become get children because the
is a alias to get children for example
you know all these ideas well for
example
cmp
gcm we talked about
get command it becomes gate command
okay so you know you have this
completion so you can type get
tab and you can get you know then you
can
have all the
powershell commands that start with the
word get
you know one of the advantage of
powershell
with respect to naming his naming okay
naming of things so in powershell they
follow a system systematic naming so
everything
when it's an action something you have a
get something so you have get command
get history get culture culture culture
get culture is like the date format the
time format you know
different culture have different um
you know
formats then you have get ps drive you
know which is a system uh interface to
different things so you know then you
have get content which is like
unix cat
you know unix unix names you know cat
you know idiot
you know speaking of
anyway so
get content is
like unix unix cat which stands for
concatenate
uh and you know get process is like unix
ps okay guest servers is get servers get
counter is get counter i don't know what
that you know so
so anyway so that's that's uh
powershell mod so if you like my stuff
go buy it okay
thank you cortes thank you alan and uh
what else
so how long so today is rambling day
okay
talk show rambling day i haven't done
this for a long time
so let me let's get back to powershell
okay so let's remove that so this is a
script
um so what i'm going to do i'm going to
do some demo i guess um
yeah let's let's write down okay so when
you are confused write things down so
you don't get con so you know what to do
exactly so let's write things down right
now okay
so here is today's talk show and i'm
gonna write down what i'm gonna uh do
okay
demo
uh
demo get file hash okay
so that's a powershell command we're
gonna demo that
and uh
um what else
and and in the demo
demo the
the
delete duplicate perl script
okay so that's another thing
and demo
the power shell
rename file
to
hash
okay let's just start with that three
okay let's get not
distracted okay so
demo get file hash okay so let's try
that let's um
so i'm gonna do that okay
so let's
pop this back
okay so now let's open so here is
today's talk show
let's demo file hash which is a
powershell okay
okay let's start
let me show you the pink window the pink
window shows all my command cores in
emacs and their keystroke here here you
can see okay so let's start a powershell
template
and pop it out
then
get
file
hash there it is
so
get help you know you just press a key
and it will open the help page you know
actually
you know so this is xr powershell mod if
you like it buy it okay so here so you
have the get file hash you know this is
not
so there it is the powershell
documentation on get file hash
and you can turn on javascript
javascript so it shows
you know the panels and all
uh so get file hash so description blah
blah blah so
so let's copy their example so
you see
so
so what's some example so okay so let's
open let's open my
images close that go to keyboard
uh okay delete duplicate copy hold on a
second let me do some
management okay open the talk show
paste the perl script here make a link
show in browser so you can see we have
the perl script here
here so that's my perl script to delete
one million
image files that may be duplicate
okay so right now let's go to keyboard
image file so let's
copy that go back to talk show
open that
paste the
image
showing browser
okay so we have an image so this image
let me easily go to the image directory
so i'm looking at the image in emacs
press the key diet jump
to go to this image directory okay so
there are 600 files and press a key open
it in explorer okay so again and
what i'm doing this um
social desktop that's part of supply
keys okay
so
so get hat file hash okay so let me
demonstrate okay so
close that
copy the
path of this image go back here
and paste the file path here okay kind
of long but it's okay so
do that okay
so get file hash okay so we can actually
actually execute the command here
do it
there it is there it is it's a hash it's
a you see
so it takes a file path and returns a
hashtag a hash key basically a sequence
of numbers
uh not numbers a sequence of uh you know
as a string a sequence of letters
so
so we demonstrated a
git file hash
and i need to demonstrate perl delete
duplicate
uh and demo powershell rename file to
hash okay let's let's demo the
powershell rename to file hash okay
so let's go back to this image directory
so you can see
thousands of images
this
cute girl lovely some someone else's
photo i don't know who she is
so you have all these images fantastic
okay let's copy the image
let's copy the image directory so um
so let's see
so let's go to here
keyboard let's go to talk show talk show
go to the talk show directory
and
create a new directory let's say
x x t t
okay we just created a new directory
open it and go to this image directory
and copy it over
yes
do you want to copy recursively yes
recursively that's a unix jargon
shouldn't be named that but anyway so we
copied the whole image directory here so
we can work on it we can you know
delete or whatever so i don't screw up
my keyboard you know image directory so
so here is the other images let's see
so you can open images in emacs so you
can see
lots of images
that
that that
you know some of them are icons icons so
okay so images
okay let's do let's uh let's uh let's
wait how do you do this in uh let's see
let me show you okay so copy so we don't
have to re we we don't have to do this
uh
let me let me tell you what i'm doing
okay so copy
uh
basically we want to copy your directory
over so this is how you do it okay
yeah with powershell okay so close that
go to
talk show today open the image go to the
directory copy the file path switch
window
and paste it here so we have two
paths here so this one
uh
so this one is a directory
let's say let's
say the uh so that one is a directory
okay so
and
this is a second directory
okay in fact this we want to copy this
directory to that directory okay in fact
let's
um yeah okay so
let's do that
okay so this is a command we can
copy the directory over anyway but for
now
for now let's do the powershell um
let me demo demonstrate this powershell
um
rename file okay
so copy that
comment that out comment that out paste
the code here
magnify
so
we
are working in this directory okay so
open that copy the file path
so my directory will equals to that
okay let's rename it extra
and let's just leave it
miter okay
so this is the directory
and we don't need the file name just
just a directory so here is a directory
and for
so we are using listing directory
and file names only
and pipe it to each part each object for
each object that means for each file
get the file name extension
you do that by split path
dash extension okay
then you
create a new name so the new name is
going to be
git file hash
it returns a object
base basically github file hash returns
the hash
stream
but however in micro in powershell
everything is object
so you have to so instead it actually
returns a object and this object has it
has a property named hash
and the value of that property is a hash
string you know this is a bit complexity
i didn't really like this but this is i
suppose more powerful so
when you call get file hash
it doesn't it doesn't just return a
string it returns the object if you
really actually want the hash you have
to
call the property hash to get the
hash stream then plus file name
extension so
what you get is a you know
a hash key with a jpeg or png then you
call rename item to rename it okay
that's how you do it so if we run this
now if we run this now
you see all this
you see all these images
let's magnify okay
you see all these images they're gonna
you see there look at their name they're
gonna be all renamed into a hash okay
let's do it
okay close close let you know there are
many ways to run it i can run this in
emacs
or i can run this in powershell let's
run it in powershell okay so let's just
copy that
paste it
paste anyway yes paste it
what
and what did i paste oh god
what did it do
oh okay so you see
i pasted the so this is
you know i paste it
you know basically you you can these two
lines needs to be one single line
otherwise it
consider the first one just as a command
that's why it's actually listing the
directory so you see the mida dash file
that's actually listing the directory
okay so
so cancel that okay cancel
okay cancel so these two needs to be one
line okay
okay now let's do it again copy it
back to powershell cls for clear screen
so we start fresh
paste it
paste anyway
okay
enter executed
execute
done now go back to our directory you
see
the file names
now they all become hash
unique to every file
so let me open this picture because this
girl is beautiful
okay so anyway so
let's look at some of the files okay so
okay so anyway so you can see what
anyway so
success okay so let's let's change this
to
file path
so you can see um what
anyway so that's it that's a demo of
this
uh powershell script turn every file
into their hash okay
am i
doing good is it interesting
uh is it that's it for today or
something else let's see
so
any questions
okay
you know
so
if you have a question for me
you know tag me okay
so we demonstrated this powershell
script
uh let's see what else what else are we
supposed to do
close that
okay we go back here
today's talk show
demo powershell get file hash we did
that
demo delete duplicate we're going to do
that demo the powershell rename file to
hash we did that and we explained how it
works
now let's demo the delete duplicate perl
script this is gonna be fantastic okay
because it actually um
hold on a second let me show show in
browser so you can see we have today's
code here
okay now let's demo the perl script okay
the this power script is going to be
fantastic my friends
fantastic okay close that go here curse
that
okay so we need the file path hold on a
second
now remove
remove the
html so it's legible but wait
uh
there so now the script is legible so
this the
so copy that copy copy copy
okay so let's create a new powershell
template
create another one
paste
now
syntax color them all
show in browser
there it is now it's good now actually
uh
we need to remove the comment okay so
remove the comment here and remove the
comment here
and uh
delete this
oh actually you need that let's use some
shorter names so yeah that one
okay
now
syntax color them
back to browser
refresh
fantastic
so
now we are going to
demo the pearl dd duplicate script okay
written 20 years ago
17.
uh
so
yeah so first of all we need to what we
need to do so we yeah let's let's go
there okay so let's go to our temp
directory
go to the temp directory
you see image files now they are all
uh
they are all uh hash names
so
go up a directory
magnify
delete the whole thing
yes do you eat them all yes
kill diode buffer
yes okay i just we just deleted the hole
now
powershell
uh now we need to
copy
copy them over remember that's why we
did this before we just run this we can
we can run this we can run this in
in in powershell terminal or we can run
it in emacs let me show you another
command okay i press to key
i press two key then it pops up this
powershot window you see so that is part
of the emac my emacs command open in
terminal it works on windows it works on
linux and it works on mac
okay so
on any you know you
open in terminal that is part of
sapphire keys so you just press two keys
it will open the current buffer
directory in terminal okay so exit so
since i'm on windows so it opens
powershell
so we open so yeah so we can run this in
so many ways so for example um
dot x two zero
uh which one this one
so
if i run that it will copy but you know
someone different ways but let me show
you
i'm going to run this in emacs in
powershell mod so
run it
finished
okay you need in a mini buffer you can
see finished now we go here
press the key to open the directory
enter to open fantastic you see
we just deleted this now we copied over
again so now
so now let's make some duplicate okay so
let's um
again okay let me show you okay so
press the key
it makes a backup you see of this file
so whatever so let's say
that file let's mark okay that file that
file that file okay i marked four files
now i
press a key
each one of them will have a backup copy
so you see
you see
so the that command is xiaomi backup and
save that's also part of soft flag keys
okay
so now we have all this duplicate
duplicate what am i gonna do well i'm
gonna rename them okay so
rename
uh we we should have written a script to
rename this okay
so we can rename files directly here so
we add uh we we just add
let's magnify okay
so we
have renamed
all these files
uh what
okay so
add a t here
d that okay
so
done okay now actually
tx let's rename a name again okay so
press the key to start to rename and
let's do query replace
dash t
dot jpeg
replace by
t
x
x dot jpeg okay
yes yes yes yes yes okay five files done
okay
so why am i doing that so we can
highlight it by a pattern easily
so uh what
so for example i'm going to mark by
regular expression and i type txx.jpg
enter
you see it says five files
five files
marked you see so so what we did is just
we made a copy of some of the files
because why are we doing that because we
are
going to
demo the perl
script to delete duplicate okay
so
copy the file path let's now go to the
perl directory
close that
okay so
get back
okay
so sure in browser so here is our code
now let's open the perl
directory
okay so here is a perl directory and how
do you
call it let me show you okay so open the
powershell
so i can call it by
pearl
let's see where is pearl get command
okay pearl is installed strawberry pearl
that's the
pearl you use on windows okay so pearls
there
and i can just say pearl
okay run the code
so it's gonna
tell you it oh god can locate something
something
missing the module why because well the
module is right here
but it's not
yeah
so i haven't run this code for like
10 20 years for 10 years um
so why is a module not part of the
current directory i mean why is
why it does not use the current
directory as a search location to locate
modules
now i haven't been coding perl for 15
years
so basically the error is that can
locate module
in ink
okay ink you know ink is the
search path you may need okay so
you know what i'm going to
i'm just going to
copy this whole code
into the file so we don't have the
module crap
the code is only 10 lines it's just one
function
you know because back then
what is this sub reduce oh god i have a
full documentation
okay so i got more than one function
reduce and merge
ah this is pearl code okay
okay so first of all make a backup of
this file
and now
now let's go here
and
let's modify this backup okay
okay and same thing with this package
okay so this mod we're gonna um
we don't need the package name we don't
need that i need that
export isa
exported um
god i don't know i don't
know pearl for a long time so let's just
delete all these
comments and stuff this is inline
documentation of pearl
okay so removed all that
he removed all that
okay so that should be it 70 lines of
code
and this code we're just gonna copy
close it save it and put it into the
main program here
so we don't have to deal with the
let's just paste it here okay
okay and same thing so let's remove you
see here is where you call the module
use combo
command out
and use gen pairs comment out okay and
go to the directory
gen pairs okay we need to include the
code of this thing
so remove that
remove remove remove copyright remove
so
here's a documentation delete
delete
okay
here's another documentation delete
delete
okay
copy the whole thing close it save
back to delete dupes the main program
open it
and paste our thing here paste our thing
here
okay
and now
add a bunch of comments to separate okay
so now we have the program
no dependencies on modules okay save it
now back to
powershell
okay run the last code
do it
fantastic
uh wait what
yeah it runs
successfully wait what
yes it runs successfully let's clear the
screen so it's
so it's easier to see okay so do it
again so you see
so it says no argument received that's
the proper behavior
so it tells you the usage you know if
you doesn't you know give a directory
you tell your usage so the way you call
a command is
you need to give it a path okay let's
give it a path
uh that's
uh that's the place you want it to tell
you to work on i mean the directory you
want to remove the duplicate
so the path is
where is our uh
path okay let's it's here here is a path
okay
so
do it again let's clear screen
call the command
and paste the file path okay there
do it
there are a total of zero files examined
okay i think um
yeah it's not finding let's try it again
okay i think you cannot use the
abbreviation because
in perl yeah okay so let's
um
let's fix that
okay let's call it again let's
clear screen let's call this again and
this time let's give it a full path
do it
fantastic you see
so now it says there are 630 unique file
size the following files are identical
you can see
there
you know if this each two files are
identical sometimes you have five or ten
files that's identical it will just all
list them
so now if you want to delete you can so
you know
and it tells you if you delete these
duplicate files you'll save this many
bytes
so if you want to delete you can just
say dash d okay so
so let's give it an option uh
i believe it's dash d okay let's double
check let's go to the pearl
let's open it let's see
yeah dash d okay
so
do it
fantastic
okay so now let's go to
let's go to our image directory
open it
open it open it
you see
the files are good you see this file the
original is good also this file
you see because there's no more uh file
of the same name before you see
exa
okay and here's another one you see
success
okay that's it that's it i think that's
it so that's the
so that is the pearl dd duplicate
uh code i wrote
17 years ago
okay
that these duplicate files of you know a
million potentially a million files in
your directory
and it works in the most efficient way
because that's how i code okay the most
efficient way it's not you know
uh and uh you know now but
so back then so how do you compare if
two files are different you know you can
first of all you you know first of all
if two files have the same file size how
do you make how do you um check if they
are different you can call the compare
command or you can
use the hash table
now there's a question i don't know you
know i have to think about
so which way is more efficient
is it more efficient to call the unix
cmp command to compare
if two files are identical or is it a
fish more efficient
if you simply generate
the
hash key for each file
then
compare string of the two hash key
i don't know you know i i don't know
which one is more efficient
so that's an interesting question to
look into uh fantastic thank you celtic
uh yeah i think that's it i rambled for
an hour just an hour perfect
okay bye guys yeah i'm shutting down so
we did a lot demo we did a demo of emacs
workflow
lots of emacs commands
soft light keys commands software keys
and
powershell mod
um
and
and clean up and i'm shutting down okay
so
if you like to try this script you can
find it on my website
somehow shall rename file to hash just
search for xr powershell tutorial
okay so that's that close
so that's my delete duplicate perl
script now i'm going to put this onto my
website okay so you can also have this
uh script available you know
let me show you okay so
you know
for about 10 years
the script is of it so this is a web
page for that perl script
you know starting in 2005 for about 10
years it's available free on web
you know so here's a example output
it has many features for example if you
have multiple directories
not nested you know you have one
directory in one drive another directory
in a different drive
but you want to compare you don't want
to merge them you you want to compare of
all you know all files in these
directories if they are duplicate you
can do that with this script you know
you don't have to first you don't have
to first move one directory into inside
the other
folder
and you can specify
according to the directory order you can
specify which duplicate should be
deleted first you know so you have like
for example a master folder
where
where this is your you know master
folder then you have other folders if
they are duplicate you should delete the
duplicate in the other folders first so
that's you know that that's part of the
feature
of this script
but then you know
around 2010 i was you know
becoming very poor so i started to
you know
pay you have to pay to get it
but today actually there are a lot you
know i there are a lot um
programs that do similar things okay dd
duplicate but i'm not you know but
you can be sure that mine is quality one
okay i'm not sure what's the quality of
the others or if they are efficient but
so if you like my stuff buy my stuff
okay pay me paypal patreon
uh let me show you okay so i need to
surrender info
so
where is my paypal patreon okay they
moved to the bottom
patreon me amazon gift card me paypal me
or you can buy my tutorials
emac this tutorial fantastic i've been
working on emacs
lisp tutorial a lot a lot update in the
past month you know you see for example
yesterday i updated one to you know 10
10 also files and the day before you
know so many updates
so i've been working on that a lot you
can buy it
it's on emacs tutorial
or you can buy
wufang language is free and i wrote you
know this is one of the main thing i'm
working on these days wufang language
tremendous powerful programming language
okay you should
get it for free
and learn it okay
benefit you for life
which is uh i talked about often in fact
i think next video i'm gonna do wufang
language again
okay and my javascript tutorial is the
most in-depth javascript tutorial out
there i would say one of the best one of
the top three best in english language
if you ask me i would say it's the best
in the english language
of javascript in depth okay it doesn't
matter it's printed doesn't matter it's
online resource such as mozilla you know
you know the firefox thing reference
my
javascript in-depth tutorial is superior
uh in clarity
in organization in the way it gets you
to understand how it works
okay that you know so if you like my
stuff buy it
uh and
uh yeah so but all these you know all
these are free online too you know you
can read them
okay bye guys
um
you