hello guys welcome to another episode of
star talk show
so today is 2022
march
16th
san francisco time
it's noon
so i'm going to do random today so it's
random chat random
live stream and mostly i'm just going to
code
uh working on my website so you are
going to see emacs workflow so my emacs
workflow
so you can um
you know if those of you who watch my
videos you know
what is this about so you know
so okay so if you have questions
comments just post it now okay post you
know rent like random so today is random
so i'm just going to work on my uh emacs
website so the first thing is you see
there's a lot of photos here
you see tons of photos and i can press
the key let me show you the command
press the key to um
start direct open in infra view
iphone view iphone view is a classic uh
image viewer so let me show you okay so
um
so this is iphone view okay let's cancel
it
let's
view it
so you can see a bunch of images and uh
okay you can you probably cannot see all
of it because part of it is hidden yeah
okay so let's change info view so info
view is a classic windows application
for viewing images it was the best one
throughout 1990s and 2000s
today it's not so it's not that great
because you know the user interface
changing and they are sticking with
kind of 90s in interface in 1990s
windows api
so for example all these fonts are too
small to to see
anyway so let's uh i need to fix
something so the images are always in
the center
so first of all video check audio check
yes good okay so
iphone view you want to
make the image in the center so where do
you
um
put windows in middle of the screen okay
so there so now i can switch yeah so i
can
so you know usually every
three hours i walk around for half an
hour with my tablet windows surface
tablet and i take notes so these are the
things i need to do for example the
movement
for example if you go to my website
and you can see you know uh programming
language tutorials and this wolfram
language and i was thinking of creating
a new logo
for uh wufang language
now watch my wufang language
videos okay it's free you can download
it free it's and and it's the best
language
so
so i take notes these are the things i
need to do and you know create a new
logo for that that's one thing and this
is my javascript tutorial uh these
things i need to work on
javascript symbols which is a new
feature
around
2016 or 2015.
i still haven't worked on that page
javascript in depth that's
this tutorial okay
and a bunch of other things you know i'm
doing my live stream and sometimes i
need to change the title you know take
notes for myself
so but let's get on to some of the
things i need to do actually so you know
let's start to do them
okay so emacs tutorial so if you go to
my emacs tutorial you know recently i
did kind of a little bit slight
reorganization of the topic
box topic pages table of contents so it
used to be there is a link to the emac
list
tutorials or at the top
but now i rely on the back to you know
the red button the back to
uh table of contents
uh so but
okay so let me show you what i'm gonna
do so copy the url
switch to emacs
i want so i want a
topic box so you can see let me let me
explain okay so you can see here's the
table of contents you know there are
several main entry points for my emacs
tutorial and the most important are
these
seven of them so there's two sections
the emacs tutorial
so let's magnify
okay
and by the way i'm using the new
keyboard um
yeah i'm using a new keyboard so i'm not
too familiar with the setup yet i
reviewed this keyboard yesterday you
know in my previous video
you can find it on my keyboard blog this
is
key move dk 61 ke mov
you know watch my uh
video before today
so
so you have you can see here is the main
entry points there's a two major
sections one is emacs tutorial and one
is emac lisp tutorial so in the emacs
tutorial section you have the
basic generic tutorial and if you go
there click one of them you see the
current page will highlight in green
okay
so go back go back so that's the emacs
tutorial into the set three sections
generic tutorial emacs init or about
initialization
let's magnify
then uh emax keys okay
let's see did the magnification work no
jesus
okay let's set up the magnification so
it's always magnified so firefox
settings
uh
general
you know each browser their settings
becomes diversified diversified each
browser supports their own
uh
settings so it's you know usually you
have to spend hours to get the setting
correct okay zoom default zoom let's say
okay
my close key doesn't even work okay
so
emacs tutorial section three major
subsections tutorial
emacs init and emax keys all about emacs
keys so you can watch my video there
then there's emac list section generic
tutorial practical emac list
introduction
then uh emac list examples
where you can see sample code you know
all these sections is sample code of
emac this
you can see each one of them do
something useful
then there is emac this advanced
in this section you learn about more
fundamental
aspects
technical details of emac list the
language such as cons pair
list what's the difference between list
and vector and sequence types you know
how do you map how do you go through
uh
sequence type list of vector
throw and catch you know technical
details of emac this
emac this advanced
then you have a more advanced section
about how to write the emac list major
mod so if you read this you can write
the major mod
uh in an hour
so there is the table of contents you
see so right now i rely on you know once
you are on any particular page for
example this page emac list advanced
association list which is a particular
particular data structure
in emac list so
anytime you are in a particular page
you
right now you rely on clicking on the
uh back
to emacs
tutorial homepage you know to get to the
top table of contents
what i want to do is i want to create a
topic box let me just do it okay
so
so let me just do it
copy the url switch back to emacs
open that page yeah
um
okay open that page
so now we
copy this
uh wait so
show the pink window
okay so actually
uh
close that
yeah so
copy this
list
and go to one of them here
and here
and if i just view in browser yeah
viewing browser that's this page okay
now i want to
topic
that gives me the topic box and paste
these links
okay so if you view in browser now
it looks like that okay which is not
what we want
so go back here
and
so i'm going to show you what's going on
okay
so
delete that to do that
let's say xr emacs tutorial
then change the h4 to h3
you know i'm not familiar with my
keys here
so what's the key
i'm not familiar with this keyboard so
change
bracket pair okay so not
here so let's
change contact okay f9 uc
i'm using vera keyboard so
f9 uc so
h3
now you can see the title uh wait
uh
you see h3 uh okay
three is over here
so now you can see the title is now h3
then
move this in
inside paste paste okay
now
viewing browser you see
fantastic so you got the table of
contents you know
instead of going back to the top you can
just directly
conveniently switch to different major
topics
oh not found ah jesus
okay so because they are in a different
directory so the directories are wrong
so
the file path is wrong here so you need
to actually so let's fix them
actually let's let me show you okay so
yeah let's just fix them
yeah so copy that
replace
you know this is 60 keyboard so you
don't have arrow keys whenever i need to
press arrow keys i need to hold down
hold down function key a pain in the ass
60 keyboards are a pain in the ass okay
now then showing browser fantastic you
can see now i can switch to different
topics
emacs init
emax keys
practical emac list okay now i need to
put this navigation box into each one of
the main topic okay so
press a key to cut it undo now let's
just go to this page
and
search for main
search okay
and paste it there
showing browser there it is okay
now go back to emacs
so let me copy it
undo you can see all my command codes in
the ping window
so let's just do it
okay now showing browser now i click on
emacs init
and this is not the box
something is wrong let's see emacs keys
ah god i did it wrong so
the topic box is somehow
what's going on oh whoa i forgot [ __ ]
so actually i need to copy
this part f6
so let's fix them
um
and
four
okay
now show in browser
try emacs init fantastic
try emacs keys fantastic okay it's here
and try emacs practical emac bisp there
try e max list examples there
emac this advanced there
and how to write the emac list major
mark so you see that's done
thank you for
666 of flamio fantastic pine pine
pineapple today fantastic thank you
so
any questions you know when you pay
you got to ask a question
so
essentially that's what i'm doing uh
that's what i want to do okay
it's probably confusing to you because
you don't know what i'm doing you know
you just see a bunch of key presses so
maybe i should explain maybe
um
you know because i'm using stuff like
keys so maybe i can explain some some of
it
yeah but i got lots of other things to
do um
[Music]
so
you see that lisp logo
is
should be at the bottom you see so there
is a
css issue
uh well that that happens because this
is a inline block
okay we don't want a inline path okay so
the easiest way to fix that is to add a
dive
okay then view in browser there it is
css you know check out my tutorial i
have a css tutorial
so anyway so how did i do this okay
let's try this again
okay on this page this box probably
should be at the top
um
[Music]
i don't know you know so this is a
design decision you know
so this topic box
allows you to switch to different major
topics you see
emac these examples emac this but
advanced emac this how to you know
ideally you see ideally
let's see emacs tutorial emacs init
emacs keys okay
emacs tutorial ideally the box should be
should stay put so it doesn't matter
which page you are they stay in the same
position
so if we want to do that we need to have
this topic box always at the top
however
that violates another principle another
the other principle is that whenever i
have i have this topic box you see these
topics
excel
that should be at the bottom of the page
um
so you know when you design there's lots
of conflicting um issues
so in this case i think it it makes
sense to have them at the top at the
same position emacs keys so let's do
that so emacs keys let's fix it let's go
here cut it move it to the top
and view in browser you see now it's at
the top
uh yeah but
you know the design issues that's a
detail
so let's fix some the others so emacs
advance and how to write the major mod
okay so let's also move this uh to the
box to the top
cut
paste
okay so now it's you see all the topics
box should be at the top you see now
it's kind of
um
yeah except the intro sentence you see
there's an interesting sentence there
that
design issues so i'm not sure what to do
about that i have to think about so
think about that so there's a lot of
these issues so
let's see what's the comments here sorry
if this is off of topic what is your
thoughts on
ligatures and do they contradict gnu
emacs ascii philosophy
i talked about that many times like
major topic in past year about
font and ligatures
uh i suppose you are not trolling
because that is ligatures is the one of
the most idiotic thing
that is obsessed obsessed by the hacker
type of programmers by programmers
you know by programmers they it's they
have a obsession about
about literature and about font and
that's the worst the most idiotic [ __ ]
possible i talked about that
for several videos for one hour you know
so
go check
out my videos in
2021 or 2020.
um
okay for example let me let me just show
you okay so you go to saudi org actually
just search for
xrd
ligature okay
you can probably find unicode liquidus
unicode latin
uh
my twitter post you know
there it is one article okay the
monotonicities of the typography but
however this is
someone else stole my website you know
content into their
you know lots of these there the
moralistics of typography hyphen dash
quotation marks
so you click on that to open
switch to it the moronicities of
typography hyphen dash quotation marks
apostrophe so in this article i also
talked about gnu
convention for quotes
this article does not talk about
ligatures but
but but here at the bottom there's the
related articles box so you can see the
tech pestilence
related issue okay that's another nerd
you know urine cycle obsession
intro to
chinese punctuation
then english english phonetics uh
good article
diet then you have article on diet
critics
trauma omelette macron
macron
macro circumflex
you know all these dia critics what you
know what's their purpose
their origin you know their name you
know these unicode characters and
matching brackets in unicode
and
english writing style oxford comma you
know that's um that's kind of a mean uh
you know about grammar
uh typography as high art you know
typography is the most idiotic thing
which is obsession of donald glute uh
idiotic obsession
so i i talked about several hours on
these topics in the past but however i
haven't found the main um topic so let
me go to find it okay so first of all
copy the url
go to talk page and paste in
what we talked about today
okay so you uh we have a record so you
you go through my top of my website
xrd web then you click on sally info
uh just about any topic you can just
search for my name and whatever the word
you'll find my opinions on it so exactly
code study code then you go down
then you go down
then you go down to a bunch of essays
then there is a section on css sucks
okay
um
user interface design okay let's go
there
because this is related to font okay
then you go down
you can see
there is my video donald glooth steve
jobs and the idiocy of typography okay i
did several videos so two of them are
here i did more than that actually one
of them is here but
um
the idiocy of typography and end and
ligatures leakages the worst the most
worthless idiocy you know what they are
they are like themes you know themes in
emacs
you know like people you know the
especially the male engine and zuma say
they have themes they make them pretty
okay that's about that so let me go back
to do what i need to do okay
so what are the questions do you uh
do you know what virtual youtubers are
no i don't know what is virtual youtuber
we probably buy a kinesis advantage to
end of this month
fantastic
big fan of me okay great thank you you
know i care
you know i got lots of thanks
uh which i appreciate but
the sad fact is that money okay you
donate to me
money talks
otherwise you know i get thanks all the
time
uh doesn't do much to me and i
you have practiced struggling have you
been interested in card tricks no not
really i don't not you know juggling and
and
magic magician juggling and magic is
usually tied together though you know
and this is also uh one of the main
interests in programming notes you know
you'll see a lot of programmers
and nuts no type of programmers such as
the unix hackers you know you're the
unix
philosophy linux type people they they
will juggle and they will often many of
them will
be interested in doing magic you know
card tricks or handkerchief or lots of
lots of you can buy props you know i was
i was in that community when i was a
teenager for 10 years
but for me
i'm not i'm i'm i was never interested
in magic i've seen a lot you know i've
seen a lot of them tons of them
uh
but magic is not my thing
you know some say you know let me talk
about magic okay you know
according to these people you know some
you know some
you know the magicians many of the best
one they make tons of money they are
million you know 100 millionaires
billion you know maybe not billion but
they become very rich
um
magicians you know and they some you
know so magic you have the small tricks
like card tricks can't achieve disappear
coins and so on then you have like big
tricks usually those are called
illusions illusionist
illusionists
you know for example they can cut people
in half you know you see that and and
there's modern ones you know young
younger generation malenchen zuma's on
youtube you see you know chris something
you know big name
they make hundreds of millions dollars
so magic is to that according to them
many of these phonetics magic phonetics
they'll say
magic ma and and many of the magicians
are also into physics okay so like math
physics juggling all kind of related you
know
so to them to the magic phonetics
they'll say magic is truly magical
because they are
they are kind of understanding physics
they are kind of um
you know somehow related to fix physics
they
and also part also another topic very
highly related is psychology
the manipulation of human mind you know
in real time
you know so and this is also related to
con men you know which which is another
topic i'm highly interested so for for
example some people you know and there
are movies hollywood movies about
magicians about comment you know so i
can talk to you i can just say things
and your i'll earn your trust you know
you'll believe what i say and i'll
yeah i can manipulate them uh
manipulate you
and then there's another topic of about
uh
hypnosis um
hypnotics you know hypnosis you know
basically you i put you to sleep like
then i can tell you what to do
that's usually crap okay so anyway so
magic you know all these are related
topics so from juggling from computer
computer nerds to juggling to
mathematicians to physicists you know
then you have magicians then
then it also ties to
uh psychologist psychology and comment
and brainwashing real you know like kind
of real time
so
um but uh so what's my point so i was
going to say magicians yeah so
uh
i'm not really interested in magicians
so you know
magics magicians so how do they work
there are two
there are two major things
the two major elements on how magic
works okay either the small ones like
disappearing or coin like i can pop i
can create a coin out of your ear
you know or or
you know you know like all card tricks
so that's small tricks then you have
bigger tricks illusions like cut people
in half or disappear a whole building
that that becomes very fake that becomes
a camera tv manipulation but people do
that because
then they become comment because you you
know they disappear a whole building
how is that possible well oh magic all
magic is actually just fake in a sense
you know because they are not you know
they deceived you
that's you know because there's no real
uh magic well you know if you talk you
know so this is the very
fertile topic you know magic
so
then you get into higher dimensions then
that's another possibility you know like
multiverse and so on anyway
practically speaking
all magics are just all magic is just
fake okay
that's reality that's why they some
it's in some sense that's why they are
interesting
it's fake but they make it real they you
are
and it's it is fascinating because
magic tricks you see them you cannot
figure out how it's done
you know
um
so but ultimately magics
magic are just fake you know so
and there are two major parts
of how it works okay
one is just
slight of hand
side of hand okay for example i can
i can make a coin appear in your head
well how does that work that's because i
already hold i already have the coin in
my palm
you know but somehow you didn't see it
you know i just make you believe that a
coin appeared from your ear you know
that's a very classic trick
that of course the trick is how you you
have to practice it you know magic magic
is not easy you have to practice
practice just like programming you know
for for daily for hours a day for years
then you can then it works
so
it's just fake okay so part of it is
just
skill okay skill of of your hand of your
manipulation you know
that's one part of it
um the other part is psychology okay
psychology so i can you know so
this
so this becomes where interpersonal
skill those social type of people you
know some of you maybe but usually not
nuts not programmers the social type of
people who can talk smoothly you know
sales people
they can they can do that well you know
they they are more inclined to do that
well so
much psychology so when i talk to you i
have to
make you like me
you know make you you know say whatever
i want you to believe
and uh
and evolving uh understanding psychology
many aspects of it
uh and draw your attention away things
like that
um
yeah it's like yeah
so that's the two major components of
magic okay
hand skills you know little skills
physical skills and
psychological manipulation
and some other things you know such as
sometimes mathematics a little bit
mathematics a little bit physics for
example some magic tricks are just
physics for example i can i have a cup
of water
you know clear water i pour another
clear water into it and it becomes blue
how is that
wow that's magical how does that happen
well it's just physics chemistry you
know so in card tricks there's some
similar things you know i let you choose
some cards i put in somewhere then
eventually that card is the number you
you you guessed
and
some of the card tricks come down to
math
so meaning that there's no magic at all
it just mathematically it works out that
way
you know so we get into mystery mystery
of uh mathematics
so anyway and probability and so anyway
so magic uh is not too interest you know
i'm not really interested in magic it's
most you know fake
but i'm interested in psychology and
brainwashing uh especially the grand
scale type
uh and which you know usa and all
politicians they are doing that in in
apple and big corporations anyway
so that's about magic okay so
that's kind of um
yeah digression about magic
did i miss you know that that we had so
many topics to go into but i probably i
forgot you know so if you want me to
talk about that mention it
and pay me
no framework no more html file i'll say
okay also reading the source code on my
own also answer the question okay what
is the question okay oh i answered okay
so found it thank you so much uh what is
that about
oh yeah leakages okay so hey there i
know the answer to virtual youtuber
question
oh virtual youtubers oh i haven't seen
uh i guess i know what i'm what you are
talking about like some computer
generated you know youtubers yeah
so i didn't know it's a thing it's
that's interesting
uh and i don't think i love it
there being a bill gay day okay i don't
know what what he said okay
so
let's go back to emacs theme uh
so now let's so i want to work on the my
next thing 10 people watching comments
and questions okay keep them coming so
topic box this thing we have done
so
next thing what's the next thing
okay uh some web tutorial we need a
topics box again okay
now let me mention how did i work how
how did i just you know made all this
topic box uh where is it
already it's gone somewhere so
so how did i uh add them
let me show you some some of the tricks
um
no let me let me push on so let me push
on okay so i want to go to let me just
do it okay
so you can see i have a tutorial
javascript in depth
you go top you go up a level you can see
your tutorial on html
on css
on javascript
on javascript reference javascript
object reference
and on javascript working on dom
and svg
okay so these topics are all related
because usually if you study one of them
you would be highly interested in one of
the other and usually when you work if
you are web dev you know usually you uh
it's
usually you want when you work on you
know in web dev you need to reference
javascript css html all the time cross
reference
so i need just like the emacs tutorial i
need a
related topic box so you so one can
easily navigate from one of these to the
other without
without clicking on the you know going
back to the table of contents okay let's
do that
copy the url
um
open that okay so let's do that
so i'm going um i'm going to do this
quickly this time
so http protocol so
okay
so now i go to the html one
and
and place them at the bottom okay so i
don't want at the top so now i
press a key to linkify this
and i type
topic t
to create a template for the topic box
then i want to delete
the previous list okay and change the
title
change the title to web dev tutorials
web dev tutorials and
capitalize the title
then change the h4 to h3 so
let's do that
h3
you know on this keyboard it's staggered
so i'm used to the orthogonal
layout but it's staggered so now i'm
when i'm on staggered i type whenever i
want to type three
i typed four instead you know staggered
idiocy
so let's change the title to h3
um
let's try again so three
okay so you can see now it's three then
now i want to
grab that
block okay
now show in browser now
got
showing browser there it is that's what
i want i want this on all of these pages
okay let's do it
let's put it on top okay so
yeah so copy that
then go here
and okay so
and let's go here
okay
now show in browser fantastic html
tutorial
visual css tutorial
javascript in depth
javascript object reference
dom scripting tutorial
practical svg tutorial okay
that's okay so again like i said before
i'm not satisfied with this design
because when you have these um
you know
the question is should this box at the
should this box at the top or at the
bottom
you see when it's at the top
it's great in the sense that you know
the topic remains in one position
but however it's kind of confusing
because for example this page is
practical svg tutorial so when people
arrive at this page
they see the title
but then
then they see something else they see
you know these are not svg tutorials
these are just navigation blocks to
somewhere else
yeah so
okay so let me think
let me make a
design decision right now instead of
working offline since i'm doing just
random topic today so let me just
um
have to make a decision so should the
should the related
thing
at the top on at the bottom
uh
this is especially when this box when
this navigation box is at the top
it's especially
annoying for the css
tutorial because the css tutorial this
page the index page the main entry
page
is a bunch of you know it shows
visualization of css
so
on this page if you have the navigation
box at the top it's
it's kind of irrelevant it's
it's confusing to users who just come to
this page
so this design issue
so let's you know let me dive into
my
my process of how i arrive at design
decisions for my website okay let me
give you a view of that bottom so
off or flamio is correct you know i
agree with you you're a good you know i
agree with you
so if you have the boxes at the top the
advantage is that
when people navigate around they will
see you know they can remain in the same
position you know
but it's it's just
so that's the advantage the disadvantage
is that
some
entry page some of the entry page
you know they have actual content there
for example why why do you need the
actual content for example if i click on
javascript in depth you know this is a
few hundred pages you know a giant
chapter i mean a book by itself you know
a few hundred pages
so when people arrive at this page they
you need some kind of introduction you
know like
you know so i say this tutorial is
better than mozilla or any other
javascript book in print
you know that's my that's my marketing
you know that's my blurb you know when
you have a physical book
on the covers usually they have a little
blurb you know you usually marketing you
know they tell you why you should read
this book you know what's the relevance
why should you know there are ten
thousand books why should you read this
one so so that's you know the technical
name for that little little chord that's
called blurb and that's literally you
know if i have article on the etymology
of blurb
you know literally that the technical
name for that book um you know on the
book cover that's called a blurb
uh and so i have a blurb for my
javascript tutorial and it's essential
you need that
you know because otherwise people come
to my page they don't know who i am you
know they just see javascript in depth
okay who is this you know why should you
know you don't you know so you need some
kind of introduction
so when people come to this page
if you have the you know this topic box
at the top that's irrelevant to this
page that's no good
okay so
okay at the bottom then
i'm already used to the bars on wikis
and they are at the bottom
on wikis which wiki okay let's move them
to the bottom okay let's do this
so now you can observe my workflow so
let's uh visuals okay so visual base
visual css go to the bottom
let's put it here so
okay close
yeah
close
what close
copy that again javascript in depth okay
that
okay put it here show in browser
now there's another question you know
should this
by javascript be on top of this or below
it
and you know so many design issues okay
but that's
you know for example this page
javascript object reference
um
[Music]
yeah so i'm not actually so
i'm not actually too sure about this
box but even because even on this page
is a little bit disorienting
disorientation
because people come here you know they
want javascript object reference
so if you don't have this box then
people will focus on the panel which is
the actual table of contents
you know you have
uh
starting from here so
but if you have the box you know people
look at
people think this is the main content
yeah so you yeah so
so this is uh on the whole this is this
is um
this is a major
problem about
navigation panels you know i've been
looking into this issue for the past 10
years
and never arrived at the satisfactory
point because if you go to other website
let me show you okay
let's go to let's see
if you go to some website for example a
javascript let's search for
okay
so you go to the mozilla's javascript
tutorial reference you know
you can see they also have a panel you
see they also have a panel here
and you if you go to a javascript
building
on
w3schools which is kind of idiotic um
website usually have wrong incorrect
information
uh let's magnify okay so
you can see they also have
a navigation panel
okay when you enlarge your new window
so
when you
lots of website you know also wikipedia
so basically you go to almost any
website
uh on programming languages usually they
have a side panel
and
if you look around
they are all
idiosyncratic there's no standard design
so they are diverse in many different
ways first of all the format is very
different between websites for example
in mozilla
you have
in this article you know they say in
this article then you have highlight in
this particular way
then you see you click on constructors
uh god they
you see
it's let's see instance methods
you see it's very confusing that i mean
the
so
each website their navigation panel
are all very different
and in
two aspects one is the formatting is all
very different
okay the other more important aspect is
that the semantics like how should the
navigation box
b i mean what is it supposed to be is it
for convenience of linking two different
places or is it a sort of table of
content or subsections to this page
or is it table of content to the whole
general book
so that's a different semantics so but
if you look around all the websites you
know on javascript on powershell you
know let's let's see powershell
get child item let me show you a
powershell one okay
you know when you when you don't have
the javascript they don't show the side
panel you see again it's very different
depending on the website
on w3school
if you don't have javascript
the panel shows okay on the mozilla if
you don't have javascript the panel also
shows you can see the panel the
navigation panel but on the for example
on the microsoft powershell
documentation
if you don't turn on javascript it
doesn't show panel but if you turn on
javascript which is
99.9 percent of people
then you see the
panel okay
so the design
of this navigation box
there's no standard and it's extremely
i'll tell you i'll emphasize this
extremely confusing
you know
so i have been thinking about designing
my my own website's side panel you know
i've been working on this for
for about
it began about 12 years ago 2008 also
and over the past 12 years
they went through several changes you
know for my javascript for my emacs
let's go to emacs
god what is this
and
view browser okay viewing browser you
can you can see my emacs blog
they don't have a panel on the site
you used to be like two years ago if you
watch my video you'll see a panel now i
removed it
so what i'm saying is that over the past
12 years
my site panel has went through
like every four years it went through
some change
but i was never satisfied with
with how it works
and i have spent
you know every each time i spent a week
almost like 30 hours full time 30 hours
to study all the different issues it
just cannot arrive at the satisfactory
design for the side panel
you see part of the reason is that the
side panel the side panel is kind of a
odd beast
you know because traditionally if you
read a book
if you have a book printed book the
first few pages are table of contents
okay
and at the end of the book is index
index bibliography
uh epilogue
um
several other things you know
but tip but the most two important thing
is at the beginning of the book you have
table of contents
which is a logic logical outline of the
content of your book okay and at the end
of the book is typically index which is
a bunch of keywords and which page they
are on
okay so table of contents and index and
these two are universal so when it comes
to a book
you know such as my javascript tutorial
or
you know any programming language
reference you know you can also try
python you know
uh
you have you know so when you have a
book
usually the two most important thing is
table of contents and index and these
are standard universal
but when it comes to web pages it
becomes a mess okay when it comes to for
example programming language reference
you are looking at powershell
you are looking at mozilla you know
javascript mozilla then you are looking
at w3 javascript
on you know on javascript tutorial or
reference or you're looking at
powershell
there's no standard way to do that
well one way you can do that is you
so let me show you a emacs okay emac
this
emac this reference menu okay
so let's try to html uh
one page per knot okay so this so you
are looking at the emacs um
lisp reference menu okay now the emacs
people are
old people so they follow
they follow the more traditional way
so now you are looking at table of
contents emac list and if you click on
one of them for example these data types
you see there's no side panel there's no
[ __ ] side panel
you see
and in this way it's very simple it's
very simple if you want to go to the
table of contents you go up
there you can overview of the table of
contents but if you are in a particular
section
then you have a subsection you know
table of contents for this section but
if you are in a particular page you see
there's no
side panel okay so this this is a
classic traditional design
the advantage is that it's very logical
simple simple and logical you can you
can kind of always
expect
you know you have
you have
um
predefined expectation you know you
you know you know where to find things
but however the disadvantage is that
there is no side no navigational panel
so that that means is sometimes
inconvenient
because each time you have to go up mini
buffer then go up again
then you see the
total of
table of contents
you know the way emac this is
laid out the design is that you know on
the table of content on the home page
you have table of contents of the main
chapters
then you have
then you have table of contents of each
sub sections
okay
you see then there's a lot so anyway
the home page is you know the entry
point for everything
very logical simple and classic design
but now if you are working on javascript
let's try javascript it's kind of
confusing each website is very different
and
the problem is that this um
let's stop this
the problem
the navigation panel is kind of
convenient but it's the problem is that
it's just
there's no
proper expectation you don't know what
they are until
you use this website for like several
days so for a week you know
then you you become familiar on this
particular website what the navigation
or panel is for you know are they just
table of contents or are they kind of
related topics to this page or are they
subsections
of a topic that this page is part of you
know
there's no way to know i mean each site
is different
so let's turn javascript and also the
javascript is the issue the
implementation of a particular design is
a very um it's a major issue because
javascript cannot do it actually
so um so let me let's go to uh objects
so
now i want to find booleans for example
java javascript links okay
so you can see
on w3school
the left panel is basically table of
contents okay
yeah so the on javascript school which
is not which is not a good javascript
reference at all usually it's incorrect
and you know they they cater to the
beginners to people who don't know what
programming they never done programming
before they don't know what's a variable
they don't you know they don't know any
they don't have the experience
so the w3 school is for those people
which is 90 90
of all people looking for javascript
so that's why they are super popular you
know they don't know things
in particular the rumors
so anyway for them the left panel is
table of contents now let's look at
mozilla now mozilla reference is more
advanced for the hacker types so if you
look at you know their boolean page
the left
panel is about
is basically
the technical detail
the the technical organization
of the boolean concept in javascript the
language
in other words in javascript language
a boolean is a object you know
and it has instance methods
you know then it has examples and it has
spec
very confusing you know so
we if you look at the w3 school you can
you know after we look at these four
four five minutes we can see
how it is organized you see
so javascript tutorial
then you have javascript versions then
javascript objects basically different
topics okay then you have just
javascript functions classes async
um
you know in javascript browser boom
javascript web apis you know this kind
of messy
very messy
because this way they organize things
it's not
it's not in some
hierarchy it's not in some standard
hierarchy it's rather just different
related things they put together so in
other words
the way w3 school designed their site
panel for the javascript at least
is that the side panel panel functions
kind of as a table of contents plus
convenience
so
in other words whoever looking at this
page
what they would be interested is likely
to appear on the side panel so for
example i'm looking at javascript
booleans then you might also jump to
uh
web apis which is not part of javascript
the language
then adjace which is kind of trick you
know kind of
several topics that's related to a
particular thing you need to do
then you have jason javascript json
which is actually part of javascript the
language
you know then you have javascript versus
jquery which is which is kind of essay
it's not a tutorial okay
it's just the opinion opinion piece
about different technologies you know
javascript then jquery is a library
you know not part of javascript language
not part of doom not part of browser
it's just a third-party library but very
popular
you know so you they also put javascript
versus jquery query and you know from a
logical point of view this is out of
place because all the others are mostly
about tutorials
but here javascript versus jquery is
kind of it's that's an essay that's
opinion
however
it is interested to those people looking
at javascript you know those people
especially beginners they would they
want to know they want to know what is
why should i use jquery or should you
use javascript
then you have javascript graphics you
know that's kind of funny because in
javascript language there's no graphics
okay so they they you see they list a
bunch of javascript
graphics libraries
you know then you have canvas which
which is part of dom
you know the part of standard javascript
you know
then javascript example so
in short
the way w3
school design their panel for javascript
is that the panel is kind of convenient
link table plug table of contents of
javascript the language
tutorial plus
anything
people might be interested
convenient jump place okay
now mozilla now let's now let's do a
analysis on the mozilla's side panel
design
first of all look they are very
different you know this is the the width
you know it's very different
um
there's a lot to talk about this but
anyway let's let's focus on the
semantics of the side panel so now we
look at the mozilla's
javascript side panel you see so when
you are on boolean page they show you
a description okay so this is
subsection of the boolean so you jump to
description section
then you have constructor section then
you have instance so are they on the
same page or not
that's another confusing point you see
okay so in this case they are on the
same page
so this
so in the mozilla side panel
at least the top view
they are jump points to the current page
they don't go to another page they are
just jump points to
sub sections of the current page
okay
then you have specification section yeah
order on the same page
okay then you have
see also section on the same page too
so in the c also section are kind of
related topics you might be interested
when you are reading about boolean okay
so okay so that's the top
so there it is that's why they say in
this article so you see formatting very
diverse things you see
you see their formatting so
in this article
so this
so on the side panel
a subsection of the set panel is about
in this article jump points to positions
in this page
then
um then you have related topics then
then these these boxes these boxes means
a function
you know they mean javascript object you
know very confusing
so
related topic topics standard building
objects okay
then methods then inheritance
what the [ __ ]
okay so okay so now i get it so
a boolean object
by the specification of javascript
language
by the hierarchy of javascript technical
detail
it is the standard building object of
the boolean word
and it has these methods
and
it has a parent
which is this function
you know the word function
then it has things called properties
okay
then they're very confusing you see
these
so on so on the second part
of the mozilla's
side panel
they named related topics
so on this section on this let me can i
select it so on this section
uh god i cannot even select it so you
see it's very the side panel is just in
general just so bad
i cannot even select it properly
so
in this section
these the way they are organized these
are
about the technical detail of javascript
language a hierarchy
of the boolean object
okay
all technical details you know
properties parents methods
the object name
then then the prototype properties you
know they don't they are not
they are not very clear okay
yeah so now we start to get into the
technical details of javascript you know
uh which is
very confusing as well because you have
the
you have parent and child relation
relationship
but you also have object and properties
relationship and these two relationships
forms their own hierarchy they are not
related at all
so let me say that again this is
important aspect of javascript okay let
me show you for example you'll see it
you know read my tutorial if okay if you
don't know javascript so in javascript
you have objects object
is is the main thing kind of you have a
sky of objects
you know
and each object has a parent
and child
relationship to other objects
not all objects has a parent but most
building ones do so you have a parent
and child relationship
so a parent is another object child is
some other object
um
right so so and and so so parent and
child forms a hierarchy forms a tree
okay of all the objects
but on the other hand
each object may have different several
properties
and the value of those properties is
again an object
okay so object may have properties and
properties themselves are objects and
those prob
those objects you know can have
properties again
so this
also forms a hierarchy
okay
but the parent child hierarchy and
object
properties hierarchy
they have nothing to do with each other
so
you have these very messy very
unintuitive
relations because at one time you think
of parent and child as like a tree
then sometimes you got confused you you
got deceived thinking about the the
properties and you know the object and
its
properties
so
now if we go back and look at
the mosita you can see some of that let
me explain okay let me
like let me explain to you about the
spooling object
ah
very complex you see this boolean
keyword
that's a object okay that's an object
that object what it does it's it's
actually a function
that it creates boolean objects okay
very confusing in other words it creates
objects who are
it creates objects
that are boolean instances
okay
uh
and you have methods okay now let me
explain what the [ __ ] is this
very confusing you see
you see it says
boolean.prototype.2 source okay what
does that mean that means boolean
has a property called prototype
okay so the boolean
thing the boolean keyword the boolean
you know literal expression
b-o-o-l-e-a-n
that is object okay that is actually a
function
now that object
has properties okay and one of the
properties name is called prototype okay
remember
parent child and object property there
are two different things okay so now we
are talking about property so boolean
is entity and it has a property called
prototype
and what is that that is object so you
have a prop you have object called
boolean.prototype
okay
the boolean thing has a property called
prototype okay and
what's the value of that thing that
thing is the object which we just call
pulling.prototype okay now that object
has a property called two source
okay
a string property
and that probably the value of that
property is again
a object and in this case it's a
function
so that's why they call it methods so
you you kind of get what i'm saying
so then you see okay so this section is
about properties you see
boolean methods and now they mention
inheritance now this is about
parent-child relationship okay so the
parent of the boolean object is this
object called function literal
expression f-u-n-c-t-i-o-n
okay and and that object
again has properties
ah god you know so the way this you know
this way you know this
mozilla
side panel is very very very confusing
it's not friendly to beginners like for
beginners
they they cannot figure this out after
five years and i'm telling you because
it took me several years and i still get
confused sometimes
for beginners this is completely
incomprehensible
but even for seasoned javascript
programmers let's say you code
javascript at google for three years
this is still confusing because the
because they do not clearly show
the two different type of hierarchies
okay one is parent-child relationship
the other is object property
relationship and these two has nothing
to do with each other
okay
besides these two kind of hierarchy you
can you can use
you know their relationship to to
organize your panel
there's another there's another for
example you can organize them
in a more practical sense
where you don't talk about parent-child
relationship and you don't talk about
object property relationship but rather
you talk about
you talk about methods and properties
okay so this this is actually more
practical
so you can see
they try to they try to
indicate that a little bit by saying by
having the title methods
and properties
so so the so in the mozilla
in the mozilla's you know side panel
the first section is about
jumping points to the current page then
the second section is very confusing
they try to you know there's some
some of the parent-child relationship
you can
see you know in in the in the
in the inheritance part
uh where is it what does it say there
so part of it is parent-child
relationship part of it is the object
and properties relationship
then
another part of it is the practical
issue of which is the methods which
which are the methods which are the
properties
like like
non-functional non-function properties
meaning values
so
do you guys know what i'm talking about
maybe i'm losing audience on this techno
technical javascript technical details i
don't know if i'm making sense to you
guys
because you really need to know
javascript in order to know what i'm
talking about and you need to know a lot
of um so yeah the mozilla so the
mozilla's
side panel to me is a complete failure
complete failure
because you can you
you have no good expectation of what
what's going on here
you know
not in a sense you know they don't have
a clear indication of the parent-child
relationship of the current page you are
reading and they don't have the good
you know
hierarchy of the object
and property relationship
it's kind of they mix them together you
know
a failure
so
okay so that completes my analysis of
the mozilla's side panel or complete
vodka
but for my experience you know i
of course i write my javascript tutorial
and i have referenced you know i have
read a lot of mozilla's you know
and i just never i almost never like
not even once
why
when i read the page on mozilla mozilla
i use the side panel to go to find
something else almost never
usually i just completely ignore it okay
so that's so in summary the
the situation of the side panel is a
major problem on all websites you know
there are 10
000 websites you can you know try them
yourself usually it's just too confusing
uh and uh
let me show you the microsoft powershell
uh side panel it's also very confusing
okay
now i cannot give you a analysis of it
without
without having to give you uh you know
to talk about the technical details of
the powershell
you know i have a powershell tutorial
you can just find it
just search for xally powershot
so anyway
on the microsoft
side panel for powershell it's also very
confusing basically they
again it's a mix of few things
so on one hand part of it is about
about
the technical hierarchy of powershell
the language organization like
powershell the language their concepts
you know certain things are
belong to certain libraries or core
libraries or you know different modules
you know so on one of that part of that
is that you know they you know part of
this site panel is about that
but part of it is about kind of
convenience link to to to to tutorials
for example learning powershell here and
install you know how do you install
powershell and overview
so part of it is that
very confusing okay then then then then
you have microsoft powershell security
that's kind of another component
component of powershell
so
yeah anyway
so in summary
in summary
the side panel the navigation panel
there's just no
there is no standard way to do the side
panel
so so far we have talked about the
the semantics issue of side panel what
should it be you know we we we talked
about the classic
table of topics way which is uh you know
of google emacs list
so site panel so there's no standard um
uh how do you say standard
semantics for side panels side panel
what they should be
other than just
normal table of contents
and the other issue i haven't started to
talk about is the
it's kind of the design i mean the
actual format
as you can see right now
each one is very different you know they
like each website is idiosyncratic
and also what happens if you click on
one of them
you see now let me show you one of the
very annoying thing
you see on microsoft powershell if i
click on link okay
so some some of the link will jump you
to it directly but there's a
there is a
like regeneration very annoying like
when i click on that you'll see it flash
okay you see you'll see the side panel
disappear for a second for half a second
and reappear
it's like disorienting
okay so if i click
some of the link some of the link if you
click on that it expand okay
so click on that now if i click on this
one it's gonna flash it's gonna
disappear and regenerate
very disorienting okay that's one of the
major problems across all sides
now let's try the
w3
w3 school i believe that also happens
yeah let's try
okay they did it uh they fixed it
okay let's see
yeah they you kind of see the flash you
see
basically when you jump to a different
topic the flash happens you see now i
click on that you see check
you see
it flashes you see
it flashes then
your your current cruiser position
becomes relocated i mean
you see that
you see we click on that
but that move moved
uh to somewhere else let me try again so
i'm gonna click on this
after i click you know i'm gonna click
this topic at uh ajax
xmlhttp okay
after i click on that
you know that link is it's gonna move to
somewhere else now
watch you see
it move to the bottom so that is very
annoying that that is a super annoying
thing
so that um
and let's go to mozilla let's see if
that happens on mozilla so let's click
on the function.link
you see it also happens
oh god
so that concludes i think that concludes
my discussion my analysis of the site
panel thing you know because i've been
i've been thinking about this
in the past 10 years every every three
years i spent
a week on this
and it's just so bad it's just so bad
so sometimes i have been thinking
you know just get rid of the side panel
at all you know on my website
on my website now let me show you let me
demo okay let me demo my website you see
they stick you see you don't get the
jump [ __ ]
okay
you see it doesn't matter where you
click
you know they they the topic sticks okay
no flash no minimum flash and no
javascript required okay you don't need
javascript
you don't need javascript okay but if
you don't have javascript you don't have
the highlight
yeah that's the problem
so
anyway so still this is not
very satisfactory to me so
sometimes i thought about just remove
the side panel
but that
that kind of introduced inconvenience
because
it's pretty it's really income
inconvenient every time you have to go
up you know to the table of contents
for example if you are you know reading
my javascript tutorial you can see how
to learn javascript
after you finish reading this you want
to know javascript basics you know right
here javascript basics
then you know after you read this you go
to the top you can click on operators
you know that's kind of the
logical next
uh thing you want to read
then true and false this is about
javascript booleans
uh and branch control
you know but
if you don't if i don't have the side
panel
what do you do you that means you go up
to one page then you list all the all
the topics you know
um
not convenient
so
so that almost that that concludes my
analysis my story about the side panel
design
but let me tell you one more thing okay
let's go to html
let's go to
frames
all this problem
all this problem was solved 20 years ago
okay let me show you
okay
the thing you are looking at is called
html friendset
it was
popular
in year 2000s okay
it it was popular throughout up to maybe
year
2010 until the html5 the html5 scrum
came up
it killed it
okay
html and google killed it google says
this is no good
the and all the web gurus you know the
design gurus they are hacker news you
see every day they tell you what to do
they tell you oh this is a new theme
this is new design oh this is flat new
metro design no flat new flat flat
design new dark theme good for your eyes
whatever crap they you know for the past
20 years the design gurus
they work at google they work at
facebook or you know twitter or you know
like they are the big guys they you know
they tell you what to do
they talk and and all the people
you guys idiot got convinced you know
happened for 20 years 20 years so
20 years ago
we have this technology called html
frames okay
and it works perfectly you see
i have a side panel i can control i can
adjust the size
you see
and i also i can also have a bottom
panel i can adjust the size
and i can
i can click uh to change you know
whichever topic i want to see
and you will not see flash
you know you will not see none that
okay and you can you you can also have
highlight okay so
so right now you are looking at my
my tutorial about html frame set okay
this is getting obsolete because they
you know and you can also nest it you
see let me show you this funny thing
um
and
how can i get out
oh yeah so you can click on that to get
up
so
this technology is there and it's widely
used too let me show you um
you know it's white widely used by
java okay let's see there it is okay
you know java is a giant language and
you can see you know java is a giant
language oop
object oriented language so you can see
they are using frames html frames you
know this is
20 years ago back in year 2000 1999 also
so you have frames you don't have the
jump problem so you see the
top panel allows you to choose
what second panel is gonna be you see
no flashing no jump you know an instant
okay and no no you don't require you
know no need javascript you see i have
javascript turned off
and the second panel allows you to
choose you know
a topic to show on the mainframe
okay
that's called html frames that's part of
html4 you know and it's widely used
then sometimes around 2005 the google
the google skin
they say oh fam is no good
because it [ __ ] up their search engine
okay that's what i don't i don't think
that's true but that's what they say and
they sold the idea to all the idiots or
the to the masses to the programmers
so every every web design guru you know
if you are in web
dev you know you will tell your friends
oh whenever people mention them you
you're going to tell them oh
frame is not good because blah blah blah
because oh it it's not you know it
violates some usability principle it
violates some disabled person principle
or something something like they they
always have reasons
you know
this web guru design
crap
so this technology
got killed
by html5 you know what's html5 html5
came from these people
uh basically uh the
opera browser and apple and then google
they killed it because they they want
push html in a direction
that benefits them which is which is
commercialization and search engines and
all the crap
so for example apple pushed for canvas
so that they can you know they they can
have have games on their phone
instead of instead of relying on the on
the flash you know on the adobe flash
technology the market media
so apple pushed their things and google
pushed their things so image so anyway
html5
killed
this frame technology from html4 because
html5
do not support it in html5 they say this
is obsolete
then all the idiots that you know the
hacker you know this propaganda you know
this giant basically that's the way is
um you know i'm getting old so that's
the way i started to to see things this
way
lots of things you know as a programmer
you know because i've been in the
industry for you know 20 or 30 years
depending on how you count
so lots of the things you follow
all the libraries other practice
are partly
to some significant degree
they are
what the
top people wanted you to
see
uh they they kind of
yeah
and the way they do that is be is by
massive you know you can call it
propaganda you know massive spread of
information you know they have money
they have resources they can put into
ads or
or to pay some writers to write about it
so
that's what you know that's what you
think is good so what you think is good
is very questionable and one of the
latest thing is that
for the past five years is that people
google has been pushing https
and lots of you guys are asking me every
day hey exa why don't you have https oh
my god why is your web page not secure
which is a criminal you know it's a
google is doing that why they want to do
that so that so that they can have
control
they can have control like centralized
so that
it's already almost you know very much
centralized you know like today you have
google
facebook twitter amazon ebay paypal you
know the whole webs you know i talked
about this many times you know the
entire internet is basically like 10 20
major websites people visit
all the rest people don't visit
so centralized so why google is pushing
https so they can centralize
they can control then they can say which
website they support you know if you are
follow you know if you
uh no more people they let you live okay
if you are like me you know you say if
you you have opinions that they do not
approve
they kick you out like my website like
my website right now
for example saudi.org
okay it's not too big here you see you
see that lock sign with the cross on the
phone you you just say
this website is unsafe or unsecured
something like that
okay that's so that's that's
you know and to the vast majority of
people they have no idea what https
means
they just know all they know is that oh
this website is not safe oh my god i'm
not going to use this site anymore
so that's the way
google drive
control information
so
so for me
you know so so i can so what i have to
do
is i either pay you know fifty dollars
to get a cert
or there's a free cert organization you
know
you know you guys love it free software
open source
free cert
but who pays the free search you know
i haven't looked into but yeah
the answer is not good okay
okay that's it for me i think that's it
for today i talked for
close to two hours
so anything else anything
you guys have to say so i kind of
rambled for an hour on the web
panel design
uh
okay
and so that becomes the main topic of
today website panel design
and actually i have quite a lot of other
things i need to do
which i haven't done yet i was going to
show you
okay
another day then
okay so we shut down in
five minutes
any comments
okay so here is another thing
bye nugu nugu naga
you
so now this is done
uh there's no delete key there's no
delete key on this keyboard
you know in order to press delete you
have to press function
function
yeah function m
you see so that's why i don't like 60
keyboards
and in this application open view you
have to
you need a dd key to delete the image
i'm not sure there's a different
uh
key binding
it's a edd file of course you you might
create a key binding but it's
a problem so
okay
con function and n for dd okay
so that's another thing i need to do
sync emacs package okay
back to emacs um
not here
go to
excite to do
sync
and
delete that okay that is done
function
m to delete
then okay delete that
those are my notes kind of
and mozilla screenshot okay so
yeah this this article is about
uh user interface design
yeah another user into his design so let
me show you
mozilla button yeah let's do a
screenshot okay
so let me show you what that page is
so you go to
xrd.info then you scroll down
then you go to
css sucks
so this section is all about user
interface design
then you go to
[Music]
mozilla okay firefox one of the most
idiotic in the past 10 years
they
they become worse and worse
in general following the industry
was in was user design and remember look
at this skeleton screen
this you you probably have seen this
it began around
2018 okay
uh so what i want to
now let's yeah let's go to mozilla web
design so
the page i want to
do is
uh ui design pip show windows great text
on white background idiotic skeleton
screen the most idiotic
disappearing button ui so here so
mozilla the firefox around 2012
10 years ago
you know they disappeared the back
button like
when the back button is not available
they disappeared
so that when you browse the web you know
you you'll see your user interface
jiggles around
that's a
so let me uh so
so i wrote article about that so this is
a very bad user interface design when
you have a user interface a control
panel for example knobs you know control
panel you don't want the user interface
element to jump about every time you do
things or scroll you know your buttons
change position you don't want that okay
so firefox did this you know in 2012
you know what extreme idiot you know
back so back then i looked into you know
uh in around 2012 there are still blog
writers you know today become blog
writers disappeared almost entirely
except me you know a few people you know
mostly you read twitter and facebook you
know the propaganda information
they made it that way you know you you
don't know if you are a male engine or
zuma you don't know but they made it
this way so you grew up that way
you know 10 years ago there are people
who write blogs which you know a lot of
people you know so actually you have
different point of view
independent point of view but it's good
so anyway in 2012 mozilla they have guy
they have design gurus they tell you
what to do you know they they explain
oh why you know why why this is a great
design kind of kind of you know
and they came up with this
i remember because i
you know during that time i read you
know these gurus you know on hacker news
you know every time they post to hack
and you're so reddit you know you'll see
a lot of people following them
so i look at you at what they say um
and up so apparently they are you know
they they they have status you know
among the programmers or design design
community they
you know they are
they are somewhat famous you know and
they tell you and
apparently the guy works at mozilla they
tell you you know the design and it
should be this or that way
but it's it's really it's the it's the
worst you know so this is one example
skeleton screen is another example i
don't know how
i don't know the exact origin of
skeleton screen
i think it's from
let's see
yeah they you know one of these gurus
see
duke w i you know hold on a second let
me read i don't want to be mistaken so
you have this duke
guaboski guy
luke w is an internationally recognized
digital product leader digital product
leader yeah
that word is popular about 10 years ago
digital product leader who has designed
and built software used by billions of
people worldwide duke is currently your
product director at google earlier he
was a ceo and so on okay
now
who you know i want yeah origin okay
yeah
so this is my story you know
where does this
[ __ ] scum idiotic user inter
interface
practice came from
like i said before it it came from
design gurus okay like big name design
groups and groups here's an example
you see the origin of the skeleton
screen
is from this guy
duke w [ __ ] okay i'm gonna i'm going to
tell you right now this guy is an idiot
you know he he worked at google you know
how can he be an idiot if he worked at
google you know and all the big you know
design used by billions of people
um
you know i don't know this guy in detail
i yeah all i know is about
is is
on this page
but you should but what happens is that
in these giant corporations especially
in the past 10
years
what makes you
a leader or you know your you you become
a manager higher and higher rank
you know
is um
basically you follow orders you play the
game you climb the ladder you climb the
ladder in a corporate uh
environment so you have to be nice to
people
you
you know you you you have to have
good social skill
and not offensive you know don't talk
about things
religion or politics
uh
you know you
keep to yourself you know you you just
be a community player
and
but always but make sure you always
focus on your own interests and benefits
so you know it's like political
situation you establish friendship you
know and also it's important you know
you have to know
which person is important you know you
don't want to make friends with idiots
okay with people hacker types who never
get anywhere
like many of you like us okay most of us
you want to make friends who are you can
see they are going up
so
that's what i think what happens
so all the managers you know
it wasn't like that
uh 10 years ago at google but
google become
highly corrupt
so that's a game you play you know you
play the power game to climb
uh and you know
he came up with these incredible you
know
he he is just one of the example
benchmark capital the chief design
architect at yahoo
lead user interface designer at ebay and
the senior interface designer and the
ncsa
the birthplace of the first popular
graphics browser
so why is he creating this skeleton
screen
this is very bad
you know
you don't get to see what is there
and slower in general
okay so
so the reason he says is that
conventional reason tells us that when
things are going to take a while we
should let people know in most mobile
applications that translates to adding
proper spots or spinners when something
is happening or loading while the
intentions behind these progress
indications indicators are good the end
result can actually turn out to be bad
no con so what's the point what's the
point
it can be bad because the progress
indicators by definition
called attention to the fact that
someone needs to wait
it's like watching the clock tick down
when you do time seems to go slower
we learned this lesson the hard way on
polar
when we experimented with using web
viewers to load parts of your native
applications interface
it's you know what he says is hard to
read you know long sentences
what's your point
webviews
are like little embedded web browsers
that can fetch pages from a server and
prevent
present them within the app but only
after they are loaded
okay he's talking about the spinners
he's saying that spinners should be
avoided
but
but where did he say about
the skeleton screen okay probably maybe
it's on with his website
so where does he introduce skeleton
screen
okay there
with skeleton screen the focus is on
content being loaded not the fact
that it's loading and
and that's real progress
yeah so
according to him
the reason he introduced
you know the skeleton screen
is that instead of seeing some kind of
spinner
to indicate the page is loading
he says
don't show the spinner but instead show
the skin
shoulders shoulder skeleton like
instead
which is [ __ ] the most [ __ ]
idiotic [ __ ]
because you know i don't know
you know because
right now
most websites for example youtube
when you have this skeleton it's
actually slower
you know
i don't feel
you know it before the skeleton it was
faster i i feel faster or it probably
measured faster that for sure
but with a skeleton screen they they
they it becomes slower and feel slower
like normally you would see the text
already but now you are seeing these
gray boxes [ __ ] what the [ __ ] [ __ ]
up
you know i'm rambling over today i'm
thinking of just deleting the video
so there are still nine people watching
me
um
okay so anyway i probably need to
add a screenshot about
okay bye guys
i um i want to say
so the skeleton screen is one of the
example quite a few other examples
the other giant examples is
the grey text on white background you
know this happened earlier
this happened around
great text on background
then it became pervasive everywhere
where it becomes very hard to read
text on background
then skeleton screen around 2018
skeleton
uh screen
uh
and other things okay then disappearing
buttons okay
okay bye