good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound talk show
so today we are going to do geometric
inversion ufm
language coding and uh
and lots of fun stuff okay basically
centered around around the mathematics
geometric inversion you are looking at
some of the fantastic images of
geometric inversion and i'm going to uh
do some live coding and teach you oofam
language how do you do that
and wufang language is free by the way
so uh you you can download it just
search for wufam language free i'm gonna
show you my links okay uh and also so
you are looking at some of the images
fantastic beautiful images of geometric
inversion okay the the uh
the concept of geometric inversion and
also works in 3d so
and also okay so today and you are also
looking at my keyboard so i got a new
camera so let me show you uh the new
camera okay so you
uh
so i bought a new camera because the
logitech
so now i have two you can see my
keyboard i'm gonna work on it and you
can see how i operate the most efficient
way to operate
with emacs stuff like keys and keyboard
markers with the ultimate hacking
keyboard and kinesis advantage two
keyboard red switches red switches okay
you want linear light switches if you
already have
repetitive straight injury hand pain
okay and today is
2021 october 1st
okay so anyway so i i bought a new
camera because so right now i'm using
this one logitech c920 okay uh something
like 70
then i bought a cheap uh china cheapo
okay this one fantastic only forty
dollars
and uh
so the china cheaper you are you are
seeing is this one
well it's it's it's pointing at my
keyboard
and so i have a review here so you can
see uh i explained that you know what's
good or what's bad okay so i i would
recommend the china cheaper 30 dollars
cheaper than logitech okay so just
search for go to my xrd keyboard blog
and you know search for this your
logitech c 920 versus cheap webcam
you'll find my review
okay so that's about webcam i bought
and that's about the keyboard
uh and let's do shall we start to do uh
geometric inversion okay so let's see
what topic let's look at my notes
show graphics so i showed you some
images of geometric inversion the web
camera and okay so let's begin
to talk about
what is geometric inversion okay so if
you have questions comments posted okay
i'd love to see your comments and
questions hi guys
hi people of the world
okay so geometric inversion it's pretty
simple concept okay so we are we are
getting into math now uh so you can see
so so listen carefully okay geometric
inversion basically is a function okay
it's a function
that takes in a vector or point in the
plane or in three-dimensional it works
in any dimension okay so
geometric inversion is a function okay
it's a function
the argument is a vector okay
two-dimensional vector three-dimensional
four-dimensional whatever it's basically
a sequence of real numbers
okay uh that's the input that's the
argument to the function a point okay
let's let's let's just talk about in the
two-dimensional case so a vector to
d-vector okay
the output is another 2d vector so it's
so it's a function that takes a vector
and output a vector okay
oops
so this uh
let's see my
my keyboard shaking
so
so a function okay so now let me show
you so how is this function defined let
me explain okay so
so given the function
given a point p
remember it's a function that returns a
new point a new vector okay so given the
point p
it returns another q
but how is it defined well
it's defined this way okay you draw a
line from the origin from the center of
the coordinate to the point p
so you have a distance from o to p
always origin so o2p is the distance
so the q is another vector that lies on
the same line from o to p
but the distance of oq
times the distance of all p is equals to
uh the radius of inversion basically one
okay so
okay let me explain
so to define inversion you you you need
a circle okay let's say the circle at
origin
of radius r okay
so
so given point p
you want to find that it returns a point
q such that
q is
q lies on the same line from op okay the
op ray q lies on the same line as op but
however but then where is q then where
is q well q
q is such that the distance
of o times p the distance of o p
times the distance of oq equals to the
radius of the circle
okay that's a you know you can go to
wikipedia just look for geometric
version you'll you'll find actually go
to my website okay so
uh go to
go to visual dictionary of special claim
curves so that's my website that's my
most popular website linked by thousands
of universities math departments
uh starting from
late 1990s
so you go to uh
you know visual dictionary of special
plan curves then you just go to
inversion okay so there's an inversion
invert envelope evolute uh roulette uh
geometric inversion okay it's called by
the way it's called geometric inversion
not just inversion because inversion
means quite a quite a lot of things but
essentially the geometric inversion
okay we already gave you the definition
so you can read the details here
and i also want to tell you so so we
gave you the definition of the geometric
inversion so but what is essence what
what what does it i mean why do you need
this function
essentially it's a this geometric
inversion kind of defines multiplication
so you you could say
in a way
it defines multiplication
another way to characterize it is that
it's a function that
that swaps
let me see if i have a good picture
somewhere here okay so let's see it's a
function
that swaps any point outside of a circle
to inside of the circle okay so let me
see if i have a a good image to
illustrate that
uh
beautiful you know geometric inversion
is beautiful theory i mean i mean
beautiful of a very beautiful process
okay
and it's related to complex functions
okay so
okay we are getting um
a bit digression it's related to
complete
complex functions so let me see let me
show you um what let's see where
so you have geometric inversion now
where's the
gallery of geometric inversions okay so
uh where's my galleries
um okay so anyway so
somewhere linked you know you can find
so here you are looking at all the
geometric inversions so for example this
picture
this picture is a geometric inversion of
seven circles
nested inversion okay so you begin with
you know one two three four five six
seven seven circles then you invert
each circle
with respect to each of the circles and
you do that two two or three times
nesting okay so you got this picture
beautiful
and this this image for example you
begin with a bunch of circles arranged
like that configuration like that and
you got
and you invert them with respect to each
of the circle then you got that so now
let me get back so now i hope you will
learn you will understand fully after
watching this video what geometric
inversion means okay so let me emphasize
a few things
geometric inversion is a function
given a point
in a plane or in 3d space or in
n-dimensional space given a point it
will return a new point okay that's it
that's it it's just just a function that
takes a vector returns a vector
and now
but so what we mean so so when you see
these
how does that work you know
so because each point
uh okay so here is you know this fancy
graphics is is uh
more complicated okay so let me
uh perhaps we should uh focus on you
know just remember it's a it's a vector
it's a function that takes a vector
returns a vector and it's defined
um based on a circle of radius one okay
so what it does essentially is that
it swaps any point outside of the circle
to the inside of the circle and any
point inside us
of the circle becomes goes outside of
the circle okay and points on the circle
of radius one remains on the circle they
don't change okay so those are fixed
point uh in mathematical jargon
so so that's how you do geometric
inversion i mean that's a function of a
point returning a point so what but but
how do you get the graphics like that
okay so let me explain in basic detail i
mean for those of you who are not too
familiar with math okay so
so here what what you are looking at
okay let's go back okay so let's go look
at this image okay so here you are
seeing a grid okay
and
after applying the geometric inversion
function it becomes that okay so how
does that work well
you see a grid is a lot of points you
know it's made made of lines and so you
can see that each point on the line
okay for example the corner point over
here so you
you you apply the function geometric
inversion to that point and you get a
new point okay for that for that point
in the corner and you do the same thing
for every point in the line for every
point on the grid then you get these
okay so that's
geometric inversion of a 2d grid that
looks like that
does that make sense do i make sense
i hope you understand okay so and i hope
i'm not you know being repetitive
repetitive okay so in this case so here
we apply geometric
uh inversion to a you know a grid lines
of grid
now
in this case we apply a geometric
inversion to
a bunch of squares oh by the way let me
also mention when we apply the geometric
inversion here
we actually do not apply to every point
on the line rather we just apply to the
grid points so
so like we apply here here here here
here
and same thing you know here here here
the grid points
so once we do that we connect the points
like how they are connected before then
we got that
now now if you do not if you apply the
geometric inversion to
entire points on the line what you get
is bunch of circles because by by a
theorem geometric inversion
any straight line becomes circles any
any circle becomes a line or circles
okay that's that's a theory
that's one of the theorem in geometry
inversion
so on this page you can see the full
explanation and i hope you go there and
study it so we are you know learning
mathematics
so okay so
now i want to show you demonstrate some
wolfram language code okay so we explain
how this image you know what this image
is so in this case we have a bunch of
squares
laid out on a grid and we apply the
geometric inversion to each corner the
vertices of the
of the squares
then what you get is this beautiful you
know this fascinating this decor you
know decorative uh mathematical patterns
so okay so so here we and we do the same
now they look you know there's a signifi
this kind of a visual impact how they
are different because this one you start
with a square in the middle
then you get that
and this one you don't have a square in
the middle and you get that
you know they are exactly the same thing
geometric version but the the outcome
the visual impact is slightly different
okay am i am i good
uh let's see video check audio check it
so let's
remove that and
okay so let's
continue
so next i want to show you so here is a
geometric inversion of a square grid
then here
this is spectacular now this is a
geometric inversion same thing like that
something like that except instead of
squares you have n gongs regular
polygons you know you have hexagons you
can be triangle hexagon
heptagon
seven-sided
regular polyhedron
or
octagon
or and so on and pentagon you know nice
sided so
okay i'm going to show you so here's a
code this is a wufam language code
then here is a spectacular you know you
do the same thing like the first one
like this one but is but now you make it
into 3d so you have kind of a tie out uh
you know like pavement like nice garden
pavement
pattern
uh and here and and and you know you see
so geometric inversion remember
it's based on a circle any point outside
the circle
becomes inside and inside
goes to outside
so that means when you have a plane you
know you have lots lots of points out of
outside of circle they become congested
in the middle you see
they they all have this pattern they
become infinitely small in the middle
so but that doesn't work well if you
want a you know
tires you know garden pavement tiles so
is there some way to make them to to you
know to have this beautiful pattern but
without the congestion in the middle
well yeah we can do that i tried to do
that so
this here is a result
uh so what you do is you
start the grid you know remember we
start with the rectangular grid
now
you move the grid points apart further
apart
by using geometric inversion again
and also the the size of each square
will also be different depending on how
far
they are from the engine
so you begin so basically you begin with
this pattern you know not
you know not just a rectangular grid
but you begin with uh you know this
pattern then after applying geometric
inversion you get this one so this one
so now we have a tiled version
okay and there's also a 3d case we did
like a month ago so here's a
three-dimensional case of geometric
inversion fantastic beautiful
now let's do some wufang language coding
okay so
let me show you
comments guys comments okay
so uh
so let's go to let's look at uh let's do
some movement language coding okay
so we expand geometric inversion and
let's okay so copy the code
go to firm language
select all paste it evaluate so you can
see
so there it is okay so let's show some
other you know some more um
copy it
go to frame language code select or
paste
uh actually undo let's do a new one at
bottom do it
okay you can see
then you can also uh magnify it
okay
so let's do
okay so now this one is interesting so
because there are so many variations
this is a regular polyhedron so let's do
some experiment on that
uh let's uh okay so let's
and i'm going to explain the code okay
i'm going to explain
uh the code so but
so you see so let me actually show let
me show you the um
let's make them
you know rendered as uh you know
as mathematics so this is woofam code
you can you know it's fantastic gruffan
language is mathematical feature so you
can have you know you can have this
uh kind of um
typeset you know math mathematics you
know on the flag as you type
so no no no more you know the the
typical industrial programmers you know
including these coders python you know
they they
they want to argue and idioms and coding
styles about when to press the tab you
know when should you have a tab and
whether it should be space or tab or
whether how you code formatting you know
idiocy here you are seeing
automated
uh formatting on the fly
you see for example let me let me for
example this line you know it's a long
line but if your window is small
you know it automatically become you
know it's it's it doesn't fly off the
window you know like typical programmers
you know that you know
like in emacs field field region that
idiocy
you see so you are you are looking at
the automatic you know formatting okay
on the fly and not just that also
mathematical type setting
okay so anyway that's a bit digression
so you are looking at so let me let's
modify the code okay so let's see the
polygon
so let's change the polygon to uh
polygon number of sides okay so actually
you cannot see that so let me change
that polygon number of side four okay
evaluated
so you got that okay
um
okay so now let's try a polygon number
let's let's magnify this so that
and
let's make it smaller
and let's
remove this image okay so let's remove
so
let's do that okay let me show you
do that okay so let's also remove that
one
okay so we can see the graph directly
below
so now let's magnify a bit okay
now let's change the
polygon radius okay polygon radius
polygon radius
0.5 so so that they don't overlap
so you see now we got little squares
they don't overlap now let's
polygon number of sides let's make it
five pentagon
so you see pentagon
now let's say make it six hexagon okay
now
the side let's make the side larger so
it's more interesting so
uh
three okay let's see
so they overlap
okay so it's not
this one is not so aesthetic
okay so
so anyway so you see this one start you
begin with this pattern and after you
apply geometry inversion you get that
okay
so let's see
how long have i been talking um let's
see maybe i should uh move on to
10 okay we already talked for 30 minutes
okay so let's do the tiled version one
okay so
copy it make it smaller go here
and
paste it
okay so
here you got it okay so
then
then you can rotate the thing
okay so now
now this one okay now
this one is fascinating so but let's
copy let's use this code so it's uh
fancy
so let me show you this code okay let me
show you in uh let me also mention
from
emacs wolf mod okay let's see let's let
me show you
so um yeah let's start to do some typing
so 3d
tile
okay so here is my html mod magnify okay
so you can see here's the image of that
this
this section correspond to this you see
on the right
so here is the code
okay this section
corresponds to the wolfram code here so
but
let's make it let's um
do a backup
and let's
put it out onto a new buffer so here's
the wolfram language code and you can
see it's using saufa mod so let me show
you okay
describe key then press the key to go to
kasa wu friend mod documentation so you
are looking at the documentation of
wolfram mod okay so actually
um
let me turn on this okay so you can see
so let's go to the uh the source code
so here's the source code i just wrote
this about two months beginning two
months ago so it's fantastic so if you
are a wufang language coder so the you
know there's lots of uh
you know here are the building functions
of buffer language lots of code so if
you have language uh
user and also an emacs user you might uh
try my code and buy it okay so just go
to paypal send me money and buy it okay
so let me show you
you know i will find mod
okay so here so so that's the emac these
you know so then but but let's let me
show you how this works okay so here is
a code
uh this is how the code looks like
so what we want to do uh yeah okay copy
the code
so you know one of the interesting thing
you can see is that um
you know how the code looks like
in a typical you know like emacs editor
and how it looks like for example let's
copy okay copy and paste it here okay so
and and then let's make it
uh typeset okay so you can see it's much
easier it's it's much more readable when
you have two-dimensional typeset uh code
okay now evaluate it so you can see
so here we got what we want
and magnify and you again you can rotate
it
uh
and
you know
so
so you can see here is how wufam
language um
renders the code and also you can see
syntax coloring very interesting choice
you know there are so many schemes for
syntax coloring the question is
how you know should you how do you color
a programming language code
for example in emacs because i will find
mod i'm coloring all the building
function names blue okay
so that's how
how i do it but in language they color
basically essentially they color just
the local variables and this is
fantastic this is actually
i believe this is the most useful color
the local variables okay
but this this is not it's not easy to do
in uh you know in for example in emacs
because you need syntactical you need
syntax analysis you cannot just do it by
uh text processing methods or regular
expression you actually need to know
the grammar of the you know not just
grammar not just the syntactical grammar
you need to know the
the semantics of the language you need a
pasta for the language
not just the pasta you need act you know
you know you need you need to know the
semantics of the language in order to
color
the color just the variable names okay
so that's how woof and language does it
they color the variable names
i think i believe that's the most useful
so but also you can see how much
readable you know is when when you have
this you know rendered in 2d um
typeset
so anyway so in my in
uh but however the
flaw
with the mathematica notebook is that
it's hard to edit you know because
let me let me let me show you okay so so
for example for example i want to
comment out something okay so let's
comment out
uh
it's coming out this one okay so
comment down that one copy it okay
paste it
evaluate
so you see we don't see that so in order
to comment out all i have to do is press
a key you look at the
pink window you'll see the command
name and the key i pressed you see i
just i just press the key
semicolon and it calls common dream do
do what i mean and and it command out
this code you see i can do it again do
it again do it again so if i want to
comment out a whole bunch of lines i can
just press that okay
but in wufang language you
you know
it's um
plus uh plus four too common
you know it's not as easy i don't even i
don't remember what's the key to comment
but anyway you'll find you know i
believe there's a key
to comment out code but then
you have to select the code first okay
so actually so let's look for it
uh
uncommon selection yeah you see
so you do that it just comment the
current word
you know so you have to select the
expression first
then
old slash is uncommon selection okay
but by the way oh slash that's based on
wait am i missing never mind okay
yeah so to edit code in languages is
that's a flow i would like i would say
so i much prefer working emacs that's
why i created the wolfram language mod
okay so what do i want to do next so we
showed that so um
so let's see
so the 3d case we don't want to so okay
what's next
comments
no comments okay what's what's next
let's do some
live coding of
some new things with geometric inversion
okay
can we do that uh
yeah so basically i think we are do we
are done today
uh we talked for 36 minutes i think we
are done probably maybe
we can do some live coding of language
or
uh let me let me let me think okay what
we want to do
uh
beautiful thank you
i aspen sentry
okay so what's next what do you think
aspen um should we should we do some
live coding
of wufam language or
any
or do you
it does just do i make sense about
geometry inversion let's see what i want
what else we gonna do
okay so if you want if you like what i
you know if you like
language you know they they sponsored me
they gave me a free copy
um
language
so you i you know because i've been
coding wufang language for 10 years in
1990s you know it's a it's basically the
first language i mastered thoroughly
i coded every day for several hours a
day for over 10 years
and i you know and i did several videos
on ufam language before you should watch
just go to you know sari wufam language
search for it
uh and
and uh yeah so
if you like to use it of course it costs
you two thousand dollars if you if you
want the you know certified version you
know if if you are a
employee at nasa
or if you are you know google
corporation you know it costs you ten
thousand dollars ten twenty two thousand
dollars something three thousand dollars
but if you are a student it's like 200
uh 250 something or you can get it free
if you buy a raspberry pi
uh you know 70
you get it free it's bundled or you can
download free
wolfram engine or wolfram script is you
know it's free
for personal use
so i highly recommend it it's the most
of that is the most advanced uh language
by far it's a magnitude beyond you know
i talked about you know for an hour
about why i think so and
and and you have you have seen
some of the features that that you and
you will not see anywhere else
you know for example you know i want to
typeset this code okay i press the
button
you got you know you got these two
dimensional fractions and also square
root you see
now in tech typically the unix people
you know the
unix people attack you
you know it's city
in
super city
okay so i'm i think i'm done for today
um
do i have any kinesis keyboard okay the
question is about keyboard any new
developments in the keyboard space
yeah okay maybe let's you know maybe i'm
you know i'm hoping
possibly i'll do some
wolfram language coding but let's talk
about keyboard for a while
any new developments in a keyboard space
my comments is
kibo is just like yours it's not tactile
which i don't like
uh what do you mean
do you have all the other kinesis yes
the tactile ones
okay let me let me explain let me answer
okay
so kinesis keyboard you are looking at
fantastic okay yeah you know look at how
i operate you know i talked about speech
efficiency you know i'm a keyboard nerds
i study the keyboard layout let's go to
keyboard block okay so you can see all
the things you want to know about
keyboard so here's ergonomic keyboards
so i highly recommend kinesis that's
what i'm using right now and also the
ultimate hacking keyboard you can see
reviews my reviews my video reviews and
every detail
okay so happy hacking keyboard
i also like it's the best for marco key
marco if you want the most
the best key marker system for example
let me show you the
let me show you okay so ultimate hacking
keyboard
so you can see my current configuration
for my keyboard markup this is fantastic
okay so this is my keep keyboard markers
okay switch to last window this is one
of the most frequently used commands
switch to last window okay or you can
switch to um
wait here
okay you can switch to previous window
next window
okay one key press okay i don't know if
you can you see it okay wait
you know one of the annoying thing about
window is that it doesn't
show
windows that you've hidden for example i
want to go to obs it doesn't show
because i
minified it idiotic
rather i prefer if you just cycle
through windows it just should turn up
every window so you can see so yeah
checking if i can see myself you see
just single key press okay
um
so anyway ultimate hacking keyboard is
the most
powerful and easy to program with a
visual you know software
that allows you you know for example i
want to shrink window i do this often
you see
usually
uh you know press one key okay i don't
want this uh
so you know press one key
you know and if i'm a browser you know
much of uh macros here is designed for
browsers okay because browser is what i
use the most browsers and emacs in emacs
i've got soft flag keys as you already
know
uh and in browser and also see how i
switch window there's no key press see
typically you know the typical
programmers you know they they what they
do is alt tab okay
not now here's all here's tab okay so
here you see this is what people usually
do
so for example i want to switch to
chrome
um you know let's say i want to switch
to obs okay so you do this okay oh oh
where's obs which one oh i i overshoot
it okay shift
oh wait actually obs is this one okay
that's idiocy
okay you know so
so the
so i don't do that okay so first of all
you should turn on
um
hoover who will activate windows so
why so i hope you can see it yeah you
can see it in my mouse you see who will
activate window you know you i don't
have to because i type so much i have
rsi right now like over here okay
like i i don't feel so good right now
because i typed too much you you can
imagine
so
why should you use
mouse hoover click because
you know it doesn't you know even press
a single key that
if you have hand pan rsi you have hand
injury the idea of pressing a single key
that's painful okay you don't want to
you don't want to press any key the best
is that the best thing to do is that you
just think what you want to do and you
know things do it themselves okay
so hoover to activate window is one of
this one of the steps okay
so in my videos in the past two to three
years you you you'll not see me do oh
tab you you have you ever seen this you
didn't never see it because
it's either hoover
or if it's a last window i just press
that key okay because
when you switch windows by statistics
the most of the time what you want you
are doing is switch to the last
application okay so that key
okay most of the time
so
okay so that's uh so that's some tips
so if you want to know uh so in browser
i let's go back to my keyboard do i
still have it here somewhere
okay no
so go to emax press the key again you
see close the window go back to emacs i
want to launch this in browser so press
the key you see
keyboard log
then
then i um let me explain hoover window
okay i i explained this many times so
here
some keyboard blog is every aspect you
want to know about efficiency in using a
computer keyboard including what's the
best keyboard ergonomic keyboards
or
do-it-yourself ergonomic keyboards
there's so many varieties okay
or
no more keyboards no more keyboard
generally if you do not touch type and
this is your thing okay
which is fine okay touch typing is kind
of you have to spend a month or two to
learn
and
it's a good thing okay but
depending on how you know what's your
need if you are a programmer maybe you
don't need to learn such type but if you
know there are a lot of programmers who
say oh touch type is not important touch
type will get you hand paint
that's educ okay touch type is very good
but it's true
that touch typos we are more likely to
develop the repetitive strain injury
why not because the technique well
simply because when you actually learned
touch type then you will type a lot more
okay like when you code
if you don't know touch type you you
know you you you have some kind of
method of you know
idiotic you know uh hunting pick which
gets you about 50 words per minute okay
but once you learn touch type you will
start to write documentations for your
for your for your programming you know
you will start to for example in my code
everywhere i have documentation detailed
documentation for every command i ever
write okay so
uh you know
complete documentation with links and
all that
now this if you do not touch type you
will not do this okay you you just put a
few words okay that's a that's a problem
with not knowing touch type
you you you feel you are doing great but
actually once you know touch type you
will start to type a lot so but
if you touch if you type a lot then
you're likely you'll have higher chances
of getting rsi okay so touch typing
that's about touch typing
so let me show you yeah so i have here
so let me show you back let's go back to
the um hoover
so i have for example i have articles on
all the things you want to know about
typing typing habit how do you measure
typing speed how do you learn
and what's the proper you know ergonomic
sitting posture you know and pronation
is keyboard tenting important things
like that so here this section is about
typing and about the hoover took click
is over here okay so hoover two click
uh let's see
keyboard shortcut mouse uh
hoover to click uh trackball uh keyboard
shortcut okay it's over here so for
example on windows you click here it's
all you everything you need to know
about windows keyboard shortcuts and
whatever software so some software you i
highly recommend is
microsoft power toys okay
and also autohotkey i have a tutorial
here
uh a detailed tutorial including key
syntax
uh disabled keycaps
many of the frequently needed things
okay the how do you do that in auto
hotkey and also uh useful scripts okay
so anyway so go back so that's this this
is about windows now let me show you
about
uh
mouse hoover to activate windows so here
on this page i show you how to do how to
activate that okay on windows and also
on the mac
uh so on the mac
this is what you want hoover mouse auto
click
mac doesn't have
who you know who were to active activate
window but however it has hoover click
which is similar
but except it will also do a click
it will do a click whenever your mouse
stops moving so on the mac i use this
also fantastic
and on linux okay on linux you also have
them okay so you you have what you know
linux called hoover to raise window okay
so
here's how you set up in you know
depending on which window manager you
use so i have an example for open box
which is lxd and example for uh
xfce uh you can also do it in gnome or
whatever
okay so you have hoover click i mean
hoover to raise window to act not just
you know to raise window okay not just
focus you want race okay focus is
idiotic you want to raise the window and
on linux you have the another thing
is hoover mouse click
so anyway go read my articles i'll i'll
tell you the details okay so
so that's uh here so you everything you
want to know on linux about key binding
how to do them okay and on the mac you
know what tools to use everything you
want to know is here
uh and of course emacs emacs everything
you want to know about emacs keys how to
define a key
uh let's turn on javascript so we have
we have the that
you have key syntax major mod keys minor
marquees how do you uh how do you
change major mod keys minor keys
everything you need to know okay about
emacs keybinding and how do you define
key sequences
so that's about emacs you know so so
let's go back again you see
previous tab previous tab previous tab
next tab that's how i use the browser
key marquez
so we
were talking about this question about
kinesis okay so
because i type so much okay
one of the tips for programmers if you
thinking about you know
keyboarding issues what you really want
to know is let's go to uh typing okay
so look at the article
bad advices bad keyboard of advice from
programmers you know there's a lot
search
what you know so you know you might
wonder so why do you claim
many programmers advice you hear them
all over the place you know on hacker
news on everything everywhere you know
programmers will tell you oh you should
do this you should remap control keys to
the catalog your idiocy okay extreme
idiocy you should do this or that
you know the really easy way to the
criterion to determine
you know what type of people gives great
advice about
keyboard usage is that you want to look
for people who type a lot what what so
what is what does a lot means you know
for example novel writers or uh
you know the
data entry clerks you know what's a data
entry clerk their job is to type you
know given a data sheet they just have
to input into computer
these days it you know data entry is
less
it becomes extinct because
words recognition takes over in many
cases but still there are some cases you
need data entry or in code for example
stenograph systems stenograph you know
stenograph you need to record in real
time what people say
you know things like that so i also
cover many different systems for input
you know so there's uh
several stenograph systems this is a
piano based using
used in italy
so signal graph systems how they work
standard machines they cost they cost a
few thousand dollars okay so anyway back
to
how do you judge what's a good advice
you know what type of people gives good
advice for typing so you want to listen
to people who
either they already have hand pain you
know they went to see a doctor you know
there are some
several famous programmers who had that
you know they went to see a doctor
or people who truly type a lot you know
like
like data entry clocks i was a data
entry clerk for two years from 1991 to
1992 1992 to 1993
anyway two years okay all you do all i
do is just type in keep typing you know
you sit down computer you just type
non-stop for an hour for the whole day
basically now of course you take breaks
so that is you know that's the magnitude
more typing than programmers ten times
small you know five times small
you know programmers they they think
they know stuff they tell you oh you
should do it keymap this way that
you know because when you
actually
uh see people who type 10 10 times small
they got you know then they actually
have good advice about what's good or
what's bad okay so you want to that's
how you judge
so i have article on that go to typing
so i tell you you know some of the
idiotic advice from programmers you know
programmers tell you you should remap
control key to the caps lock which is
the edc
they tell you you should not learn touch
type that's an idiocy because because if
you don't touch type then you cannot
even you know
for data entry clerk if you don't touch
type you're out of the job you know you
don't have a job
it's like saying you know for example
sports okay let's say football
american football or soccer okay
so programmers like is they are saying
oh you shouldn't
you get trained you shouldn't be a
professional athlete athlete because
once you become a professional athlete
you're you're prone to injury
yeah that's true but that's not because
you are professional that's only because
you do a lot more in a more professional
manner it's like kung fu you know or you
know karate or self defense
you know those people who actually
learned kung fu you know they they
learned you know
martial arts or they they become
champions in you know martial arts uh
champions they will they are prone to
more injury in fact all almost the
professional boxers they will they all
have injuries okay many in many cases
serious brain damage because of the
concussion
but that's not because but that doesn't
mean their professional training in
boxing is okay
that
that's very good it's only because they
do it too much
same thing with typing
you want to learn
touch typing because that will make you
far more efficient given x amount of
typing you will do it more faster and
easier on your hands okay
less strain on your on yours on your
head on your shoulders because you can
finish it in 10 minutes without touch
typing you will finish it in one hour
it's a big difference okay but why is
that touch typing people are prone to
injury that's because they type 10 times
more okay
so that's that is why not because the
idiotic programmers they say oh you
shouldn't learn to trapping because this
hunt pack is fine
and then they cook up reasons okay
they will say you know they will say oh
for a programmer you don't need to learn
touch type because
because programmer
because programming
most of the time you are spending
thinking it's idiocy
if you don't touch type then you are not
likely to write full documentation which
in turn damages your
design flow okay when you write the
function i for example for my k in my
case my personal style i always i almost
always basically always
write full documentation first before i
even code a single line of code because
that way i know exactly what you know i
know what i want i thought about the
problem fully and write it down when you
write something down it helps you know
your your thought flow
okay then programmers say you know they
have many things to say they say oh this
keyboard is better than that that
keyboard is better that's okay
the typical programmers then they say
you know
yes swap caps lock and control then they
have good they have reasons like
and in particular because the
programmers especially the unix
type the unix type the linux type the
emacs the vi this edit type of hacker
type of coders you know they'll tell you
what to do
they think they are the supreme you know
they they think their their advice their
thinking is the best they say oh you
should swap caps lock with control key
or you should use linux or you should
use uh you know tidying window managers
these idiots idiots
you don't know what they're talking
about okay when you go look into detail
scientifically
so basically they are saying you know
you should not learn touch type the best
way to avoid injury is not to go pro
that's what they are saying
and some will say ergonomic keyboard is
useless you know you can see that on
youtube if you just search for it you
know they'll say ergonomic keyboard is
useless or work is useless
you should just hunt and pack and kodi
that's idiocy so again
you want to listen
to people who are qualified how do you
judge
you want to look at those people who
really type a lot like you know what do
you mean by a lot
what do you mean by type a lot okay
scientifically that means you measure
your number of keystrokes by a key log
okay so this article how many words do
you type a day you actually can measure
it
okay so for example look at key login
software i have compiled the list of key
login software so you can actually see
how many number of keystrokes you type a
day
you know you do it this for a month you
can average then you can see oh my god
you don't type at all you're
idiotic programmers compared to other
people so i have a key lock so here's a
key lock of my emacs you know i i lock
my keys for about
10 years by now
beginning like 15
beginning like uh 2008 something like
that when i started to do ergo e-max
project which is a
e-max mod
so you see
so measure your number of keystrokes you
type a date so you then you know what
you're talking about okay so there are
several there are some of the things i
about
about keyboard about typing about sub
okay
now did i answer the question about
kinesis
uh i think that i think that's it for
today i'm done okay 11 o'clock we talked
for an hour
so about key switches about key switches
okay so
i recommend linear light switch
so for example cherry mx red or cherry
mx silent red so i recommend linear red
switches i mean
linear light switches the switch should
not have more
activation for smaller than 45 grams
okay that's what i recommend now this is
important i highly recommend this
especially if you already have some kind
of typing discomfort okay like i do
it makes a big difference okay i mean if
you are a beginner if you never got into
ergonomics before okay and you you know
maybe you are young you just start out i
recommend
like right now
go out
buy
i mean if you don't even touch type okay
if you don't know anything about
ergonomic keyboard i recommend you go
out buy a chinese cheap keyboard cheap
mechanical keyboard right now
you want mechanical key switches
absolutely okay
for example i you know i have
you know i have 30 years experience
because because beginning in 1991
in 1991 that's before the internet i
read a lot about typing you know i'm
kind of typing freak so
i started to touch type in
on a maquette on a
typewriter okay on electric typewriter i
learned quality touch typing in 1988
then
in 1994
so six years aft after i touched type
for six years on qwerty i i switched to
vorack i learned you know i learned
about vorag in 1991
you know so i went to the libraries you
know read about research on typing and
different layouts so anyway so i have
actually so i know
i read a lot about repetiti about
keyboard about typing about layout all
kind of things since 1990s okay
and i switched to work in 1994
and
my the first time i used emacs is 1998
okay so that's my basic history you can
find the article i have several articles
about it
in detail about my
rsi history just search for
sally okay so
uh i'm sorry isi history okay so you'll
see it
uh
sorry isi history so somewhere here okay
so it's not finding the right article
uh
sorry typing history
anyway it's linked somewhere you'll find
it okay so basically anyway
so what i was going to say so yeah i
recommend red linear switches
if you already have rsi very important
and brown switch is not good okay you
know
about eight years ago
when i started to got into you know all
these ergonomic keyboards because
actually i be it began in 2006.
anyway so
in the beginning i don't care about you
know when you look at on reddit you know
the mechanical keyboard communities you
will see
these
uh
people
they are very particular about key
switches there are so many types okay so
let me let's show you okay so keyboard
design
key switches okay so here you're looking
at you know here's the most common
rubber dome switch this is the switch on
your keyboard which is no good
and here's a scissor switch on your
laptop it's also rubber dome no good
then you have mechanical switches the
most popular is cherry mx
looks like that
okay so all my keyboard you see it's a
this it's all mechanical switch okay so
this is
this is uh cherry mx
red silent okay and this one is
um is uh
this one is also red silent but it's
made from china it's uh what's what's
the name i have a
kyle okay this is a kyle red
so kyle red is actually five grams
heavier than cherry mx
red
you know i want light as a slight as
possible
so anyway so i was saying
you know many years ago 10 years ago
when i started to get into mechanical
keyboard you know i look at other people
they talk about that i think you know i
thought that these people are crazy
these few are not jobs doesn't matter
okay doesn't matter well these
are you know it's it's the same okay
just get one you know just get one of
them and because consider vast majority
of people 99 of keyboard users they are
using don't robot dome which is far
worse so once you switch to mechanical
that's good enough okay don't be so
picky you know it's not like oh i must
have this one you know they get so crazy
about switches
and
and variations you know they talk about
that all day day and night
i thought these people are not jobs
you know so i think you know
any of them one of them is good enough
okay but actually now i have so much rsi
you know i type so much actually i have
opinions as well and a strong opinion i
recommend
okay here's a here's the thing
assumption
if you already have hand pin okay if you
already have rsi or if you truly type a
lot okay then i highly recommend you
want to get red switches you don't want
the brown okay you don't want you don't
want the brown you want the red switches
okay
that's the recommendation i can get i
can give you also if you just being
if you just start out you don't know
nothing about it right now you know like
right now go to go to you know my
website go to this
this page and get a chinese cheaper
forty dollars right away okay do it
for just chinese cheap ones forty
dollars they work fine okay they'll last
you for a year or two
uh important if you type a lot
okay that's it for today
i talked about that's it for today
let's uh quickly read some comments okay
donate to me okay donate go to my
patreon
uh you know it's you know you'll see my
links on my patreon
okay
patreon me amazon gift card me
uh you know pay me
if you like nice stuff
wufang language you can download so we
talked about wolfen language you know go
to my homepage saudi sarco saudi.info um
language you can download for free and
you can watch my past videos on
details about the language
so here's a question how do you define a
limit to prevent the geometric inversion
from
running forever that doesn't run forever
it's just a function it's just a
function that takes a point and returns
a phone point okay so it doesn't
it's not a recursion thing so it doesn't
run you know there's no such issue
but of course you can repeatedly apply
it
you know you can you can repeat it apply
the
inversion
but if you repeat it just revert it back
to self you know because it simply swaps
points outside the circle to inside if
you repeat to the same points it just
it it is it the function
inverse function is itself so that's
what the way to say it
a happy hacking keyboard okay fs
straight
uh
so do i think keycaps are important
keycaps are not not really important you
know keep keycaps is uh you know it's
it's good for
it's not really important okay keycaps
so if you go to so you can see all the
details about keycaps
uh keycaps you know basically there are
four looks you know for example there's
you know different technologies for
keycaps mostly the plastic material used
to create a keycap but the most popular
is abs plastic abs is sometimes some
kind of chemistry okay so
you know
so if you have a key cheap microsoft or
logitech keyboard
that's what you have abs keycaps and you
have this shine problem or you have this
kind of problem you see they rub out
so the better quality is pbs pbt keycaps
which is more expensive so
then you have also label key label
technology so if you have a cheap
keyboard
chances are microsoft and logitech cheap
ones non-gaming ones you have this kind
of label
technology they rub out you know after a
few months after a year
so the better so there are many
technologies for key label so for
example here's a lace
laser
etched one
then you also you know
many quite a few then you have dyes of
elimination which is the best okay
so
here is a picture of dice of elimination
technology so essentially they you know
the key label is part of the plastic you
know so it will never rub out
so of course they are much more
expensive and by the way you can buy
keycaps on
amazon and then there's also print in
front which is great because you never
touch the key label so they don't drop
out so this is also a great
thing
but also keycaps you know they are
pretty keycaps for example cute keycaps
you can buy
but they are just for uh for the looks
so i've been using celtic orthodox says
i've been using the same two gap 2gb
netbook for seven years no external
keyboard i work on it for hour
four hours a day okay
i guess you are good you know
you know the injury the typing injury
happens it depends on people you know uh
for example
it also okay so you you saying you've
been using this laptop for seven years
typing
for hours a day but exactly how much you
type like i said before key log you know
tell me exactly how many keystrokes you
type a day
you might be surprised you don't type
so in your case you don't actually type
that's why you don't have a problem
compared to other people
so that's it for today thank you guys
for watching bye
okay so go back to uh wufam language go
back to um
you