good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of SCI talk show let's go to
Google let's see so let's get prepared
pop this out today we're going to talk
about IPA that is international phonetic
alphabet and Emacs so I'm gonna say
today is March 28th and here is
California sunny California 5 o'clock
p.m. so I'm going to show you Unicode
Unicode IP a which is international
phonetic alphabet and maybe give you an
introduction to Unicode I've done that
before but I'm not sure it's very good
but I'm gonna talk about that maybe
introduction to Unicode for programmers
then I'm going to give you talk about
Emacs keyboard macro and yeah I'm gonna
show a demo of Emacs keyboard Marco hey
Isaac what's up were you from what's
your location so let's start let's start
by let's see ok let me fix the date fix
the title so IPA Unicode IPA and a
Unicode Emacs key mark row and stuff ok
so
hey Nicholas greetings from Hong Kong
sham gong
very good so Hong Kong great so we gonna
do okay yeah let me get started so let
me put right title here okay so what
should i do first well let's do the ipfs
let's do actually isaac is from
california cool sunny california the
best place on earth you know as you
consider us kind of like the best
country to live that is not a research
statement yeah III but I think that yeah
that is pretty much still true but of
course if you live elsewhere you may not
think so I haven't been around too many
phrases so anyway let's go back to
Unicode Unicode Unicode yes Unicode
let's go to actually before we do
Unicode let's do some Emacs demo because
usually people coming later so let's do
Emacs so okay let's begin so I could go
to my JavaScript blog so as you might
know I have already written JavaScript
in depth now this is egg I spent two
years on this project so if you are done
in JavaScript this is a good
you might try out my tutorial and this
is in depth so I would say it's valuable
even if you are working a company code
in JavaScript for two years I would say
this is still contain many useful info
for you and there's also a section for
JavaScript script reference in yeah so
anyway so let's go back to my web
Blagh so I have all these pages each one
of them has a reference link to the
JavaScript suspect I talked about that
yesterday so what I'm going to do is to
remove all these links
yeah the Akuma script suspect it's you
know they come in like 10 or 20
megabytes in one page so it takes a
while to load a comma script so let's go
back again if you have any questions any
comments any opinions just post like
type it post post post any you know
anything I'm like talking about then you
can you know post so each of link of
these contains a reference you can see
reference link to the Specht so all
these are already related then we have
dates javascript date date dot UTC which
is a property and so on so my tax task
now is to remove all of them so I'm
going to use emacs marker to do that let
me show you how to do that so I'm going
to first of all start command log mod
now command lock mod is a mod that
records all commands I call you Emacs
so if you know whenever you see you know
how did he do that you can just look up
on the Left panel you show the command
name and usually many of them are my own
commands and they are on my website you
can just search for the command name so
let's start let's so let's look at this
article viewing web you see there's a
reference link so normally if I do it
manually I just search for it
then delete it okay delete it showing
browser now it's good so back to Emacs
close it that's one of them done so
because there are many of them and they
have the same pattern so I'm going to do
a keyboard aqua so let's start okay
start record macro forward word-for-word
word for word word for word okay that's
good
enter to open the file go to the top of
the buffer then start search for greater
than greater than sign see reference /
okay such to search for the reference h2
tag okay
exit then I'm going to okay actually
that's a mistake
I want to okay cancel cancel cancel my
recording so let's see I want to search
up to these yeah so I want to search
that let's copy that so I just copy that
okay close so let's try it again
open go to the top search wait okay so
let's just do this
I'm calling sausage current word so that
is actually searching it so let's try it
again
open go to the top start search next
[Music]
okay this is not going well as planned
okay it's try that again okay now it
should be walking so open go to the top
such that yes then delete back delete
save close okay now that's good now I'm
going to start to record a macro start
mark well then 1 2 3 4 forward 4 times
open the file go to the top start I
search find the next item good exit I
search then let's do this let's select
the line delete it backward word digital
I then close the buffer say yes then I'm
going to move to the then that's it ok
I'm gonna stop the mark or now stop the
mark or recording ok I have a marker
recorded now let's go to the next line
let's call the mark well done
now let's try to select this all this
array part and call apply macro to
regionalize to juju juju woohoo it's all
done should be now let's look at in the
browser so we pretty much did all the
array articles so let's look at them
open open open open open so let's see
no reference good no reference good
clothes no in here no reference good no
reference link so we are doing good so
that that has we have just recorded mark
well you see for all these array to
remove the link so now I'm going to
apply to all the way up to let's just do
that
let's see now I don't want to do all
them in one shot because some of them do
not have the correct format format for
example let's see for example if I go to
well almost all over them
it's correct that's but for example
let's go to iterator prototype
okay that one applies operator new okay
that also a prize yes 2015 object
literal expression extensions okay that
applies as well but some of the article
for example here at the bottom you see
object overview now this page gives you
an overview what is the what is the
technical meaning of Java Script object
and its kind of tutorial so you can see
there's a reference here which is not in
the you know under the heading of
reference so it that's kind of a special
so this thing I may or may not want to
remove I have to decide later but right
now I'm just removing all those you know
with the same format so let's just apply
to let schnitz apply of true map let's
just do another example
so call the command of hi Marco to
regionalize yes and that's all done it's
all good
fantastic so those are the map sections
open open open let's just check three
that's good that's good that's good
so that's Emacs Marco demonstration I
hope some of you find it useful hey
Danielle great to see you hey Scott
great to see you Scott in nomen and web
dawg great so many of you okay
twelve minutes so we are on good timing
so I'm going to I'm going to talk about
Unicode and API then I mean not API I pa
International phonetic alphabet so
Norman says what do you think is the
newest JavaScript suspect that that's
still compatible with 90% of browsers I
think I would I are you here yesterday
Norman because yesterday we I talked
about that for like one hour
javascript suspect you know and how it
is how it relates you know they change
they have a new version every year now
and they try to be compatible that's
their decision so yeah so the gist you
know the the so there's a tug of war
situation you know on one hand if you
remain hundred percent compatibility
that is good because that makes you
popular people don't want to change you
know people a lot then you know millions
you know a thousand or the programmers
out there they don't want to oh I want I
need to relearn you know a new thing you
know they can just use JavaScript the
way they know it and learn a little bit
you know as they go on the other hand if
you go the way of Python you know you
know make it incompatible you know you
really want to improve the language like
remove the ugly stuff that you made you
know ten years ago
then you got the situation like Python 3
where after 10 years nobody likes it you
know you got 50% adoption so so it's
kind of good and bad I cannot say for
sure you know JavaScript you know yeah
so because they remain compatibility
with you know 20 years or 30 years old
old baggage so javascript is very ugly
and very convoluted
so anyway yesterday we talked about that
for like almost one hour so you might
check it out
yesterday's video so Scott says I'll be
watching at a lot laptop in about 10
minutes
oh cool after I clean up from dinner
cool
but for now listening on my phone hi
Daniel hi I am so typing this for my new
Google Docs really good keyboard I gave
up on learning ball rack yeah Google
Docs is good in general the Cherry MX
browns are so nice to type on okay so
maybe we talk about cheap keyboard a
little bit but let's let's go back to
the Unicode IPA because that was the
topic I announced earlier to people so
okay so let's go to sorry sorry Unicode
so I got this page of Unicode characters
and you can see there is emoji and you
move the mouse there you can see the
title and the code point of the emoji
and here you can search anything like W
a T then you get all characters that
contains name water like like contains
and characters wate so it's a great tool
if you you know you might want to use it
so anyway I added collect recently in
the past month I added many languages
you know in Unicode
so here's Cyrillic I'm not sure how you
pronounce that
does anyone else Cyrillic
but anyway it's using Russian in lots of
other languages and also added for
example Japanese Japanese Tibetan not
Tibetan is an exotic one you see they
looks like alien languages so anyway
what I want to do is I want to add a new
page which is international phonetic
alphabet let me show you sorry
IPA so I want to add a new page to my
Unicode page and that will involve okay
look at this article that will involve
Emacs of course and let's talk about IPA
for a little bit so I got this article
so IPA is a international phonetic
alphabet
I think it's invented in France by
French people so the purpose of the
phonetic alphabet is that you can use
this to annotate pronunciation for any
language any possible any language
historical or you know French English
Chinese
japanese any language I mean is because
it's designed to capture your mouth
mouth you know human speech mouth mouth
movements and how your turn is plays and
so on so it's you know at least in
theory it captures all possible sound in
human languages so here is some examples
Americans in general are typically
ignorant about IPA because American for
example here is a chart on the left is
you have IPA symbols on the middle is a
HD which is American Heritage Dictionary
on the right here is a merriam-webster
dictionary now in American dictionaries
each of them they use their own symbols
like not standardized you know each
dictionary use their own ad hoc
cooked-up symbols to indicate how a word
is pronounced so anyway this one for
example dark heart Park car hawk father
those are our sound but in American
Heritage Dictionary it's it's you know
and merriam-webster it's like a with two
dots on top but IPA IPA uses this symbol
so that's what IPA is now so I have the
other kind of bow son I mean these are
the major symbols for English at least
but IPA after that you know the IPA
symbols has a lot more actually oops
online dictionaries you know I have
obsession about dictionaries so I you
know so back in 1990s in 2000 I you know
I look up dictionaries like at least
nineteen most 1990 early nineteen
eighties and and late 1980s
I look up dictionaries like few hundred
times a day every day and so I you know
I have a you know obsession about
dictionaries
and I have you know comparison and
review of them there but anyway let's
get back to IPA so I need to create a
IPA page so first of all let me copy
that go to my programming blog and the
section create a new section let's put
the link here and find a Unicode okay
copy that put it here so that's a link
to the Unicode critic page so back to
Emacs close that I put a link here so
copy it paste it here so this gonna be
Unicode IPA
okay Unicode IPA ok type that
capitalized okay now I'm going to copy
the content of that page to here now
this link doesn't exist right now so but
I'm going to make it exist so I have a
command called saw copy HTML by link no
it's done so I can press ENTER open that
show in browser now you know it's a
content from the critic Cyrillic page so
I'm going to I need to change that but
the point is that it made a copy now I
need to copy the title open that again
change the title ok and update the
timestamp created March 28 then just
delete that delete that delete delete
delete delete et de DT let's go all the
way so delete
delete delete delete showing browser
that's empty that's good that's what I
want go back here then okay show this
fading browser so so here is the IPA and
you know I'm going to start to add
content to it so I need to get all the
alphabets of the IPAs so let's search
for IPA there's a page on Wikipedia that
lets you do that international phonetic
alphabet
you know the IPA is also used in opera
singing you know you know you guys have
gone to operas right so in Opera they
have you know oh you know it they okay
the up the text of our prize is like
sometimes in Latin sentencing what what
is a typical lyrics in opera is it
French
oh is it Italian oh I think he tallien
right
but anyway so you know opera singers i
i've read that they actually hold on a
second let me shrink the page god
it's super slow for some reason yeah the
opera singers they you know they use IPA
to help them sing because you know when
you sing some you know the was
especially if you are sinning or
different in a different language that
you don't know the language but however
you know many scene singers you know
their job is they have the talent with
their mouth mouth you know so a lot of
scene singers even if they don't know
the language for example chinese english
singers even they don't know English but
they can sing English songs in english
you know in such a way that you cannot
tell she doesn't he or he you know she
doesn't speak English you know but a lot
of singers do that so I suppose seem you
know
opera you know opera seen us so they can
read you know some of them use the IPA
to help them so here's the IPA and let's
get the characters IPA is like you know
you actually have to spend time to study
it you know because there's how do I
know IPA because actually fought a lot
of Chinese you know when you learn
English the pronunciation symbol our IPA
you know in fact you know that's you
know that's in Taiwan I think it's also
okay I'm not sure about China but that's
a case for Taiwan where I grew up so
that's how I I that's that's why I am
familiar with IPA at least for the way
it's used for English but anyway so yeah
you have to know you know these symbols
it's not difficult though you know you
spend one day bit and you basically
capture it you know just like this page
it captures everything let's see the
comments so what do you use to insert
Unicode characters in Emacs showing with
showing in previews of the characters
helms UCS is super slow in such are
doesn't have well I use my package I
mean for the symbols I use the most most
often I just I have a brief for it for
example okay there are two ways I take
math symbols of stuff in Emacs okay
Unicode in Emacs one is abbreviation for
example that doesn't work okay here P
you stand for bullet you see P you space
it becomes a bullet I use this character
all the time so and you know if if we go
through my ably let's see
Emacs a bleep so this is my Emacs a tree
file
by the way I also talked about these in
one of the videos so you can see you can
see you know PS PS is does and his end
is a ie RT is returned I use this word
all the time when writing tutorials so
that I don't have to type or e tu RN so
I just type RT you know for example if
I'm writing something if okay not here
because right now is in eMac this mod
and he makes Li smart I have a brief oh
you make this so but let's open a new
buffer and now if I'm taking a sentence
if you are you see if you are I just
type if you are fan of KB is keyboard
you see if you are a fan of key keyboard
you see so so so that's abbreviation I
have a video about that video tutorial
but it's also on my site website just
you know here's a link just such folks
re Emacs abbreviation so that's you know
I show you how to set it up but anyway
so if you can look at this page you will
see here are my Unicode briefs so let's
see your example good okay you need to
magnify
okay good bullet cat face hot face okay
Haru
so actually many of these I don't use
much because I sometimes I forgot the
brief oh this one I use often oh my god
and star these two I use a lot okay so
that's one way in fact that this this is
the best way to insert a brief okay to
the insert any Unicode for characters
you use often Oh another thing I use
often is right arrow like when I'm
writing tutorials like function return X
okay so you know is right arrow so the
so for the characters you want to you
use the most often create a break for it
that's a most efficient way okay now you
see Maya brief they are only like 10 you
know 10 Unicode characters that's many
but they are you know hundreds emoji and
and and hundreds of math symbols so if
you for example I want a Sun symbol you
know I don't have it as a brief but I
can do this whoops s um what I just
caught is some math input change to
symbol so that's so kasam math input is
a mod I've written that lets you type a
few hundred you know called math symbols
you can you use so if for example circle
plus you know so I'm learning math you
know I can type CP and for soap operas
yeah so a user breathe first you know
the problem with a previz that you
forgot what abbreviation
to type because once you have like over
let's say over 20 Unicode characters
then let's say suppose you have hundred
a brief soap for 100 Unicode you know
math symbols or emoji or whatever but
once you go over 20 you kind of forgot
what a brief so that's really annoying
so so I kind of have this package let me
show you okay wait okay the command echo
is some a simple change to symbol and
it's in this file let's open that
magnify go to the top and so this
package here is the package here's the
URL let's look at that ensuring browser
so it lets you type all these characters
mostly math yeah and you can add your
own you know whatever you want to add
and it's on male part you can use it so
that's how I type Unicode you know just
set up you know the symbols you want the
most often but if you do not have you
know suppose you want to type as Unicode
symbol let's say you rarely use maybe
you use once you know you know year you
just know the name what do you do you
can just for example let's try this
tibetan letter d da okay let's try it so
these Tibet Tibet and letter car okay
okay to the bit top okay so I do let's
see I have a command let me see
there okay wait not this one this one in
such ah so you just call the Emacs
command in search ah then
to bed turn there we have it
Tibetan what was that I forgot what was
that
Tibetan letter car okay Tibetan let your
et car there it is there it is
so yeah so for rarely use unicode
characters you can just go in search ah
so that lets that's that
maybe let's get back to IPA or something
let me read the comments
ohyeah italian german oh is that that's
an opera singers Italian engine German
some are Latin yeah yeah I wanted let me
show you as some song oh okay I don't
know if this is appropriate for YouTube
but you know don't worry there's nothing
not safe for walk here everything is
safe safe for work okay yeah but there's
some latin songs it's such folk sorry
Latin I don't have I'm not sure you'll
find it
okay Latin it's a music pattern okay
lean lilium is one of them that it's a
Japanese anime very violent and so I'm
not sure I want to go there but however
the music oh my god that song that piece
music is incredible it's just you know
actually there's not much you know you
can listen we can we can look at that
okay good YouTube anyway anyway so it's
a it's a Japanese you know anime song
from and it's really beautiful
I'm not okay I'm not gonna play it
let's get back to Unicode oh yeah but I
was saying there's another music that
that's in Latin that's good to show let
me show you then
tell-tell songs Little Mermaid and
sunshine miscellaneous Prince exotic
exotic here okay nella Fantasia that's
also I think that's in Latin limit on
JavaScript
so you know we are talking about we are
show me some songs why not his talk show
so this guy is a Korean he is a very sad
story and you probably have seen because
it's hugely popular on YouTube few years
ago like comedians you know watches you
know so he grew up
he's an often often you know without dad
or mom and he lives homeless you know he
busy mom basically all his life but
anyway he started singing singing you
know but mostly by himself and it is an
incredible performance it's kind of long
so let me see the comments Wagner's
operas German okay yeah you so brief -
okay cool emoji oh you did that okay
yeah the thing one thing about Emacs
Cooney max you know free software
foundation is that they removed they
removed support for color emoji in Emacs
why because you know apples Korea Mooji
in so does Microsoft but however the
Linux world the open source you don't
have that because you know it takes
money to do that if you do open source
nobody give you money that's actually
true you know so then then Richard
Stallman told people to remove actually
yes be move it's already there but they
want to remove you know the ability to
show color emoji for the Mac version of
Emacs you know so they did that because
the reason is that they want to they
want to you know they don't want Mac
version - you know appear more severe -
then the Linux version it's pretty sad
so let's see how emoji proprietary
very nice yeah that's a big story if you
want to look at actually sorry max you
can read everything things like this
happened like every year you know is you
know every year there's something
happened big issue then it's show hacker
news overrated yeah GUI max removes
color emoji support for the Mac and this
is this is back in 2016
big news and it's not just this instance
and it is every few years every two
years you have another big issue then
people forget forgot oh god what about
it
health King yes elf king that's the one
I reread oh wait he said a different one
or what is TV BG
oh there's audio echo sorry
okay so we are we so
so here is a song yeah well it's a
Japanese enemy but the song is beautiful
though let's let's not play that but
there's another one I want to show okay
this one nella Fantasia is also in Latin
I think so actually you know for each of
these are actually you know I'm a you
know I'm a nerd info gathering so this
is in Latin this elfin v8 you know dia
is a German for song anyway so this one
is in Latin so here's a translation the
mouth of the just shall mediate wisdom
in so long let's go through then this
one - I have a lyrics in Italian okay
nella Fantasia is Italian and and there
are other singers you know she is also a
kind of a very young talented singer and
this this girl also sings it they are
like incredible and there's another one
anyway so let's forget about that then
jack says hey hey Jack the image you sho
looks like an actor of t PPT whose IQ is
super high but what what is T BBT Talent
something something
Health King okay so let's get back to I
PA so I've been talking for 40 minutes
okay
IPA so right now my task is to collect
all the IPA phonetics I believe that is
all let's see let's copy that
okay there are two ways to do it I'm
gonna I'm gonna show you both so first
of all copy that copy go to Emacs paste
shrink it a little bit okay shrink again
okay
then I'm going to replace all ASCII
characters I don't want ASCII characters
so I'm going to call query replace let's
show the panel query replace rejects
then I'm going to give a Emacs specific
rejects which is this one first
this will find o ASCII characters a
sequence of SC characters so I type
enter replace it by by nothing okay then
type extreme nation to remove them all
good so I have it here
what is this I call describe char and
this one is soft - I don't want soft -
so reface remove or soft - yeah okay
then I'm going to put them into I want
each character to be a line so I'm going
to do start mark well I actually start
Marvel movie actor to the right enter
stop mark well okay now I'm going to
call the macro yes call as Kiba Marco
call as kibo Marco cholesky Bamako
that's good I'm going to repeat it by
calling repeat last command so I can
hold down T and you know just do
everything
okay it's all done now I'm going to
select all and sew them okay now you can
see some of these repetitions for
example this character described cha is
xf0 a latin small letter F and oh these
two are actually two different but
anyway some of them are the same I think
let's go 158 so anyway let's select all
let's call the command wait what is the
command I want to call
I forgot I forgot the key but let's just
call the name they need to placate I
think okay delete duplicate lines let's
do that okay it says T did 64 duplicate
lines so yeah so that's good so I got
basically all the I think IPA symbols
then I'm going to switch to HTML mod
magnify actually let's just copy the
whole thing close close
select the whole cross we don't need
that then let's go to the IPA page
remember it's empty now paste it here so
I got it all here select it narrow to
region so I only see this part magnify
magnify magnify I'm going to record a
key one aqua again so start start
recording move the character to the
right then cause I hear male mark
Unicode and stop mark well then I'm
going to call a Primark go to region
lines that's good so I'm gonna select
them all Primark or to region lines okay
so so now widened okay some of them are
got rights
I got it all wrong actually you see you
see if you showing browsers you know
what I want to do is I want to mark any
Unicode by you know by your HTML mark
tag but you see some of them I did a
command wrong so that's why you see that
so no worries so I go now to region then
code is come here
besides Gmail remove HTML tags let's do
it again
start amok well move to the right make a
tag move to the right stop mark well no
I'll try to add check it's still wrong
it's true let's try to do it again start
marker
stop okay wait there is something okay I
know what's going on because some of
these characters are actually
ok let's try it again
okay I know what's going on so let's do
it again
start marco / - right make a tag
then just go down okay then stop mark
well okay let's try a primal code to
region lines you know there's something
wrong here because you see this this one
is not right this one is I can't believe
this why waste let's try again
stop apply to Makkah region nice
now something is wrong I am not sure
what that's something I have to fix
it's open and again
so why is that
let's try it one more time start Marco
No
I'm not sure why I said okay let's not
use of high region let's try it one last
time
so I'm going to start macro do that just
move down stop macro then I'm just going
to call mark or one at a time okay
there's still something wrong I think
something screwed up you see you see
this this character it shouldn't be like
that I'm thinking because they are
combining characters because actually
they are two characters there but anyway
create a new language okay the color
emoji okay
anything else maybe we this is pretty
bad i can't believe i get this doesn't
not working oh yeah so that's all you
see I know why now because you see this
let me magnify you see over here let me
go back here
no no to region select all remove that
marks you see some of these characters
are not single Unicode code point they
are like combining characters so that's
yeah so how do I know it's it's a let's
call describe chart describe Charles I'm
we are looking at this character and
this character is display come composed
to from that see below
No
yeah I think that that is why it's
making yeah you see this is what happens
you know I hate those composition
characters you see normally if you just
have a character let's see let's copy
that it's fully here so normally if you
if you just have a character then you
call the command it put a mark to that
character you know mark tag wrap around
it now for this one we if we're gonna do
that you can see you can you see it
actually so it it did it for this you
know this aim under script but so you
can see they are actually two characters
here so this that character is made up
of this one in this one so that that is
why the macro is all screwed up so ok
anyway so that's one way to do it let me
just show you another way in watching ok
so let me just show you another way
let's go back to the Unicode and in a
search box let's type IPA
okay I want to get all the IPA
characters so what I was trying to do is
to search part of the name for the IPA
characters so let's try this one
latin small letter gamma so actually the
name doesn't contain IPA okay so this
this is another failure
I guess it's such this one not a small
letter z easy edge okay because I was
thinking all of them contains you know
then their character name contains IPA
but that's not a case where are they
so what is this injective consonants
maybe okay all these are consonants
where are the boughs International
phonetic alphabet chat chart I should
have gone to this page instead
and he's taking a huge time to load I
think that's it maybe that's it for
today what else am I going are we going
to a visual chart yeah IPA is so yeah so
I'm gonna do that but yeah let's see
what else we are gonna talk about talk
show talk show keyboard mark was Jeff
reference okay we did that
yeah that's we exhausted our topics yeah
so you never watching should should that
be it for today anything else
type tablet guys anything else if
nothing else then maybe that's it and
maybe we all do another one today maybe
you know like four or five hours from
now okay Norman says off-topic but can
you explain about the relationship
between Taiwan and China yeah
okay so Geoghan says headaches ah I'm
trying out your wonderful software keys
yes thank you and it's great but there
is one issue I'm not too sure okay what
is that let me know type it okay so the
difference I mean those relationship
with Taiwan and China is that so
okay back you know back so that here's a
very simplified history of hey Scott a
very simplified okay yeah we got so many
topics now is great we're gonna talk
about maybe 10 or 20 more minutes so let
me talk about a short history history of
modern china taiwan china so around
world war ii you know that's 1940's and
maybe 20 years before so so China has
been always being a Empire what do you
call the the well anyway so in 1940's
that's when what what happens so Japan
is invading China a very bloody war but
but even before that it was there's a
civil war going on between China for
maybe ten years before the Japanese
invasion okay so the civil war is it's
extremely bloody okay far more so then
say American Civil War it's like you
know million people died so the civil
war
it's between the Communist Chinese
Communists in the National nationalist
basically the China you know is is doing
you know in the early 1990s Oh around
1990 there's a lot foreign invasion you
know from UK from you know Germany from
France from Italy from USA even you know
they are or even in China in China is
your other war you know okay opium war
and so China lost because you cannot
beat you know the westerns guns and
ships so China is in a very bad shape
you know people want to start to
revolutionize you know revolutionize the
you know change to the education system
you know we cannot be that way any
longer we have to learn from the Western
societies you know countries so change
education change the government you know
stop the Imperial I mean whatever the
Chinese impact you know they stop the
government system the traditional I
forgot what's a proper name
what's a proper name for Chinese the
easiest way is China history dynasties
yeah that's a war dynasties no so China
was always in Chinese dynasties ruled by
dynasties so anyways so they we want to
change that because all the war you know
we lost to the foreign powers then but
there are two factions why is the
communism now this is when communist you
know the Russia just had their
their revolution you know communism is
becoming popular the idea the ideology
where all the people you know you don't
have to walk everything bleep you know
it's like a commune you know there's no
you know we don't want capitalism
because you know we want each people
helping each other you know give what
you have if you can you know those
capable to what they can those you know
you do whatever areas you can to you
know and you contribute there's no
private property everything is like
commune you know you share share it's
like it's actually just like the
ideology of free software or open source
you know you share things so one faction
is the Communist okay then the other
faction is nationalists now the
nationalist is supported by us well this
is even before but anyways so there are
two factions they want to change China
so they disagree they fight very bloody
then the Japanese came in then then we
they started to fight Japanese you know
they kind of collaborated to fight
Japanese Japanese I mean officially they
collaborated but I mean history is very
complex but they still fight internally
so then the u.s. dropped you know
nuclear bombs on Japan Japan surrendered
so technically China we the the victors
you know in World War two then the
Communists and nationalists civil wars
resumed you know and it's very bloody
you know millions you know bloody and
then so but the so and and by it by that
time the u.s. is like putting money and
money weapons in now do what they can to
support the Nationalist government and
and the Communist Party is supported by
part of Russia you know Russia is
supporting of course each count what
each of these big countries you know
they want their ideology to win so
anyway in the end the national nation
list failed you know they lost so the
Communists took over or China the
Nationalists fled to Taiwan my dad and
my mom is from China and so we fled to
Taiwan and and so that's what says so
that's what happens and and since then I
mean Taiwan is always very much
supported by USA you know you have you
know us you know ship fleet you know
going around the the the the Taiwan
Strait which is a sea between China and
Taiwan
let's see Google Apps so that's
basically what happens so that's why you
have Taiwan and China you know China is
ruled by communist government and China
and Taiwan is ruled by you know the
Nationalists called coming down okay
coming down and it's it's just show a
little bit that
yeah so I'm going to show you the map of
what's so that's California that's where
I live
Silicon Valley we rule the world with
Google and Facebook and AI so here is
USA you fly all the way then you have
China North Korea South Korea you know
lots of politics and West Germany East
Germany that's that's you know the World
War 2 era so Taiwan is this land it's
part of China you know in anyway the
Taiwan so we fled you know the
Nationalist Party fled to Taiwan and
it's it the story just doesn't just end
there because of Taiwan so Taiwan has
people in Taiwan they are native I mean
they are kind of native I mean there
they are you know they are kind of still
Chinese you can say it's an ethnicity
yeah I mean China has got lots of
different ethnicities so anyway Taiwan
has people that already lives there they
are
they are like they are Chinese and your
most most famous speak Chinese but when
when Japanese in during World War two
Japanese his rule in Taiwan you know
it's part of Japan so anyway Taiwan's
got people that the the Nationalist
Party moved to Taiwan and they ruled
Taiwan rather ruthlessly okay they so
they take advantage you know the it's
pretty bad you know the the government
in power so and they have there's also
massacres you know so the in Taiwan so
so it's like politics you know it's like
politics you can USA or anywhere in the
world you have different parties you
know that you fight all the time you you
know you talk you know so so
Taiwan is kind of so you have so anyway
anyway
so but since the past you know like 30
years
Taiwan became the Guam in town party you
know that the nationalists who fled to
Taiwan kind of so they have like a
democracy kind of now like like the USA
because Taiwan is very much influenced
by USA whatever USA is doing Taiwan has
it you know like today you have you know
gay rights you know feminism women's
right right this than that that Taiwan
kind of almost copy it you know almost
everything but China is kind of in treta
more independent you know China so I
have never been to China and I grew up
in Taiwan until I was 14 and I moved
around you know so that's a basic story
so cracks are a key so what what is the
issue okay so maybe we talk about golem
but probably we're gonna finish today
maybe yeah okay ten more minutes maybe
and I'm thinking maybe we're gonna do
another talk show tonight you know in
five hours so you know for people in
China or Europe can join so in a slam
repose
so Geoghan says in a science lime ripple
wait what is slime I kind of forgot some
reports so when I typed that when I type
coma gives me a command prompt
now slant slime is a common lisp right a
coke for a package for learning common
lisp
so okay anyway in slime wrapper when I
type coma it gives me a command prompt
gives you a command prompt in the bottom
and when I type space once it sometimes
give me into insert mode yeah I don't
know the sign is the mod of interactive
comedy system yeah as far as I know a
slime is pretty complicated you know
yeah so I don't know about what I don't
know about that because well the basic
thing about the situation is that you
know Emacs I mean despite all its
flexibility you doesn't really have a
system designed for key bindings so by
that I mean whenever you have minor
Martine you have major mod key bindings
you have minor mode key bindings but
minor mod you know when you have a
buffer you can have several minor mods
Oh so which minor mods Keys takes
priority okay there is a way that space
you can you can change it yourself but
at maybe there is no general way to
define that defines you know which one
should be you know have priority so each
minor mod can they actually do overwrite
each other's keys if there's a conflict
so I I don't know if this is a problem
that can be solved in general because
this happens in Windows as well because
you know you have different applications
each one tries to override the other you
know applications key you know and you
know because you have many different key
binding tools for example so you know
each one wants to be the you know have
priorities alright so in general to
solve these problems in the video for a
person what you can do is to you want to
try to find out okay you call the key
code a command describe key so when you
are in the situation where some key is
over right
in that moment in time you want to call
the the command describe key then tap
that key and see what command it
actually cause and where is that firms
to see if that if it's from that minor
mod so yeah yeah I don't think this is
actually a good explanation because
especially with sly mod you know the
situation is that within many of these
especially complicated mods for example
in the case of interact interactive
pepper for common list they do they have
lots of like tricks and hacks to get you
know to do what they do so in in a case
of key binding they may have their own
key money and also Emacs has a you know
you can define a key that is tied to
text so for example when you've if you
are using magic
meaning keys are bound to specific chunk
of text so when your cursor is in that
chunk of text you know it's actually
called a key so I mean this is a case
for magic mod mod so immediate so so
there's a lot of complications so
there's no Jim Jannard
generic way to solve that in you know
except case by case that's that's what I
think so if you like you know file a bug
report on you know I'm soft like he's
it's kind of piled up I haven't had you
know looked in the past month so they
have quite a few things piled up so you
you know if you are really want serious
about this issue put put the issue there
please and I'll get to it
of Tommy can expand relationship okay so
tell me it's just the province Jack Lew
says Taiwanese are just a province of
China so that's actually yeah you know
that's Chinese people you know people in
China's take you know hit highway is
just a province
you know Taiwan you know I actually I'm
more in favor of China I'm sorry to say
because I also have you know I was born
in Taiwan and my family is in Taiwan but
my family is very messy and you know
there are people from Taiwan and and
actually Taiwan Emacs users they have a
user group they because they are fairly
popular and they follow me but but you
know I'm kind of more in favor of China
because Taiwan you know Tama is kind of
very small and the thing is in Taiwan
politics politics it's extremely messy I
mean it's not like it's it's not like
they are you know unified you know
peaceful because you have people in
Taiwan they are you know they are not
from China
okay for example my I moved to China we
I'm from China okay but 70% of the
population maybe maybe 70% or something
you know 50 percent they are they are
they are they are in Taiwan or
originally then there's then there's
also no more known as native Taiwanese
which are people who who live in
mountains they are kind of so anyway so
it's like you know it's like politics is
complicated and they fight for you know
they it's very messy then there's also
corruption you know there's part of
Taiwan people you know they want Taiwan
independence but only that's only part
of them you know wanting that not not a
whole you know so it's fairly
complicated so Taiwan back in you know
in the 1990s everything is made in
Taiwan but now is typed China is you
know taking over you know just China is
big and now they opened up you know the
ten shopping they opened up the economy
basically capitalism so they become so
rich that that is why you know if you
ask for my opinion you know before China
China China was communist you know very
poor you know you don't have you know
like thank you roscha
you know but then shopping opened up you
know at least the economic aspect you
know so these striving you know
everything so I think that's it for
today thank you guys thank you guys a
lot for coming
possibly I'll do another one in maybe
five hours or something uh announce it
on Twitter and major mas Fisher has
humanics reading in front of you so I
see you guys you know Nick I'll talk
about this comments next time thank you
bye guys oh yeah the goal and I'll talk
about that yeah next time Scott