good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2022
february 2nd today is chinese new year
actually yesterday
so
i had a great time great time and what
are you guys doing so today's topic is
going to be random i'm going to uh do
some live coding of stuff of things i
need to do okay
and how many people are here
so you guys here
two concurrent you viewers nobody okay
well in that case i'm just going to
start to do whatever
okay
so video check audio check one more time
video and audio check
fantastic
okay so
nobody's watching so i'm going to do
what i need to do
okay so let me first of all mention i
made the saufan mod open source
so this is
wolfram mod
and if you search it you'll find it i
believe let's try
some wolfram mod and you are looking at
my keyboard over here this is kinesis
advantage too
and this is ultimate hacking and you can
see it
you can see it just by search those you
know just search for saudi keyboard and
you'll find it my reviews and stuff so
here is you know the
google results
i mean the
goal web search result of wolfram mod
so the first one
you go there and you can see this is
mod you know
a e-max mod for wufam language wufang
language is the fantastic the best
superior superior language
okay that's so you are looking at woof
and language
okay and let's you know nobody's here so
i'm just gonna
do random so let's do random okay so
magnify you need to
expand
let's say x to power
plus x x
plus y
third power
plus
c
and raise the whole thing to the 13th
power
okay
that is the power of wufang language
fantastic
and nicely formatted let's add some
square root okay let's say um
x y times square root of
x
okay something like that
try it 13th power is huge let's try
fourth power
okay
and we can also try some nesting let's
let's put some fancy square root
to a power of
square root of x
i don't know what's going to happen
oh
okay in that case it will it cannot
expand because it doesn't know
what is x anyway so this is wufam
language
happy new year
the dude hello the dude
where are you from the dude so today's
topic is random so you can ask me any
questions you want okay
and um
per mm noob
is that right for my noob okay for my
new happy new year
fantastic you just found me tonight
get get a load of me you know my website
is worth
let's see so they are about
let's go to the top so there are about 7
000 articles written in the past
23 years or so
and if you so there's mathematics
there's programming there's technology
mostly uh technology oriented
why is my website so slow right now
what
okay this is this unicode i showed many
times i talked about many times
it's kind of slow so anyway so you go to
xrd.info
and
study.info is technology oriented
mathematics and programming mostly
so intellectual stuff technology and the
intellectual stuff and you can play
chinese chess
you need to turn on javascript
so there's a question so legion says
could you talk about your new shorthand
system no that i'm much obliged that is
the
you know cassandra new shorthand system
let me tell you about that that is
fantastic you know this is chinese chess
very popular
so let's say you know boom
i'm gonna take my canon and eat the
night
canon take night
and this is written in javascript you
know copy the url
okay he's gonna eat my
and in that case let's raise the hose
so copy the url
back to emacs
paste the url here wait
what is going on yeah there is the url
so
it's magnify and the pink window is all
my emacs commands and you watch my stuff
you know you know
so let's make it this into a link and
make it
oh not here well
what
okay so let's go to class talk show so
i'm gonna talk about the questions you
guys asked i'm gonna answer okay but
yeah so let's get to it so what is this
wufa mod okay i'm gonna tell you about
that one thing at a time
um
chinese chess so today's this is the
topics we talked about today a record of
it and after the video live you can go
to the this url
uh you'll find it
so first of all wufa mod so this is a
mod
emacs mod in wufang language and now
it's open source okay so
you know i did a video
programming wolfram language fantastic
you see that those geometry things
you know let's go to youtube
geometry
mathematics programming that's the
things you guys love you know you call
this this is non-trivial by the way this
is
this graphics is one of the graphics i'm
proud of so you you know this is one of
my youtube talk show and you click the
link
here
then you go to the home page of the talk
show so there's a topic
over here so you can see it's magnified
so you can see the topics
geometric inversion
so on that episode of star talk show i
talked about how do you do this what
does it mean
deep mathematics stuff complex analysis
relativity einstein
okay
actually i don't know much about
relativity and i'm not a physicist i'm
not much into physics
actually but i'm so much into math
so this is complex analysis one of the
huge branch of
mathematics and
and one of the most fundamental process
in complex analysis is geometric
inversion which you are looking at is
the plot of one over x
where the x is a complex number that's
that's the what it looks like
so back to the talk show and you can see
geometric inversion wu found code so
that's what we you know so you you might
go watch that video you'll learn
mathematics and you will learn
geometry i mean the and and you will
learn wufang language so you see look at
this that's wolfram language code let me
let's let's copy and paste it okay so
today again the topic is random you post
questions i answer okay
so paste the code wufang language code
let's shrink it a bit
okay there is the code and let's pretty
fine let's make it two two-dimensional
rendering okay so i press a key
fantastic you can see those fractions
those delta in fractions okay and and
this is a pure function this is the
lambda okay for those of you lisp people
you know into lambda lambda calculus so
evaluate
you see you got the graphics you got
these
fantastic graphics that's woofing
language go buy it it's free and and
also it's free i explained this a
thousand times just follow my links
you'll see
you know get it for free download it for
free it's free since like two years ago
and uh some technicalities of wolfram
language mathematica from engine will
frame script what's the difference with
script is like powershell or bash you
can use it so i have like full tutorials
i talked about this many times okay and
more videos okay so that's uh
so but one thing one of the thing is the
wolfram language mod which now is open
source that's the main thing i want to
tell you guys
so
so this wufang language mod just search
for it and you'll find the github okay
so let's go down
let's turn on javascript
okay reload
and
download download right here on github
the power of microsoft github
so you can download for free okay and
thanks to wolfram research for
sponsorship
okay and you can look at the source code
let me just show you a little bit source
called the wolfram language
the emac this
source code for the wolfram language mod
okay so
there it is
so this key
runs the command saw woof and mod and
the source code is right here
so you can you are looking at the source
code
2500 lines
and if you go all the way to the top
and we go to the top you know lots of
7000 building functions you are looking
at the function names of language 7 000
of them body and you don't have to load
any library it's not like oh i need
regular expression which library is
regular expression in python you know
for example in python ruby golan c c
sharp c plus plus you know i need to
traverse the directory oh which package
which
which library do i need to load none of
that
functions filled in
at your fingertip okay
so
see this fantastic graphics you don't
have to say oh which which graphics
library do i need to load or
or the words jump like the javascript
which which external graphics library
which community do i need to and which
one is better oh that one sucks open
source you know this all that
none of that
you want artificial intelligence you
want crypto analysis you want to you
want to do bitcoin or you want to do
whatever
wufram language one shot does it so you
are looking at the source code that's
this is emac lisp
okay and now it's free
you can download it and it's open source
okay close that close that so that's so
that's one topic so the other topic the
question
common guys okay common okay
the other question is the shorthand
system okay let me explain so you should
let's go to it okay on a pink window
you'll see all my emacs command cores
such as moving cursor and the keystrokes
so those are work layout i'm using work
there okay
so let's go to a brief my shorthand
system
so you are looking at my shorthand
system for example let's show some
example okay
magnify see the full glory what the [ __ ]
you see that's expansion
t-i-s-t-i-s
expand to it is okay
um
let's see um
by the way okay btw expand
and
so that's a emac
abbreviation so there are
there are
five 500 of them okay and also for all
programming code for example
for example i'm now in xa emac list mod
you can see in a mini buffer
emac this mod so i type d
becomes different
and it becomes the template different
okay so
region beginning you know region
beginning expand
let l for let expand
expand fantastic this is emac please
this is emacs abbreviation feature
i did a video about emacs abbreviation
like a year ago so if you don't know
just go to the website
emacs abbrev
then you have the full tutorial
okay
trivial in one minute you will get all
this power and you can define any abbrev
you want it's versatile because you can
define a brief for english words you can
define a brief for
for shower commands for example let me
see let's let's go to esha okay
so i want um let's say i want to reduce
image color okay
so i press this key
image 256 you see the mini buffer give
me several choices of the abbreviation i
forgot you know they are like i have
500 a brief i forgot what's the name so
i have another command which is called
you can see here
you see xr interactive a brief search it
you'll find the source code so that
allows you you see one of the problems
of a brief
you know is that you have 500 of them
more than more than that because this is
just english then you have gold language
a brief emac list of a brief shell a
brief whatever you want and you see
there's also unicode a brief for example
if you want a smiley
it's magnify okay
hot
doom hot okay so wait do i have that
well anyway that's not
that's not a brief but anyway so you can
use a brief or your favorite emoji
actually i have it
ammo
there it is
there it is these are my favorite
practical
emoji
that i use for discord for example right
now i want i'm in the mood for cloud
so go here
cloud
there it is
so
emacs i brief one of the most fantastic
feature of emacs okay you want to learn
it why am i talking about a brief
because that's what i'm about to talk
about the
abbrev system
oh that's a big thing my friends that's
a big thing that because my vision of
that
project
it'll take a year to finish okay and i'm
getting old i'm not sure again but
but this is the idea okay i'm i'm gonna
tell you about it in a bit okay
so why am i talking about a brief
because you need a brief to do that
you know this is basically that's a
fundamental that's a technology
to do that
but it's not just limited to emacs okay
so let me okay hold on a second let me
finish this topic here so i breathe
so yeah so you're seeing the abbrev
let's close that oh yeah so
so i want to do a shower brief so image
let's say reduce that i have so many
commands so let's say
let's say image convert okay
there it is that's the syntax
you don't so you don't have to type them
that's a syntax for
um
reducing jpeg qualities okay
let's try something else image 256 so
this is this one this is a shell command
for the image magic
you know
command that allows you to now you don't
you do do you know what is image magic
okay sorry image magic
so oh fantastic
you know the this you know so in modern
days we have search engines so let's
let's go to the search engines fantastic
this is all images
related to kasadi
some of them are not mine so what is
this one
okay
and what is this one that's not mine
the rest are mine this one is not mine
you know this is my
my my my not my
my
not my
not my not my
okay so this one is um
anyway
you know so these are a lot you know
most of these uh images are my images on
my website
not that one you know so anyway so math
and
technology and computing you will be
highly interested math technology
computing this one is paul rave for
example so you can go to the
there and you can start learning about
paul rave
which is ray tracing you know many of
the computing nodes of uc plus plus
and then c
programmers and rust programmers you
love this image you know ray tracing
that's these people talk about all the
time ray tracing
which i think is idiotic and one of the
most idiotic thing in us as far as
programming activity goes
i talked about that before
so you can get into um for example
illustrating geometry with proray but
you know um
so where is it i have a full tutorial on
paul ray okay so
yeah here parade intro
you know con solid geometry constructive
solid geometry with proray
so for example to do this one here's a
source code you copy that paste into the
prey app and you get that solid geometry
this is look at this one death star
with the shadow and playing with the
shadow you know death star
solid geometry so this is constructive
solid geometry what does that mean for
example to generate this
thing this death star
you take a ball you take another ball
and you say this big ball minus that
ball
then that's what you get then you put
lights shining you know ray tracing and
you get that
solid geometries so similarly for this
one you put three pipes
uh this thing is very big in the 1990s
but now
it wasn't
well known
much anymore and it's open source
okay
let me speed up my gun so solid geometry
support ray so so we digressed all over
uh
let me get back to it okay so i talked
about
so any comments or questions am i like
too slow or something
let's go let's go to let's let me do let
me um
get on okay let me
try to focus or something so that we
so wufam language we talked about
playing chess geometry
solid geometry with pre
and
okay so what were we doing oh image
magic okay so we wanted to we wanted to
let me yeah let me show you image magic
okay
what is this
emac list manual wow i didn't know emac
is list menu actually
okay so emac this beginning version
27 they have
they have updated their
emac base code for
manipulating images
so i believe this is new so anyway so
let's go back
so i wanted to tell you about
image magic what
there it is
image magic tutorial so this is a
command line
um
application for many manipulating images
for example converting jpeg to png and
so on reduce colors and so on
so this is three this is the example of
diva you know dithering is popular in
the 1990s but not so today because back
in the 1990s
you have monitor of only 256 colors or
16 something like that so anyway image
magic okay
okay so i was trying to demonstrate you
know so this is the command of image
magic i'm trying i was demonstrating
the um
the command code
that one okay
so interactive a brief okay
and yeah so we were talking about a
brief so okay so what is the deal so
so here's a thing okay let's see let's
go to a page where i have written about
that
um
there it is okay so this is
too much cigarettes
so i'm trying to so
let me let me let me do the
prelude so what is this about
the
the cassave shorthand system
so you know today it's very popular
you have
these you know especially among you
keyboard mechanical keyboard
do-it-yourself fans
you see well these are do-it-yourself
mechanical keyboards you buy the
components and you make it you design it
you know some of them they designed each
and every one of these
so
it became popular of the idea of using
you know those mechanical keyboards to
do steno okay so this is a steno now
what is the standard steno is a
input system
for english and also other languages for
french
not so much french but i i suppose i
mean for
german for many languages okay so it's
an input system fast input system so
supposedly 300 words per minute if you
type touch type you know maybe you are
good you get 100 words per minute
or 120 when you are young
but
with say no you can type up to 300 words
per minute
so i did a video before talking about
how is it possible how does it work
basically first of all it's a
multi-key simultaneous key press system
so you don't press one single key at a
time like a
typical keyboard you press multiple keys
so so that saves you you know that saves
you time because you are it's like
parallel processing
you know in instead of sequential
parallel processing multiple keys at the
time and then and also note the keys are
specifically designed for your for your
hand to press them
multiple keys at the time okay so this
is a standard system
so that's one thing multiple keys
in one shot that's one
reason why steno is very efficient very
fast 300 words per minute
the other reason
is
it's not
alphabet based
it's it's phonetic based so you don't
type for example there there are
five apples you don't type t h e r e
space a or e space
f i b e space a p p l e
sequential alphabet letter based that's
that's what typically you do with
computer keyboards but with the standard
system
you don't type the each letter you it's
a phonetic you type the pronunciation so
there
are
five
apples
at post okay so it's like you type five
times
with code you know instead of you know
so that is why that is the
two major reasons the fundamental reason
standard is very fast but however signal
has got a problem
it requires you know according we have
an expert of zeno in our discord emily
who is not
who is not on much
in the past few few months i hope she
comes back i don't know
anyway so this is her machine this is
her photo you know she bought it she
showed me she taught
she
she taught me many things about steno
and other things
so this is her machine and she's expert
she's she's
kind she's becoming she's amanda expert
in steno because she also started to
you know she studied she bought the
machine
very expensive you know those machine
sells for a few thousand dollars
no kidding few thousand dollars because
the market is very tiny three thousand
dollars so she bought a used one costs
like
still a thousand dollars or something
so anyway stay no okay the reason is
fast because it's
multi-key system designed that way not
like the computer idiot like
you have to hold down control first then
press a key c then release that key then
release
control if you just press them together
it doesn't work the [ __ ] idiotic
computer [ __ ] loved by the
do-it-yourself people idiots with their
thirty percent [ __ ]
so anyway stainless multi-key system and
each key is designed for for your
fingers for you know for the purpose not
like the computer keyboard okay
and it's phonetic based
phonetic okay phonetic however there's a
problem
the problem you know
emily told me and also you can read
wikipedia it's it takes like one or two
years to master it takes one to two
years to master it
and that's not all
each phonetic system for example if you
can you know once you
do this on our day
you know you can watch this video she's
an expert you know you do stand out you
learn it an hour a day
after two years then maybe you can type
300 words per minute you know two years
and you know because there's a
certification you know
if you you know you can be a
stenographer you need to be certified so
you have to you know
anyway so generally i think it takes
like two years to master it
but also
this is more problems okay
now emily is a big fan of steno but
but i don't think this system is not
that is is that great okay because first
of all it takes a long time to learn but
once you learn it
you can only type english
so if you want to type french or italian
or greek
jesus that's another two years or
something
for each every language because the
phonetic the system it will be different
so
in a terminal in a jargon of the steno
community
you know each phonetic system for the
for that particular language is called
um
you know they have a name
it's called um what what they call it
the dictionary
uh let's magnify okay i forgot you know
but they they have their own jargons the
phonetic the
you know steno community you can by the
way if you are on discord if you haven't
already oh [ __ ] [ __ ] memes
who the [ __ ] are posting these memes
it means
fan name
this guy [ __ ] [ __ ]
you know i despise me memes the
brainless [ __ ]
why why where is our admin
okay are you guys still there say
something guys
check let me check okay
six people
god my the poverty of microsoft nobody's
paying attention and nothing
okay so phonetic system okay so i was
going to say yeah so what is the name of
the um
theories okay that yeah this is kind of
idiotic so phonetic in insano community
if you want to type english or french or
whatever you have to pick a
theory that's what they call basic
basically that's the system to type that
specific language
and and not just that for each language
there are several different
theories okay so so depending on your
preference or you know
you know this they have several
different systems
for one particular language
you know for so so for example emily
explained to me so there's stan ed
system
you know they call it theory you know so
you have stain ed theory you have
phoenix theory
you have prover theory pervert is a new
thing okay let me let me explain you
have magnum's theory so anyway
so phonetic system standard system
to me
it's got lots of problems okay
lots of problems
uh and uh
you know of course many of these
sim you know i don't know that much
about steno system i haven't spent time
to study them in depth
but from the impression from what emily
told me and you know some readings
myself
to in my opinion steno
system is no good okay no good
no good you got to be eliminated god be
you know
it needs the modern technology with our
computer saying this is no good okay i
believe
with modern you know
in today's you know era we
could and should have a much
better system you know that doesn't
require two years to learn it and can
type you know let's say 100 or 200 words
per minute easily
so that is the that is the reason
that is what
shorthand system is about okay i'm gonna
that's the that's the reason i want to i
want to have a short hand system let me
explain okay
so let me read uh the comments a little
bit so you guys are still here to say
something okay so that's legion's
question
okay the dude says
would you be willing to get into some
basic game programming
yeah i'm willing but i'm not able
because i mean i'm now old okay i've
been wanting to learn basic game
programming for a long time but i never
did
okay it's
yeah yeah i know about the you know
unreal engine which is free and there
are several but every you know every
five years or so i looked into them you
know i spent several days to look into
the libraries the 3d engines but i never
got anywhere uh
it seems to me fairly complex and
usually and then the other thing is they
require c plus first which is the
language i despise
you know and
i just never get into you know although
it's a topic i'm highly interested but
the game engine you know i really like
to understand game engine how it works
like you know like 3d games i love you
know 3d games how is it possible
or google earth google earth
virtual you know virtual metaverse
virtual life second life i played
instagram you know i always wanted to
learn them but
i just never
i never
actually
learned a thing basically and all forgot
you know i'd never get into i
3d game programming what i particularly
want to know is how the 3d game engine
works
you know for example i always wanted to
how do you how do you
3d graphics you know open gl and those
you know you have to you kind of get
into those how do you get you know how
do you simply draw a cube that i can
rotate
you know i looked into them like since
15 15 more than 15 years ago every five
years it turns out to draw a cube you
need one thousand lines well actually
100 lines
well where whereas in language is one
single line you know
so this is a digression let me get back
to the shorthand system okay
okay that's all you need for a cube you
know you need to specify where the
center of cube is
size of the cube like you know length of
the side
that's all you need
like
with technology you should be able to
figure out
where is the lighting where is the
viewpoint where is the ambient lighting
where is the cube size oh that's all you
have to do you know i wanna i wanna draw
a cube so all i need to do is say where
is the cube centered
what's the length of the side and if
they are emitted just make a small
choice like centered at zero
you know origin that's what this is and
if you don't specify the size you know
just one okay this is a cube of length
one and
then
you want a graphics 3d of it that's it
that it is it's wufam language okay
now can what kind of idiot what kind of
idiotic technologist
don't understand this okay
you know computers is getting 10 000
times more powerful over the past 30
years but you don't have you don't have
nowhere haskell or whatever python [ __ ]
you don't have nowhere like that does
this
you know and let's not mention more
complex graphics like this
okay complex graphics
or like the typical 3d games where you
can like a fly you can move around you
know for example you know you can create
a maze and you can shrink your viewpoint
you know you can imagine your viewpoint
is inside this you know gap and you can
walk around you know that's 3d graphics
that's what they are that's geometry i
know geometry i know
you know i know
fairly advanced geometry and
computational computational geometry
but i tried to learn the 3d games you
know this is boring you know i want like
uh maybe realistic you know like uh you
know textures oh god textures [ __ ]
idiot the most idiotic [ __ ] in
programming technology like you you fake
the textures by grabbing your image
anyway
so my point is
several points okay i want a high level
system but the industrial coders does
this c c prosperous these compiler
idiots they just they just they don't
they don't they don't think of that way
okay they never have a system
svg is very close svg okay
okay this is this is a giant digression
okay but let me let me integration okay
so svg is very close but svg is only for
2d okay
but then apple created the canvas idiocy
[Laughter]
which which drags him back he drags you
back to all the
all the bits and pixels idiocy the
canvas you know i have an article
canvas versus svg okay so this article
is about canvas versus svg
and you can
turn on javascript so you can you know
look at
look at these two one of them is canvas
one of them is svg and let's magnify
okay
let's magnify magnify
you see the canvas becomes fuzzy crap
svg sharp so any anyway the point is svg
is high level okay canvas is not canvas
is in the tradition of the c
c plus first of the
bits and pixels and
memory memory management and and low
level and you know and and and float in
painting you know that's idiocy and that
is what the gaming engine is like you
know i tried to study it you know
since the 15 years ago every five years
just i just
cannot
uh
it seems you know um
to level uh too low level but however is
it possible
is it possible to create a game system
or the you know the opengl the api is it
possible to create such a language that
that is high level
yes it is
however just look at mathematica okay
look at wu family but for many
reasons
part part of the
industry reasons making money it just
never come up okay and i i blame it in
part to the eunuchs and sea idiots they
they don't know what they are thinking
okay so that's that's my giant that's
that's that is in fact one of my giant
gripe against the
coding industry you know and you you
talk to other people like they they
don't they don't they they will never
see this idea
where high-level graphics they don't
they never thought of it
you know you you go to the hacker news
you know or twitter or whatever you you
know every every month oh new library oh
well this is library is going fantastic
oh haska or whatever
but then you look into they they never
never ever
have this idea of this this thing you
are looking at wufang language
mathematica this thought this high level
never occurred to them
when they see it their brains like oh oh
that's fun and then then that's it
by tomorrow they forgot all about it on
the other hand the opengl webgl you know
100 lines to do a cube they are excited
oh pixels you know [ __ ] idiots so i
in part i blame
is it possible to have a technology or
game engine is it possible to have a
game engine or 3d graphics api that that
is high like high level where one line
you know just one single line does a
rotating cube yes
it is possible but why does why
why didn't it never happened
you know in my personal experience of 30
years or 20 years of computing why
why is no you never see it because
i would say the the the most fundamental
reason is social is the the way industry
software industry works and they and
these things are deeply tied to the cpu
the gpu hardware as well
so in america
the computer system developed in america
in america system basically you have the
um
capitalism you know a type of capitalism
so basically money money talks money
decides what technology you're gonna
have what kind of technology you are not
going to have money and also it's
immediate you know it's like not long
term you know it's like so
in this system in this social capitalism
system in usa i believe that is the
reason why that is the most important
reason why
today to this day you don't have a high
level
uh computer graphics engine or system
you know
this is one you know you know this thing
i'm talking about you can consider it
one of my biggest gripe
in software industry you know 20 years
ago
you know i've been coding wufang
language since 90s you know i know this
you know i i the very first cube i draw
like that is like
1992 1993 okay but back then you cannot
rotate it you
the rotation feature in uh language be
started in 2006 i think okay
anyway
so back then i know this but but then i
gradually started to code you know pearl
you know the unix you know i got into
web programming and unix tar emacs you
know
web servers apache database you know i
started to get into you know industry
programming but why but it puzzles me
greatly
i want this where do i find this this
technology other than just wufong
language where can i find it
you don't you talk to all the
programmers they don't understand what
you're talking about
they say
just just learn go like i mean just
learn open gl that that you know
governor or today webgl
they they don't understand this c
c sharp you know c plus plus java
programmers they don't know they don't
understand this concept that that deeply
puzzled me
deeply pursued me for like for 20 years
okay
now now i'm getting old
and this question when i was younger i
now know the answer well
well because the industry okay so part
of it
is the industry the reason the social
reasons you don't have this technology
and the other reason is
i blame the eunuchs idiots the unix
[ __ ] okay the unix and c
programmers
every day they are like dribbling about
memory about int and float
they are excited about it and today
the the version is it's represented by
the rust fanatics rust people
they love it
they love this kind of thing they don't
they don't understand this this high
level they don't they don't care
it's not they don't they don't
understand it oh yeah that's nice that's
it
the [ __ ] idiots
so
that is why so i've been trying to i
wanted to learn if if someone can teach
me you know you guys who asked that
question
um the dude okay so if you go to discord
you know if i would be very interested
you know teach me i have a lot of
questions but just answer my questions
you know i
guide me hand by hand
how
you know how how the game engine works
i love it i would love it okay but
i just never did okay
so that is the um that is um
that is the um that's about the 3d about
the game engine in my experience yes and
i'm getting old you know i'm not i don't
know if i can if you can teach me that's
great
but i'm getting old i got lots of other
things to do i want to know more about
you know differential geometry um
you know lots of lots of proof proof
systems
uh in you know proof mathematics you
know proof theory and so on
yeah that's too bad okay so that's one
thing so back to uh let's go back to the
a brief system shall we
so i was talking about a brief system so
i was talking about steno okay steno
that leads to a brief system
so in my opinion
today we can have a system that does not
require a steno machine
no
no this thing i despise you know the
keyboard you know the do you know the
computer keyboard
emulation of the steno machine such as
this one
this one is also from oh this one is
from resi rez is a great member of our
discord thanks to razi and thank you you
know thank you many guys many of you
donated
if you like my videos you know donate
okay
i'm i'm no longer
you know lingering around death by
hunger you know that was so 20 years ago
i'm no longer but i would appreciate you
know if you like my stuff and pay me
paypal and
patreon and so on i have links on my
website okay
so
so i was talking about so that's uh 3d
graphics okay so then steno so
so so i don't like you know so there's a
lot
community around steno that
tries to use the computer keyboard
especially planck okay let me show you
where is the blank
especially the blank keyboard
okay so
so i give reasons why i don't think this
is good okay i mean she she's a she's a
creator
marrow by knight
she's the creator one of the creator
prover which is a system
which is a stainless system
however you can type it with a regular
keyboard you know usually um
usually the do-it-yourself prank was
where is my do i have a photo here i
must have a photo here
i mean i need a link to it where is it
i don't have a link i'm not going to
show it but it's on my website you know
the plank keyboard actually i want to
show it okay so let's go to okay okay so
you click on do it yourself
then you scroll down
you scroll down
and you started to see
then you scroll down more you can see
this non-ergonomic so this one is prank
keyboard it's one of the do it yourself
keyboard very popular super popular
among the do-it-yourself nuts
a lot of you guys
and and this keyboard i despise it
[ __ ] the most idiotic design
but you know a lot of you like it love
it and you started to use these look at
she's demo you know she
she you know proved you know you you use
this keyboard
to type steno using the prover system
okay so
you know she says video you can watch
you know this this video is uh
seven years old 80 years old by now
you know plank okay so
so that's my complaint about steno okay
although i don't know it too well i
don't know it well
but i think
i think they are
i believe this potential for
alternatives that uses a normal keyboard
but it's not based on the signal okay
so that is a
that that is why i'm talking about
shorthand system by the way if you want
to know about
steno and emily's stuff emily
you know uh
one of our great person in our group you
join the steno
discord okay the prover okay so
it's a vibrant community
you know emily is here often i believe
you know so
say no they talk about all kind of
standard things they also talk about
alternative keyboards such as do it
yourself keywords
which i
okay so for example miscellaneous input
let's show it
okay so for example many of these
keyboard are designed for steno this guy
who sent me
georgie kibo is also a great guy
okay george kibo where is he
anyway so you can buy this to it
yourself you know buy it from his
company
uh
you know from g boards you know heavy
industries g heavy industry you can you
can buy it from them and they sell
several others you know
um
but anyway so
steno okay
and turns out i don't like you know i i
i don't find zeno to be
a great you know i think i think i mean
i think there's a great potential for a
normal keyboard
to be able to type very fast like 200
words per minute
but without the whole standard thing and
you can learn it in let's say three
months i be three maybe half a year i
think okay
so let me just quickly finish okay
oh god there's a bug with the
so this
so
so what is such shorthand actually it's
not shorthand
so i'm gonna talk about such short hand
um
so start your hand you know if you don't
know shorthand system
let me let me show you okay
okay let's go to my website
search for xrd unicode you scroll down
okay
you scroll down
scroll down more
you'll see
deseret okay and you'll see cheviot let
me show you okay
so this red
this is desolate alphabet this is the
system invented in 1847
by by the moment moments
which is a phonetic based english
alphabet so you use this alphabet to
write english
but however it's not
it's
it is phonetic based that means each
sound each one of these character
they represent a sound so
so this page you know this red alphabet
explains the detail
there is a wikipedia article
there's a wikipedia my my wife just came
home i told her to go this week this
wikipedia article i've been talking
already an hour okay
okay we we are we need to wrap up okay
so this wikipedia article
about this red as well this red alphabet
you can read about it okay so so here is
how it looks like so
uh the little star trinkle twinkle
little star this is how it looks like in
dessert okay let's magnify
there it is okay
so
this desert alphabet is a phonetic based
system
and created in in 1847
then we have a chevian alphabet which is
created in 1960
it is also a phonetic system for english
so
you know so you are looking at it and
with this system you will be much more
efficient
you'll be faster you know if you imagine
you map your keyboard to this uh i
believe there are you know you map your
yeah they are you know you can they are
chevy and communities and so on so you
can
study it join it and you can start type
type chevy and so it's
phonetic
system for english okay
and uh
has many advantages because english
spelling system english turns out the
most became is one of the most idiotic
spanish system the spelling doesn't
correspond to the
to the pronunciation
you know maybe a little bit 50
so for example women women women you
know
and so on
so anyway so you have phonetic system
and the chevium alphabet is based on one
of the it came from the origin the
history
the impetus of the chavan alphabet is
based on what's called a
pitman shorthand system okay
you know
so we are talking about history so you
are looking at pitman shorthand system
so this shorthand system is designed for
handwriting you know back then you know
not like today you have computer
keyboards so
for writing by hand however it's a
shorthand system so you each one of
these strokes represent a particular
uh
phonetics you know the pronunciation of
english
for phonemes okay so pigment shorthand
system then
so this is the basis of the
champion alphabet okay so it allows you
to write much faster than than the
normal scripting you know english
okay so that's a shorthand system so we
have a history of it and that's not all
so if you look at if you look
if you read wikipedia
okay you read wikipedia let me show you
okay
english
spelling reform
okay
that's a
sizable article okay
english spelling reform it talks about
quite a lot
spelling reforms in english
from which
chevy and alphabet
and there's this red are part of it you
know they they are they are a particular
type of spelling reform by replacing the
entire english alphabet
you know so so some of them are mild
reforms some of them are just replace
the whole [ __ ] english latin alphabet
throw them away
some of them are mild and there are many
others so it takes days to read them
i've been reading them since like 10
years ago
you know it's and and there's links to
what two particular ones so there's
there's lots of spending reforms so
so essentially
so i have so i kind of have the idea
where so you can see some of my um
let me go here okay
let's see
let me finish the topic okay basically
so that's that's what my son you know
it's dramatic name sasha then system but
actually i haven't really designed it
yet i'm just like gradually you know do
it one by one a little bit you know so
the idea is that you should just type
you know for example represent okay for
example this okay so i type rip to type
represent rps
so that's the idea so i believe
i'm not hundred percent sure but i
believe this
can become a practical system
that will make you safe typing make you
type 100 or 200 words
a minute
without so much learning time
so i started to do it but i have a lot
to do you know i need to go through
first first thing you i need to do from
what i see
is that i need to
find all the
condense the english pronunciation to
two kind of phonetic system such as
chavian
there are many others okay there's also
uh called unifon you know there's quite
a few the
the english spelling reform quite a few
so go through them
classify or gather you know all the you
know pronunciations then
then you have to
map them into the latin alphabet you
know i i don't think i'm going to design
you know i'm not going to use a
different you know alphabet and just map
them to
so you don't have to spend so much time
to learn it you know
so
use the kind of standard
representation of pronunciation you know
kind of so this is a lot to do so that's
a basic idea about
social hand system
so
i'm thinking maybe i can create a github
project because i'm getting old so if i
do it myself you know maybe take a year
or two
and i don't get paid you know i need
money to survive so i can't just do this
so
but maybe i can start a github so
so i have a design so first of all
there's a design about this so like how
do you do it okay so first of all
you go through the dictionary i
explained somewhere on github on discord
okay you go through the english
dictionary
you find the frequency of each and every
word which is very easy to do you know
today with computers you can write a
python program or ruby or or whatever in
in few hours you know you you want to
know the frequency of each every word in
english dictionary
then
for each word you
remove
their um not their vowels okay so for
example represent is just rps
okay
then
you do that for every each and every
word
then you
rank all the words by their frequency
you know these are articles you can find
in english word frequency okay you rank
them so for for those
at the top most frequently used words
uh for example they are
so i have some of them here
uh you know these are the most
frequently used word okay
about after because actually this
you know
this end
there you me those are more frequently
used of you know of you know i mean
anyway then these are second second most
frequent anyway anyway so you rank all
words by their frequency of use
then for each word you count number of
letters you approve them to you know
remove the vowel then
there are many words whose abbreviation
will be identical
okay so for the identical identical ones
you pick the one to represent the one
that's the most frequently used
okay so basically you have an elementary
system like that
and
just like that
we'll speed up your typing by twice
i would say you know twice and also we
haven't get into phrases yet for example
how are you today how are you today
that's a very common uh
phrase so
you might want to give a a brief how are
you today you know h-i-u-t so you type
that it is expand to how are you today
let me show you okay
so for example
huh
are you today so you make it
that just
hurt okay evaluate now i type h-r-u-t
how are you today so that's a huge
saving you know that's
four key strokes becomes 20 key strokes
you know so when you have a sentence you
know the most frequently used sentence
you save
by 10 times by 20 times okay
so you you besides was you want to get
the most frequently used phrase like two
words phrase
like how do you how do you is very
common how do you do something how do
you do you know oh what is what is very
common
so for example for my for me
so if i want to type what is i just type
ws okay what is okay so
so that's the basic idea about xa
shorthand system
so this system is designed for typing on
a computer keyboard using today's
technology
and this
and you see this already in your phone
the word completion you know usually
like words oh there are certain words
that always follow some other words very
frequent so you have you know so that's
idea okay
okay that's it for today anything else
okay pay me guys okay and let me read
some of the comments so is that
explanation one hour explanation about
sasho tan system satisfactory
to you
the dude who asked it
legion wait who who is it
yeah the legion asked that okay
is that okay you don't know
donate that's the main thing okay
you know i'm not gonna like like my
videos and and [ __ ] like that you know
just pay me
so i talked about 3d graphics systems
gaming systems okay
from the dude the question
okay that's it for today thank you guys
are you from the linux community are you
from the linux community well watch my
videos more and you are now
still here you can learn game
programming through unreal engines blue
printing system
no i need someone to teach you okay i've
been
i have been a self-taught man in my life
i did never
took any class of programming
you know i learned everything english
programming everything you know so
if i really want to learn
the unreal engine or how to program game
i can
but
but that means you know i stopped doing
some other things such as my you know my
shorthand system which is i'm far more
interested on mathematics you know so
you have you do this you cannot do that
okay so
if i really really really i must
learn
how program how gaming system works how
do 3d graphics works yeah i can i'll
i'll dedicate my life a month or two
into it
i don't know
but you know i'm getting old i got two
other things that's more interesting to
me so but if someone of some of you can
teach me that that's a great time saver
okay just you know
you know so dude the dude says well when
you know geometry and math you will do
really well in game programming yeah
that's not really
not really you know just like
the game engine you know i kind of know
you know the opengl they are not about
math at all in fact
in fact you learn just like the unix
commands okay you know you guys familiar
with the unix command line
find ls grab each one has like 10 000
options and they are incompatible they
are not consistent you have to
each one of them is ad hoc just like c
and c plus first
one [ __ ] one bunch of garbage
not well designed you dive into and then
you read documentation but this lousy
you know bad documentation and
many of them half of it there's no
documentation
that's what it is learning game
programming engine that i can i kind of
know
it's not about math i know the math
already i know
linear algebra i know differential
geometry i know you know lots of
part of discrete geometry you know but
game programming programming in general
is not about math okay
okay that's it for today
and back to what i'm saying so what i
want is this system okay this high level
system but you is nowhere to be found
and you guys you know i asked you know
no nobody mentioned this kind of i am
this is what i want okay
and there is a similar system for this
coming up okay i i have a blog about it
about
uh for example
sally game engine
let's see what article you'll show up
okay not there okay so
alexa d 3d graphics programming
okay here's an article i wrote back in
where i tried to you i tried to get into
java to do
gui you know graphics and
god
after several hours you know to write a
sim simple button or menu you got 100
200 300 [ __ ] lines of code java
this is 2007 you know java oak
swing
you know the gaming system is like that
it's far worse you know i also you know
so i study you know gtk
qtk that's
that's the gui part of graphics then you
have the 3d programming okay i looked
into mensa you know mesa open gl direct
3d
incomprehensible to me
you know it's like c and c plus like
bunch of idiotic crap
then you know i i i read a lot i'm
studios studious you know you have
graphics graphics pipeline you have to
know that graphics pipeline scene graph
space partitioning shader level of
detail you know this [ __ ] idiotic
[ __ ] z buffering anti-aliens in
anti-aliasing after composing [ __ ] f off
of their ass
mipmap texture mapping bump mapping
you know this extremely idiotic [ __ ]
you know these are these mathematics i
know differential geometry my friend
i know computational geometry my friends
but none of these are then this is this
[ __ ] crap that's what you do 3d game
you know there back then you know 2007
guys 2007 then i looked into game
engines you know because i want to know
you know i want you know i don't want to
just work in wufang language which is
great but i want you know real 3d games
where i can
you know but then you have to look into
then this j monkey engine you know many
many of these are probably dead by now
it's crystal space it's ogre 3d
you know
open source you know game nothing is
blender game blender and whatever that
is
pronounced and you know so i look and
there's also then physics engine which
is another thing
oh god so i spent time reading wikipedia
it's mostly incomprehensible and open
source they'll say oh goger is the
easiest
it turns out you know they are
all kind of the low level thing
um
i like to learn but
probably i'll never
pass on you good morning good evening
good good good good eve good morning eve
to germany
and bye guys so today is 80 minutes
so today we talked about game engine
computer graphics
and a brief system stay now okay
summarize we're gonna shut down in one
minute okay
shut down in one minute today's random
talk random chat relax
so what's going on like saw discord is
are you guys watching
so the chaos you know my life chaos
well that would be great dude so come in
and participate in a chat we have lots
of we have all sort of people here you
know so also the people on all kinds of
things all opinions
um
[Music]
so if you join i'll be great you know
but i am not gonna you know don't friend
me don't add me as a friend or don't
like don't hold me
as the center because i got a celebrity
problem you know like there's hundreds
of you i mean that's that's unpleasant
to say but that's true you know i don't
know i don't remember you guys i don't
know who you are really
that's too bad but you want
you know so unless you use your
one of them one of the things i
recommend is use your real name like our
friend dion fantastic guy
great guy from uk
and many others okay i'm not gonna go
over so you know use your real name and
go on chat sometimes we have online
voice party you know voice party where
we chat to each other in real life and
sometimes uh video
so anyway
i know andrew and andrew is um
you know a friend who
joined our chat often
so we know each other many of them so
yeah that's so let's start disco so bye
guys
bye bye
so the etymology so we talked so let me
clean up i'm closing down in one minute
okay so i'm just gonna
copy my articles and put on to my talk
show
keyboard close
because
talk show yes
close copy the url back to emacs paste
it here
and what is the image magic okay showing
browser that's the topic we talked about
it's not a brief system okay i need to
write about
xr short
hand system
okay because
what is this 3d engine okay
close
english language spanning reform okay
pitman shorthand system
close
chevion alphabet
paste okay
actually put it here
chevy and alphabet
close
deseret alphabet created by the moments
because
unicode fantastic spread my links okay
thank you guys if you want if you like
my stuff
pay me okay
and recommend my links that
also helpful so
heavy industries keyboard that's great
google keyboard for example
uh so we are talking about standalone
systems
close
so here's blank keyboard the most
popular do it yourself
is a canvas s versus svg
let's paste it here
let's make a link
okay some of them not
linked what is this okay so actually
what
okay i need to fix uh okay i need to fix
my i've been reworking my html code
excite html mod
canvas versus svg
standard type machine paste link yeah
stupid windows
image magic tutorial
emacs i don't care close that a brief
mod i command let's copy that
that's it bye
i'm going to have dinner
you