Hello, good morning, good evening
everyone. We are going to do advent of
code 2025
uh in Wuam language 2025 advent of code
day three problem one if you are here
say hi love to see your comments if you
are not here play at 1.5 speed minimum
okay so let's just start coding okay wam
language if you don't know yet I have
done hundreds of videos in the past of
introduction and download where to
download and complete tutorial just
search for it wam language for
programmers you can see complete
tutorial from the ground up
okay and that's a wam language is a
magnitude more high level than all
existing programming languages
okay so so let's begin advent of code
number uh day three so we go back to
this advant of code idiotic thing and
start wam language
let's see we'll code for an hour maybe
and let's see how far we can go or we
can finish it I'm a slow coder as I code
I talk I tell you my uh analysis about
whatever things okay so new notebook
three shift enter to evaluate it and
start the kernel and let's magnify.
Okay, so we got three. So let's see.
So far so good. Video check, audio
check. Okay,
say hi. Okay, so you descend a short
staircase, enter the surprisingly vast
lobby, and are quickly cleared by the
security checkpoint. When you get to the
main elevators, however, you discover
that each one has a red light above it.
They are all offline. Sorry about that.
An elf apologizes as she tinkers with a
nearby control panel. Oh, it's a she.
She uh some kind of electrical search
seems to have fried them. I'll try to
get them online soon. You explain your
need to get further underground. Well,
you could at least take the escalator
down to the printing department. Not
that you'd get much further than that
without the elevators working. That is
you could if the escalators weren't also
offline.
Okay. So, they are uh what what is this?
The elevators and escalators. Okay. But
don't worry, it's not fried. It just
needs power. Maybe you can get it
running while I keep working on the
elevators. Okay, I'm confused. I don't
know what he's talking about.
Ching ACP.
Happy holidays. Thank you ACP. This is
my yearly donation. Fantastic.
Fantastic ACP.
So, so far I read a story, but I didn't
pay attention. But let's see. There are
batteries nearby that can supply
emergency power to the escalator for
just such a occasion. The batteries are
each labeled with their jage rating.
A value from 1 to 9. You make a note of
their jage rating. Your personal input
for example. So we got
all numbers. Okay.
So that's the input four numbers. The
batteries are arranged into banks. Each
line of digit in your input corresponds
to a single bank of batteries. Okay?
Each line of digits.
Okay? So you got four numbers. Each one
is a bank. Within each bank, you need to
turn on exactly two batteries.
Okay. The jage that the bank produces is
equal to the number formed by the digits
on the batteries you are turned on.
You've turned on. For example, if you
have a bank like 1 2 3 4 5 and you turn
on batteries two and four,
the bank would produce 24 jolts. Okay,
two and four. Okay, so you cannot
rearrange batteries. Okay. So each
sequence, each number you are given, you
are given four numbers. Each number
there are many digits
and apparently you can manipulate each
digit.
Each digit represent a battery
within each bank. You need to turn on
exactly two batteries. Okay? So you need
to pick two digits in this number. And
when you once you picked them you
combine those two digits that forms a
new number in this case 24 and that's it
that is the jolts
okay for this given sequence of digit
okay you need to find the largest
possible jage each bank can produce in
the above example. Okay this seems um I
looks like I understand already. So
given this number 98765
something something you can make the
largest jage possible 98 by turning on
the first two batteries. Okay. So you
just pick the first two digits 98 then
that forms the number 98 that is a jage
that's the largest possible. So
basically you want to pick
the first you you want to pick number
close to nine.
Okay let's see you can have 91. What's
let's see what's the priority. Okay you
can have 91 99. Uh maybe not
that's not available. You also can have
let's say
let's say you have five
um
well I don't know yet okay to pick two
numbers now in this 8111 something 9 you
can make the largest jage possible
possible by turning the batteries
labeled eight and nine okay
producing 89 js Okay, eight and nine.
So, let's see. One, how many digits are
there? RP. Uh, back to Emacs. Paste.
Select
15 characters. Wait. So, this is not
um
what?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight. Wait, how does that actually
count?
You got
15 digits there. Okay.
So then in this number you pick 78.
Okay. Then in this number you pick large
jage is 92. You pick. Okay. So here is a
tricky part 92. Okay. The total output
jage is the sum of the maximum jage from
each bank. So in this example the total
output outage jage is 98 + 90 89 + 78 92
equals to 357.
Okay, there are many batteries in front
of you. Find the maximum shortage
possible from each bank. What is the
total output?
So you just pick two digits out of them.
Their position doesn't matter. Just like
pick two digits. Okay? So you just pick
two digits.
So let's let's let's let's
begin to do this problem.
Okay.
Language code.
Um
so what is the problem? So make them a
comma.
Okay.
Um
then
input you got these four numbers. Okay.
So but so let's say this example you
pick two numbers. So 81 what about 88?
Oh you can also have 89.
So you need to pick two numbers. So
there is interplay. So uh the first
biggest number. So
so you could have a um well the you know
we we need to figure out the algorithm.
So you could have
nine
So first step you find the biggest
number. So that's nine. The second step
is you find a number that's after you
pick a digit after the digit you picked.
So in this case
uh 91 if you go by this algorithm. So
nine is the biggest then
second biggest I mean then the biggest
after nine would be uh two
so this would be 92
okay so it's actually correct
so there's no big deal you just pick the
biggest digit first
then you pick another digit after that
after that digit. Okay. Now
complication. What if you
what if you have a number let's say nine
uh let's say a9.
Let's say three 2 a9. Okay. You pick the
biggest one that's nine.
But there's no more digit to pick. So
you can pick nice. So So first step.
Okay. So let's write it out
steps.
First
pick the largest
uh uh okay largest digit in the number
but not the last one. Okay, you cannot
pick the last one.
Then
pick the largest digit after the digit
you picked
from the digits that
that is after the digit you picked.
Okay. So that is the algorithm.
Looks like that's it. Is that it?
If that's it, it's pretty simple. Uh,
but are there special cases? What if
there's zero? Um,
okay. I don't I don't I don't
um
anyway that that Yeah, it looks like
that's the algorithm. Okay, let's work
on it. So,
even a number hold on a second. I gotta
go.
I'll be right back.
Hello guys, I'm back.
Hello guys, I'm back. That's a long
delay. So what happened is that
I'm going to stop this video. So we need
to do this again. Okay.
Um
yeah. So that was a 30 minutes delay or
something. So let's do this another day.
Thank you guys for being here.
Bye guys.