welcome to another episode of s talk
show today we are going to code emag LP
emag LP coding and if you have questions
ask me okay so I'm just going to code IM
mag and uh and have a
drink this is red wine half red wine
half apple juice
cheers my keyboard this is glove 80
fantastic keyboard This is Ultimate
hacking keyboard fantastic keyboard This
is newa n u l EA track B fantastic this
is my main Mouse that's Logitech
g502 I think sometimes now I use it for
the spin wheel the spin wheel okay
that's my keyboards okay let's let me
show you my
screen so today emac BP and if you have
questions comments and uh post it okay
let me type it today main topic is emac
dis
coding if you have any questions ask now
if it's not related to emac emac then
maybe I'll answer next time but maybe
I'll answer today we'll see okay if you
have not already join my my Kar Discord
and
join Kar
Twitter Lusk x.com
ons.info you can see all my links on
Twitter on Discord here
okay so what so what is it you're going
to code today so let's begin coding yeah
it looks like it's going to be a lonely
night so I'm just going to code so start
a emac bisp and I'm going to tell you
what I'm going to do uh defund not
delete file defund so I'm going to write
a
command this command will be
named
uh show duplicate links okay so in a
HTML page uh let me show you talk so let
let's see let's see you see this is my
programming blog lots of things and
uh uh let's go to emac emac blog okay so
you can see can you see it yes you can
see this is my emac blog and there's so
many
pages so sometimes I need to
know if a link is duplicated here so for
example I might have this link some
somewhere in the body and I don't want
to repeat so so I need so given a HTML
page such as this I need to gather all
the links and uh see if any one of them
is duplicate
duplicated okay so that's what I'm going
to
write okay so let's close that close
that close that close that let's
document uh uh print any duplicate
links in a
HTML file in a current HTML file okay so
that's a
documentation
important always write documentation in
fact that's my style of coding before I
code I have to think about like design
the interface what exactly it does and I
write the documentation first that is my
style some people I think half of the
people most people actually don't do
that they just start to try out and
error okay so so anyway so okay so that
so we got the structure scaffolding down
uh we going to start to code so given
HTML file you want to find all links so
first step is to get all links in a HTML
page okay
fortunately I already have a command for
example show talk show this is today's
page I for example I select
all uh let me show you the pink window
the pink window shows all my command
Calles and
uh and key press you can see command
names on the right side and key press on
the left side I'm using softly keys
excuse me S Keys the most efficient key
mining system for
emac okay that's Sly
keys and I'm using a v keyboard so on
the left side all the keys are borak so
anyway for for example I can delete this
paragraph press enter delete uh you know
paste delete delete delete paste or you
know I can move to um you know delete an
element for
example let's say delete that element
and do so you can see all the command
names are there and the keystrokes on
the pink window okay so so for example I
have let me show you so for example talk
show I have a command to get all the
links extract all the links on the page
so first of all I need to select all
press the key it's done so you can see
the name the command name is HTML
extract URL now a new buffer paste it
you can see they nicely extract all the
links now go back to the page you see
the first link is this which is a CSS
file let me show the full Glory you see
the CSS file it's link there and uh you
uh and uh you see it actually shows the
full path so let you see this is a
relative link but it extract the link
and also expand to full path so that's
what this command
does this uh you know I just press one
key and did it uh I extract you where
did this scroll or something
it went all the way to the
top okay so back here yeah okay so
showing browser so you got all the links
now if the link is not a local link such
as this YouTube link you see then it
just you know return that link so this
is command is great so I once I got all
the links all I have to do is just find
the duplicate okay so the first thing to
do is extract link I'm just going to
call this command we already
have so we're going to call this command
let's see the
documentation okay so the full syntax is
this begin and begin and optional rout
okay
so we want so beginning and end are
beginning and end positions so we want
to design this show duplicate links
command such
that such that
um such that if you don't have a text
selection it uses the current block if
you do have a text selection use a text
selection okay so you need two variables
xp1 uh xp2 position one and two okay
so
okay
if region active uh region active P okay
so if region is active then uh let's set
okay set Q
uh actually let's use set SE set
sequence
okay and uh we want to set those two
arguments variables and uh we're going
to do this okay let's delete that so if
region active predicate if it's true
then
return return a
vector okay actually return
it doesn't matter uh let's return
Vector uh region beginning and the
region end that Returns the position
okay that's the
function so if region active then do
that if otherwise let's do the whole
page okay yeah let's just do yeah okay
so
um yeah so that that is more convenient
because usually I want to do the whole
page comments and
questions no okay
so whole region point mean Point Max
that's above a minimum position so point
mean would be here Point Max would be
here okay so that sets these two
variables okay now just let's just
extract uh okay beginning and xp1
xp2 optional
root uh root would be the
current and full
path uh okay so I want the full path
let's see do I want the do I want it to
return full path or not let's read the
documentation
fantastic okay
so root will be the current files
directory so okay
so so that variable is default directory
which is the usually whatever files
directory Parent Directory okay full
path true so I want it to return full
path Okay add a new variable
set links to be that
okay okay so we collected collect all
the links now all we have to do now is
to find the duplicate in the
links find the find the
duplicate okay typically you can do with
sort okay uh oh my God how do we going
to do this so you know there is a
command let's say TT
TT TS okay so there is a command in emx
such that you can find the duplicate
without having to
sorted and that command name is
called um
let's
see
uh okay a propose
duplicate delete duplicate lines okay
duplicate do what I mean duplicate the
current line or region n times oh I
didn't know this that command duplicate
Line tab duplicate okay delete duplicate
lines okay so you do have a delete
duplicate but you don't have a show
duplicate I don't think so not I know of
in emx let's look at delete duplicate
okay delete duplicate lines is auto
loaded okay you at beginning end delete
duplicate lines you see this command
will delete duplicate lines which is not
what we want
however this command may contain what we
want which is to identify the duplicate
lines you know we can look at how it
does so the begin and optional reverse
adjacent keep uh blanks okay in
active Okay so we can look at the code
see how it's done I I gather it's fairly
complex probably not something we can
use you see identical lines needs not be
adjacent
you see so this is very
convenient okay return number of delete
okay let's look at the source code let's
see okay documentation is long let's see
what we want to do is to see how it
does oh it makes a hash table
okay so if it's you know if you are
deleting lines without sorting them
first like not adjacent then you make a
hash table first let's see what what's
the key and value so they are using a
hash table for lines lines is a hash
table
so
um make so they use hash table to do it
right so so the key I suppose the key of
the hash table is the line text hash
table by the way if you don't know it's
like Python's dictionary it's just a
collection of key value pairs so you
have keys you know and each key has a
value you use the key as identifier so
wherever you know the keys always unique
so they use a hash table a collection of
key value p
which is like javascript's object or
Python's
dictionary uh and so what is the key
used here so we can see it's probably
the line okay
so count begin copy marker
begin comments and questions
so here it gets the line let's color the
line so you can call this command so all
the word all the identifier line will be
highlighted and that command you can see
is here highlight symbol at
Point okay so let's also color the first
line so now it's easier to
see so
so you have get hash
there now where's put
hash so there you have put hash put hash
adds the to the hash table get hash
returns a key it's value from a hash
table okay so let's
see so they make a they use a hash table
and uh
first line reverse uh setq first line
setq line equals to both of substring no
properties line beginning position line
and position so you you get the line if
keep blanks string something we don't
care if adjacent something something we
don't care then get hash there it is it
tries to see if the line is already in
the hash you see if if it is in the hash
then you see it deletes it delete
region otherwise then it checks you know
if it's adjacent
uh okay so yeah so it basically use a
hash to implement this delete duplicate
lines without requiring to sort it first
cheers okay that's nice what's next what
okay so that's the end basically that's
the end of program set marker with
interactive D lines
okay so the main idea we got from this
is the implementation it's using a hash
to Hash table to do it hello palash
backup first time catching this live
fantastic thank
you okay so we got this so you know the
idea is just using a hash table okay
yeah D duplicate lines so let's now
let's look at what we want to do okay so
we need to
find we need to make a report not not
find but
report any duplicate lines and
ideally we would also like to highlight
any lines that are duplicated you see
let me show overall so again in a HTML
file like this we want to collect all
links for example all the
HF you know all links such that their
file path is actually
duplicate so we call this command press
a key then we'll highlight all lines
that are duplicated okay fantastic okay
let's let's make a sample example so uh
for example let's just make
this
um make so you know let's put in some
duplicated lines so that
we and make sure they are not adjacent
you see now we have this line and this
line they are
duplicate and also okay let's try to you
know you see we only need to find the D
links not necessarily the tech text okay
so now
this and this are duplicate but and not
adjacent so that's also important so
this will be our test test case you see
this so we you want to write a command
press a key and you it will highlight
all those duplicate links okay that's
our goal so now back here that's our
code so what we want to do
so now I'm I'm I'm 20% drunk 10% I'm not
a drinker this is just 100 ml 100 m lit
of red wine
you need that to soothe my brain because
sometimes coding too much like all day
or reading too much
politics uh okay so we so what we going
to do so we first of all we got a bunch
of
links
and H
okay so actually maybe we don't want to
use this
command so one of the algorithm we can
use is just simply in HTML file we go
through
all link tags tags that contains a link
such as a tag anchor tag you know by the
way it's not just hrf
attribute but also include for example
um I mean it's not just anchor tags for
example also link tag and sometimes um
image files they have Source attributes
so it's the attribute is not necessarily
just hrf I mean it's more s
SRC source for image and others
too
so so first of all so okay so
one algorithm is
to is to go
through go to the top and find
each
link for example
href a href tag or image SRC tag and
there are others okay then
then for each what you do is
[Music]
you extract the link if it is
local then expand to full file
path known as absolute
path
okay then add it to
a hash
table
okay then find the next
link if
that link is already in hashtable
key added to Hash okay if that link is
already in hashtable key
highlight that link okay maybe we should
do that because if we use this command
extract URL it just return all the
extracted URL it doesn't give you you
know it doesn't tell you what position
it
is okay so we go with this we're going
to write this you know
fantastic so I hope you guys are
learning some emac this jupter
says what computer laptop do you use
okay that's kind of commonly asked
question all you have to do
isali
computer you'll probably find
it Kali LinkedIn I haven't updated like
my LinkedIn for 10
years uh s computer
Kali gears you know if you search for
chat GPT
onali you know if you just search for um
s gaming computer you'll find
it
uh there it isar gaming computer
2021 by the way I bought that this is my
current computer and I bought this
because you guys donation because
Andrew for $500 Allan for
$2,000 Allan okay on Discord you'll see
uh Allan okay Alan Alan Wang
goic that's the name he goes by right
now
$2,000 CH ching and uh
Dion Dion also gave me 250 over 20 over
like three years by patreon so Dion is a
big
patreon and there's also Lunas and
there's also Lunas and also the
Icelandic man and several others and
Chrystal you know uh smaller amount but
you know so this so there's Andrew
there's Allan there's Theon they gave me
a big amount donation so I bought this
computer in 2021 this is actually my
first good
computer and uh I'm still using it now
so that is my machine you know like it's
a common question among the you know
online people I mean like what what's
gear what uh you know they have a word
for it it's not gear it's the
um you know also it's a word musicians
use uh uh let's see let me think about
okay I'm slightly drunk slightly 20%
30% let's see what's the word they
um you know a Comm a normal normies word
would be set up so I mean so but I mean
to Linguistics and English
vocabulary so there's a special jargon
for pops you know like Gamers what is
your um what you know what is your gear
what is the word what is the word
guys
uh I can I I will remember it if I
really try in a
minute but I need to focus okay but is
uh
okay there's a better way that allows me
to find the jargon I'm looking for
faster
than than my you know just thinking
about it I'll find it if I really think
about it for a minute or two but a fast
way you know if I want just to
be practical you know let's just find a
word without you know any restrictions
the Restriction is supposed to be I
should you know really just think about
it and find it that would be best for my
live stream but but another practic way
practical way is just look up right away
so for example let me show
you uh
props okay so boom boom boom press three
keys and you'll get synonyms for props
okay
then you can see you can you know the
word will come
up what is word The Gamers you know that
you know there's power station there's
battle station but there's a uh like
music musicians usually use it
uh
gig I think it's a uh is it gig okay no
wait peripherals no accessories no those
are two formal daily driver no
no come on guys like rig rig rig is the
word my
friends my
friends rig okay press press press okay
actually you know so you know you see
the power of emac I look up web by the
way if you want that describe function
lookup web you have two pay
calup you know this is the my package
calup you have all these oh Fantastic
look up street map on Google Map look up
Google look up
atmology look up what def word
definition look up Chinese character
look up all dictionaries okay by the way
the so okay so let me show you I have
infinite amount of things to show Sala
package pay me and you'll get
it and by the way it's open source just
like Richard stowman you have to pay him
to to get emac in the early
days the first 10 years or like send me
you know what was it $100 or something
then he sent you emac fox Richard
storman okay so rig let's look up
definition rig
you know that's
uh I believe First the musicians use
this what's your rig okay to let's see
to provide with a harness or equipment
fit out okay to equip a ship with sales
shrouds and yards oh so I think
originally this Jon came from nautico oh
exactly right rig you know RI you know
nautico you know you know selling is a
big thing you know that was a big thing
you know you have the cells and lots of
gears masts and yards you know lots of
JG nautical jargon okay so I I think the
the word rig originally came from
nautical
jargon then the musicians and Gamers you
know start to use it like what's your
rig am I am I right does that make sense
H coming in groups okay gaming rig yeah
yeah yeah daily driver okay so what's uh
what's a
question uh very nice what computer
laptop do you use okay first time catch
okay is I thought I saw emac question
okay does emac dis have a pre-build hash
table yeah of course hash
table uh okay so I guess you are not
familiar with my emac tutorial you
should just go to emac then you'll go to
emac
this then there's a full chapter well a
section about data structure well a
chapter uh let's say lisp Basics then a
chapter
about list data structure so you have
list Vector sequence type and hash table
so you can learn all about it hashtable
in emac thisp okay now back to code
let's get back to
code so yeah the question is about my
rig my my computer you know
so I have this article not just this
article but you can find other articles
such as my monitor okay this is the best
monitor this monitor Asus okay then you
can find my
keyboards my padle station now this is
kind of my current with glub 80 and
there it is kesis 360 with ultimate
hacking keyboard and there it is
automate hacking
keyboard
double dual
wield aing keyboard okay and then then
you have you know the kesis then you
have others okay so that's
the OBS Studio reconnection successful
what the
okay let's get back to code okay so
I let's write finish writing this so
I've been 33 minutes yeah we can finish
it in in 10 minutes or so if I hurry I
can finish it in five minutes but let's
take it slow okay any more question s
okay so we want to write hash table okay
yeah actually so we do
need I myself need to read about the
hash table because I don't remember so
emac dis Basics then go to Hash table
data structure hash table fantastic okay
okay what I need Okay so let's just
follow this algorithm okay follow follow
it and you will find the
treasure okay
so go to CH go to
CH Point meme that goes to the beginning
of buffer then uh find each link for now
let's just find href okay so search for
word HF equals
to equals to
you know uh double colon I mean double
quote okay then bound we don't care uh
well bound NE we don't care no error
true because sometimes a web page may
not have any link but actually all my
page has a link at least one okay so you
search for word you find the link then
once you find link find the link you
want to
extract whatever the h e
f you see what whatever the value for
the href attribute okay it's a technical
jargon for
HTML this so the for example um for
example this is a
list this a is a anchor
tag this a character is called a tag
name but the whole thing is called HTML
element okay the the things inside it is
called uh for example this this is
called attribute so we have HF attribute
then we have this data access attribute
those are called customized
attribute okay if you don't know you can
find my HTML tutorial then you can learn
all about it okay and CSS and so on okay
so anyway let's go back it's not waste
time so what we doing uh okay
so so search forward for
hrf right let's just do that one so once
you find it you want to add you know you
want to add it as a URL I mean extract
the link okay uh so we don't want links
okay
so so let's call this this quickly
because I got to I got to get this done
instead of you know so okay so X URL
okay so let's just X URL so set X URL
equals to uh thing at Point okay
uh uh What
uh yeah we let's write this quickly uh
bounce of thing at Point Okay so URL
okay so not URL so actually we just file
name okay that will get the beginning
and end positions of a file name inside
inside the hrf value okay so you set
that to so instead instead instead of X
URL let's rename
it X link okay because you know it's
easier
Jon okay so you you uh actually this is
not the link this is the position okay
so okay
so X begin and X end
then God uh God too much okay so
let me just write it boundary okay so
setq boundary that's what this thing
returns then set X
begin is car expounder okay then set
xn is
c x boundary okay so that's a beginning
and end position of the file name okay
then then you then you set X link
to um both of substring no properties
okay then X begin X end so ultimat this
X link is
the you know is a value for
href
attribute okay you know uh the mouthful
here uh there there are simpler ways but
you know but I have to use my own
function but if I use the bounds of
things at Point that's more Universal so
everyone can understand that because
that's part of emac because you can
describe function and you can see the
documentation it's part of
emac uh but yeah but you then you have
to you know get a boundary then do car
and cter to extract the positions and
then extract the text okay so anyway
that's that that that okay so so so now
you just basically you just get
uh
um you just get you know this code block
the only purpose is just to get the link
okay now we can rewrite it okay so let
me show you how to rewrite it so uh
rewrite it is yes okay so uh in a much
more kind
of more better style okay let me show
you okay
so there okay so you see there are two
styles to write this one is this let you
declare several variables But ultimately
you just want the xlink you want you
want to set it okay the other way is is
like that is like this but but you know
in the first step you just say set so
the code becomes clear what you are
doing then whatever complexity you know
you declare variables local variables
temporarily then you get the boundary of
the beginning and end position then you
you know then you get the position then
you extract it so the final result is
set to X link okay so this is more this
style is a better Style style
okay now that's a side note on lisp in
general this applies to other
lisps okay so now we got a link what
next then we need to push this link into
a hash table okay okay first of all we
need to declare a hash table okay this
so let's declare a hash
table uh here okay link table
okay there beautiful okay so you decare
a local variable link table how do you
do it let's look up emag list Basics
what is this HTML tutorial there hash
table
okay okay let's just copy
that uh set here we don't need there
okay so basically that okay so that okay
so that
will
uh link let's say let's call links table
okay so make a hash table so now that's
a hash table okay now
let's now we put this link into the hash
table but before we do that we need to
check if it's already there so okay so
get hash okay get has is a function that
checks your key is already in a hash
table any comments and questions okay no
am I still like alive and kicking check
I've been talking for 43
minutes uh looks like like I'm still
going
yes yeah that looks fine yeah let's go
back to code okay so
now get hash so the table is that the
table is that the key will be xlink okay
get this key from this hash
table uh and default we don't care so we
want to say if if the key is there if it
is
so then we got a problem well not a
problem you know if the key is already
there that
means this you know this L is duplicate
so we want to highlight it so let's
highlight it so let's let's
comment okay that's what we need to do
now if it's not already there we added
there okay so put hash so that's how you
add a key so
xlink uh not that uh
wait X so put this xlink as key to the
hashtable xlinks table
okay clear you know clean purify the
code so that's what we want if the keys
already there highlight the link if it
is not then you add it to the hash table
okay fantastic in fact I think it's
almost done
so so our whole code is like almost done
let's let's make it compact
okay uh so let's make it compact so that
you can
see so that people can
[Music]
see find each
link that's what the algorithm find
each link
then for each extract the link if it's
local then expand to find absolute
path then okay then add it to the hash
table
check if the path is in hash
table if
so highlight the
link else add to Hash table okay
repeat to next link okay that's kind of
uh I
didn't I just rewrite that the no
effect there okay so kind
of okay so anyway
then so you know one thing we need to do
we need to make this a while loop okay
so
while we need to make this a while loop
okay so while
search there then do all these things
okay okay then remove this extract we
don't need okay so in fact that's the
whole code okay so let's now
compact
compact there it is fits in one
page comments and questions what is the
advantage of using Windows over Linux
okay uh I'm not going to answer that
because that being answered a thousand
times in
particularly Maybe three month ago just
search for YouTube like Windows versus
Linux you'll find it talked about it
many many times greeting from Egypt abto
hi I think I remember you why do you
define the with let and then set the
value set Q L later you can just use set
Q to Define and set at the same
time you mean you can just use Le to
Define yeah that's a style issue okay
so uh
basically you know in I explained this
before but basically it's better if you
use set Q set outside of the let unless
it's one simple setting like that one
otherwise it's usually better because
later on when you add a code if you have
all the settings of a variable inside
the lead then the order matters because
you cannot you know if you have a
variable whose value depends on
previously declared variable then you
make you need to make sure they are
happens later also you need to change
the lead to a lead star things like that
so it gets you know it's much simpler
and easier if your let declaration is
simply variable names except
you know we have one exception here you
know it's just one very simple value
okay so
that's that's what I prefer after you
know after 10 years of coding in this at
one time I I started to you know
actually don't use any let and use let
Star so all my variables are defined
within the lead then you know anyway
that's a style issue not too important
okay so any did I anything okay so let's
finish this okay so almost done so we so
double
check go to the purose beginning go to
the beginning of file then search for
hrf then set the link okay it's so set
the link so we we need to expand the
file name okay remember
uh let me explain okay so we need to
expand the file name for example this
file name we need to expand to the full
path so for example this file name
should be that because if you don't do
that then this same link can be
um can be you see this two lines refer
exactly to the same file wait uh what is
it hold on
second uh for example let's say you see
here here you see this file this line
and this line refers to exactly the same
file however they have a different value
for the local link you see that is the
reason you want to expand them to the
full path otherwise because these two
are actually duplicate because otherwise
you won't be able to find when you know
there to let's put it there okay so did
that so go back so so now you need to
expand the file name okay how you do
that you do it like this
okay uh so beginning okay so per sub
string no properties so that's the value
then you want
to
uh expand file name okay expand file
name okay I think that's just that
okay and the path with respect to is
um is default directory okay
there okay so
so grab the link expand to the full path
so now let's rename it to full
path uh
okay we got some more things to do
because we also need
to yeah okay let actually this will be
fine uh well actually no because when
you see when you have a link that's HTTP
for example this thing then you cannot
expand it
but because it's not the local link but
what happens if you expand it I don't
think there's any harm so let's try
expand file name this
URL evaluated it no okay har is done it
becomes you know C user so that's not
good so that's not
correct okay so you need to add a little
condition here if um string
match so if string match let's say it
begins with let's say
HTTP
[Music]
then then don't do anything
okay uh okay what is your string uh so
actually okay so we actually need to do
more things
here uh okay let's say
you X HF V
okay
so set the value of HF to be this meat
then if HF match
HTTP
then then just return hrf value
otherwise is you need to otherwise it's
a local file path we assume then you
need to expand it okay then just return
it okay so now that's a bit more
complex okay
so okay so this is the full file
path or Ed okay so proper name should be
hrf value because it's not necessarily a
file path but anyway
so so then we try to get the hash to see
if it's
there um let's rename it URL okay yeah
let's rename it X
URL uh let's rename it xlink back to
xlink diding with the naming of things
okay so anyway so check if it's in the
hash if
it's so if it is not we need to
highlight it oh okay now if you need to
highlight it you need you need to know
the beginning and end position like
that you know beginning end so we cannot
do it here because you know that's the
local variable there
so what do you do okay so okay you need
to restructure the whole thing so the
whole let the whole value is available
to uh to this block of code yeah
restructure the whole thing
okay okay let's okay now watch me
restructure
okay okay so set link okay
so set link to
be okay so now we have this let whole
block oh okay so so
actually there there there there there
okay so we got this Leo block boundaries
X begin X and hre value boundaries X
begin hre value then possibly change it
to link depending if it's a HTTP URL or
a local file
path then that's the link okay then you
check the link is in the hash if it
is if it is in the hash that means it's
the duplicate then you highlight the
link okay how do you highlight the link
question well you all you have to do is
add a text property now this is when we
have to look into emac L writing color
comments uh text properties this is how
you add and we want to add text
properties actually we want to Overlay
highlight okay then I'll show you what
it
does there that's what we going to
do so we want to highlight the link
overlay put that's how you do it
beginning end that's a two positions so
X begin and X end that's two positions
and how how you want to highlight what
color I want uh face Bo no I want it red
you see I want it to be
passionate let's use the font lock
warning face okay so I want it like
Jesus W
okay okay prettyy it prettyy so it's
more readable
see
pretty uh what
put a comment
there so if it's already in a hash
highlight the link that's right
otherwise highlight the link and print
okay so I we I also want to print it
okay so not just highlight the
link but also print it to messages okay
so you want to print
xlink so you you want to say
duplicate
okay I think we are done
beautiful I'm thirsty I need to get
another drink see any comments
okay so I think that's it for our code
we can you know this is the whole code
for today print any duplicate print and
highlight
highlight and print any duplicate links
in current HTML file
Beau
uh actually there's one more thing we
like to do so once you know you know
usually your HTML page it may be long so
I can make a marker so that you cannot
press a key we jump to all the found
position duplicates but let's do that
dat okay but I believe this is the first
of all go to make a backup go to the
directory bu compile yes oh warning put
hash code without two argument but
requires three
okay uh put hash oh yeah we forgot the
value let's see put hash key value table
okay yeah so value value we don't care
is one okay
wait
[Music]
uh duplicate so if it's already in the
hash
table
sorry that must be some
jarring by The Chance by any chance are
you amb
dextrous techn technically no but being
ambid dextrous is one of my kind of
my obsession so I especially when I was
younger up to age 35 or 40 I have always
tried to do anything also with my left
hand so I have I can kind of write with
my left hand as well and I try to brush
my teeth with my left hand and so on so
but I'm not a natural and be
dextrous I mean does that actually exist
on there people who is naturally
ambidextrous meaning that their leftand
dexterity and their right hand dexterity
are
equal I'm not sure there's actually
that that's true maybe maybe very few
one
in 100,000 or a million
something there's lefties of
course so anyway that's our code uh so
now let's uh backup let's bite compile
successful fantastic delete it close it
evaluate the buffer now we can try it go
to a HTML wait what's the name I show
duplicate links okay go to HTML sort we
don't need go to okay so showing
browser so there is a
duplicate that and that okay now meta X
social duplicate links please let it
do yeah fantastic it seems
worked wait Jesus okay
no oh actually it did work you see these
two are duplicate it highlighted it
become red and go to the messages
bu uh oh this is actually
wrong it printed seven times but it
printed the same thing it should
actually print the link okay but
basically our code is somewhat working
okay uh somewhat not exactly something
is wrong you see this this and this are
not
duplicates yeah okay something so let's
go back let's double check some minor
error
okay
so if a
link so get hash so if it's
[Music]
already so if it's already in the hash
table then you highlight
it and print okay now what is the X
link okay I think I'll expand file name
yeah here is wrong so expand file name
of course you need the
link you need value not just you know
eval the buffer go back to c talk show
close it reopen it show the pink window
go back call the
command show duplicate links do it
fantastic you see it highlighted
correctly this one is dup cut you
see and uh then the fantastic job
complete fantastic okay job complete
that's fantastic beautiful code of
course this isn't mean you know we need
to clean up you know we need to do a
final check and clean up so every
Everything Is Beautiful it's already
beautiful
okay okay let's just pop it back
highlight it showing browser that's
today's
fruit the basic basic structure the how
to is already all here so hopefully
that's useful for you guys into emac and
emac this okay I think that's it for
today now let's do random chat for 2
minutes or three
sounds good does that sounds good how
many people watching
Four let me get a drink and we shut down
in two
minutes e
okay fantastic so this code yeah it
works and uh yeah it did work and let's
go to the message
buffer did it show there it is duplicate
and duplicate
fantastic okay great thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff you can of
course go to to talk show go to C code
and you can buy my emac
tutoral buy it
okay the best emac lisp tutorial out
there and you can also buy my JavaScript
in depth and the best thing is just
donate to me okay you know give me
uh $100
$50
cheers cheers bye
guys for