hello hello hello hello good morning
everyone welcome to another episode of
xr talk show
so today i'm going to code emacs lisp
and so i'm going to teach you emac list
okay and we are going to code a command
live
and this command is called space to new
line now let me demonstrate what that is
okay so for example you have a text
so uh so so you have you know uh lots of
text let's see
let's say that okay let's make them long
line one one big long line okay so
you know sometimes you got a long line
and you want you want to replace all the
space by a new line in other words you
want to um replace space by new line
like this okay so i call a command
done okay so you see now everything
every word basically is a new line now i
actually that's not a good example so we
are going to code that okay so
uh this is going to be 20 or 30 minutes
then after that i'm going to maybe uh
answer some questions uh for 10 minutes
let's see am i am i alive am i alive
alive and kicking video check audio
check okay good
okay so if you have a emacs questions
for me
ask me okay and uh donate don't forget
paypal me buy me a drink paypal patreon
whatever uh you know you can find the
link on my website
be a sponsor you know today's show is
sponsored by you
okay so uh so
space to new new line so let me show you
an example where this makes sense the
most okay so uh if you're a programmer
you need to you need this often so let
me show you where
uh wait
okay
done okay so let's look at this source
code
uh this source code okay here here's a
good example so you can see here is my
you know my emac this code html
attribute names so you have you know uh
html attribute so there are one single
line let's turn on the highlight current
line so you can see so sometimes when
you need to edit this code it's uh
you know it's um
it's hard to see so
put a space there
i mean put a new line there then call
the command
now it's easy to see now you can see
html attribute name so you see undo
redo so you see that's what this command
is for and we are going to write that
you know sometimes you know like
this occurs often like uh in many uh
situations you have this
uh
case
and
for me for the code sometimes i want to
compact it so you see
you know
anyway so that's not important so that's
the purpose of this
uh
this command okay and we are going to
code it so let's look at the i already
wrote the command so let's look at where
let's look at the source code
so describe key
press the key to call the command so you
can see this command is called space to
new line okay and it's in sapphire keys
it's free online you can get it um
and the pink window shows all my command
cores and the keystrokes okay the pink
window and i'm using kinesis advantage
keyboard right here and down on top
that's the ultimate hacking keyboard
if you search for
xrd
keyboard
you can find my reviews okay sorry
keyboard guide there are
900 articles so there is my keyboard
kinesis advantage and
stuff
okay so let's get back to the code uh so
yeah so here is the code subspace to
newline copy it new buffer paste it here
and uh make it uh emac be smart emac be
smart so you can see the code is pretty
short okay
so
so how you know
um
i'm going to explain how the code works
since it's already written but the more
important but there's uh one thing i
need to change
that is for example sometimes you have
um
a long line
but you don't you don't want to break it
in by space you want to break it
at certain other character places for
example let's uh let's
let me show you an example okay so go to
go back to talk show
so today's talk show page this copy the
whole thing new buffer paste it here so
you can see
you know this is talk show page and
let's join all lines so
replace a new line by
by nothing okay so sometimes you get
this
one single line html very very common
you know basically every website this is
one long single line so you want to in
this case you don't want to break
you know it doesn't make sense to break
at each space
in this case you want to break at for
example each of the
you know greater than or less than sign
so so what so normally what you do is
you
copy that then you do query replace okay
that's a command building query replace
you paste
you know you paste that character
okay can you can you see it
uh yes
it okay
then you want to replace it by the same
character but with a
uh new line
there so you do that then you say enter
and you ask you each time so yes yes yes
and you can type a exclamation
symbol to do it all so you can you can
see
now this is easier to read so
in this example you want to break you
want to insert lines at
at the at some special characters you
know not just space
so
so for example undo so we are back here
okay let's close this close this okay so
so what we need to do and let me go back
to the code so i need to modify this
command so you can
you can
you can tell it to uh use a different
character
[Music]
okay so let's do it so first of all how
do you how does this work so first you
know you
this command first of all you need a
beginning cruiser position and increase
the position that's the p1 and p2 here
you know that's you know in e-max buffer
if your cursor
has a position you know the beginning of
a buffer is one okay it starts with one
and okay
um
so you you need the beginning position
or end position to work on
so for this command if you do not have a
selection for example i can make a
selection
do it
you know
you know it works on the selection if i
don't have a selection it will just work
on whatever the current
text block defined by separated by
newline so if i don't make a uh
selection
let's let's do it here okay so let's
let's try it here
okay new buffer
okay so
if i don't have a
let's do it here okay let's copy so if i
don't make any selection i just call it
it'll just do on the current paragraph
but if i have a selection let's say you
know select here to here i call it it'll
work on the selection you see that's
how this command um
that's what this for sarge bounds of
block or region by the way that is also
free uh
yeah you can you know it's this this
command is part of fly keys so this
thing this star get
circuit bounds a block or region it
returns a pair it returns the beginning
position and end position
if there's a region this position is the
region beginning and region end you know
region means selection if there is no
selection
the beginning and end positions are the
current
paragraph okay so you get that you get
the positions then you set it to the
beginning position position one and
position two
you know so you begin
with
two positions where this command wants
to work on and this
this is a e idio idio idiom this is a
idiom in uh
emac this pretty common okay lots of
commands you know you want to act on a
region
if there's a selection work on the
selection if there's no text selection
just work on the region
you know for example when you want to
copy for example i want to copy
if i don't make any selection let's turn
off this okay if i don't
make any selection i do copy you can see
in the pink window you see i called uh
this copy line or region
it just copied the line for example i
can paste it here you see but if i make
a region
then copy then go here
paste you see so
this paradigm you know
work on a selection if this one is very
convenient so you you know you you don't
have to force user to always make a
selection first okay
so that's what this command is already
doing you know if there's a selection
work on selection if if if there's no
selection work on the region okay so
once you've got p1 and p2 position
that's the key here that's a key in this
block
position then you
then you want to do what you do is you
narrow to region narrow to region is a
command very useful it um
it makes the buffer
focused on only a region so you
so let's expand expand is called white
and that's that command widen it's very
useful even if you are just
uh using emacs so that's a command
narrow to region so you narrow to the
region the beginning and end positions
then you go to the beginning
of the
of the region point mean is the
smallest position in in the buffer okay
it's not one because because you
narrowed to region so you know the the
first character in the beginning of
buffer is no longer what so you now to
region then you go you move the cursor
to the first beginning
of the
region then you do a while loop so while
search for word if there's a space
you know this if there's more than one
space
and uh if it's found when it's found it
returns true
then
you do replace match replace match by a
new line so this command that's how this
command works
so let me summarize okay is that i hope
that's clear so first of all you get the
beginning and end position
then you narrow to region so you focus
on the just on the on the region
then you move the cursor to the
beginning of the region
then you do a while loop
and you start to search for one or more
space if you found it then replace it
with a new line character so that's how
this command works this space to new
line so let's try it again okay so let's
for example
um do it you see
okay
so that's how this command works so
so now let's add a um
add a feature so so let's first of all
write the documentation what we want to
modify so
uh
save this first of all save these
xx today's date and the the command name
dot e-l so we save it as a file here
a temp file okay
so now
so this command uh replace space
sequence to a new line character in
current block or selection that's right
now let's add add a feature okay
if
if universal
argument is called
let me do this okay let me i'll explain
so if universal argument is called first
ask user to
enter a character to replace
okay so um
[Music]
yeah
yeah so we got we are going to add these
features so
okay so
hello justine uh hello guys instagram
this yeah
oh flamie oh so familiar what's what's
your question
so okay so we are going to uh
add this feature let me explain what's
universal argument okay in emacs in many
commands
let's say
let's go to uh let's jump direct okay so
you can see i call jump diet jump
i press a key
and that goes through to the directory
of and move the cursor to the current
file so that's here
so that command is
dire jump
extremely convenient with that command
you never you never call the meta x
diode
you you you never need that anymore you
know focus on files you know use
bookmarks to open files and always and
whenever you need to go to a directory
just direct jump you'll go to the
directory and put cursor on the current
file and you can move up and you can see
the current directory so let's dial jump
extremely useful
okay we are digressing okay let me show
you an example what's uh let me explain
what's the universal argument okay
so if you are in
for example some commands
you know there there are by default
about 1 000
commands in emacs building you know by
default so many commands some commands
you can
you can have it do a different behavior
okay for example
right now i mean diet so if for example
i want to copy the file path of this
file let's say
okay so what is this css mod okay first
of all delete all the
backup files okay so i want to copy the
file path of this css mod okay so what i
can do is i can press w you can do that
too so press w in direct
so you can see
let me move back here so you can see the
w correspond to the command
diet
copy file name a skill okay it's copied
now let's create a new buffer paste it
there you see
so it essentially copies the file name
the short file name okay but let's try
again but what what if let's close that
what if i want the full path instead of
just the file name
okay so you call the same command same
exact same command okay where is it
direct copy file name is key okay you w
you call the same command but this time
you press ctrl u first okay
control u okay
and
actually let me do it again okay
ctrl u okay then
w
okay now you can see
you see control u is the universal
argument that's the command name
and then i call direct copy file name
skill now if i open a new buffer paste
what
my mistake it's not control you it's uh
control you you you need to give an
argument oh my god okay control u
zero okay then
w okay
then open new buffer
open a new buffer paste so you see you
got the full path so the point here is
that you know among the 1000 emax
commands many of them
takes a argument
that
that will give it a different behavior
so in this case
the command is
direct copy file name skill and you can
copy just the file name or you can copy
the full path you if you want to copy
the full path you press ctrl u 0 first
so let me show you the documentation so
describe key so let's do it again
describe key w
so you can see
w runs the command x
uh the command dial copy file name is
kia
and uh it's bound to w in diode
and the copy name of marked or next
argument of files into key or ring
current basically means copy paste
history you know emacs has a
keeps a history of all your copies
passport so emacs has a history of
pasteboard clipboard okay so
the name is so you can not just copy the
file name of the of one file but
multiple files i'll show you okay so you
see it says here
with a zero prefix arg use the absolute
file name for each marked file you see
so that's why
we are doing the control u first okay
so
next time when you uh describe function
read some emacs documentation you become
familiar with the emax jargons so
you know look here you'll say
uh you know prefix arc you know you'll
say prefix up like but if you are new to
emacs like what what the hell is that
but now you know it's it's the full name
is universal argument you you just you
know you just give it a different
behavior okay so let me demo okay so
let's say i want to copy all this file
file path
okay so now i do
ctrl u
then w okay now i open a new buffer
paste there it is that's a full path of
all these files now again you see they
are not separated by space so we need to
make them into a new line so we can do
that with our own command fantastic okay
so
that is about
so far we've talked about what is this
universal argument is for
so we are going to do the same thing for
our command
space to new line
so that we can press ctrl u
then you'll ask you what kind of
character you want to separate
you know
okay
so that is about emacs usage uh
universal argument now let's code let's
how do you actually implement this
that's that's the key we are what what
we are doing today
okay so let's go to emacs blog so you
can go to my emacs tutorial
and
so go to emacs tutorial
and go to
a practical emac list
okay
and
then you go to
uh so we are in practical emac list and
you want the command universal argument
so we have a
section here
writing a command writing a command
basics interactive form get user input
and blah blah blah and get universal
argument there it is
so click on that so here it explains
how do you actually
make your emax command to take a
universal argument
okay
it's okay so let's code that so that's
what we need to do here so
it's a bit tedious to explain so you
know go read you know go read my
tutorial but i'm just going to first of
all let's just code it okay
so let me just code it so you maybe you
can see what i'm doing so
so if
if this variable current prefix arc is
true
this can prefix arc is a building
variable
so if user pressed control u
before calling your command
this variable will
contain
the value will be true okay so if that
is true
then what we need to do so
yeah so if there's a universal argument
then you want to prompt user you want to
ask user what stream so enter a string
so for example
enter a
uh
enter a character to separate how do you
do that
enter a chart to
break line okay enter a character
enter a character where you want
line breaks okay something like that so
we want to prompt user
uh and how do you make how do you ask
user questions there it is get user
input
okay read file name
ask for directory name as for stream
that's what we want read stream okay
so here is read string
okay
and the prompt will be
into a type of character
type of character where where you want
line break okay
okay then
optional
innit input let's ignore them for now
okay
so just that
so we
this will return a string
let's clean up the code
and shrink a bit
this will return a string so we need a
variable to store the string okay
char
to
line break something like that okay
char to line break
so that's the character we want to um
ah we
okay so set
set queue chart to line break then
ask the question okay
okay so if there's a
prefix argument then ask that otherwise
yeah we need a lot to code here so
otherwise
uh otherwise let's just say space
okay
this is not so good we we need more work
to do so but anyway let's just do it for
now okay
let's let's make the code cleaner and
it's in show
okay so if there's a
um
let's say
yeah okay
let's just do that
okay so now
now this is not good so
let's let's say
type a regular expression
where you want to line breaks
where you want line breaks okay
so
so if there's a universal argument if
user pressed control u
then you ask them otherwise it's
zero or more spaces that's that's what
space plus means i mean that that means
one or more space okay then here
then we can replace that part by that
okay that's it
okay
evaluate the code let's try it okay
evaluate the code
then that's
okay so let's then
okay hold on a second
let's go to um
let's find some
okay here here's a good example
so let's let's just
okay this this uh that's some good
example
you know this uh
you know so normally let's call the
command okay so normally
we call the command and it becomes that
that's not what we want
because it's breaking lines into space i
mean it's breaking space into lines okay
undo
rather we want to break at each of these
you know we want it to look like this
you see
we want to break at
you know that that
between the brackets okay
so undo
so now
let's try control u
control u then
call our
command okay then it asks you
you can see in the mini buffer type of
regular expression where you want line
breaks
okay so the regular expression is gonna
be
right square brackets
and
left square brackets
now
square brackets in regular expression is
has a special meaning so you actually
need to escape it so you need
backslash
okay
that should do it so let's do it
fantastic almost almost we got a bug so
it looks like let's go to the top
oh yeah so we yeah so we um yeah so
we got into tricky parts
it worked
you know as you know it worked except
that our code is actually incorrect here
because we are replacing it by new line
okay so this um
you know we can't just replace it by a
new line we have to
basically we need to add new line after
that
so how do you do that let's see
so type a regular expression you where
you want new line
after it okay
so
okay so
and here we need to put back the
characters so
replace match
format
okay so this format
will add the chart to line break then
let's try that okay
evaluate the buffer evaluate the whole
buffer now go here let's try it again
ctrl u
then
space to new line
so
type a regular expression we want line
break after it
so let's do that
okay so the mini okay
uh let's just do that
okay
invalid of use of backslash in
replacement text okay
so we need to escape
so now the problem is
okay
so far so good
uh godox easy uh i used you know i
haven't used ergodox easy ergodox easy
is one of the earliest
mechanical keyboard
let me finish the emac piece okay so let
me finish it
so let's see
30 minutes okay we already overdue okay
so let's let's
so instead of using regular expression
let's not use regular expressions so
here
regular expression search word search
for word let's just say search forward
okay no regular expression evaluate the
buffer go here now let's call the
command
call the command one
okay it's not doing anything it's
incorrect so
let's see
oh yeah so
so this needs to be just space okay
evaluate the buffer
and put the colon evaluate the buffer
back here
do it okay right now it's just replacing
space
by new line okay undo
now ctrl u
and do it okay it asks you
to type a regular expression i mean it
asks you to type a character let's say
let's say um
right square bracket
okay do it okay
it works
it works okay so i think
but the command is not perfect
because
the command is not perfect because
sometimes you have multiple spaces
you know you uh
let's
let's reduce the number of
lines here so we can we don't have to
okay so let's
you know sometimes you have
lots of spaces
you know then you get this situation
where you have lots of empty
lines
because you have multiple spaces
so that is why we need to use regular
expression before
but
if you use regular expression
then you have
other complexities because
you know because the backslash and you
have to
unescape it
yeah so but for now i think for now
this is good enough you know for for
this um
for this uh
tutorial you know
this is basic
function i hope you learned some you
know writing emac lisp
okay
so yeah so we talked for 30 minutes i
think that's it for today five more
minutes then we close down
okay ins instant instant
insta insta key okay i'm gonna unban you
okay
so
anything else let's see i think that's
it for today
okay let me let me talk about oh what oh
okay docs okay ergodox keyboard keyboard
is my obsession so ergodox is one of the
earliest
uh ergonomic keyboard
it's one of the earliest do-it-yourself
ergonomic keyboard basically year 2013
okay so year 2013
is you can think of that as a date
the beginning date of the
ergonomic
do-it-yourself keyboard
uh
craze you know so 2013
about eight years ago and that is
because you know the 3d printers become
became popular so we are looking at
history you know 3d printer became
popular and you know organics is the
earliest
so ergodox you know
uh it's based on you know it's it's
basically borrowed from kinesis okay
you know it borrows the design
um of the keyboard i'm using kinesis
advantage go buy it okay go to my
website saw
you know saudi keyboard and
buy it for my links thank you
so it's based on kinesis and kinesis in
turn kinesis is based on
motron
so kinesis begin around 1993.
and motron this is motron motron begin
in 1977
okay 1977.
and it's it kind of is the first one
with the curved ball surface but
you know but there are other earlier um
you know japanese keyboard um let's see
1977 orthodox
uh
there are ergonomic keyboards for
example this typewriter is
is
okay and i'm not sure this is the
earliest there might be earlier so
anyway
ergodox is the kind of the first
do-it-yourself ergonomic keyboard okay
where is it organics
okay and it's borrowed from kinesis
but one of the things many people
complain is that the thumb keys
is a bit too far towards the center
meaning that if your hand if you are not
a basket basketball player you know
we've got big hands or black people here
then you have the issue of constantly
moving your
fingers
to the thumb keys you have to move it
too much
so that is a very common complaint of
orthodox
and in fact if you read my
you know my for example here
we have a friend
you know he showed um
anyway so
there is an example who uh yeah this guy
who is a big fan of or dogs he's a
well-known guy in a keyboard community
what's his name
geek hack
david okay he's a big
uh
guy
in keyboard community this guy so he
wrote the article you know he bought
several ogre dogs
then he discovered you know he started
to have pain around his thumb and he
couldn't figure out what's the problem
he thought it's a tenting so he adjusted
its attention but it came back you know
so eventually
he sold all his orthodox
and
and he went back to the
he went back to uh the normal keyboard
you know he went back to uh leopold i
believe
you know so
this issue about thumb is important it
also applies to uh
to
thumb based trap balls
for example this i have i'm using when i
lie on in bed you know many of the thumb
base so so you want to be careful and
even on kinesis advantage as well you
don't want to keep moving your thumb
instead do this okay move your hand
instead so when i want to press uh the
thumb key
i don't
i don't you know do this i don't do this
i move my whole hand here if i want to
press the ctrl key for example i usually
moved on my whole hand
like the whole hand consider them
fixed you know you don't want to move
you just move your hand instead so
that's an issue to watch out
uh so that's that's what i have to say
about ergodox i never use it i don't
have it okay so that's my analysis
uh and these days there are a lot a lot
variations you know or based on orthodox
so for example you know
the moon lander is a popular one it came
out two years ago a year ago
about a year or two ago so
but they didn't really fix the thumb
problem i think the thumb keys is even
worse they made the thumb keys
adjustable but but however it's still
too far
inward
so
okay that's my opinion about equidox
thank you guys for watching
bye guys
how do you reset key mads
you know you know i have it all on my
website just read it carefully
are you the guy on discord saying that
the manual is not good kinesis advantage
manual is the best manual okay just read
it
bye guys
close close down in a minute
so here is today's code
justine hey justine
justin hayes jones from canada
uh
haskell coder and haskell and
scala
bye