good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of out talk
show
today is 2021 july
26th and today we are going to
code emac lisp and wufam language
and pepe and girlfriend
pepe's got girlfriend look at this image
fantastic beautiful artwork i love this
video check audio check okay good
morning guys
uh and you know pepe and and and
girlfriend you know this is a
one you know one of the great folk
art uh you know in 10 years ago it was
the
uh rage comics comics and now it's a
watt jack and pepe and stuff anyway
you know most of the memes are crap you
know the ugly
[ __ ] but but but this uh
pepe is got a some kind of a stylish
thing going on so i you know i find pepe
is actually
um
uh fun artwork
you know of course it's tied to politics
so you know depending on you know which
side your politics is on you may not
like it
but from just a art point of view
i think you know some of them
is ingenious okay so you you know so i
love these uh
uh image okay so we're gonna we gotta
adopt a lot to do so for example so this
is pepe and artwork so first of all so
emac this and wufang language coding and
random okay if you have a comment
uh post your comments and questions to
me okay
uh and donate don't forget patreon me
and chi ching you know uh
you know super chat whatever youtube you
know put money in my pocket
so let's let's do uh you know i want to
modify this page to
you know i want to move this image to
the top
because i i consider this image the
artwork quality is
uh better you know also another thing
about this image
let me tell you let me tell you guys
millennial generation you young idiots
you class know nothing you know
uh you know you know care about nothing
the millennial generation beginning in
late 2000s the idiots that that this it
is the millennial generation
you know for example you look at these
pictures beautiful classic art but the
millennial generation no nothing they
look at this oh oh oh
boring you know what they want
what they want is let me show you what
the millennial generation are into
okay they are into okay so this is
some kind of the thing they are into a
weird you know weird stuff
and memes okay so rage comet rage comics
is all the rage
during the uh late 2000s you know
that's so this is what this is what
millennial generation invented that's
their thing
okay and some of them are great because
they represent you know they
are the pop street art they represent
you know every
everyday people average people and uh
and in many cases the rage comics they
illustrate the emotion of
of of human animals you know to the t to
you know to perfection with the simplest
uh number of lines you know
and also they represent the kind of the
street
the mentality you know the the
the millennial generation under the
current
age of society you know the info the
posting for age
where they feel powerless they cannot do
nothing
and every day they do is just dribble on
social networks on facebook and twitter
so so this uh you know this
uh rage comics was all the rage
uh about 10 years ago but now there's
something so anyway
so you see what millennial generation
like and
even this one okay this was a very
popular street art
uh this style okay by by whoever i
forgot you know very popular but that
was the hacker generation 1990s okay
like you know so this this would be like
the
this style of artwork you can look up
the guy whoever created this
this style uh you know it's in the 90s
but then
let me tell you so millennial generation
so what they are into they are into this
kind of thing
so you know this this guy is this
character is what jack
whatever but it's funny okay this
this one so okay and this one is also
millennial generation this is the
earlier
millennial generation what the
millennial generation calls
the boomers okay
so you know it's very interesting
linguistically we we are getting into
the
uh the realm of linguisticality okay
uh so so the word
boomer boomer the word boomer originally
refers to a generation that's 1940s or
1950s who
who are born in those years today they
are 70 years old okay
that's so that's what buma refers to but
however you hear
a lot millennial generation they talk
about boomers
like okay boomer it's millennial
generation
idiots lots of you guys
but you know so the millennial
generation they have the word boomer
like
typically like okay boomer but there
buma refers to
not not the 70 years old their bummer
refers to
30 years something millennial generation
so in fact it refers to themselves just
older
so the the reason that happens is that
because
you know the millennial generation they
are accustomed
to the social network you know the
chance the facebook
the youtube the garbage [ __ ] posting
comments you know you go to youtube
you know media thousands of comments
like oh no [ __ ]
[ __ ] contentless [ __ ] these are the
millennial generation
you know so they they are used to that
that's that's normal that's that's their
life that's their view of the world that
to them is like this is the way to do uh
two things
and being a nom like you you don't know
who you are you know not
you know bad name your names nicknames
or the
um bad batman or princess or whatever
you know nicknames they are into
anonymous thing anonym
ninity so this millennial generation
they grew up that way so they just
uh dribble and [ __ ] post and and know
you and whatever
you know online so among their group
this is kind of community of course not
all millennial generation are like that
but i'm mostly talking about the
american
typically or the american uh significant
number of young people let's say
50 more than 50 young people they are
like they are like that
okay for example you go to twitter you
go to twitter
or twitter or reddit you know almost
every
any social network you see the comments
then you see
you know all the comments are like gift
animations like
oh usually black people [ __ ] idiots
these
millennial generations idiots
contentless they don't they don't have a
brain don't they don't have content they
don't have something they really want to
say
or they don't really care about
something about society
they they say they care oh this all
these politics you know this that
but actually they from there they don't
really care
so that's a millennial generation okay
so and and this
meme this meme means invented sometimes
around 2007
also meme okay the word becomes a thing
me so this one is actually old you know
remember this uh
there's a name for this neon cat okay
this is 2011.
okay yeah 2011. you know this you know
it's kind of old
so millennial generation they're into
these kind of things
while if you show them you know you you
show them this classic eternal beauty
they don't know they don't they don't
they are too like to them
it's like oh oh they don't they
they have nothing to say about it all
this beauty you know
that's a millennial generation okay so
you see
all this beauty is extremely beautiful
this is human animals
this is in india by the way uh so
and cathedrals yeah of course millennial
generation they don't care
about they you know they about this
grand cathedral they are far removed
from from it especially also because you
know
partly because christianity is kind of
uh went away that is dying it's
you know so so i was talking about
millennial generation so what are
uh what they into of course the you know
memes and uh
and even these kind of uh anime you know
these kind of
great drawings this is truly you know it
takes
it this is this takes years to master
okay to draw these
uh supposed to reach comics you know
malignant generation into that rage
comics you you you go to a website meme
template and then you copy and you
[ __ ] idiots the millennial generation
[ __ ]
so millennial generation yeah so they're
into memes they you know this kind of
thing they don't
appreciate like they don't appreciate
because they've seen so many that
they're all you know because of the
internet you know
you know they they don't have when they
see this they don't say oh my god this
beautiful drawing or things like that
they don't they don't care they don't
their brains like uh uh
you know what's going on you know truly
is because their life is too comfy
you know their life is too comfortable
they don't have to do nothing to earn a
living you know they just
go eat peace out especially in usa
america okay
drive you go eat pizza what whatever you
go to
millennial generation that's uh that's
what they are like so i was going to say
you know so what millennial generation
are into
for example rage comics which happens to
be uh actually this is uh
great okay because um and
and also remember i'm not saying that
millennial generation not stupid okay
that's not true
in fact i think iqs is actually we
getting better but it's just the
the cultural the perception of things
they they are
becoming kind of degenerate that's what
they become they become degenerate and
they
care about nothing they don't they don't
appreciate beauty they uh
and most of the things i put on my
website actually are beautiful
including beautiful girls uh
so yeah i don't have that many
millennial generation things
you know but you know what i'm talking
about you go
you go to twitter then you see you know
millions of them every day
so what are you guys talking about um
jnz
okay gem z is kind of similar
okay so let me tell you so i've been you
know i
i study things you know from history
from
linguistics aspect that's what i mean to
from psychology aspect
from science or math i mean to uh kind
of
lots of things there are certain fields
i'm not
too interested for example financial
stuff
but anyway so and so uh and uh
so what i want to say is that um
uh so anyway millennial generation okay
they are degenerate yeah they're getting
degenerate and i think it's the
collapse of uh usa deposit you know
possibly class collapse of it's an
indication
or possibly you know we'll see class
collapse of usa and also white countries
okay so that's about that uh so so
so pepe we were talking about pepe so
now let's drop back
let's get to uh emac list okay
we're gonna go we we're gonna so today
it's gonna be random so
i'm going to talk random all over the
place okay
uh am i are you a millennial girl says
gir says are you a millennial
of course i'm not well i'm so i was born
in 1968
i mean i'm an open book okay and you
probably you
you know you probably haven't uh know me
you know you you you are new here
probably
but most people who watch me you know
know a lot but about me my website my
you know i'm a kind of open book my
history my life history my
age and it's open so i was born in 1968
so technically i'm the i'm the
generation
after the boomer or maybe the last
boomer okay i'm the generation after
boomer what what's uh what's the name
boomer generation okay um
you know we we can find uh we can find
uh baby boomers okay that's a full name
baby boomers
so if we look at the
baby yeah so i'm generation x yeah 1965
to
1980 i'm generation x okay
then you got the [ __ ] millennium [ __ ]
then you got generation z generation z
is kind of similar to one lane but you
know
i i can't say it's better or worse but
but basically the
millennial generation they the onset the
characteristics
the what made them is the internet
the you know the it's actually
technology technology
is the is the most fundamental
the most fundamental uh
thing that changes society that changes
cultural norms that changes society
for good or bad okay and millennial
generation their thing is because
they are like that is because internet
mostly internet
or in general it's called communication
technology
so internet then phone iphone begin you
know with apple
made it hugely popular that's the that's
a
era that's the decade where everyone has
pocket phone that's more powerful than
than their computer you know they can
you can talk to
anyone internationally so millennial
generation they are
kind of they they are most influenced by
internet mostly and and phone technology
so they became
they are the kind of the first
generation to you know bone with the
internet technology so they so they are
like
i'm mostly i'm talking about american
millennial generation or
more broadly uh white okay western
society now in asia or other places the
of course they also have millennial
generation uh but
they are not quite the same as the you
know the western ones
there's there are something there's some
parts that are similar okay similar
characteristics but
uh some are not i'm mostly talking when
i say millennial generation i'm mostly
talking about
american because that's this is where i
live i what i see i know i
you know every day so my little
generations so i'm generation x
okay
so back to what i was saying you know so
these millennial generation idiots
self-entitled and no nothing else no
nothing else
you know they they they they say boomer
oh
okay boomer but their boomer refers to
themselves 30 years old boomers
uh okay so back and forth
so right now i want to start the pink
window where i
it shows my emacs uh command log
so i want uh so normally i just call
these keys
you see start command log mod so for
example i call it
do it then then every key
key i press you can see my keystrokes
and you can see
my command name you know in emacs
but what i want to do now i want to have
a key
so instead of instead of me doing you
know meta x
star start command log i want to have a
key just press a key and you'll start
that so let's do that so
the that's the first thing i want to do
okay copy that so
now open bookmark i want to go to
emacs key okay so
here is my emacs key i want to add one
for uh start command log mod okay
so copy that do that do that do that
that that that
that that that that that okay
so you know the key which key
should i buy this command which should
shortcut should i have that's a
that's an art and science i have to
think about it for 10 minutes
but typically what people do is you just
slap it on
because it takes some quite some time to
decide
you know which key actually do i want
that to
be uh
yeah so you know i have to think so for
now it's just uh
leader key because i use a key you know
some leader key then hs okay
so so okay so let's restart emacs
save file yes okay one key press to
start emacs okay one
one key
fantastic okay now open a new window
now magnify okay now go here
now let me press that key space
space h s
to start command log mod okay space
space h
s there you have it okay fantastic
that's one step done now
another thing i want to do is that every
time i start a youtube
live uh live stream
i i need to magnify the font
so because normally okay
close we open normally it's this size
it's too small for you guys to see so i
so oh so every time every time
i open a new buffer i have to magnify it
twice open a new file you know
but i wanted to set the default font to
be 16
okay so normally what i do is i go to
settings file okay so you can see this
list code
that that sets the default font so i
copy it
create a new buffer paste it magnify so
you can see
and set it to emac this mod and magnify
again
you know whenever you change mod it
becomes the default size again so
so then i go here i say console
16 okay then i evaluate the buffer
okay now now every time i do open a new
buffer for example open a new new window
okay
then something then that's that's the
default that's a 16
size okay so it's kind of tedious i have
to open the file i have to
you know close that you know i have to
open this file copy that
open a new buffer paste it here set it
to ximakbi smart then change
it here then evaluate it then close this
and don't save
and close that file you know too many
steps i want
now one command that does that and give
it a key so i just want
press one key and it does that okay so
let's start to write that command so
so let's go to this i'm going to just
going to go very fast
um uh do we have the yeah so here you
see
my meanwhile here you see my emacs
command for now okay
so so now the task is
create a command that set the default uh
font size in emax and give that command
a key so let's do that
so go to where do i go to
go to a brief
so this is my emacs init file
search for miscellaneous so this file i
put miscellaneous commands
you know just like a dump dumpster
then later on after a few months or
something i clean up
this file move move the functions to
appropriate places
so okay so different so
set okay set
default font okay let's shrink that
okay so here is the new command so we
got a lot to do i'm gonna just
talk fast and then stop and uh and
keep typing okay so version day to day
state so this will be
set default font to 16
uh for live stream
for youtube
live stream okay this is just a draft
version of the doc okay so how do you do
that so
okay so how do you do that go to the
okay
copy that close that
remove that window and paste it here so
basically that's what you want to do
okay purify the code
magnify okay actually let's uh just uh
increase that so you see because i said
default font this is kind of just the
temporary
temporary function i use for myself so
if
uh if the so if the
operating system is windows then
if the console's font exists of course
it does because that's a
default font on windows it's it's a
default best
mono space font okay so change it to 16.
now
if i'm on the mac darwin then do manual
something probably
you should be bigger but anyway i don't
have i'm not on the mac and i'm not on
linux so don't worry about those
so okay so here is my command great
evaluate it evaluate it so emacs knows
about that
now go to my key key binding uh file so
go to my uh init search for key
key okay so this is a file
open it and uh i want to give it a key
so let's just uh
wait wait what okay what's the command
name okay
set default font okay copy back to here
so that's the command i want so copy it
put here now set default
font uh d okay let's make it just
temporary keys
so so you see usually these three
commands are called together whenever i
want to do a live stream
it's not clear recent history so i don't
want you guys to see
what kind of file i've been looking at
my personal files
phone files file names
then then also you know then
then you know set default file then
start emacs log
okay so that's all related so now
quit save file
save it one key press to reopen emacs
again
so now we are setting up the e-max
session to
to truly begin now we begin the star
talk show
or before that is prelude okay so
let's see so so
space space uh wait okay so i'm going to
call these three commands okay you're
gonna
you're gonna see let me magnify first
okay
actually let's do it this way
so first of all i'm going to call this
command space
space hc so if you look at the mini
buffer at the bottom
xr clear recent history done okay
now let's call this command okay space
space
let's move this window to here so
because i want the
uh i want the command log mod to start
in this window so
space space hs fantastic
now go back here space space
hd fantastic
now actually i have to adjust the size
of this window something like that
that that that then close that
then close that and actually we go to we
dive into e shell
git status
git add
git commit ado
get push push
now it's my on my github okay so
close close now now
close close now the real beginning of
star talk show
okay but before we do that we switch to
browser
three two browser copy the copy the url
back to emacs
uh paste it here so this is what we are
going to do okay
paste it here linkify then open the
you uh the url so you are looking at
this page i want to move that
pepe this image to the top okay so
cut it to the top because that's the
best one then i want to
change the update date you see by
cassady date
that okay so i press the key you see
it's updated showing browser
magnify fantastic beautiful pepe's got a
girlfriend
okay pepe's got a girlfriend uh
you know so related to this artwork
i want to show you let's go to my
artwork blog
okay uh related i discovered this one
okay
so this is a war jack character you know
whatever
and this is uh this this girl she's got
the name duma girl i think
stupid millennial generation jargons
okay so
so this i find these comics fantastic
this guy you know what sad face
millennial generation you know got
nothing to do
and you know you want to go out
sometimes like
and she says yes yes and
a few weeks later they are together and
you can see a
kind of smiley happy face and the girl
is also happy so this
is fantastic this is this is
you know there's a word for this that's
called romans
romans okay romantic that's that's the
human animal that's the fundamental part
of human animals
every human animals for thousands
millions of years okay
even the millennial generation idiots
cannot escape it
so this is great thing you know this is
how we
survive this is how the romans you know
sex
sex is a bad [ __ ] you know [ __ ]
that's a bio
biological perspective but
uh from a cultural or human perspective
you know you can say
romans love so this is the how we
um are not you know this is why we are
not
extinct extinct yet we have the desire
to be
paired together love okay uh
love so this is a great um
artwork that shows you know one of the
most fundamental thing about humanity
and even the millennial generations
cannot escape it
it's a great thing okay it's a i think
to me
this comic is kind of outstanding
outstanding from the from the thousands
of mean
[ __ ] idiot crap of the millennial
generation this is good thing
and i hope you guys if you are young you
know um
starting you know your life or whatever
i hope you guys
also find your mate okay
so that's about that
copy the url go back to talk show
and okay close that paste it here show
the pink window
linkify it make it a list and
combine the list okay then show in
browser
let's see what we got okay so we have
so we i want to do demo some woofer mod
we
i want to demo what we did yesterday
fantastic okay
and i'm going going to start to code
wufang language
and we talked about creating a key for
that and
okay okay so we talked about
let's um
let's uh write it down okay so i want to
write down what we've done
so in emacs instead of saying creating a
shortcut you say
bind a key you know that's a kind of
emacs community emacs ways of thinking
the unix kind of uh communities
way of saying you know in windows you
say create a shortcut key
create a keyboard shortcut for some
command in emacs you say
find a key for something so that's
so uh wait um
okay hold on a second
okay so yeah so we have
let me just write that okay start
command-line
okay so so we write
a command that and
give it a key okay that's what we did
make it uh code
create a key for find the key okay bind
the key folks start recent history
write the command subset default font
and give it a key
and also also
also
see we did these three okay we did this
three
now
now let's clean up here
now we also talked about
okay we talked about about pepe and
girlfriend pepe and pp
her name you know her name is pp
fantastic
name also the naming is important for
you know if nami is quite you know it's
part of
um part of the art you know
just like poetry you know the way you
name something especially mean
stuff uh how you name it matters
it
it um you know just like poetry they are
good poetry they are bad poetry
good poetry uh it
um good poetry tickles you you know
a good song good music you know it it
it vibrates your emotion
you know what's the word it it sing sync
it um you know it touches you
so so what i'm saying is that the title
you know pepe and pp
her her name is pb
it you know the the naming matters
because
if you have bad poetry you read it it
you know it
it doesn't um you don't relate to it
okay so
so when when the name is good it
vibes you know something like that
so we talked about that uh we talked
about millennial generation uh
malan jin and the
jargon boomer okay
okay then we we okay then we did uh
these three emax things then
then let me show you some of the things
we did yesterday okay wufang language uh
let's start with language
let's let's um
okay so so so let's open a new one
mufam language uh let's see
claim bottle okay we did this
so so i i wrote a wolfram
mod okay for example if i want to know
if
let's let's begin okay so for example
let's
create um
create a wolfram language code make it a
template
so now pp parametric plot 3d so i just
type pv3
space you see it extended to that space
you see you got the parametric
um function so let's say
0 to 9 0 to 9 okay
so function sine cosine let's change
let's change it to
sine okay let's see what happens to this
okay let's just plot it let's see what
happens
a line incredible okay i don't want the
line let's say
sine sine u times
what okay let's modify here
sine u times cosine v copy that
back to woofam land
let's see what happens okay that's that
doesn't look oh yeah yeah because you
don't want them to be the same
so cosine
what is this
okay so interesting what is this
twisty okay so let's uh change the
cosine uv
cosine u times
let's see v plus u you know this is the
fun part of math okay what is this
okay so the point i want to say you so
yesterday we did so i
so if suppose i want to look up the uh
the documentation for parametric 3d so
in emacs i just press a key so what is
the key let's see
um here f90 okay
so
there it is okay so that's one of the
things we did yesterday
and now and let's uh
you know copy that copy
paste okay now delete that paste it here
okay pretty fine show in browser so we
got wufang language code here
now if i want to make a link to the
to that url i just copy that okay so
paste it here uh called
word to link oofam word to link
okay so it becomes a link
okay there's a bug you see
this 3d part i can show you here so
there's a
bug okay uh
yeah every time you you know so let's
fix it
let's fix it on the fly so someone from
word to link is a
interactive list list closure in that
inside html mod
so let's go to the source code
so here is the code narrow to region
magnify so we're gonna modify the code
so that it will grab the three as part
of it
you know as under the cruiser so
are you guys still with me
whoa what a pessimistic rant what
pessimistic
rant are you talking about my reference
to the collapse of usa
you know if you read my uh what i talked
about
you know on this score because you know
even i do youtube videos
for like an hour almost every day in the
past you know
that doesn't that is not enough to
convey
you know the millions of things
happening in the world
so so suppose you know
if you want to know my opinion you know
not it's not necessarily
great okay but so you know suppose i
want to know your opinion about
something
it's not and one hour a day it's not
enough
well unless you cover specific things uh
anyway
so so back to the point you know i was
thinking you know i was
you know this this thought you know you
you know collapse of the um usa is
happening
okay for you know
i can talk about this topic but you know
then google youtube is gonna censor me
you see that's what
that's one of the problem that's one of
the indication of the fall
of usa okay you know censorship youtube
is going to census
you know and and youtube control
information control
you can say what control what you cannot
say there's no more
free flow of information and ideas
okay let's go let's fix this code
let's see um so i want to grab so
the problem is that something or region
oh yeah so i want to add
zero to nine here zero to nine
so i want to also need to grab the
numbers okay
but um yeah okay so
expand put today's date update
evaluate it okay now
go back now undo undo undo undo undo so
can we undo and do yeah
so let's do it again okay so what's the
key uh
wait what's the key i forgot
let's search for it there it is word to
link
f9 iw for me it's
thumb key my thumb key is f9 you know
my kinesis keyboard
am i this fantastic kinesis keyboard can
you see it
uh where is my obs audio yeah
so you see this this is f9
set in emacs so okay
that that is the kinesis advantage 2
which i talked about many times
it's a fantastic and also it's a red
switch is brown
i mean red line linear you want linear
light switches
the one i'm using is uh cherry mx
silent red so you go to my website just
search for xr keyboard
you'll find kinesis and buy it
okay so let's so i want to
link this wufang language word into
the wolfham language website okay so i
just call this
command i forgot what's the name again
i mean what's the key search for
okay iw so
f9 iw there it is and make it
a you make a list okay then show in
browser
then you see reference then you can
click
you see that's a command you see why do
i need this because if you write a lot
tutorial blogs then use you know
for example you can see if you go to my
programming blog
you can see lots of references sometimes
like if i'm going to explain wolfram
language how it works
sometimes i need references so people
can click
so that is why this command
fantastically useful for example let's
say
i want to know the function polyhedron
so i just type here
you know so actually let me show you
what i'm going to type okay i i
create a wolfram language uh
template then go to the buffer
then you can see this is actually in
some woofer mod okay you can see this uh
this is the mod so i type
poly polyetch tab
for completion you see the first choice
is polyhedron okay enter okay that's a
i got completion of 7000 function names
okay
now copy that polyhedron okay i i don't
know
uh what i'm gonna do that so
so anyway close that so i
paste polyhedron here now
press the key there it is a link
now we if we go back to uh you know if
we show in browser
let's let's make it a uh list okay
showing browser
there it is so that's why it's useful
now let me show you another command is
that sometimes you already have a
wolfram language link
okay so if you already have it you can
paste it here
and linkify and then
you show in browser it will show in that
format
instead of the full url you don't want
the full url so
so that's the three commands i did
live online we i finished two of them
and i completed afterwards and today we
made a
bug fix so that's a demo of those okay
now back here
close close because i mean delete
okay now let's do some
am i in sync with you guys we can take
this to discord you are right about
youtube yeah
uh you know i should give you guys a
warning you know
those of you watching me so i have a
discord but
over there lots of opinion flies okay
lots of opinion flies
uh wait i don't i don't even have it
okay so let me let me show because i
don't want to show
my um
you know i have a discord you know lots
of opinion flies and lots of weird
people
um you know but that's
that's the thing you know free speech
that's that's part of the thing
you know free speech i mean free speech
the term
the phrase free speech has become very
political
so when i say free speech cert you know
almost all you know already
you know people have a preconceived idea
like what you are saying
you know but so i don't like the
what you know that's american that's
america's problem you know
i don't want to talk about politics
because people you know youtube is gonna
censor
and also because americans you know so
so free speech you know
that's free speech the concept is
free speech is fundamental
it's part of the american culture okay
deeply you know the the free speech and
democracy and so on
but now anyway so
i'm not going to go into details let's
get back to uh
uh uh wufang language and coding okay
so uh so we did this so what what else
to
talk about
no comments okay so i'm gonna
do
so i'm going to code i'm going to code
some wolfram language stuff then
so how long have i been talking close to
an hour
so but i have a lot to do so let's just
let me do it uh sphere we did yesterday
client bottle we need another
representation of client battle so let's
do that
okay first of all let's let's go to
wikipedia okay
so there is klein bottle and uh
crime bottle is an interesting surface
because uh okay so they give that
okay yeah folding an intersection
they have several parametrizations of
the klein bottle
the one i want is not here
but can we um
so let's go to
so let's go to wolfram klein battle
let's use this
uh this
this parametrization now
is there a
okay so i'm trying to find
so i don't have a notebook here so what
is this
okay
yes in this wolf this wolf and uh
mathworld is the most idiotic and
non-professional website
so here's another advice never when
if you want to study math or math
related information on the web
wolfram math world is one
is the worst okay it's the worst the
better place
is uh just uh encyclopedia wikipedia
okay
so let's go to wikipedia because
wikipedia the information is far
richer far pro far more professional
when it comes to mathematics okay
far more richer more professional
and more accurate okay the wolfram world
it's crap it's it's it's crap
it's uh in many cases it's even
incorrect
wrong information
so so uh i want so so let's um
can you make a pythagorean cup what what
what what is that helloxide i recently
read one of your
2002 era article on pep
on paper on programming jargon
uh 2002 article on programming jargon i
think you are right about everything
thank you so what is pythag
pythagorean cup i don't know what that
is
oh okay
so you pull water here and
uh
okay pythagorean cup
cup of justice something something it's
a practical joke
device is a form of a drinking cup
credit to pyth pythagoras of samus
when it is filled beyond a certain point
a siphoning effect causes the curve to
drain its
entire content okay yeah
so can i make any mathema in wolfen
language yes of course
yes of course but uh you know it takes
you know take
an hour to an hour or so you know
uh yeah it will take an hour to create
that
to plot this and uh
you know so so in order to plot this so
you see
in order to plot this this is depending
on how you want to go okay so
if you presume the cup
the surface of a cup is just like a you
know just like a
thing you know no thickness just like a
surface then
but then how do you represent this uh
how do you represent this hole that
you know i have to think about how the
hole is actually constructed
so you have a hole
okay think of a straw okay so you have a
straw kind of going up
and down yeah so essentially it's like
you have a straw
poking from the bottom of the cup
that's right so yeah the easiest model
is just to have a strobe poking at the
bottom of
the cup
yeah so and uh and uh
so in order to so how do you
oh yeah so so it is possible so so what
i'm thinking first of all is that
whether you actually have to create a
model with a thickness to represent you
know the curve
or so if you need the thickness you know
then then it's like you know basically
you create a model draw something like
that
then it's more complex or can you simply
represent the curve by you know by a
thing
by just a surface like no thickness
then the problem is how do you represent
that hole that's easy it's basically
just a straw okay
yeah essentially so you just have you
just have a parabola okay
you just all you have to do very simple
okay all you have to do is um
let me show you okay all you have to do
is you just have a paraboloid or
even something like that okay just the
top just the
top half then you just basically draw
draw a cylinder with empty
you know inside and poking through the
bottom to the top then
then basically that will work as an
actual model yeah
so that's pretty easy but should we do
it yeah i can do it now but it will take
like
it will take 20 minutes and the result
is not so
beautiful so so let's not do it
so i want to do so kind bottle so first
of all i want to
plot the klein bottle okay so
so let's get back to the um
the figure eight immersion okay that's
that
we already have the 14 non-intersecting
okay so that is a different one
pr can be modeled after the flat torus
okay what is this okay
so
then bottle shape the parametrization of
the three-dimensional
immersion of the bottle itself is much
more complicated
the parametrization of the
three-dimensional immersion of the
bottle
i don't know what is it talking about
but let's
let's let's try it okay so first of all
show this page okay close it
and uh and we talked about pythagorean
cup okay
go to talk show pythagorean cup
paste it here so that we you know
something
okay then close that
cursor i don't want to find word okay
copy that claim bottle
and we okay go back here
open claim bottle then let's go here
ufam land okay parametric plot 3d
okay okay then we gonna write
this formula this formula is going to be
let's magnify
so let's try
this one okay so you have two variables
r equals to
let's say four okay so you got two
r
p p okay so
two variables let's say two that that
then
you have r
times
tedious this uh cosine
cosine theta divided by two
times
okay this is tedious to type this cosine
cosine v
minus
sine t divided by 2 and sine 2
v okay so
that then that
wait x y z and w so this is
a non intersecting four dimensional
parametrization
okay so that's a four dimensional
so this is a four dimensional surface we
cannot
plot it uh
we wasted our time
so
so actually what we need is this one
you see but the the idiotic you know the
wikipedia they you cannot copy this
you know wufam you know client bottle
you know the formula for you know wufam
language is the earliest
two plot crime battle like in the 1990s
there's uh
in fact one of the uufam language
version two or version one
klein bottle is one of their um logo
something like that okay so i'm pretty
sure there's
turns on the web okay
mathematica kind bottle okay let me just
find the formula
okay
okay so this is a four dimensional crime
bottle
projected into three dimensions
something like that
oh he built a continuous transformation
of the klein bottle from
40 to 3d fantastic
and this is actually wolfen language
code yeah this
this is fantastic okay so what's the
question answered how to visualize a
four-dimensional
parametric surface give function for
producing
images okay but let's try this fun fun
thing okay this is
language code and what's the other pages
let's see what is this page
uh downloading okay download to desktop
copy to clipboard so that's another
[Music]
another and what's this one
colored crime bottle
uh you know this wolfram language live
version they don't usually work well
on a web you need
you know ufo language mathematica
yeah that's not so good but first of all
let's try this one okay
so select or paste okay so this is casa
wolfe and mod
so you can see okay let's go to
let's go to firm language
paste it
magnify so here's a code
let's check the code the check the code
looks okay there's no
you know virus run it
there it is
so what is this so this so this is
a 4d client bottle
this is a 4d client bottle without
intersection but you know we are looking
at the projected to 3d
version and he is
transforming it into
you know into the more typical
uh shape
topological representation you know one
of the
shape so what is he doing x y
z okay so this formula is basically the
same from wikipedia a four-dimensional
uh crime bottle then
he defined a function client uv
to be a module and with these
local variables uh by 16 sign
so if if something sign is two pi so
let's make this better
okay so go to standard mod
okay so we can see the actual
uh math type setting okay so you can so
it's
much easier to read so module is uh like
this let it's a it's a function to
declare local variables so
this part is local variables so you have
vx
then you have bi then you have red
then you have xyz capital okay
then x equals to
that if if that then x
equals to that okay if
u is between pi and 2 pi then that
otherwise that then why is
this if expression if
you know it's between pi and two pi then
by otherwise by plus z okay so
basically if it's within a range then
then then it
bx and by so what is so this is bx
so this is b y okay so basically just
minus plus those
all these red okay so this
so this is a function that
a function of two variables and
it returns basically you know a list of
three things
basically three functions okay three
expressions of
u and v yeah so this function takes u
and v
value and it returns three it
basically it returns a point in space
okay then
then what is this claim value of four d
two three d
okay p r e alpha m
parametric plot so
so where is this kind used so what is
this
so x y
x y z t x y
that that that plus okay that
first line so this is where the function
is used
okay then u from zero to two pi v
from zero to two pi power range or
measurement
actually let's say mesh true
let's say mesh four
okay exclusion none boxed force
boxed true so
i want to see it x is true
plus style opacity and
color function hue okay
then this animation okay let's do it
okay i don't want the hue hue is
annoying because
hue usually looks pretty
but they they
make the visual visualization worse
okay let's say grade
grade level okay
that's the color function
okay so let's not even have color
function
let's do that
and opacity let's say one
i don't want it to be
so opacity one i don't want it to be
transparent
oh wait oh yeah it's
you know
you know you should
wait wait you know this is not so
good
this shouldn't be like that okay you
shouldn't see a block
like that this is this is not
well done you see that
okay this is not you know this is not a
very
good one
who is this alex tronev
uh looks like russian russian people are
good with math
russians a lot great russian
mathematicians
and what about this copy to clipboard
okay let's try some of these i never i
haven't tried this
some of these wolfram things oh so you
can actually just copy it
so what does this adjustment do
okay axis of rotation
okay we don't care about that
and what is this
oh this is some kind what
what does this do
shape parameters okay
display options
okay so now this is solid
this is opaque i want solid
it doesn't look good incomprehensible
this thing is incomprehensible
performance quality okay
color
random nice
randomize everything okay now
okay what is this
mesh yeah okay with mesh it's much
better so this is supposed to be a
crying bottle but
but it does not
okay so so this is a graphics done in
wufang language
you know from their demonstrations
project
in a demonstration project is their
website where
you have tens of thousands or hundred
thousands contributions
from people you can upload yours so
usually they
try to visually demonstrate some
mathematics
some you know geometry or some physics
or science
visually visual demonstration so this
one is uh
written by who is this source code
uh richard okay so 2013
richard henningen so he uploaded this
and here's a copyright you know
by common common license
so you know that's what visual
demonstration project
is everyone can upload stuff usually
visually demonstrate some physics or
math stuff
or engineering and so this one 4d
rotations so this one is titled 4d
rotations
of a crime bottle you just you can copy
it and
we have seen it
4d rotation okay so it
it satisfies what it claims to do it's a
four dimensional rotation of the kind
bottle that's right so
so you have you know four axis to rotate
about
then you also have
[Music]
you know it's kind of weird because it's
a four dimensional thing
you have more than you have quite a few
axes to rotate about one two three four
five six
they show you know the combination of
axes
then shape parameter okay so
yeah but they you know it does what it
claims to do but it does not really
teach you about what is claim client
battle or how it transforms
from 4d or to 3d how
is the projection done uh you know it
doesn't teach you that it's just
for the rotations of the kind bottle
okay that's
not so good okay i
don't like it
i mean it's pretty good okay but but i
don't care about 4d rotations i want to
see the
okay that's uh you know that's
so what else are there in this one okay
and that one
then this one copy to clipboard let's
see what that is about
paste it here
and let's see what does this draw
okay this one is even more lousy
yeah this one is even lousy what what is
it supposed to do
colored klein bottle okay
yeah i can see its color but what is it
you are trying to show so this
visualization
shows an animation of a klein bottle
into
r3 a closed non-oriented
or surface it can be created by
joining both pairs of opposite ends of a
rectangle after giving one pair of a
half twist
it can be embedded in four dimensional
space without selfies
intersection yeah okay but it doesn't it
doesn't do nothing
it's no good so
a lot i i believe a lot of things you
see on woofam demonstration project
is like this you know usually by
students
uh not very good so you waste a lot of
time
but some of them are superb okay but
also the earth
the other thing i'm interested is in how
does this work okay
so when i copy this let's see source
code
copy resource object so i want to see
the source code
but usually
i think i can see it yeah so double
click okay yeah
so here is a code so these you know 20
lines of code
we all do this now what about this one
let's open it okay here's the code
okay let's let's shrink let's shrink so
we can see
let's magnify so this is like more like
200 lines for the four dimensional
rotation
manipulate show
parametric plot then
a bunch of options
okay then oh you have a projection
function oh
hero hero this function himself project
4d to
3d so
so you have show then
then you have a bunch of you know user
interface for the manipulate
control type none you know and then
then you have what is this control type
okay
so all these are user interface widgets
style and grid
then control placement more control what
is this control placement
initialization oh god
okay
compile
okay anyway so i don't you know this is
not so good i
so okay so that's not so good so
what am i going to do i'm going to close
this
i don't care i don't care for that i
don't care for that
i don't care for that okay wikipedia
so now back to my
okay delete that delete that
showing browser
okay then that's
close that close that
let me do something else okay cross cap
surface
so let's plot this one
so i have this gcf deleted
then copy copy that
go to the top paste it here
and the zip file
unzip it
okay delete the mac os directory
delete the zip file
open the notebook this is
15 years old notebook okay
copy it close it
paste it here
go to wufang language
paste it here okay
what about this one
okay it's about the same
delete that
then this notebook we can close it we
don't need it
open it delete it delete that
and delete that
okay and uh now we want to show a
cross cap show in browser that's right
i want to have this image
i want to make it
past force
axis force
let's see how it works
okay so
[Music]
pie and pie close it it and
boundary style
okay and plot
points
max recursion zero
so i have full control of how many
points to plot
and one plus down let's say
opacity okay
what is this
wow
now i don't fully understand the
relations between
you know i still don't fully understand
the relations between
the grids on the surface and
the edges of the poly heat
polygons that makes up the surface
i don't fully understand it so right now
if i
say h form red
that means every edge of the polygon
is red
let's say thick
okay edge form
what is the
uh
oh this is this is looking better than
before
you can see some kind of spiral on this
thing you see this
you see we tracing this spiral
okay so what i want to do
what
do
oh
what
let's add some reflection
520 so let's say
five
fifty
okay the surface is not very smooth
as you can see their reflection is kind
of
so max recursion let's say
three now let's say
four
now we got a problem of too many in the
middle
that means we need to adjust the
parametrization
okay
specularity
let's try opacity again 0.9
0.5
the color is not so good
okay this is getting kind of boring
max recursion
yeah this is getting worse
our earlier version is much better
specularity red
then what is the glow specularity
darker glow specularity
white so specularity is a graphics
directive
which specifies that surface of 3d
graphics objects
which follow are to be taken to have
specularity s
use specular exponent n
what oh what
oh so
so i guess if you have transparency then
it affects spec specularity they are
kind of related
anyway i'm kind of tired
tired of this now you see
they cross a bit i don't know what's
going on
and i don't want and i want to change
color okay so this color
so let's try some random color
okay so let's try some random color here
okay so
so now we try point eight
try again try again
okay i think i like this
okay i'm gonna use this uh
max recursion let's say four
okay now the color changed yeah i like
that
previous color do it again
do it again until until it gets a color
i like
let's just use this okay
save graphics
png
okay then copy the copy that
paste delete that
qualify syntax color file then
the image here cross cap
hello who else is here i can do that in
true
basic
really are you kidding
matt
okay i believe john holton conway
suggested a different name than cross
cap
okay this is fantastic i want that so
replace the old image
we replace with that one so
cross cap
delete that show so we have that
and we have the formula and we have some
explanation the quest cap is a represent
representation of the projective plane
and blah blah blah then
yeah so that's what we want and we if we
go back
here we need to replace this icon
so go here
make a small image so here is icon
cut the file path then go to
the directory on top then search for
cap here so you can see it's there
then paste the image
you know linkify it go to the browser
refresh you can see the new image now
we're gonna delete the old
delete it
go to the browser okay so i also need to
do this
i need to add a dive on them so
refresh fantastic we got that done
so
message retracted so i'm just going to
continue
you know this is just gonna be because
our talk show is now
kind of just my walking session okay
close that
so we finished that so that is what
we're gonna
yeah so we finish that cross cap kind of
you know we i'm gonna work on this
on and on and on uh there's tons to do
so what about this one there's no
simple formula but we need to delete
this
gcf file so this gcf file is a graphing
calculator
it's a graphing calculator it's a
fantastic
application okay i talked about in one
of my video
uh is this this one no it's not that one
you know it it's created by a hacker
which
you know kind of new cac okay so here's
his website
very old this is 19 you know
1999's website style uh you know he's
still working on this so you might you
know buy his stuff
anyway so that's a graphing calculator
file that's what this file is
and i'm going to delete all of them on
my website because
uh i had them like 20 years ago
i don't have it now
okay so now i want to
what i want to do i'm just going to work
on my website okay let's go
let's check this page close that
check this page okay that's fantastic
close that go to my talk show
sphere okay climb auto
okay we still need to modify that
cross cap surface okay just for the
first version
forever paraboloid okay let's do this
i wanted to you know
[Music]
probable parabola it is the most
simple okay so all these we did today
you know we don't need anymore i'm not
going to keep them
so wufam so there it is your paraboloid
okay so
uh color function so i want let's add a
color function
plus style directive random color and so
on
yeah i want random color
avoid default color of any application
when you can because otherwise
everyone's website
is gonna look the same
so
so this is a paraboloid i mean this
is this is a paraboloid uh the cross
section of this thing is a parabola
in fact it's just a surface of
revolution of a parabola okay
now this is one way to look at it
another way is that you want a bounding
box you see right now it's the bounding
box is a box
it's a cube
but alternatively you should have a
you know a circle you know a ball to be
a rounding box
when you do that what's going on
when you do that if you have a circle
it's a bunny box then
you won't see you won't see this thing
at the edge you will see
in fact a circle so it's more like a
cone
it's more like a cup uh so that's some
interesting thing about
um hold on a second let's regenerate
this
okay so let's magnify
let's save this as
okay then also copy that
for my website paste it here delete
that okay
make it htmlized
then
add the image here
showing browser fantastic okay
now delete the old one
okay then we
yeah make a
thumbnail here's a path delete it
then go to the top of the page
then you see paraboloid search for
paraboloid
here
paste the image make the link go to the
browser refresh
so this is the new one fantastic now dd
the old one
delete that delete that
that that that fantastic
okay then so we got the formula parabola
is the surface okay
surface of revolution of the curve
parabola okay
let's move that to the top then show
so here's a formula then there's a zip
file
we are i'm what i'm doing is update
update my website that was
um that's created some 15 years ago
so unzip the file let's see what we got
delete the mac delete the zip
do it then open the mathematica wolfram
notebook let's see what it's in here
nothing
okay so nothing close it
back to emacs open the file delete it
refresh remove all backup files
do it yes okay so now we just got
we just got this new image okay then
you know we got this file gz this is a
polyhedron you know actually we don't
need this gz anymore
you know white is it there because back
then 15 years ago
you have java applets that runs in
browser
so i actually have an applet that allows
you to rotate
these 3d graphics in the browser
but the java applet mechanism has been
removed beginning with google google
decided to remove it they
cite safe you know safety reasons
uh but in reality it's more than that
more than just safety that you know they
decide safety security reasons
because the reason you know part so part
of the reason they
google removed it you know since google
removed it in their browser
and google browser is the most popular
then other browser also started to
remove it
so today thousands of java applets
that's written in
you know 1990s and early 2000s they are
good they you know so the part of the
reason they remove it google officially
say it's for security reasons but you
know i
i suppose part of the reason is
political because java is not google's
product java you know some ecosystems
created java and it got
bought by oracle and oracle are not
exactly google's friends yeah of course
they have a lawsuit
between oracle and google about java
because google
kind of store it i would say you know
google is not a good guy
so this opinion is contrary to most tech
geekers they think you know
anyway google basically took part of the
java api you know the user interface and
we implemented
uh for their android phone which
also angered apple because google is
stealing apple's
spread uh you know so fundamentally
the issue is really about
money and about profit about you and me
you versus me
not about about you know security or
you know whatever so lots of you know so
this part of drama so i have this file
this is data file for
you know polygon and i'm going to delete
it now because
it's no longer useful because it was
used for for the java
visualization now it's you cannot do
that
also the other reason is that these
graphics 3d you see this is
uh this is ufam language uh um
syntax you see graphics 3d then polygon
so each polygon specifies you know each
polygon takes several arguments each one
is a point you know three-dimensional
uh point you know coordinate
so so and polygon is just a
a bunch of
you know let me show you okay so if i
can see
so anyway polygon is just a bunch of
points they form a polygon in free space
okay so so then you have hundreds of
polygons
so you can see
you know you have hundreds of thousands
ten or thin ten thousands of polygons
so they form a surface and this is
woofing syntax but now
beginning around 2007 wufang
created this is still still works but
however woofan created another
a newer syntax to represent 3d graphics
called graphics
complex okay graphics 3d complex also
let's see
for example let's um so i'm in
i mean woof i'm not okay so let's say
kasa wu from
okay so now you can see now now i'm in
wolfram
mod so let's make this
let's add a space to it okay so so each
one is just a line so now it's easier to
see
so you see so now i'm in uh
wu fan mod so it's you can see it's
colored you see
so before 2007
every 3d image
is represented in wufang language by
this graphics 3d
function kind of inward function you
know so this
this thing then contains a bunch of
graphics primitives
then ufo reads this and and will show
graphics like that okay this is before
2007 and still works now
but however there's a flaw with this
image
syntax because for example you if you
look
at the parabola you see you have lots of
polygons
now each of the polygons they share
many points so essentially many of these
points are repeated many times
for example like four times each point
it is repeated for that for example this
number
can we find another you see there okay
twice
for example let's pick another number
this one can you find
it there you know so essentially each
point is repeated four times in general
you know so that makes the graphics
kind of redundant you know it's not a
efficient format to represent the
graphics you see
for example let's try this this point
okay
search you know so again it's repeated
four times
let's try this one okay so that's
so so wufam language has a new
uh kind of syntax for graphics 3d that
does not repeat
so how does the new one work okay
let me show you okay first of all let's
go to um
let's call t look up wolfram dock okay
so so you are looking at the
documentation for the graphics 3d
function
let's turn on javascript
okay so wait
can we refresh refresh okay
so graphics 3d so it you know lots of
documentation
this this is the this is the most
fundamental this is
the uh data this is the syntax to
represent
any all graphics in wufang language
graphics 3d
any any three-dimensional graphics okay
not 2d
2d is just there's a function called
graphics anyway
so so you can see but
so you see this is very old from 1998
introduced in 1988 version one
but in 2007 when wufram language
uh six came out they updated all the
graphics so they
so they have a new format let me show
you okay
called graphics 3d complex
i'm not sure they mentioned it
okay you will find it here graphics 3d
object
so basic 2d and 3d object special 2d
special 3d object sphere cuboid
and so on graphical geographic
visualization object directives
directives are controlling colors and
you know things like that
texture opacity dashing coordinates
transformation compound constructions
okay
graphics complex there it is this is the
yeah
so this is kind of uh
kind of the new format not necessarily
replacing graphics but it's just a new
one
so this in this in this way
this graphics complex takes two
arguments the
the sec the first argument is just a
list of points that's
it then the second argument refers to
the point
uh before that to indicate what vertices
they use
so for example let me explain first so
for example you see
this one you know first of all you
define v to be a bunch of points this is
two dimensional
you know uh points then you
have then then what
what what is this graphics complex
yeah so you can see the graphics complex
takes
two arguments the first argument is v
which is just a bunch of these points
the second
second argument is a polygon and inside
the polygon
it says one two three four those number
just refers to the index
of the you know the disappoints so
that means the polygon is the first
point connected to the second point
connected to the third point
connected to the fourth point so forming
a kind of a square
but normally the polygon the arguments
to the polygon is a list of points
you know like we show here so
so so this graphics complex
syntax is uh is kind of more efficient
way to store
uh graphics because you don't have
repeated points anymore
got a jet brother got to see you still
working hey uh
see you guys wait can you put on those
number back up i'm copying down by hand
what numbers can you put numbers back up
uh
okay i think
i think i'm done you know i'm just
working on my own website so
so yeah i don't need this anymore
deleted
so in fact i need to delete
all files in this directory so actually
if you go up here
go to powershell
and the recursive
recurse include
let's magnify
include then
that
so you can see
okay so you can see then dash name let's
just
dash name so you can see all the files
you know that mgs gz
that's mathematic mathematica graphics
compressed by gz
so all these files should be deleted now
because i don't need it anymore okay
let's delete them
are you sure yeah okay let's do it so
pipe it to remove okay
this is a power shell
do it can you
find it so we remove them all
okay so so paraboloid
and also dot mb this also remove that
okay and also let's
show in browser so paraboloid is a
surface of revolution of the
curve parabola okay
very interesting uh
you know you can see optical properties
then
so if you revive that around the line
then you get paraboloid
and what i want to do
yeah we talked about using a boundary or
circular boundary to to draw these
let's so let me try that okay
so let me try that
so this talk show today's talk show is
just non-stop
of me working on my website
uh
where is my google youtube for people
so first of all in order to have us a
ball boundary i need to read the
documentation
the documentation to uh yes because i've
seen
i've read yesterday while lying in bed
reading the documentation there is
their region
function so this is what we want to use
region function okay
so click on region function fantastic
so i'm going to give it a region
function here
okay so you can see
paste a region function now what
what should the region function be it
should be
inside the sphere okay so region
function
i'm not sure this will work but let's
try it
so x squared plus y squared plus z
squared forms a ball
so they their sum should be less than
one
i don't know if this will work let's try
it fantastic
let's say less than ten oh
what
why is that less than let's say
less than 10 maybe or maybe because we
don't have
oh yeah because we didn't extend the
let's say 10 10.
we don't have enough extension of the
surface
there it is
okay so you know it's funny it's got
this
kind of
tradition so this means
you know i know what's going on so we
can refine it plot points
let's say 200 let's just max it out
it's kind of fun
now axis force okay
okay now this this looks good
yep i'm gonna just use that now is it
possible to have
like clear-cut spherical
um clear-cut you know
sharp straight no jagging
it should be possible but um how does
this work
region function so we are specifying a
region that's right
region function and
okay i don't like this color
and 4 is is it because
now is it because we don't have enough
pony guns five point four thousand
yeah so you the more plot points the
more we find
are the
uh the bounding the region cut
okay let's let's just use this one i
like
i like this one okay
i i want a different color let's see
seven want you now is what youtube is
telling me
about you still here it's kind of boring
okay so i'm just gonna
you know this is just me walking on my
website
god give me a good color man
okay i'll just use that i suppose
save graphics
okay so
show in browser fantastic
now we i need to crop this image i don't
want the
so open it go to diet
here is the image now there is a command
the you see image auto crap
f9d f9d
there it is so it created a cropped
version
show it indeed close it
optimize png on that file
so that you can compare the file size
refresh good it's actually smaller than
the original so
this one deleted this one
we want copy the file path close close
make an image link and rename it to
that okay do that that
that that that
fantastic
okay and we need to paste the formula
the wolfram language formula
so the formula to i mean the code to
generate this
is this one so
paste it here
make it htmlized there it is
okay so okay i gotta i'm i'm tired so
that's it for today
uh thank you guys for watching
visual poetry so what's up what what
what have you been doing uh
can you put those numbers back okay i'm
gonna go abroad
uh
so fantastic let's let's go let's check
okay let me let me let's just
check my stuff parabola i have that
updated
there are more things to need to work on
ellipsoid you know lots of
let's change to something let's let's
change
to some doing something other things at
all so
close that show close that close that
close that this is graphics
complex we explained close that this is
a graphing calculator
and let's let's uh actually
reopen copy that paste it here
link if i close very calculate i don't
care clean bottle close
i yeah i think i'm gonna go and uh
12 o'clock already yeah thank you guys
for watching
bye guys
bye bye