you
test test test
Vidia no problem no sound now there
should be sound now right okay finally
yay so stupid I've been talking for like
thirty minutes without sound mic so I'm
not sure what to do well okay so let's
see yeah this OBS you know sometimes by
guys I mean it's so far it's been pretty
good for my basic usage but I guess I
get a crashes you know whenever I
changed something in crashes then today
just somehow that the sound part didn't
pick up so let me read those comments so
so break the loop great to see you and
George great to see you and hi pal like
okay so I did not think your son has
been walking yeah so yeah that's so
funny so so I was thinking you know
we're gonna do a a RC chat so this is
gonna be like a new exploration you know
like this is a this is not a podcast you
know you have these weird terminologies
podcast which is actually just love live
streaming of audio that's the proper
term we could podcast then you have
broadcast which is you know usually
refer to corporations then you have a
video live stream live stream you know
then but if you individual does that
usually score a live stream from
originating from the gamer community I
suppose is kind of so anyway so so I was
thinking so we cannot do it we we have a
video live streaming but no sound but
instead I type and you guys type so it's
gonna be a new new chapter of stuff
oh wow you're gonna donate me a second
one that would be that would be so much
appreciated actually yeah yeah I need a
second monitor so I can always see the
chat on the screen I think you know I
think I actually to properly see the
chat for example right now I'm seeing
the chat right that's not that's not
what people usually do I mean the chat
is supposed to be like visible just to
me and doesn't show on my screen you
know so that I can talk about things on
my screen and I can meanwhile see your
chat you see your chat but so usually I
think the way people do it is that there
are some options here I can add some
kind of sometimes sometimes the
extension I don't know but I think
that's the way people do it so you know
I can see the chat and but yeah i mean
ii monitored actually yeah so break the
roof you know that's that would be
appreciated for sure you know me you
know I invite you to dinner you know and
it makes you know this week or something
let's talk about that offline what was
the problem
yeah the problem is the OBS I think it
you know this audio input you said it -
it was set to default and default was
you know anyway so it's something to do
with that yeah I'm gonna I contact you
tweeted something so so okay so what we
do so I just wasted like 30 minutes
talking about JavaScript and and mouse
so should we should we go back and we
talk about those topics or should we
let's just talk about something else
do you know if your Logitech mouse
custom key vine works in Linux yes it
does so that's why I say when you buy a
mouse or when you buy a keyboard one of
the most important things you want is
you want programmable mouse or
programmable keyboard with built in
memory that that part is important
because some Mars such as those made by
Razer they marketed as programmable but
actually if you do not install their
software and if you do not have a
internet connection your buttons your
custom buttons doesn't work so you don't
want buy anything Razer anything about
made by Razer don't it's no good
Logitech is pretty good so this applies
to keyboard as well as Mouse you want
buy programmable ones and with building
memory you know when you buy you know if
you look at my website I have like you
can pick the one you want and I usually
talk about whether it has building
memory basically all Archie Tech is good
all Archie Tech Mouse is good for four
months I usually chose just Logitech I
don't buy any others I don't
in particular you don't want anything
from razor like this what razor well
anyway so yeah so once you have a
programmable Mouse with built-in memory
that means you program it one time okay
how you program it depends on the mouse
but usually it's a Windows software you
run you know you start the application
it's a variable for the Mac as well then
you set which key you want to do what
such as copy control C for example then
you then it's set in a memory firmware
then you can you can you can Trash the
software you don't need anymore I mean
usually you keep it but you don't need
that anymore
you can bring the mouse to office or any
computer Windows Mac minutes plug in you
press the key the key wheel does exactly
what you programmed you know such as
control C or whatever
for example yeah so I was talking about
okay I kind of wasted you know previous
silent talk so I was talking about why
you need Tim button smiles and why you
need a spinning wheel and you know okay
let's maybe go over that a bit so you
see that so my mouse you see so if so
all these buttons I have programmed that
does things on my for example you see
this one okay so let's go back the food
for example let's click on that okay
quick now if I want to go back I just
press this key go back oh oh oh wait
hold on
so this top two keys is previous had
previous tab previous tab you know next
step next step next tab so for example
of my Firefox you know usually I like
you know use you know usually I switch a
month
I didn't load them before anyway so you
see I can switch I'm on tabs in anything
tab I want and if I want to close the
tab you just I I have this one I just
close the tab let's see if I can see it
yeah okay close the tab oops
across the wrong window but anyway so so
like close a tab close you know switch
to some tab I want close okay oh I close
my mistake be open reopen reopen you see
so I can you know I can fly through my
tabs and I can let's see five two and I
can close any one I want and I can
reopen them I can create a new tab I can
close it I can then copy cut paste is
all one single key press operation so
I'm doing that on my mouse so so the
for example yeah so you see switch back
and forth and also for example on this
page yeah
oh you can't see it my video
technique is still very bad let's see so
you can you see switch tabs switch tabs
and if I click on that I can go back
with this key forward back forward back
forward and if I want to close this
window I press this key at the bottom
close you see so it only got one two
three four five basically five useful
programmable keys and if I know the that
we all left and right left is zoom zoom
in you know right is zoom out so many
pages this is very useful because many
pages you want to zoom out especially if
you get when you get old you know like
he needed to be bigger so yeah so my
point was about so I was saying why you
need 10 buttons Mouse and so my point is
about so that's why you know so it's so
your hand stays on the mouse you don't
have to go back to the keyboard then Oh
switch to last tab is like control and
and it's different in different browsers
and different operating systems so on
generally and on Linux is control left
arrow I think so you know that you
switch your hand back to the keyboard
control left arrow to you know to switch
tap you know ought to go back to the
previous page then you go back to the
mouse again you know that you don't want
and you know so that that is why you you
get a 10 buttons Mouse it's efficient
your mouth your hand is just there you
know you can do everything so that was
like one of the things I was talking
about Tim Burton's mouse and the
spinning spinning we always great
greatly important for example I'm like
spinning this page like spinning this
page my hand is here it's a feature you
want especially especially on this page
like very long like my n is here you
know I can just see it you know
scroll over you know and I can stop at
any position I want so yeah that's about
the mouse you know that so I was you
know talking silently about which ma how
how you pick a mouse for programmers not
for gamers for programmers so um see the
comments I have a problem oh you have a
razor mouse so break the loop loop says
I have a problem with country with razor
mouse where the mouse settings do not
automatically work when connected yeah
that's the problem
yeah so there is a mouse it's very
because they are very big you know when
one company gets very big they become
pretty bad usually because why because
actually you know actually razor you
know for some of their models they
actually intentionally remove the memory
or remove the programmability they
actually you know did that for some of
the things with razors stuff then they
they they they create this software kind
of like called the driver software you
always have it running in order for your
keys to work for your customer keys to
work and sometimes also you it requires
you to have an internet connection for
your set of keys to work once if you you
know don't have internet connection your
keys don't work they do that then they
market it as a like oh crowd and this
they have a term you know razor synapses
yeah synaptic they called synaptic then
you know or the you know the ignorant
chemist is like oh synaptic technology
you know we cannot get that so so they
do this because actually so they
use you know the the cost for them
because you don't have memory anymore
and then you also create the cloud so
you you gather all the people's data you
can you sell that data of course all the
companies do that so you make more money
then
and also they market to cameras because
you know frankly not everyone is you
know study about anything you know most
people like even I mean me I know about
Mouse I know about programming I know
about keyboard but if I'm going to buy a
chair I don't know nothing about the
chair you know so I'm good just going to
read you know the marketing says oh
these chairs got you know just but
ability in five ways oh that that looks
good yeah I'm just gonna buy that chair
that's the same way with you know other
companies so so they actually grow and
they become bigger but for the
connoisseurs oh you know if you actually
know the stuff razor is like the worst
so Jordan hey Jordan how do you
pronounce that
that the Oh with a slash I mean that
that is a Scandinavian language thing
right Joe with all with a sash Jordan
loaning so he say he says first one for
peyote memory I configured my Logitech G
3 0 3 on Windows and the settings work
wherever yes geo 3 ok I not sure about
which one is geo 3 let's see I think ok
it must be here is that tight Atticus or
something go3 wait not here mouse wait
comparison g30 3 ok it's like this one
right that Titleist I address they all
have these names for gamers what kind of
stuff do you bind to your 10 mouse
buttons yeah I think I would just cover
that I did the demo you know so I mean
if you want to know the okay it's up to
you and I mean it's up to each person
because you know maybe your Photoshop
user you are a gamer of course for
gamers if you if you play a specific
game then you have you know some
specific specific buttons you use but if
you are average you know for programmer
most of my time at least you know he's
spending a lot in browsers like for
example like okay let me show you so my
hand is on the mouse okay like what one
hand is on the mouse I can so browser
tabs and you can close it and then
anyway so let's go to this page then let
me show you this page so because I have
detail about that so why 10 buttons
Mouse so that's an explanation about
white hand button mouse so why do you
need 10 so you need left click right
click middle click go to the previous
page you go to next page close tab
previous tab next tab copy paste select
all select all is also used in
conjunction with copy like usually for
example in a URL box or in sometimes
it's not selected you wanna select all
and copy and and zoom in zoom out for
example again Zuma on a mouse again
zooming so so just this you you need 13
buttons already so on this mouse I have
it doesn't really have that many so I
have about yeah 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 I have
those you know then I discussed other
things you you you desire you know so
yeah so that's Tim Burton's Mouse so I
find using the mouse for for George
Jones say so if I'm using the mouse for
just about anything breaks my focus
there is mint - there is amen
context switch yeah that's true but I
mean there is nothing you can do I mean
I you know okay so this this is one of
my big gripe about common programmers
they also tell you not to use the mouse
I mean it's I mean if if I work in Emacs
I don't use Mouse much you know never
okay
actually I do use squirrel but other
than scrolling I don't use the mouse I
use Scroll in Emacs for a specific
reason because actually the mouse
scrolling is the most efficient way to
navigate to to scroll page up and page
down but that's another topic I mean you
you may not agree with me on that that's
okay forget about the mouse I mean I
Emacs I don't use Mouse at all like
except for scrolling okay I don't use
the mouse I copy and paste for example
cut that new puffer paste you know I saw
okey Barbara and close this buffer wait
wait I close this buffer don't save and
undo we are back to you know so I don't
use the mouse in Emacs but in a browser
is actually kind of necessary and and
especially if you have programmable
Mouse and you know ten buttons it's far
more efficient for example for example
let's say this window okay let's say the
master done window I don't need it
anymore you see the master window right
here I don't need it anymore
I want to close it what do you do you
well you have to use okay one way with
the mouse is you move and aim the cursor
there then you click okay you want to
avoid any aiming kind of like you have
to like carefully aim you know don't do
that you know it's opening it back okay
don't do that you always want to operate
a computer in such a way that you can
close your eyes then just press the
button somewhere you can feel the button
like I can close my eye I know this one
you know I press the key it's gone oh oh
wait
that was reopen last close so so I just
reopened last close but I'm going to
close it now close and now I'm backing
Master Dan page at I believe okay now
let's close it again now I open my eyes
okay I got it wrong
fancy but anyway so you want to do it in
a way so that it's personal operation in
such a way you don't have to like spend
any brain psycho
if you can okay avoid brain psycho
Prince Prince psycho is a was one
example with brain psycho is this common
every in every operating system in mac
or windows always you know this is a
waste of your brain cycle like oh which
window I wanted there is over here oops
I went over let's press shift and you
know you don't want any kind of that
that you have to like take a moment to
think you know so you want you know
avoid that and also the in Emacs there's
a common package that's ace windows or
code you know ace jump that is for
example you want to jump to specific
place specific phase you type a key
let's say s then it then it it has lots
of choices like letters like ABC the
year have efg like then you press the
key to jump there that's no good okay in
comparison to all possible ways that's
no good because when you when it pops up
all the letters you have then to like
visually identify which one then you
have to like you know it takes a cycle
of brain to pick you know which letter
it is you don't want on that so for me
on Emacs I navigate just by pressing
keys you know and then visual with the
visual contact visual contact is kind of
if you can avoid visual contact contact
that's even better but you know first of
all avoid the brain cycle you don't want
that then if you can avoid visual
contact
spitter for example closing a fire you
don't need visual contact for example I
can close my eyes I I know the key you
know is closed and reopened you know I'm
back
right so so anyway so muscle memory pure
muscle memory without visual contact and
and without brain psycho that's the best
then sometimes you may need visual
contact
like you know I'm doing like I'm if I
want to go through you know anyway so
then print psycho like brain psycho like
like this is the worst so I never you
know you know my videos you never see me
do this okay I have a key a single key
press that just switch to me to the last
command like I can close my eyes just
switch switch me to the last window or
last app so so okay that's one of the
tip now okay so back to the mouse you
see a mouse is actually necessary I mean
on the inner browser a lot geeks you
know vim vim users or some eMac mostly
vim users you have pen tactile you have
vim parade you know you install this
extension so the browser becomes like
vim Emacs keys and you can for example
you want to click this link you type you
type a key combination then it shows you
know like ABCD efg like then it then you
click the link you know like this one
would be P you know I suppose then you
press B then it goes to that link that's
that's okay that's pretty good I was I
mean I wouldn't say that's no good it's
pretty good but it's it's not optimal
it's not in general it's not I wouldn't
go for it I mean if you are really
concerned about a fee I mean there are
several issues as efficiency concern
there's speed concern how fast you can
do it efficiency is well efficiency is
kind of speed part then you there's
economic concern
ergonomic is like if you have to do this
continuously
stop let's imagine you know you are in a
torture chamber you know a devil put you
in a torture chamber you have to do the
operations continuously for 10 hours
non-stop
then you can see when you do that then
you can see which method is actually
more ergonomic because the the less
ergonomic once you begin to feel pain
you know you'll feel tired or feel tired
up with your eyes you know you begin to
feel that so this is how serious I mean
consoie you know I don't want to say
what I mean I mean this is kind of the
way I'm thinking you know how serious it
is because for some people if you have
hand injuries it is really that serious
because for me okay there's other things
for example I don't like the you know
the common saying about not using a
mouse because for me I want to use the
mouse because my hand is on the keyboard
10 hours a day the the the the thought
about having to press a key it hurts
just the thought of that I want oh yeah
I can you know move my hand away from
the keyboard and do something different
you want that when you type certain
amount you then you such want that so
you know so again back to you know all
depends on how much you actually type so
I have another article here keybinding
typing software typing okay you go to
typing this page is about typing and
hand injury then there is a many tips
about typing related issues and hand
injury issues and one of them is about
okay go back here go to software
actually go to software and key log list
of key lock software so I've been
talking about this in several articles
you won't actually get a key lock so you
know exactly how much actually you type
then because you know programmers data
entry crooks different people or your
mommy and dad or your grandparents
you know they they type the amount you
actually use the keyboard or Mouse
differs greatly for for average
programmers you may think this is
everyone do but actually know some other
programmers they type ten times much
than you and you compare to average you
know web users they go to Twitter or
whatever you know maybe your parents or
maybe they think you know they think
they you know they they they you know
they are in a different class you you
type 10 times more than them but each
person thinks you know you don't see
other way other people so that's
important you you know how much let's go
to typing so here is all ago how many
keystrokes program a type of day and I
have I talked about this yesterday or
two days ago so anyways this is an
article you can read so you you want to
you know get the scientific details
about all that yeah so that's about
mouse versus keyboard also also I was
going to say that the mouse is important
because sorry 3d because some for some
operations
another reason okay so for some
operations okay not not this article
okay list of 3d modeling software okay
you see I mean you you seen this right
3d modeling software you have you know
cat and let's turn JavaScript
come on show okay reload
okay so you you know you have all these
3d software's
and you can see you can see obviously or
Photoshop obviously here the mouse is
it's actually critical or the or the pen
tablet you know or the pen tablet you
know so different input method input
systems actually you know in some
situations you really need that there's
no way you know if you use you know the
typical hacker you know tube Imperator
of him
you know keyboard you know it's it would
hurt your hand it would be as much so
you know you cannot do it okay so I mean
when we are talking about browser
you know clicking links you know you can
kind of get away with not using a mouse
with imperator you know so-called vim
Pareto's but you just can't in general
like for this it's more efficient if you
actually use the trackball or Mouse or
you know pain tablet you know so so
that's the point you see this is one of
the point about efficiency you know
these are different different tools for
different jobs right that's a common
saying it's okay back to I hope you know
it sometimes I to attract you know some
things I hope not I'm not doing that so
one hour and seven minutes
okay so let's read go back to the
comments XML SWOT analysis I'm gonna try
to find a mouse with tim burton's
yeah I need to okay there's another
thing you should be careful about tim
burton's because for 10 buttons Mouse
there is a there's this this type this
is got 1020 buttons okay this mouse got
20 buttons and there are many similar
this is called typically they called mm
o mas which stands for massive multi
online gaming mouse for a certain type
of games you know not first-person
shooter but anyway so they call this
like mm or
something Mouse okay I have this one
actually I don't I'm not using it right
now but let me show you
so you can see so you see this is one of
them this is from China they send it
they sent it to me actually to review
but this one is not a good one I haven't
used it and they said you know usually
Chinese ones are like two times cheaper
than American ones if you buy on Amazon
and this so this is the Logitech it
lights up actually I should well I don't
know if you guys want to see that but
why not let's plug it in
there it is you see so I can actually
change you see you see they have three
profiles which means three set up so I
have programmed them so this this is
when you wince white it's for Linux when
it's red it's for Mac I think blue is
Windows because you know the keyboard
shortcut are different so there's this
type of mouse with lots of like number
pad on the side you can program them so
I got so I've been using that for like
three three years so even more but you
know I you know I have one mouse for
each hand so you cannot like a mouse on
this this okay but one thing about this
MMO Mouse is that those buttons are not
comparatively are not easy to press
compared to for example compared to
compared to this one or compared to this
one or compared to this one for example
although it's got like more buttons so
you know you can do more things with it
without moving your hand but then but
the flaw the problem is I the mouse
buttons is harder to identify and harder
to press but you can though I mean you
can but anyway it takes more effort to
press them as well so so there's a kind
of trade-off depending I mean the thing
is depends on how how much you are you
in front of computer really I think for
average people that's okay I mean you
can get this mouse use more buttons but
for me like I avoid you know I like I
avoid you know like I have that previous
tab next know forward tap forward page
backward page previous tab next tab copy
cut paste close tab zoom in zoom out and
and maximize window okay so that's my my
settings for that Mouse and I mean it's
it's great but I avoid I try not to use
them I rather prefer keys because it's
when you use it like for many hours it
it's not it's you know it's hard on your
hands so you so you can get these if you
don't really type that much but oh you
know you know as half an hour a day you
know using a mouse that's maybe you know
but anyways the others for example this
this least they got fewer buttons but
however they are buttons more pronounced
and easier to press and easier to
identify like I mean even even this one
I don't have to look at the buttons like
oh which one button you know I don't
have to like I can feel it but still but
still the the other ones are easier to
use okay I need to find an ambidextrous
I I don't owe left-handed I don't
recommend that ambidextrous so I have
some left-handed Mouse for left-handed
people your options are severely limited
so for example Razer sales is this
left-handed MMO Mouse but actually I
think they don't make it anymore this is
back in 2014
yeah currently unavailable you see they
don't make it anymore and yeah again you
don't want to buy racer anyway yeah so
you know for left-handed your options
are basically very limited you'll get a
trackball you know get a trackball
instead but also the other thing about
left yeah ambidextrous in general I
don't they are not I don't recommend
them because because you know once you
get a ambi deck
here's another example of a memo mas but
anyway for the ambidextrous for example
this one or this one they okay they are
symmetric on both sides that basically
means okay all the patterns on the other
side are wasted you're just gonna never
use it or if you use them it's gonna be
awkward like you know you know you're
gonna cram your hand so you know reduces
you know half of the burdens are good
and you know so in general I don't
recommend it you want to get a dedicated
left hand Mouse but that's kind of fine
in between you don't find them and also
very expensive so on the other hand so
that's so what I do is you know so I you
know I have I have this each key is like
a function key I can close window and
copy patient so again I use that in
conjunction with that and the left side
sometimes it's a mouse sometimes you
know for example I I might have this
sometimes this is trackball but for
track boy I just use it for kusa
movement I don't you know like I don't
have to click I just moved to the place
I want and it it does a quick itself so
yeah so instead of buying a submit you
know ambidextrous Mouse you can you know
you can you might just get to Mouse I
mean oh actually one mouse in one
trackball I mean oh no one Mouse and one
programmable keypad that's a good thing
programmable keypads you want a
programmable keypad any of these is
pretty good yeah so one hand you know
let's say left hand mouse right hand
program a keypad keypad or you can get a
trackball
yeah I can you know
I show you some some some I recommend I
recommend all these four and I these are
big balls
and I also recommend all these four
small balls there's no right answer for
trackball you know because each person
have different press friend so if I mean
for track both the there's a less of a
consensus of you know which one is the
best because trackball they they differ
by quite a lot you know the shape the
general shape where the buttons are so
some people you know I read you know
hundreds of the reviews soon really like
that as something this is the best
something that is the best so it depends
on a person yeah and then also you have
big balls then you have thump operated
balls like these too
or you have middle finger operated balls
this these two are this all these four
are small they are kind of smaller balls
and again so is some upper lead ball
better or the index finger there's no
consensus I mean I read all that reviews
is some people really like them some you
know some people really like index index
finger but the web is graphical mouse is
necessary yeah
maybe you see Stu it's maiya in 3d
studio max yeah and Daniel hey Daniel
the only genuine complaint I have seen
for razer products is that manufacturing
in QA blows yeah I heard of that as well
so I think that's that's for today maybe
any any questions age how's it going
George so you back from vacation if you
are still here
so you mean so how is a sapphire keys
anything new doing for you
rome what was fun yeah Rome
the great Rome the Roman Empire the
glory of Rome Rome is not building one
day but that was a saying a maximun I
forgot what's a source or you know not a
lot of time meaning for you max new
stuff
okay so restore says these rest rope
says I used coursera scimitar 12 buttons
and IQ software make the mouse very
useful for Emacs oh okay
yeah Co Co Co Co is also a big brand Co
Co Co Co it has internal memory right so
anything else anything else I think
maybe that's it for today it's it's kind
of too bad you know the first half it's
silent okay anyway I learned a new thing
so about mouse about trackballs non no v
e makan
what does I mean solve
yeah well I think that's it for today
yeah it's nothing new for Emacs oh so is
that Latin Oh Latin okay know what I
don't know how to pronounce Latin okay
thank you for guys thank you thank you
guys for coming so let's let's it for
today see you next time bye