hello guys good morning everyone welcome
to another episode of xl talk show
so today is going to be random-ish
non-technical non-technical discussion
i'm going to show you
windows setup tips okay my windows setup
and also some hardware you know this is
prompted by a question you know in last
video last video someone asked me how
did i set up my windows taskbar so i'm
gonna talk about that
and i'm going to talk about the entirety
of windows setup how i set up my windows
and lots of articles but
you know so i'm going to cover that the
windows setup and the
nice tools for example let me show you a
few
go through windows so
here's my web page just go to
xrd.info
okay and you can find my website then
there it is the first one then just
search
and
win those
you know windows tip
uh you know just go to
or just go to
powershell
okay and the microsoft windows tips so
and there are great applications for
windows for uh image viewer for video
editing image editing share files you
know what applications are the best you
know from my experience i'm gonna tell
you it's a window setup but
but besides that you know the most
important thing
is keyboard okay your keyboard your
mouse your your keyboard your input
devices your microphone if you are doing
video streaming because
those those are the things you touch
every day
google user good morning i hope you are
having a good day i'm having a good day
indeed okay so let's begin okay
so window setup so okay so today let's
go to today's talk show so i'm gonna
show you lots of things
uh windows setup and tools uh
and uh and let me tell you so first of
all the
let me tell you my uh my computer's
stuff okay so i'm using the gaming
computer i bought a 2021 last year
and uh so this is one thousand dollars
that's my gaming setup so you can read
about it
uh which is not bad okay uh
so i have that machine and here are my
keyboards so you are looking at my desk
you know this is the kinesis advantage
too i'm using
and so let me recommend to you a few uh
good ones okay so all these are
keyboards i have my favorite my main
main one main drive is the kinesis
advantage okay
and this one is also very good signal
but however i never just i never just
never got to set it up this got a thumb
paddle so you know i
i can show you i don't have it set up
thumb paddle it's a great uh
innovation okay
so
so all these keyboards i would the the
ones i love the most is kinesis kinesis
advantage too
and this um
expose okay expose is pretty cheap and
very easy to get used to and it's
fantastic okay this i highly recommend
this one
if you are going to buy a organic
ergonomic keyboard okay so let me
recommend some of the others and uh and
this the
the microsoft soft scope is pretty good
but however the key
um
the
force required for the key is too much
for me so i don't recommend it for
long-term use you know if you're gonna
type for one hour more than
more than 30
30 minutes a day i don't recommend this
but otherwise it's pretty good it's it's
one of the most um
simple ergonomic ones okay
so anyway this is advantage to
expose fantastic okay and okay let me
let me show you so you go here to the
main page and right now i'm also using
on top you can see this one that's the
that's the ultimate hacking
fairly expensive you know fairly
expensive but this one is got the best
software uh keyboard markers so like i
can show you
um
ultimate hacking keyboard agent this is
a software this is the best most
intuitive software and the most powerful
i know many of you like qmk but that's
uh
you know it's gonna take you a few hours
to set it up
you need to be a nerd so anyway so this
is a ultimate hacking keyboard okay
it doesn't have enough keys for me so i
use it as a keyboard marker
okay so let me so i want to tell you so
i have a lot to cover so my keyboards my
computer okay my computers so that
gaming keyboard gaming computer and i
also got a macbook air
you know
mac windows and linux which one to
choose it's you know it's a difficult
decision i tried you know over the past
year you know so i started to use my
first computer is a mac 2si in 1992 i
bought it
mac 2si so i've been using a mac for
up to
2009 so for almost 20 years i'm a mac
user
in between i have used windows and by
the way i've i've using unix you know
solaris since 1999 working in a uh
in a corporation you know
so i'm
i and i also have used linux for a few
years so between the choices mac windows
linux you know
i've been thinking which one is the best
and there's always no good answer okay
for example on windows you know it's a
giant corporation they suck they don't
care about your privacy they
you know they they do all nasty things
and their user's interface is one of the
worst brandless completely brandless
windows
okay
on the other hand mac mac is the best
design in both hardware
mostly and software okay well of course
there are a few complaints let me show
you okay so
uh and mac m1 chip is truly
fantastic it's a revolution
okay mac
apple m1 chip is fantastic
but
but apple since steve job died
they got a um
they got several problems you know nasty
you know like your iphone when they have
a new iphone came out they make your
software slower you know intentionally
so
prompting you to buy a new one and they
make everything unfixable so they you
know they try to force you to always buy
a new mac
you know so extremely evil so i actually
i have article
so let's search for
uh
evil apple okay wait
not here okay so let's go
to xr code
and search
evil
apple
okay so you can watch this video you
know this from the famous guy uh
luis rossman you know he discussed some
of the apple things
and then you know you look at apple
designs that the dongle hail the dongle
hell
and then
then you have this kind of you know the
most idiotic design when steve jobs
steve jobs is good you know you have
this apple pencil and you have this
mouse
plug in the back and you have the worst
keyboard you know the worst keyboard
possible the butterfly you know now they
face that out
uh
then then you have this uh keyboard wear
you know problem
extremely ugly
then you have
then you have the touch bar the most
idiotic [ __ ] you know the tech you know
apple since
steve jobs is a great guy he's he's got
a vision but after he's gone
apple becomes
design are not so good and they actually
become evil they do all sort of things
you know nasty things so apple but
however
all things
compared you know all things considered
windows mac apple apple is still
the best user interface design in
everything in user interfacing in how
you use the computer the
the best design they actually thought
about design okay
so you don't have to worry about things
everything just works you know put the
computer to sleep and whatever on the
wind on the other hand the windows
extreme edr idiocy you know i can go
into details
so if you have comments comments okay
moon lander keyboard okay i'll talk
about that so apple
so windows you know this corporation you
know it sucks your
pr they don't care about you at all so
apple is also not so good but apple the
design is the best okay if you just want
to get things to work you know you have
a job you you know apple is still the
best
then there's linux you know ideally
linux is the best because it's open
source it's free you don't have to pay
and every code is you know if you are a
programmer like me
you can look at the code you can modify
but but linux is actually when you use
it it's worse than windows okay it's
worse than apples and words than windows
hey thank you or flamie
so why did apple servers go extinct okay
i can tell you that so windows so so
linux is the worst you know then you got
a bunch you know a thousand then
an army of the linux fanboys like lots
of you guys gonna tell you oh linux you
know it's open source [ __ ] idiots the
linux is the worst extreme [ __ ] in
design in whatever then you have distros
you know
this distro you know you're gonna
if you don't care about your time like
if you are a student you are a young
young ling or student you know you got
nothing to do you just go to online and
post means and crap yeah linux linux is
great but if you you know got a family
or if you are uh you know running a
business or if you are you know
you become adult linux is worst crap
okay in every way in every way because
i'm a programmer you know so i know the
linux technology i've been cis admin on
solaris since
1998 okay 1999.
but
even if you know all the knowledge about
programming about the kernels about the
memory you know about the configuration
for example i have a
so you search for sally linux tutorial
so you can find you know
500 tutorials or everything you need to
know about linux so here this section
this chapter is all about keyboard setup
on linux shift lock caps lock change
caps lock to control or escape or
whatever
and then you have the so here's the
linux key binding tutorial then you have
the linux by command line so even if you
know all these you know you are not you
you know but when you use linux when you
want to set some keys some macros it's
it's the most difficult between windows
and mac and linux okay
i have an arc on that just search for
i'm not gonna show it because we got a
lot to talk to
to talk about today
so
so in the past few years i've been
thinking you know maybe there is a
reason you know a solid reason that can
i can say okay linux actually is the
best choice today or mac or windows i
cannot
you know you like
you can't just find a reason like all
this is they all have problems
by the way another advantage on windows
is that you can play games
you know if you are a gamer of course a
lot of you young people are you know
gaming is a big industry but um
you know some of you
the mac phonetics or the linux fanatics
idiots that we are saying oh but but you
can also play games on the mac look
because this that that here's the list
of games [ __ ] idiots okay if you are
really playing games if you really want
to be a gamer
your only choice is windows okay and you
need to buy a windows gaming machine
like like i showed before okay so
between linux mac uh and windows so
first of all let me finish talking about
so macbook air is pretty good
mine chip is great okay read my articles
in my chip watch these videos this is my
choice you know after you know watch
many so these are great videos
so a mind chip so i have this computer
and then
let me show you other so i also have
this one
this is like six years old microsoft
surface pro tablet
it's okay okay i wouldn't say i
recommend it it's it's not bad okay but
it's okay
so you can uh you know one of the
advantage this computer introduced me
five years ago is that you can
you know you can write on it
which is great pain computing you know
especially when if you are doing math if
you are you know taking notes you know
you you just need this
so it's not too bad okay window surface
pro
uh
okay so
what else do i have uh so let me go over
okay so keyboard i talked about
so i will
you know kinesis advantage and get
exposed okay uh it's all on my website
uh then let me show you some other i
might recommend okay so actually so let
me show you some others
i can recommend so you can just go to
best ergonomic keyboards casa pic so
these are the few
i highly recommend i'd recommend the
most okay so
so there's a question about moon land
okay so let me explain i talked about
this many times in my past video so moon
lander moon lander is this one okay
so moon lander you know they they are a
next generation of the kinesis
of the uh ergodox okay so if you look at
the old ergodox did i mention it
so this these photos are from uh
christian you know christian is in our
discord club
discord forum discord and he
you know he bought it
so he's uh this is a christian
tierce's
vlog okay so anyway um
so anyway so moonlander they are a
improvement of orthodox do i have a link
to orthodox i should
oh yeah so the the problem with ergodox
is that you have the the thumb keys is
kind of too far
you know so you have to move your thumb
outwards too much and that for some
people that caused hand thumb pain
so
you know so so this is another
improvements you can see they move the
thumbs much closer
uh this one is modified ergodox
yeah and this you know the mod yeah so
so then there's the verge anyway this
one is five years old i'm not sure they
still make it so you know
in the keyboards lots of things change
so you can see they modified the thumb
keys so it's closer to uh to your to
your hand
okay so that's one way to fix it but
then
then does
the company that makes ergo dogs easy
created this moon lander a variation
the new uh innovation you know if we
call it that is that you have the
adjustable thumb pad
which
to me is not too useful they did not fix
the thumb too far problem the thumb key
is too far problem because if you
compare side by side with oh there it is
ergodox if you compare side by side with
ergodox they didn't really fix the thumb
problem so
i have not used this keyboard so i
cannot tell you really exactly how i
feel about it okay but i
but just by looking at the design
i wouldn't i wouldn't recommend it okay
so that's my opinion about moon lander
so uh
so so if you have a question for me put
my name
to it okay
and so let me continue get on to the
other things okay so keyboards and
ultimate hacking so my mouse
as you can see you cannot see but i can
there it is there it is my mouse okay so
i use a hoover
hoover click
just search for exactly what click this
is the best way to ergonomic way to
operate your computers okay
uh okay let me show you
sorry
hoover click okay i
said this many many times in my video so
so you have hoover click for linux i
show you how to do it so let's go back
to
talk show and paste the link here so
okay so you have the how to set up
hoover click on linux then you have how
to do it on the mac
auto click on the mac it's auto click
it's called um drill okay so this is how
so
i highly recommend it so you never have
to click you never have to you know
click again that
that creates your hand problems so for
example for me i don't even do con old
old tab crap you know like alt tab and
look which one it is and and stop and oh
oh oh i overshoot you know
don't do that okay so hoover kick click
is the best okay
on the mac and then on windows on
windows you have um
so did we copy that yes um
so here is how you set it up on windows
okay so let's copy that
okay make a link okay so hoover click
now let's go back to um
close that
yeah so that's my mouse okay
then what's up what else so i also have
this one this one is wireless it's
pretty good but
i prefer
i prefer this one g502
logitech because the mouse buttons
although it's got fewer mouse buttons by
the way it's got a spin wheel it's the
best thing okay spin wheel i talked
about this many times
essential okay this is essential it
spins for like 30 seconds
okay so
the buttons on this mouse logitech g502
is lighter than the g604
so otherwise
if they are the same force then i would
probably prefer this one wireless but
but this these thumb keys is got more
you you know you have to press it harder
so
so anyway i use this one wireless when
i'm lying in bed so okay so that's my
mouse so close that
close that so let me show you also i got
this trackball i
you know so if you like trackball if you
like some you know there are two
type of trackball
so
one type is
uh
index finger operated for example all
these
and the other type is
thumb operated okay for example that
that that that
you know many of these are thumb
operated
now finger operated is better okay if
you're gonna buy one and i recommend you
know
so all these are top recommendations you
know uh actually you know
the ones i put the thumb up are highly
recommended by a lot of people you know
when it comes to trackball there's no
one
absolute um
agreement on which one is the best but
however there are top five also people
agree they are the best okay for example
some would say this is the best some
would say this is the best you know
eltrak or the kensington expert some
would claim actually sling blade is the
best you know some would be happy with
the elect
huge and this uh odessa is not not
highly recommended so anyway so
if you i've read literally oh you know
thousands of the reviews you know like i
go to amazon i read every every comments
or other websites you know
uh geek hacking whatever so i've
literally i've read you know all the
reviews out there past you know all the
most of them
you know thousands of them literally
over the years so so
so there's no absolute agreement on
which one is the best okay so and uh so
but this one you know the ones i put the
thumb up those are good okay and
generally speaking the bigger the ball
the better they are
okay and this one is also very good okay
that one uh the kensington orbit okay
this one
it's also excellent
but now but i got the cheap ones i
bought this one thump
uh not so good okay i mean
if you
want some balls it's pretty good but
i would rather buy
you know if i'm gonna buy again i i
would probably buy this one instead okay
so
that's about my trackball
uh and okay so next
trackball
and so drawing tablet is fantastic okay
so let me show you i can so maybe
let me show you maybe
so you can see
join tablet okay so i bought you know
today there are tons of reviews on
everything so you guys probably are
familiar with a few you know the review
mouse or trackball or
microphone so you can see can you see my
microphone
so this is my microphone you know they
reveal uh speakers headphones you know
much better than me
they have
fancy gears you know each one is like
200 300
so if you have money
you know you probably go through them
but if you don't have much money if you
are a student then you do like me so i
give you the best choices for the cheap
ones so this one so you are looking at
you know this is a huey
huiong
dragon tablet okay i have demonstrated
before in my video so you can write
chinese okay so
i can launch uh so anyway so this is a
cheap one it's pretty good okay it works
on windows but if you are on the mac it
doesn't work so great okay
on windows on windows it works and on
linux it also also works for example
there's a guy
who
due to my recommendation he bought this
one used
and he's using linux so this also works
fine hu hyuian
but as far as i know on the mac it
doesn't work so well because i i've used
on a mac
so on the mac you probably want a webcam
so anyway so
i'm just gonna talk about the ones i
actually have okay so
uh joint tablet is great is is great
especially if you take notes okay it
becomes essential
wait what is this
[Music]
let me show you um
what is so let me talk about the drawing
tablet software okay
okay i'll get to it so let me let me
show you so if you want an external
drive this one is the best okay i have
it you know i have it somewhere so
for backups you know this is a flash
drive fantastic okay get this one
so that's that one
and microphone i got the i got this
cheap one
china you know forty dollars thirty
dollars or something
which is what i'm using now can you see
let's see
you know you can kind of see
okay so
but then i read you know a bunch of
reviews
all these ones are highly recommended
uh some of them are cheap some of them
are you know 200 or something
okay so that's about microphone then
then speakers you know
so
speakers
i was using this one
you see this uh this one this is uh
creative payable usb speakers it works
nice but after one year after one year
it broke you know the left speakers no
longer works for strange reasons i don't
know you know i thought maybe it's a
connection that's weird because i never
touched the connection i thought maybe
it's not well connected or something but
i cannot figure it out so the left
speaker spoke just doesn't work anymore
after a year so
so i went to uh the actually the local
shop and bought this
cheap logitech you know
twenty dollars thirty dollars okay
the and right now i'm using it it's okay
okay
so but if you have money of course then
you want
high grade you know expense three
hundred dollars four hundred dollars one
thousand dollars so i have a friend um
i do break the loop
who
recommended to me a few because he
looked you know he looked at high-end
speakers
so these are
six whopping six hundred dollars okay so
you guys can buy it and buy it for my
website
okay so so speakers then headphones okay
so i have some headphones
uh so that's my router you know
typical standard routers i got
i can't say it's good or bad but it's
you know router and modem cable modem
for
i'm using
uh comcast x infinity xfinity so you
need a cable modem and you need a
wireless router
uh okay so what else uh and barefoot
shoes you know this is a
strange thing for most people so i like
this shoe you know the thing about bare
foot
bare feet shoes is that you know modern
shoes for example nike you know run
sneakers running shoes you know they
have height you know they have high you
know they have thick
pad at the bottom
so
you know you think you know they
you know it's pretty new it's you know
only happened in the last
50 years so the idea is that you know
because it's got thick
source with high technology nike air or
whatever you know it protects your
protect shocking and you know shock
absorbent and all that but it turns out
actually it may it may harm your feet
okay because the the way you know the
thick
bottom
modifies the way you walk
or run so
so the idea is that actually you are you
will be better to have a flat shoe
that doesn't have thick bottom you know
actually very thin bottom so that's what
about this
flat shoe so this is a cheap one thirty
dollars or forty dollars i would you
know it's very good i've been you know
using it for a year and it's about it's
a bit broken
you know so so i'm i'm going to buy a
new one and then i bought this one too
recommended by george
george from our discord okay
so anyway
so shu
and let me talk about the desk okay this
desk you know this my favorite desk is
just this utility folding desk
this is this is the best desk for nerd
okay most practical and the lightest and
the most sturdy okay
utility desk that and i like my desk big
you know big i don't like you know
there's just tiny ones i cannot work
with those you know the i wanted you
know like right now i have that
my desk is like over
five meters five meters wide
so ut and this is our reaper
here you know and alan
allen drew this um
allen you know he allen used to be
frequent on our discord in
so anyway
um
so yeah so some test recommendations so
okay so let's go back so let's uh how
long have i been talking 30 minutes okay
so then then next
okay then okay now
those are the hardware stuff now let's
talk about
setting up windows okay let me recommend
to use some of the applications for
windows and stuff
okay let's put it back
to my keyboard okay
so windows so
you know go to my website saudi
microsoft windows tips so the first
section is about technical so if you are
a programmer you want to or if you are a
technical person working on windows you
want to read these sections so i have
the entire powershell tutorial by now
it's over like 50 pages okay
this is
i would say this is the best powershell
tutorial i've been working with
powershell for over a year now
almost every day so i dug you know
so you know as you know i have lots of
i'm a programming language expert you
can call me that you know i study
programming languages so now i have been
actually using powershell for over over
a year and study all the details you
know i would say it's much better than
bash but it's fairly complex okay so
anyway i'm not gonna talk about
powershell today so
if you are on wing but if you are on
windows and if you are a programmer then
powershell you must get to know it okay
because the you want to use powershell
instead of bash because you want to use
native
the the native
technology is always better than firing
or importing one
imported ones so if you are on windows
powershell is a must okay if you are a
programmer working on windows or working
with windows tech powershell is a must
so learn it okay
read my tutorial it's a it's it's i
would say you know at least in my
opinion it's the best tutorial out there
for powershell
concise and technical and example based
okay and i give you the technical
concept so that you can once you know it
you know everything about the system the
powershell you know the environment how
it works
uh
so then
there's a windows environment tutorial
is critical you know
then registry tutorial is also critical
on windows
what it is and and of course then you
can start to use powershell to program
rich to modify registry and similarly
for um
environment variables you can use you
know you can start to use
uh let me show you so you can start to
use powershell to modify environment
variables
okay so those are and windows terminal
is the latest you know microsoft created
windows terminal
about three years ago
so this is uh so you can look at it here
so that's windows terminal okay it's
better than the old for example let me
show you the old windows console
so both of them are running powershell
but this one with the blue background is
the windows console
and this one
the you know
let me let me open a new tab so use you
can have tabs you know this is uh
you are looking at the windows
uh terminal okay which
which has unicode support for example
let me show you so
so you might be wondering what's the
difference
you know lots of better features unicode
support so let's go to web
xrd
info okay
then
cd2
uh
comp
okay
so
the
uh
okay
okay so i want to
cat
i want to display the content of a file
so
okay
moved so what is the
no it's not moved so you can see
you are looking at emoticons in
uh
in powershell i mean windows terminal
okay
but if you do it here
they won't show okay so
then again okay
unicode
okay so here are the all the emoticons
and e-max let's launch the current
directory into
the windows console powershell
and now let's do cat the same as magnify
cat
so what is the file name
unicode
emote
because so you can see
you can see
they don't show
so
one of the feature of the windows
terminal is it shows in emoji okay
that's great
okay so let's see what else so you want
to use windows terminal okay so you know
get that
then okay so those sections are
technical sections then you have uh
what's the best windows application
what's uh what's the windows keyboard
you know everything you need to know
about
setting up keys and mark key markers on
windows so here are everything you need
to know you want to know about it it's
here
for example what software is you need to
do so i'll just recommend
uh microsoft power toys okay get that so
you can see i have it installed here let
me launch it
so you can configure your keyboard okay
so that's you know so microsoft power
toys okay so one of them is keyboard
manager so you can see you can set up
shortcuts and so on remap keys
and the other tool i recommend is auto
hotkey
so auto hard key is more general purpose
it do lots of things
so it's almost it's like a scripting
language to control user interface so i
have a tutorial here you can read okay
so okay that's about windows keyboard
and also you can you know about how to
single click to open file we talked
about
uh how to hoover to activate activate
window oh yeah this we talked about that
uh disable sleep button
sometimes useful because you know when
you get a pc like one time i got a pc
and it's installing something
and by mistake you know there's a sleep
key i hate that bit by mistake and that
[ __ ] up
that [ __ ] up the installation i have
to reboot in you know
so you can disable the button
okay so things like that okay so
let's get back to other things so let me
show you some of the great uh okay so i
think
i think that's it for today so how long
have i been talk talking uh 40 minutes
okay
so
actually so we have a lot to cover so
so the guy asked me about windows
how do i how did i set up my windows
taskbar okay
there's not much to talk about but i can
tell you so first of all you want to do
you know that's what i do
doesn't matter it's on windows or on
linux or mac i systematically explore
explore every options
for for example on windows you just
press windows i
to
to launch these um
you know the settings
then you
systematically go through each and every
one of them
for example
you know so night
night light settings so you can let's
turn it on so if i turn it on it's gonna
be
reddish so it's gonna be you can you
know
systematically explore every
buttons and
and wheels and knobs okay that's what i
do
and the sound and windows sucks you know
all these options very confusing like
you have no idea what they do then also
you know they have like spider links you
know
then
when you come to an item you don't know
look up on the web so let me turn back
the night
settings the nice settings on windows it
also sucks okay sometimes it doesn't
turn on
uh you know sometimes it doesn't turn
off you know it's idiotic windows
and on linux by the way i must say on
linux it's worse
okay i'm getting tired so let me so the
guy who asked me about the taskbar
there's nothing to you know
so you go to
you know you go to the
personalization
and there's a taskbar it's very
confusing by the way
but i've been using windows 10 for
you know now it you see what the [ __ ]
i've been using windows 10 for three
years now so
you know i'm familiar so you go to you
know here so here's how you set the test
spot you know just check you know check
out every option
then
combine task taskbar never i tried them
all like sometimes for a week
all the possible options in combinations
then you you have the notification area
then you have the system icons on and
off very confusing idiotic okay
you just you just try them okay
anyway
so i'm not i'm not gonna talk about much
about it so let me read about um
okay about spy spyware i can tell you
you know you go to privacy and turn
everything off
i did
and you know you also look you can
search search the web just search search
windows 10 or windows 11
privacy
then some nodes will tell you how to
turn everything out off but actually you
don't need to because you can actually
just you know like
basically everything they said is all
here okay
you just all you have to do is
systematically systematically explore
everything so i have like
everything off
you know
the the the
the user interface design is very
idiotic for example this location is
turning off your location okay then
instead of a button like that you you
know they have this special you have to
click to change then
you can turn it on
yeah
you know maybe you think this is like a
nuke button so you have some protection
before you accidentally click it it
doesn't make sense idiotic you know you
have to click this first
then turn it on
then then click somewhere to get off you
know it's idiotic okay windows user
interface design and
you know this you know
i can talk on our
i have a full set of articles about
windows user interface design so camera
okay camera i need to be on then you
know
check everything so
most of my things is off like i have
everything off especially notification
notification is the male engine zoomer
thing turned everything off no
notification at all
oh i have i have it on for some reason
you know but the problem with turning
everything off is that then you know
when you want to chat with your friends
or your family or whatever then you got
into a problem because you forgot which
settings must be young
then it's hell you know that's a problem
you know and you know why you know they
they intentionally make this confusing
on windows
by the way on linux is worse i'm pretty
sure
anyway so they intentionally i can i
know because after 30 years of
experience with windows or whatever
adobe
market media you know flash back then
and many websites like twitter facebook
those those are scums okay twitter
facebook you know they they'll say oh we
care about your privacy we listen to you
or what you say so today we we we come
to uh
with a new you know preference setting
so you can
grab those old lies okay the intention
ultimately that's what they do they
intentionally make everything very
complex so if use you know you can go
and set everything off
but then what happens is that when you
need to chat you know using a microphone
then it becomes impossible you forgot
you know
which settings exactly you you need you
know they make it that way so so they
they essentially they want they want to
make it so that
for most people you know
non-computer you know non-technical
people you know you just leave
everything on so your window works you
know
any they it doesn't it needs not to be
that way
but they make it so that they
make you think it needs to be that way
because oh because technology that's why
it's so complicated and that's not true
okay anyway windows um by the way you
know every time i flame about windows i
need to make sure that linux is the
linux [ __ ] like many of you you
know because you're saying oh but linux
why don't you use linux because you know
it's no no it's worse okay it's almost
worse than every way okay linux
i've been using unix and i've been my
first linux is 1998
1998 mk linux okay you guys are not born
yet linux is worse
in just about every way the only okay so
when
when when is when is linux your best
operating system
okay when you if you are a programmer if
your profession is programming and if
your environment is open source
programming languages searches such as
python
ruby
javascript web dev
okay then linux is the best and also
provided that you don't play games
and you don't do video editing and you
don't do audio like you don't chat with
your family much
okay if you are just a teen
if you're a student college student
student you got nothing to do every day
you just blah blah blah and [ __ ] around
every day
and you like you love open source yeah
then if that's the case you don't do
video editing you don't you need to
make professional presentation or
whatever then linux that's the best
environment okay no games
and also you don't have money yeah
that's the best environment that's
that's that's when linux is the best
okay
so okay so what uh what else to talk
about so i think that's it for today so
let me read the comments i'm getting
tired been sitting here for like three
hours
and
i'm thirsty i need my drink
okay so how long is it
50 minutes okay so let's see what's the
comment and that's it for today
so uh is there anything questions for me
post my name to it okay
right now
and is there anything i want to talk
about
so here are all the tips okay
um
and you know this is you know this this
this is a problem on windows let me tell
you this example okay so for example on
on windows not linux on windows you can
set your background uh image you know
you can set your background image
but however
now and then
you'll notice that your background
changed by mistake
like if you are taking photos your you
know your private photos your bedroom
photos
all of a sudden you notice it's your
background logging image what the [ __ ]
that happens by accident accident i
don't know either i don't even know how
it happens
it happens apparently frequently
happened to me a few times like three
times in the past year and if you look
online
apparently it happens happen to other
people you know
you don't know why but certainly some
pictures becomes your login screen okay
then
of course you want to delete it what the
[ __ ] then you you you discover there's
no way there's no it it is impossible
to delete them
you know you [ __ ] [ __ ] eat extreme
idiots in microsoft so i dug around so
this this this is what happens you you
know
so
it's not easy okay it's not easy to
delete them
okay so here's some of my backgrounds
you know especially
login screen that's important you don't
want your private photos becomes the
login screen okay so
i look around this apparently there's no
easy way
you know even if you are a programmer
you've been unix linux admin for 20
years me
it's
not it's not easy
so i have an article telling you how to
do that you know after spending an hour
or two looking around it's very complex
okay
so
actually the most easy way is actually
just to add more photos okay because it
keeps about
five or ten
i forgot how many
you know they the microsoft what they do
is that they grab the photo
and they put that a copy of your photo
into some special private location that
you cannot access
okay you cannot access it they make a
copy of it
so you cannot even delete it and it's
hard you know you have to change the
folder owner and stuff and it's not easy
to do on windows
even if you know powershell you know i
know powershell for a year now it's not
easy you cannot just do it with
powershell you know maybe you thought oh
i'm a powershell master i'm a tech nerd
so i'll just powershell you know remove
some file you know change on you know
change mod like the linux idiot you know
then remove those no you cannot do it
and by the way linux is worse in lots of
situations
so
so the easiest way if you accidentally
put a photo in your lock screen is
actually just add more photos like click
browse and add more photos that will
erase previous one that's the easiest
way
so that's one of the windows problem is
and it's got 10 000 more problems
windows sucks why because they actually
don't care because the team whatever
windows 10 windows 11 you know they have
pretty boys coming out news windows 11
is coming out oh and then a bunch of
idiots linux tech
tips you know and others you know nuts
they're gonna review youtube
is windows 11 better or not [ __ ] ears
you know it's like
it's not even a question to review or
not it sucks donkey ass the most
apparent way for example
to this day
you have you still have windows control
panels okay and many of these things
that comes out with a tiny font you know
for example let's say
let's say this okay
uh wait what
what's some
good examples
that you know many many of these almost
all of them okay it comes out with a
tiny font you cannot
like normally
you can
hold down control and uh
and
and draw the mouse to increase font size
or you can set the font size
by
this way okay
but that they have no effect on these
windows
especially this one this this is a good
example you know file explorer options
you know this is the option to change
your
you know change the font size and size
you know
for example okay
change the folder view uh preferences
you know then you know i have a 23 inch
screen but i'm forced into this
tiny claustrophobic [ __ ]
each word you know
it's impossible to change the font size
i cannot see
and it gets worse you know the
claustrophobic you know these little
windows
[Laughter]
this this interface
is
almost 30 years old
but they have shiny windows 10 windows
so do they have how do i control how do
i want to if i want to show folders you
know that beginning the name begins with
a dot how do i do it you have to go
through this no other way
you know like
hide empty you know the [ __ ] this is
the insult
so it's windows 11 you know they
designed the whole thing
no you still have this you have tons of
them actually all over the place
so it's a it's a [ __ ] line scum it
you know it's not like like even worth
it's not even
valid to say you have new interface or
better design my ass
this is because this is a fundamental
preference you know to control the
folder view
they did they didn't change it
you know
so it's just all uh you know scam scam
and scan
and also linux is linux is worse okay
worse
but mac is just supreme supremely
beautiful easy to change in and but of
course apple have its own problems evil
you know
stuff
pretty sad okay pretty sad situation
so um okay i'm done today uh
so
what i was yeah so what else uh
so i was going to go through many great
applications on windows but i think
that's it for today
uh okay i'm gonna just read
comments and that's it
bye guys
coffee house okay
super chat why no max servers okay you
guys
uh
oh yeah okay yeah why no mac servers let
me answer that question you know mac
well the basic
the simple answer is that there's no
market for it you know because if you
are
if you want to run a server
which is very technical you know if you
are running a website like amazon you
know so if you want to run a server
basically you go with linux linux or bsd
you know free server
the linux is much more geared for
servers because that's the industry
basically if you want to
set up a server run you know server
software
that means you are a programmer you are
a professional you know
a programmer
linux
you know the mac os yeah it can it's
pretty robust you can you can run a
server with it but there's no market
because
99.99 people
they just use linux because over there
you have 10 000 times bigger community
you have bigger support oh yeah for
example or
google
and much of microsoft
or google amazon they are all running
linux or bsd you know like one percent
maybe
then netflix amazon you know all the
major websites they are all linux
so linux becomes
just by convention almost like
convention it becomes the
the standard you know
so apple
they try it you know they like but
beginning around 19
you know basically nobody use it you
have to pay by the way the max server
so there are two questions so what do
you mean mac server so one is the max
server hardware you know apple used to
sell you know the mac hardware server
for running
servers with then there's also mac os os
10 running a special version of mac os
10 designed for running servers so they
also
both of them basically died nobody used
it okay so that's what they died like 10
years ago because you know even when
they were around nobody is using them
i you know i have actually admitted
microwave service helping a professor in
academia
so that is why
um
so what else uh anything else
interesting questions or
junior show or flamingo what about v-man
e-max yeah
i don't recommend lsp servers at all
okay so i'm as you know i'm a e-max user
but i do not recommend any lsp
if you want to use lsp go with you know
go to
excel open vs go go to vs code there you
run rsp if you are
running vim
or emax i don't really recommend lsp
especially e-max because it kills e-max
e-max this
the core i talked about this in one of
my video actually
for half half an hour
the the the core power of emacs is the
emac list language
but lsp is [ __ ] it up you know lsp is
running someone else's language on some
other people's computer
lsp well actually on your own computer
because anyway i you know i don't
recommend lsp okay
don't use lsp
if you are using emacs
okay so
i don't care about software minimalism
you know i don't care about all those
philosophies
actually i'm you know i am kind of minim
minimalist you know what i care the most
is functionality
two things okay functionality and
efficiency
these two things i care the most
in in
in software uh user interface in
particular okay
so
for example i hate you know i do not
like the window tightening windows
managers not because they are not
functional
well basically because they are not the
most efficient and the most functional
okay
they claim you know the linux fanboys
the linux phonetics the linux idiots
they you know many of them you know many
of you too you know they they they they
wanna you know linux distro and titling
window managers they claim
okay
if you care about the functionality and
efficiency then you know tiny manager
windows manager is the best okay
okay
so their
goal is the same as mine except i'm
actually more extreme i only care
about functionality i don't care about
the looks okay for example my emacs
setup is the most simple possible i
don't want even things i don't want
color [ __ ] themes okay
so
appears it appears that their goal is
the same as my
the most functional and the most
efficient okay
but but for my from for my analysis
actually the window tiling manager is
not efficient and not functional
compared to my setup [ __ ] idiots in
fact and also they don't like to use
mouse you know you read you know the
same kind of people the community tiny
window manager links you they hate the
mouse
actually you know i have
usually i have more than two i have more
mouse you know i have a mouse and then
plus per se
that's more efficient okay for example
you see you see this you see this no
mouse click okay can you you know i
didn't i talked about this so many times
you see this
no mouse click okay so i want to switch
you know switch applications
switch applications
no control tab idiocy all these styling
window managers they
most of them are still using control tab
let me show this
wait
did i get it right what
oh oh yeah oh not control tab or tab
okay so they are doing this you know
these tiling window managers they are
they are all still doing this
their brain is brainless
brainlessness is their thing they just
they just dribble they are teenagers you
know they are young people
why do you need a mouse because mouse is
the most efficient for example you see
that you see that
it's better than it's better than your
[ __ ] idiotic page up and down
oops for example i want to look at this
uh
image
oops
oops i want to see the whole thing but
oh
now i need to arrow up
arrow up so i can see the [ __ ] idiocy
okay now
on the other hand look at the look at
the other way down
my hand is here okay
oh there is a there's an image okay
there i can see the whole thing okay i
don't have so if i want to hold full
screen okay macro okay
chemo marker you see
back to the back to what this
application now back to the chat you see
i don't have to press you know
i exert the minimal
human energy
to do things to do exactly the things
you need to do
okay that's too much rent uh that's it
that's it bye guys
okay pay me okay
donate patreon you know i don't want to
set up you know youtube membership you
know those elaborate things membership
please like my video please number that
helps a lot [ __ ] youtube
yeah
so if you like my stuff pay me you know
if you pay by you know this
this uh super chat you know google takes
like 30 to something
so i sell you know i sell you know i
have links on my website my patreon
or paypal you know the money goes to me
they take like
a few dollars you know but anyway paypal
amazon paypal uh
amazon gift card
or bitcoin
and i sell my emacs tutorials it's all
free online by the way you know unlike
some other people you know the emacs
you know they they are good guys they
don't swear you know all these other
youtuber tech especially the programmers
on the emacs community they don't swear
they don't offend people
they say oh they also sell tutorials
cmax tutorial but they charge forty
dollars more than mine and they don't
cover as much but they but they but they
but then they um
you know they don't they they are nice
people did not unlike socks
bad because they swear [ __ ] because
it's crazy you know they are nice
and but it's not free they are open
source they pro they are pro they
support open source help the world
unlike staff who is like [ __ ] [ __ ] open
source all the time because it's crazy
but they they support open source but
their tutorial is not free meanwhile you
go to reddit emacs everyone is just
you know
best tutorial is there they don't
mention mine
because i'm a fancy because
[ __ ] it you know hypocrite hypocrites
but apparently that's how the world goes
you know that's why
that's why the word the the word we see
it becomes that way you know all the big
companies behave that way
that's because that's how they actually
that's how human animals
our behavior turns out to be that way
by
okay shut down in one minute uh
shut down in one minute
because evil apple okay so did i did i
actually have the links
in my uh so let's copy the links
this is emoji okay so
copy so look at the
efficiency okay
so show the pink window the pink window
shows all my command cores
so called
linux by command online
okay
and we also covered linux key binding
tutorial
evil apple you know apple
so between apple and mac and windows
there's no
no one criteria you could say that which
one you should use they are all
today they are all pretty
bad
okay that's it bye guys thank you for
watching
you