hi all so I'm going to do let's see turn
HTML mod and the HTML shortcut create a
HTML page save the file as let's just
say that and show him browser empty
that's good
so something show good in logic
okay and let's say eMac this so we might
list code and I want to do this let's
say message let's say 1 plus 1 okay
okay 1 plus to avow 3 that's good there
three and let's do something more fancy
let's say T fun xx insert in is the
stuff ok I want to insert basically okay
wait he said okay P 1 2 3 4 and backward
cha for
okay Eva we don't need that Eva and
let's run it
XX that's good that's fantastic so I'm
doing that so I'm gonna demo let's say I
wanna okay close that put it here
showing browser you see that's a code so
I'm writing a tutorial for as let's say
you make this for something then but
it's not colored I wanna color so you
know you can do that oh that's that's
good wait it's still not cool at all
because I know that's why because I need
a CSS file so go back
I'll go Emacs ugh that's good there it
is there it is the file so copy the path
paste it there make a link and go back
there it's wonderful so so this is this
this is Emacs this let's try that we can
do pro let's say oh and I forgot Perl
stuff so but we can do print 3+5 Evo
that's correct
eight so coffee yet curse that put it
here and show not colored no good now
color it sure oh no it's good now for
python it's the same let's say python
python yeah print fifa's seven I can run
it ten is good close paste make it color
that's good
and now you see lots of code here like
span in Spanish but you can you cannot
read it but I can press a button and
your show then I can
edit insert
PTAC you know I can hit it and make it
cut it again let's see we correct yes
it's correct and oh I can press a key
and the whole thing you know it gets
dhtml iced so that's good
so that's the thing I want to show you
that's that's very convenient now I have
a tutorial on how to do that now
remember it's like Oakmont let me ramble
a little bit let's like for example in
oak mod you can do pretty much the same
thing eMac practical Emacs editing stuff
hog mod embed code yeah so in oak mod
you can pretty much do the same thing so
but similarly I'm doing that with HTML
oh yeah so I have a tutorial out how to
do that so that is here
syntax color source coding HTML so here
I explained to you how it's done and if
you just want to use the code you can
it's available at side Gmail mod so you
can you can use that okay that's it for
this video thank you for watching bye