good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of xl talk
show
today is 2021
april 21st and today
we are going to code javascript
plus svg we are going to continue
our journey last time i did
two videos before that is generating
javascript with
bi-gram let me show you where okay uh
hold on a second
javascript live coding creating a bar
chart in svg so that is april
16 2021
and 2021
april 10th javascript live coding
uh writing a interactive diagram
count okay so that's two videos i've
done before you can just search for my
um let's let's go to today's okay
so this is actually today this is the
part three
okay uh let's see
so you can see we did two videos before
today it's part three
we're gonna continue to finish the
javascript coding
now two good health a little wet red
wine a day makes you live for
longer maybe possibly
so you're gonna see me drunk coding
actually you know drunk coding doesn't
work
okay but a little one won't get me drunk
okay so let's start coding
uh we don't have people here so i'm just
start to code it okay
so let me show you what this is about so
this is
uh what we the state of
our condition last time you
start to type something
and you can see the diagram start
to form so you can see
a2 happened twice i mean
st happened twice ta happened twice
all happened twice right now there's
every diagram you know so
so you have the data and you have a
chart
and so so this is diagram
and as i type more
you can start to see a pattern
because some background background is a
sequence of two letters
some diagram will happen
more often than others
okay so for example thth
is one of the most frequent diagram in
english
in english okay so this is javascript
and svg and in last two videos we
explained
we you know we live coded it but today
there's some problems you see now the
diagram the bar chart is upside down
that's incorrect well that is not
necessarily incorrect but
it is uh unusual so
normally you want to see them as
uh let me show you it okay let me show
it to you
layouts go to layouts uh just go to
search for xrd
keyboard you'll find so this
is how a normal bar chart
looks like you know so we need to fix
our upside down graph and
also we need to add a label
so you can actually see what the
diagrams are so let's start coding that
good morning good morning who is it who
comes by
lucas zambia hey i remember your i
remember lucas zambia good morning
good evening so javascript background
let's start coding so let's see where
are we so
on this page okay so for
you emacs users the pink window shows
all my commands
you can see forward word backward word
backward chart and previous line next
line
you can see all my emacs command code or
delete
uh paragraph undo and you can see
also the key i used to
call those commands and i'm using soft
like keys
and this is uh i'm using a vora keyboard
okay so actually
uh so let me show you
the borac keyboard okay every time i
have to show this
a little bit so you can see
the royal keyboard let's okay let's put
the
focus on the keyboard for a moment
so you can actually see what i type when
i'm typing
okay so this is kinesis advantage
keyboard and this is ultimate hacking
keyboard i use
as a macro pad
and if if you like it go to xr keyboard
website
go to ergo keyboard and you can see
reviews of it and there's
also video reviews so that's
kinesis advantage 2 and
ultimate hacking keyboard fantastic
go there and buy it they are good for
your hands
okay let's back to the
javascript coding okay so search for
javascript so here is the line
we open enter to open the file so the
file is only 120
lines of code okay shall we go over
uh yes we shall let me go over
the code so we can understand so first
of all you have a description
javascript app to draw diagram of a
given text
first part of the problem grab the given
text compute the diagrams and print the
count of them
example input a b c d
e t h t h h and the diagrams are
abcd you know so the input is a b c
d e the biograms are a b b c c
d d e okay that's what background means
so you want to write a code given a big
string you want to
sample output okay you can so sample
output is a nested array
so th occurs three times uh ht occurs
twice
this is just a sample okay this is not
the result of this
uh text input okay so that's the first
part of the problem compute the diagrams
generate a data the second part of the
problem
is given a map object of the diagram
such as this draw a bar chart
by generating a svg object
so that's my second video i did last
time
you can see it generates a
svg chart so now let's go over the code
so lucas says just spot the keyboard
from your recommendations the advantage
to
linear uh the advantage to lf
though from uk not us because living in
europe i hope it will be good for hand
paint i hope so
thank you uh i don't get money from uk
amazon's
it's too bad anyway so
so okay background so let's go let's see
yeah
let's look at the code okay so first of
all
first of all you want to know so first
of all when you code
svg when you call javascript you need to
be
familiar with html okay
when you call javascript so let me turn
the camera
back to
back to my face okay so so that
um
okay so
i need to buy a good snack for the
camera so i can
okay so diagram
okay now i'm feeling a little bit effect
of the wine
just a little red right 200 ml
uh okay background so when you call
javascript
now i'm talking to beginners of course
when you call javascript let's go to
my javascript website okay javascript i
have a javascript in-depth
tutorial you should go buy it if you
like my stuff
go by javascript in depth
you'll learn javascript from the ground
up
for beginners or even if you coded
javascript at google for two years
it will still benefit you so
so i was saying when you call javascript
you also need to know
okay if you go to
web dev tutorials you also need to know
html
very well okay that's kind of necessary
you need to know html very well and you
also need to know css very
very well so this is my
um my so my
css tutorial and javascript tutorial
it's necessary okay now of course
if you are just working at some company
uh
you know there's lots of libraries lots
of you know
css generators yeah that's good for
beginners but
if you really want to uh be a serious
javascript
programmer for writing web applications
you need
to know by heart css and html
well okay so that for example our
diagram
our diagram application does not use any
libraries there's no
npm there's nothing it's only 150
lines okay so
so it's a diagram okay so uh so let's go
back to
dot js okay so by gram only 120 lines
okay now we're gonna probably add 50
more lines
so make it complete so let me go fast so
you need to understand html you need to
know understand
uh css then because i'm we are doing svg
you also need to know svg well so i have
a tutorial here
you can see a clock this clock this is
generated by
javascript and svg and only
100 lines okay no library needed needed
okay so you know i'm
okay so now let's look at uh how do we
create a diagram okay so first
first of all you need two in three
important things here so you can see
one is the text area html tag
which creates this box let's use a
enter text then the other one is
span svg display area id
so this is basically you just you know
just
invisible element spam because there's
is empty you can see
and your javascript will grab that
basically it will insert svg code
into this place so that's where
you see the bar chart and similarly one
more thing
you need another span or it can be dive
as well or any other
id show box so this is where javascript
will insert
the data so that's these that is the
three
html things you need okay then
let's look at the javascript then here's
the javascript so you can
open the file go to the top you can see
uh first of all we we use get element by
id
to grab those elements so they become
dom objects so text area
then show box and svg display area okay
typically these are named root if you
know if you are using one of the
libraries like
react angular or something they are
typically they call it root
they they you know they give a id as
root
but it's the same okay so so first of
all
we we have a function f string two
diagram
so this function takes a string and it
returns a map
javascript map object
javascript map object okay i think i'm
drunk
[Laughter]
i'm slightly okay just a little red wine
i'm not a drinker uh what are we on
so so so that function
this function string two diagram takes a
string
and it returns something like that a map
object that is the statistics of the
diagram
okay so that's that function
then then we have the function sort
map which takes a
which takes a map javascript map object
which is key value pairs okay
then it sorts them okay and
it returns a nested array
where each element is a
array of two elements like that so it
sorts the map basically
so that's sort map then another function
map filter
map filter filter out certain pairs in
the map
certain keys in the map why why do you
need to do that because when you have
diagram for example
let's say you have uh you know so
this is a biogram period
and something else now you you see that
period so m and period
forms one diagram and period
and space forms another diagram
okay that's technically true you know
every two characters is considered
a diagram but however that you know we
don't want that
because typically when you consider
statistics or diagram
you only consider letters you don't
consider the
you know any punctuation therefore
we need to have a function filter map
that removes those pairs and this
function is done by using a regular
expression you can see
regular expression you know a to z
capital a case or lowercase and another
a to z
so we only want a to z if
it's not if you know the if the key is
not a letter
remove it okay
actually now since i'm looking at this
code this should be
um this code needs to be
improved because for example if i'm
typing chinese
you know sometimes you know all other
languages russian
let's say russian chinese japanese you
also need to compute diagram but
if you just remove everything that's not
english alphabet
then then you don't get any backgrounds
because chinese is all characters
so instead of using alphabet
instead of using uh a to z we need to
change it so that
so that it uses um regular expression
of characters uh you can do that with
unix
with unicode property now this is a
little bit
advanced yeah this is a
advanced topic and i am digressing
but let me let me digress okay but
if you go to my javascript in depth
go to uh object reference
then you go to regular expressions
and let's magnify okay then
here is all you need to know about
regular expressions in javascript
okay and you can see regular expression
so you have a tutorial
then you have a list of regular
expression functions
which is actually what you need to call
these are the most useful
you know let me but let me digress a
little bit again
so in javascript javascript is not a
very good
not a very well designed language
because
it is designed and implemented
in 10 days only now this is true
this is actual historical fact
javascript language is designed and
implemented you know writing a compiler
in 10
only 10 days so
so this got lots of problems but then
after 20 years
after by now 25 years lots of changes
in web technology so you have uh turns
a huge amount of baggage okay end of
digestion
now why am i talking about that because
in javascript regular expression
functions you have two
types one are
you know one set of string methods so
you have a string
and you have a function that takes a
regular expression as input
so these are string string object
methods
okay then you have you have actually one
two three four five
five of them by now then you have
two regular expression object
based function so you start with the
regular expression
then you call the method then you give
it a string so it's gonna you know it's
kind of
you may say it's inconsistent but
actually this happens
in python i believe it happens in python
as well so it's one of the problem
of designing a language uh
object oriented language you have the
issue
of a dilemma of whether you should put
the string
as object or or regular expression as
object
it's hard to decide same issue happens
in numbers
so if you have a number should the
number be the object or should
should uh uh should math be the object
you know be the be the class you know
so if if number is object so you have a
number
then you say plus dot plus you know
first it's a method
multiply is a method the right is the
method
but if you have the math as object math
library so
you say math then you dot plus
then the number becomes arguments you
know then you have math dot multiply
then arguments numbers you know so so
it's a design
it's a problem it's a one of the
kind of the well-known problem in
object-oriented language
design because which one which way
should you go
there you know is is not there's no
uh one good answer to that
so some languages has both as you've
seen
here in javascript okay so that's a bit
digression again
now back to regular expressions so so
javascript you have a tutorial
you have regular expression functions
then you have regular expression
syntax now if okay i'm digressing a lot
let's get back to the code okay
okay so now let's get back to the
question
of how do you capture characters
that is actually a character including
english alphabets russian alphabets or
chinese characters
that can be done if you go to my
javascript in depth
that can be done if you look into
let's see properties okay
let's see tutorial do i cover it here
no because tutorial is just for
beginners okay
we are doing advanced javascript now so
let's go to
properties.prototype go down
magnify
let me show you how to do that okay this
is a kind of a digression
so first of all object regular
expression we
reg xp prototype okay
so what what type is it what
is its parents what is its purpose
then you have properties then you have
the two functions
test and execute and you also have two
string properties
then you have a bunch of symbol
properties now symbol is a new thing
new data type introduced in javascript
2015.
again that's advanced there it is okay
so
then you have value properties uh
okay actually this is not what we want
we are getting complex
okay i think i found a flaw
in my javascript tutorial because where
does it say
because right now i want to be able to
match
characters in unicode not just english
alphabet
i want to match all possible
characters that's considered a character
of some language
which should include english letters
acrylic russian or even chinese
characters or japanese characters so
there's a way to do that
and i'm not seeing it here so let's
click on that maybe
so this should be considered as a flaw
in my tutorial because i there's no easy
way to find it
but what's going on let's click on flags
okay so there i found it so it's one of
the flag
you two match unicode characters use
unicode
property syntax c regular expression
unicode property okay so
here's the example how you do it so
let's see let's look at the unicode
property
regular expression unicode property okay
so here's how you do it
okay since we are talking about that
let's let's continue and
implement this this is a bit advanced
topic now let's go back to the common
let's see what common
sorry i missed it did you already go
over
svg no i did not
oh so lucas thank you so lukas is ahead
of me
he already found it yeah yeah so that is
the
this page so
so we digressed a little bit we are
talking about
a specific feature of javascript that
allows you to match
unicode that allows you to match
characters of any language not just
english alphabet
this is how you do it and this example
okay
so
let's just code it then we then let then
we continue
continue on about the svg thing okay
since we talked about this for four five
five or ten minutes now
so get letters okay here is the code
so back to javascript code so we're
gonna
we're gonna modify this code okay
so first of all paste what we did and
copy okay then we're gonna modify this
copy it paste it make a new version and
the javascript code should be p
that okay here is the syntax for the
here's the syntax if you want to match
any character that is considered a
letter
okay l stands for letter okay so instead
of
so instead of here instead of instead of
azaz which is english alphabet
we need to put this here
and cut
paste that
we need these twice okay because we have
two
we are doing diagrams so two two letter
characters
okay so we don't need this example
anymore
delete that and
this is the old code comment it out so
now we have the new code
let's see uh can you see
can you do a comparison between these
two code
the okay
let's uh let's make it like that okay
so you can see the differences between
these two code okay
yeah that's what we want so comment out
the first one
now this file is actually a typescript
file you can see the file name
dot ts so if i go to the directory you
can see this
is the file name dot ts so we need to
compile it into javascript
okay so let's do because typescript by
the way if you don't know typescript is
is a superset of javascript
so any javascript is also typescript
but typescript has types you know added
types feature to javascript
so anyway this is a typescript we need
to compile so let's call
compile typescript file okay
typescript conf compile file so command
success
okay with no output okay now let's go
back to
let's go back to our diagram
calculator oh did it
okay i think i screwed up because it's
not working anymore
press f12 to turn on the
console log so uncut
type error yeah
okay
yeah so we we screwed up with this
why
this should be unicode properties now
let's look at the
the javascript code it generated
let's see if it screwed up
no it should be fine
okay so
okay this filters the map now where is
filter map called
search search okay filter map so diagram
so filter map is probably returning
a empty map
that's my guess due to our change our
change doesn't work
ah we need to push on so let's forget
about
should you know because we haven't even
start to code yet we need to
go over the code talking about svg we
need to create
you know change the bar and and
a little digression here it's
screwing things up should i continue
fixing should
should we fix this or should i continue
pushing the
uh let's see what what's what's the
arrow here
uncalled type error reduce of empty
array with no initial value
that's right yeah so basically
our code our code here
is not working it creates a empty array
basically it filtered everything out
why is that let's go back to the unicode
example
get letters
backslash p then
braces bracket l that should mean
a unicorn oh we forgot the gu
yeah you need the gu idiotic
regular expression flags okay let's
stupid
expression flags
g u okay let's do it again
okay compile typescript compile file
enter okay success back to
browser magnify refresh
fantastic
now we have the bar chart
again now let's try to type some chinese
okay switch to chinese pinging
you can you see we can type chinese now
dd the whole thing
tt okay uh wait
english tt okay yeah tth
yy now let's type chinese
uh okay let's just repeat
these two chinese characters these two
characters means chinese okay
in case you don't know let's just repeat
it you see
fantastic you see it's working
okay so now that's a digression into
regular expressions for catching any
characters that's
that's considered a letter in any
language not just
english or not just western alphabets
okay that fix that
now let's continue to review our code
okay i think that one is what you are
looking for okay
what year did you know was the moment
you know math is something you will know
forever dizziness
[Laughter]
i wanted to become a mathematician i
wanted to become the greatest
mathematician since i was
about 21. but i failed
i wasn't you know i'm i'm not really
uh you could say i'm an amateur
amateur mathematician okay
but i become a coder you know a
programmer which is by the way
much easier uh but anyway so
let's back to back to our code so we
have
filter map function this this filters
are diagram
data then we have the compute percentage
function
which takes a diagram map object and
returns
it returns instead of the count it
returns a percentage
for example this is uh example of input
you know this is a map
object you know th occurs three times ht
occurs
two times now instead of count we want
to change that so how much
is 3 with respect to all the numbers
like a percentage
so so that is what
this function does because why you need
a percentage
because when you are generating a bar
chart you need a percentage
instead of a count okay so because the
height of the the bar will be dependent
you know as a percentage of the
height of the whole graph so that's a
computer percentage then
then we start to have svg
functions that draws svg so you can see
this draw svg function
it starts to generate svg beginning by
taking a
diagram map object and
and you'll just generate svg okay
now i'm not going to go over the details
of how you do that because
that's the content of the last video
okay
okay so let's draw svg then finally you
have the update function so
update function and plus you have the
event
listener so for the text area
text area box you know which is this box
for text area area you add the event
listener
and the event will be input that means
whenever
this text changed
we are telling javascript to consider
that you know we want
to know about that whenever it changed
we tell
javascript to call the f update function
okay then what does the update function
do
it you know first of all it takes the
text area dot value the contents of this
you know text a string
then you compute you call string to
diagram
okay so you get a map object so we got
a diagram data then you call the draw
svg function
you know then you give it diagram data
then you sort it then you filter
punctuations or whatever
then you turn it into a percentage
okay then you know you draw it
so that's why we see the chart so then
then this part is uh again
same thing but now you turn it into a
json
string and that's the that's what this
part is
about so you you so
so for user using this application they
can
copy this text you know they can get the
data and maybe they want to
feed it to python program or whatever uh
for their own uses so this application
you'll be
uh you know generally useful
not just visually okay so that's our
code so far so
what we need to do today is to fix
this upside down by bar chart and add
the label
which one do we do first
let's fix the upside down chart okay
um
yeah let's fix the upside down chart
okay so in order to do that we
dive into the draw svg
function here okay so we can see
first of all so let's go over so first
of all it specified
the svg width and height
so 900 by 600 pixels
by the way the default svg unit
is pixels now this is in contrast
to css by default
css do not have a default unit so every
time you specify you know pixels or
width or
height you have to say px
for pixels or what or cm or other units
svg is slightly different so they in a
sense they are inconsistent
okay this is the history of technology
in svg you don't have to say a unit by
default the unit is
pixels okay so width width and height of
the
svg box then you create a svgbox element
you know svg element by calling
document.create element ns okay
then you add the attribute width and
height okay
then you then you say inner html equals
to empty
why because every time you type
something
you want to redraw the whole thing so
before you draw you want to remove
everything
that's there so that's the inner html
equals through empty string
then then you want to
append the svg element into the display
area
you know to to to the hdmi so to this
position
so we are attaching our drawing to to it
then then you start to draw
the bars okay so number of diagrams
equals to map.size and bar width
each bar chart bar width is svg width
divided by number of diagrams
times 0.9 okay because we want to
shrink
uh we want to shrink it a little bit
it's not working here you see each bar
is
adjacent here that is actually incorrect
so
so we want to time multiply by 0.8 okay
let's try that
compile file magnify
refresh it's not working
so why is the width does not work by
width okay let's
let's continue on okay let's see
i don't understand why is the bar with
is not working
so then we create the box that's this
part of the code
so for each element
in the diagram map
so for we do a for each key and value
key is a diagram which is a string value
is a number
of uh
kind of a percentage ratio okay
so for each and i is the index
bar height equals to svg hey times v
so remember the value is a percentage
related to all the frequencies of the
diagram occurrences so
so the bar height will be you know
the svg height times that percentage
so you saw this so it kind of shrinks
then we create
a bar element here well x equals
document dot create element okay i'm
going to slow right i'm kind of
stuck
how many people are watching three
okay so okay so let's let me just start
to
um code i need to code this
okay then we for each bar we set
attribute
x and y is a coordinate where bar will
appear
and so on okay and then we need to add
the bar
to the svg so that's that so now
our problem is to in you know it's
upside down so
how do you fix that so let me explain
let me explain okay
in svg the coordinate
0 0 is on the upper left corner
so x start from left to right
and y start from top to down okay
so that's why our bar chart is like
upside down so we need to
invert it so we need to
this is problematic so
each bar x is equals to
x is the position so x we don't change x
but y
y needs to begin at the bottom okay
so we need to go back to the svg element
okay so you go back to the tutorial
so let's go let's open a new tab
let's go to svg so
svg svg basics
then svg rectangle
so rectangle
yeah so the bar is strong you're given a
coordinate
that coordinate is going to be the upper
left
of the rectangle
yeah so you ah oh god so you if you want
to draw from bottom up
you need to think about geometry
tedious you know it's a fantastic
problem in all computer graphics
you know you might be wondering why is
computer graphics they always started
in the reverse order of the typical math
you know
in in math convention you have the x
axis you have y axis y goes from bottom
to up
you know but for all
computer graphics you start from the top
to bottom
so you have this tedious problem of of
reversing it yeah
okay so i need to do it so that you know
so you need to think
so it needs to begin
so the
svg height bar height
should be should be start y
for svg uh what do you mean
that's what we are doing that's what we
are trying to figure out
so you know what i mean right first of
all you have to know
understand the svg orientation of its
coordinate
then you have to understand the
rectangle element
you know so when you say x and y
in rectangle element they refer to the
top left corner of the rectangle so in
our case we need to let's say let me
think
oh are you giving the answer maybe you
are ahead of me
oh svg height minus spa height
yeah you are probably right
okay so so okay
svg height
minus the bar height yeah exactly
so um let's code it so svg
height okay minus the
bar height that's right
so here let's do it here okay let's make
a
f okay svg height
minus is the bar height
okay so that
let's try it compile
success back to browser
refresh oops
okay something's wrong f12
what
some cookies um misusing the recommended
send site attribute
what uh yeah
that's a google's analytics i think
anyway so what's going on
so x is stays the same the bar height y
should be svg height
minus bar height yeah
but why is it wrong
so what is the error
let's compile again
no error in compilation refresh
and i don't know what is going on
you know svg is not showing up okay
uncaught type error reduce of empty
array with no initial value
what's what's this learn more okay i
know i don't need
i don't need your mozilla uh
okay line 57
what are you talking about line 57
oh that's referring to the javascript
line 57 so let's go to javascript
line 57
okay value is
reduced
why is that how come
we didn't change that part how come all
of a sudden you have a problem there
so so now let's
let's revert the bar
thing
so svg height okay and bar height is a
integer right
yeah it is an integer
and two string so i don't see what's
wrong with that
okay anyway let's revert and compile
let's see what what
okay so the problem is
indeed due to
due to the way we change the height
i mean the the origin of the
rectangle what
why is that
any
lucas so lucas you are a javascript
coder so what what
what is wrong here so why
let's see let's see again let's make
sure
so svg height
minus bar height that should be right
can we can we print it can we cancel log
this let's say let's say console.log
bar height okay let's see what we get
format it okay then
compile it
to browser refresh
now it it's printing some numbers edit
is
printing okay so it's printing bar
height seems to work
so bar height bar height is working
and see type something type something
type something type something
so every time you type it prints three
values is it space after closing that
uh here
so every time you type something it
prints by height
three times or more than three times but
anyway
bar height so what is the error
so there is no error but we are not
showing
you know it's not showing up any chart
so that means i think i know what's
going on so the bar is going
off the canvas probably
but yeah you know this this is a problem
with
with the computer graphics the
programming industry
despise these problems because
and you know i have looked i have looked
for a way a simple way to tell svg just
simply flip it
you know i don't want it to start from
the top to bottom i want the
conventional
start from bottom to top without every
time i code something i have to
do the geometry and you know i looked
over there's no such thing there's no
such
option uh up you know so this is
uh to me a a problem among programmers
why why do i blame the programmers
because for 20 40
50 years it's that way programmers
typically they don't complain
it you know most most of these cc plus
plus low level type of programmers they
they don't think this is a problem
uh anyway so you know so so
so it's wasting our time here anyway so
back to
why would uh okay so
let's make sure
i don't think it's wise let's make sure
let's see the semantic of the
the semantics of the rectangle thing
yeah so this square is hundred by
hundred
okay so you are drawing a rectangle
x is nine y is zero so x
starts from nine pixels to the right and
y start from zero which is top so it
draws
a rectangle from top to bottom yeah so
the
so the x y is the coordinate
of the top left corner of the
of the rectangle
so we so when you have svg height
oh okay wait svg height
okay i think i know you you don't i i
think i know you don't want to minus the
bar
height you want to minus the the height
of the opposite i mean the
the spare part of the height okay so so
basically you want to
here's what we want i think i know it's
it's not showing up
it's you know our current code the bar
the rectangle is outside of the svg
canvas
so you want basically svg height minus
the svg
height minus bar height okay that's what
you want
so so if we can simplify this
so it's gonna be svg height plus bar
height okay
so because if you simplify then it's
gonna be plus here
so svg height minus
wait um so it's just
bar height
no i don't think that's right this
should be right
right i mean this the original
you know i want to try to do it one shot
like think
clearly and logically to come up with
the correct code
then run it it should work instead of
you know like
right now i have the opportunity just
try it trial and error coding
you know we'll probably get it right but
i want to
be able to understand it you know it's
it's a trivial problem but it's often
very confusing
the the height
it should be right because i think this
should be right
but i don't understand
yeah so it should be right right svg
height minus spa
height
yeah what the hell
but if you if we do let's just okay
let's
let's resign to trial and error
compile it
go back to the code refresh
okay so
the problem is indeed about the
height but now we
got a weird crap
okay so now it's time to wait so what
what is going on
such a trivial problem you take you know
10 minutes to do
you know tedious tedium of javascript
and svg
and uh you know that started me into
another rant
about the entire computer graphics
industry
which is all hacks and
you know the the open
open gl crap low level
crap
and then people like canvas you know
apple's canvas technology that's even
worse
svg is relatively high level so anyway
so
let's see svg height
i don't understand
this should be correct svg height
minus bar height
that's where y's begin that's where why
begin
you don't understand so
on the other hand if we have these
this is just uh this minus that
so that so this becomes just spa height
so that is essentially this is just
bar height
yeah so this is just bar height plus bar
height
bar height plus bar height bar height
plus bar height that's not
it's not what we want
it should be just svg height minus the
bar height so wait what's wrong with our
code this should be right
remove that remove that svg let's look
let's look okay let's look the next line
so width width
doesn't change but width and also about
with
we have a problem because our scaling
factor is not
having any effect what is that
let's say six okay
compile
refresh
not working okay okay let's let's go
back for now let's go to
the
compile
refresh okay let's go back to this
now the width is a problem what why is
it
why is the width not working
okay maybe yeah uh wait
what
bar console.log okay
print it
and compile the code
refresh
start over it has you know
the bar width okay we got a problem
the bar width is not having any effect
yeah but what's his value okay but with
a bar with changes why is that
okay we got something wrong here but
with should never change
why is bar with changing
oh i see so bar width is indeed changing
because
number of diagrams changes all the time
because every time you type a new
character it
adds a new diagram potentially so the
number of diagrams
increased therefore the bar width will
decrease
but still bar width should be the same
for every bar
so yeah so still given a input text
the bar with you know we compute the bar
width
so svg with divided by number of
diagrams so it should get
smaller and smaller right yeah that's
right
you see 540 270
180 135 108
90 77 so
our bar width is correct
and our bar width is correct
and uh but why is it not having any
effects
it seems like it does have effect
you see
it does have effect but
it's not you know why
why is that we don't see gaps
because we multiply by 0.6
so
greeting spots
oh youtube notification is good so how
many people i have like three people
watching
yeah oh nice
okay increased say hi guys so we are
stuck with this
problem the main problem is the
we cannot we are you know we cannot
you know we cannot reverse the boss
direction
but meanwhile possibly related
is that the bar width
we are not seeing gaps between bar
and we are stuck there
we don't know what is the problem
yeah there is a transform reflect you
know i've used it but it's
it creates more problem than it's worth
yeah it does because it's not just a
flip
you have to flip and you have to move
you know
it creates more problems so let's let's
let's think about geometry because
usually you know i've done
lots of geometry programming usually you
really
need to think you know to get it right
um after some trial and error
it doesn't work you cannot you you
shouldn't
continue you know lots of trial and
error because you are missing some
understanding so why is so so let's
think
think okay svg height
minus the bar height okay the first
problem is this
why is this not right
svg height minus the bar height
then a related problem is why is the
width
svg width is not working out i mean why
is it there's no gaps
between let's let's make this
even very small let's say just times 0.2
compile
refresh oh
i see
you see that's because the x
you know even so you decrease the width
but you did not decrease
but you should not decrease where the
bar begin the
on the x coordinate okay so here is the
problem
and it's okay so here is the problem
yeah
this is incorrect
yeah because it shrinked with bar width
that's why
so okay so bar width should be
0.8 let's say 0.9 some gap
but the
okay we need another variable okay
so
so total bar width we are equals to
svg width divided by number of diagrams
then bar width will be
total width times 0.9 okay
so that gives gives you some gap
now the x coordinate for each bar
will be i times bar total width
okay i'm pretty sure that's right
compile it
so this should give us gaps between the
bars
refresh fantastic
okay fantastic that's fixed one problem
the next
problem is to fix the
you know the upside down problem
so let's just try it okay so
let's just try it oh yeah i think maybe
a similar problem
wait svg height it has nothing to do
with width
uh
so you are doing a for each loop
and so the svg height
is constant right yeah
the svg height is defined somewhere
above
here so it's it does not change it's a
constant you see we defined as a
constant so you cannot change
if you change it it's gonna be
javascript error
okay so svg height is constant
and then
and multiplied by v
v okay so v is a percentage i mean v
is kind of percentage times 100 so it's
a scaling factor
then you get bar height okay is that
correct
yes that's uh that's the bar height
then
so bar height is different for each bar
right yeah so then you say svg height
minus bar height
we should be right should be correct
what's going on svg height minus bar
height
compile
let's try it refresh
same problem f12
we stuck with a geometry problem
so what do we do now we
you know so that uh
so this problem
uh we need to fix it
you know that's our job that's what we
are doing we need to fix it we cannot
skip it
it this problem a geometric
problem ruins this video because we have
we stuck
this this is not even a javascript
problem but
this should be correct what the hell
so let's print this value okay cancel
out
by height
okay first of all cancel out bar height
so bar height equals to
so where is xmap you know xmap is a
percentage right
xmap is the argument to draw svg
and xmap and if we look at
who calls draw svg so search for draw
svg
we can see it the argument is compute
percentage
so perhaps we should
okay let's uh
let's say xx map okay let's say constant
xx map and it will be
that value then
let's say
percentage map okay
so we can print
console.log print this map let's see
what's going on
and
okay there's some problem with deno
format because it's not formatting this
console
line correctly before oh it does
okay so search for console and remove
the
remove the printing of the bar width
okay and read and comment that out
compile
so every time we type a new character
it should print the
the diagram by uh with a percentage
value okay
uncle type error some thing
okay
reduce of empty array with no initial
value okay so there's a problem with
empty array still
wait is it
did we compile why is it printing bar
with
compiler
what okay now
now that's right
some every time we type a character a
new map
is printed that's correct and
the value of each diagram is a
percentage
i mean is is a value between zero and
one that's also correct
yeah so we feed that into the draw
svg code
so here so we feed that into
you know into the draw svg code
so draw svg code gets the
you know gets gets the
percentage valued map diagram object
and then when we start to create
the bars the rectangles
we have the key key is a diagram
is the key used somewhere no
we need to use it for the label later on
but the value is the percentage
value is used for the bar
height and so far we've seen it's
working correctly
and but the problem is with
the position it is
starting to draw it
oh oh okay i got it this
is yeah again the confusing geometry
problem
wait i almost got it but i lost it
this should be correct i don't know what
okay this ruined
the video we are stuck here
let's say 10 okay let's just let's let's
say
now we i don't know what's going on so
let's just say
start from 10.
okay compile error an
identifier or keyword cannot immediately
follow a numeric
okay stupid compile
refresh so it's drawing from the top
this time
10 pixels below okay now let's go back
let's go to the html page
and let's add a kind of a border
around the svg box so
so go to the bigram calculator page
magnify we want a border around this
display svg area around this okay
so go to the top so let's add
css tag
what styles add a style tag
and id svg
display area then
let's switch to sc css mod
then let's just say order
okay fold the solid thing gray okay
switch to html mod
again
show in browser magnify
refresh where's my border okay wrong
area
oh wait we screwed up
you see our display area has a border
here but
we inserted svg into some wrong place
what's going on
display area
so we have display area in show box
uh this shouldn't be a span okay change
it
that's that's a mistake yeah
dive
yeah okay and remove that paragraph
and also change this to dive
show in browser there we have it
oh my god so this is actually a
revelation
you know because due to
html and css that is causing
uh causing us to waste to have wasted
30 minutes on this crap
so open a javascript file again then
turn this back
remove that i mean let's use you know
svg height minus bar height that should
be correct
okay compile the code okay
back to browser magnify refresh
no
what
at this point i'm very frustrated
yes
what what is the bar height
where is the way is the
this is com this
is wrong
where is the ttt
tdg occur 44 times where is that
okay i think i uh
i might stop this stream because
we stuck this and stuck on this and it's
no fun
who else is watching comments
we have night people watching comments
a people watching um
okay but but but but we need to solve
this
i mean this is so so the more it doesn't
work
the more interesting it becomes
something wrong with our code
and we don't know what it what it is and
right now it's missing
a
right now it's missing a giant bar
oh okay you see that blue thing it's
so apparently one of the largest bar
is not showing yeah okay so
x uh so there is some comment thank you
guys
hold on a second let me let me let me uh
i'm gonna read it in a bit okay so i
think i know what is what's going on so
so x starts with bar total width
bar column width so let's rename
bar total with 2 bar column width
because that's more
that makes more sense so x is the
position of each rectangle so
uh so it so i times bar column width
i begins with zero that's right because
i is the index of the
of the array so begins of zero so it
starts with
uh over here and uh
okay so i think another thing we did
wrong is
this bar total width
so about total with bar column width
is
let's say your svg width is 100 pixels
and let's say you have five
bi-grams so you want five bars
so when you divide
svg with 100 divided by 5
which is 20.
you know i'm thinking of an arrow
something like
off by one off by one so
maybe one of the bar went outside
something like that
uh
yeah but it so far i don't see where is
the arrow
so x is that and
bar height is um
yeah i am stuck okay let's see the
comments
nice setup man thank you mcnc
hi i love your work
thank you i am new to javascript and svg
thank you okay thank you guys good luck
yeah i think that's it for today i've
been talking we stuck this problem
oh god
but we've been coding for 90 minutes
uh and and and this is just not right
okay let's start from
zero again so
compile the code
refresh
so let's let's have some controlled
uh chart a b
c d okay so a b c d that's four
characters
so four characters creates three
bi-grams
so that means you should have three bars
now you see the left one
the left the rightmost one is
so the data is correct a b b
c c d each occurs one time
a b b c c d but the bar chart
the the right most one is
now we need to dive connecting
okay there's some disruption okay so
so the rightmost bar is screwed
so how do you
so where in the code does the bar charts
depend on the list you returned
well we have this draw svg function
so this function takes a argument the
argument
is you know the diagrams you see that's
a data
a nested array each element is two
elements you know array
um so uh
you know in fact as a hack we can
probably solve this
some of the missing right bar chart by
plus one here
you know but that's a that's just a hack
because i don't
i'm not understanding the situation
for example let's try abc
oh still yeah it solves the problem you
see abc
three characters two bigrams and you
have two bars
that's correct okay okay we see the
problem you see it's a
it's it's cut off so it's not the
it's not the case that the bar is not
showing
but rather for some reason it's uh cut
off
by the rendering engine yeah that is
that's likely the problem you know
that's the problem with
web programming lots of these
so that may have to do with css or
with with the svg box we are creating
um
where is the svg so you see our width
is 900. now maybe because of my website
that i have some css magic
you know i have some css magic because
let me show you okay
because let's see you see
there is a left navigation panel
but if you shrink it if it's smaller to
some degree the panel go away
so that's called responsive design
so-called
you know which is the idiotic crap
so and and right now i don't know if
this problem is
related or not but we can test it by
go to the html page close it
reopen and remove the line
that loads my custom css so we are
so so this file does not depends on
you know my css which is which is
200 lines okay so now
refresh okay it seems
the problem remains okay you don't have
the special
css but the problem remains it's uh
somehow cut off okay i i think i i know
the problem the problem is
the problem again is with css
i mean with svg so in svg you have the
view box
which is what we have i mean the the
the view view port okay um
then you have the you see the viewport
is svg width and height
that's you specify and it creates
a absolute coordinate
but if your elements went outside of it
you'll just disappear but it shouldn't
in our case because we are dividing by
the svg
width but anyway besides the viewport
then you also have a relative coordinate
this is when you say
is when you say you know width and
height but also
view box equals to something so you can
have a relative
coordinate um
we can do that uh we can do that but
it's uh it's
yeah we let's let's try it
okay let's let's try it then
so so here is the line that creates
svg let's modify it
okay wait uh
so you need to add attribute let me show
you okay
oh here is our mistake
[Laughter]
svg attribute width and width this
should be height
what the
compile code
where is our page refresh no it works
god okay a typo
created our problem uh
typo created the entire
problem for us and
wasted us one hour
one five
king hour a typo
the typo is we
this line should be width and height and
we
but instead we have width and width
okay okay now let's go back to quickly
now everything should work okay
compile now we have the we have
we should have fixed the upside down
graph indeed
beautiful
now we should have
fixed the upside down graph okay it's
just not good because it's not relative
but anyway the upside down is fixed now
we need to fix
the make them relative so the first bar
so it it
so the the height should be
i mean the the the bar height should be
the bar height should be svg height
times the
percentage of occurrence
then divided by the highest bar
so the highest bar should have you know
the full
svg height okay that's that's why
so that's why you are seeing you see
so the highest part should be the
the base okay the base of measurement so
so the so so we need to modify the code
here the bar height equals to svg height
times v
and then okay so we we need to know
what's the first
the biggest one so that one is easy the
biggest one is the first element
in x map because we you know we we
already
sorted it so x map
the first element okay
the first element of it then
the first element of it that's the value
so that is the basis so
wait wait okay so okay so we we need to
do this
constant
highest bar height okay we need to
define this let's put it here okay
highest bar height will be equal to
will be equal to the frequency
of the first uh
the the highest element times
the svg height
okay the frequency
[Music]
yeah so let's let's put it here
the svg heights scaled by the frequency
of the
of the svg height okay
purify then then for each bar height
so this part can actually go up because
does it change it does okay so
so so so for each bar height will be
will be the highest bar height times
v okay
compile back to browser
magnify
refresh oh it went
it went away okay it went away
okay now yeah i okay so now there's
something else to fix
so instead of svg height minus spa
height
it should just be
high spot height okay
compile
refresh no it didn't work
let's just say start from zero you idiot
compile
refresh now starting from zero doesn't
work
now f12 help
console.log help and chord type error x
map zero
is undefined okay so that's easy to fix
uh first of all let's make this change
this back so
so this this thing
x map dot entries
uh
okay let's let's let's shrink them
xmap.entries
why is it not working because x map is
a what is x map x map
is the argument to draw svg here
and what what is draw svg
uh svg true svg is compute percentage
the return value of compute percentage
so what is the return value of compute
percentage
okay so the return value of compute
is a map that's why no wonder it doesn't
work
yeah stupid javascript okay i know
what's going on so in order to
so we you know there is no way to get
the first element of a map
by index so our data structure you need
to change the data structure because
map is a key value pair you cannot you
know get the first element even
even even even
even so the map object is actually
ordered in javascript the map object
is maintenance order but you cannot get
the first element like that so so
either change the argument
change the input to svg draw svg so that
it takes a entry instead of you know it
takes a
array instead of instead of a
map object so it's actually much
easier to work with uh wait it's
actually much easier to work with um
array of arrays instead of a map but if
you change it to array then you have to
change
okay this size will be length
okay that can be done okay make a backup
first
so because we are going to make a kind
of a big change
so we need to basically here
joe svg so okay let's let's do let's do
it
and let's just do it quickly
and yeah i'm getting tired too let's
just forget about
efficiency okay let's just do it quickly
here
so now you get entries
now search for xmap so let's
see so this is now length
and you don't need the entries here
because it's already
entries so
okay and okay so let's see
okay let's just compile let's do trial
and error let's
let's be sloppy refresh
yeah unexpected value none passing with
attribute
so we have to
x-map
oh yeah so if you change it to array
then this syntax no longer works because
because
for each you know the for each method
for map
and for each method for array are
different
okay let's redo undo undo undo
everything
and do back to where we are
okay and do everything save
and now so instead of changing the
argument for xmap let's just change it
inside
here uh
biggest biogram okay
biggest diagram let's extract here so
we are doing this super inefficiently
okay
so we extract here then
then we can inside here we just do
that okay
typescript compile success
refresh
unexpected value none at
code my number 90 88
okay refresh
92 so line number
92 go to the javascript open
line number 92 what the heck is 92 so
it's a
highest bar height minus bar height
passing y attribute so we are getting
none here not a number where are we
getting not the number
because one of highest bar height
or bar height is
uh not a number okay so close
close back to our typescript
and let's see where is the problem so
bar height
higher spa height
oh okay so
so this should be svg height minus okay
but i don't think
i don't think that'll fix it
yeah 92
okay so
i'm gonna continue anyway so i'm gonna
finish
and you know because i need to code this
myself
so why not just uh continue anyway
so biggest diagram value
equals to xmap xmap
is a map object and we
want to turn it into
nested array by calling the entries
method then
then the entries method returns a
iterator
iterable then we need to use the spread
operator
to turn it into a actual array
once we have array
0 is the first element which is the key
and value
of array then again the first element
should be the value
wait what does entries return is it key
value or value
key javascript
object reference map
entries it returns
key value okay each yield is array of
the form key value okay so key value not
value key
because some other method does you know
they return value key
okay biggest diagram value let's
print it compile the code
refresh
let's see so we got none
you see every time you type you got none
here it's
printed none so why is it none
so
x map
can we just print x map no
so it's telling us
ah this is not
going well shouldn't take all this long
you know
yeah but actually this happens often in
real life coding
yeah if if i think about you know
real life coding in images or in in pro
this does happen all the time you are
stuck
with some stupid for hours
then you go to then you see you know
that's why you see stack overflow a
bunch of questions
you know some of them is valley question
you know but some of them is just
because you
you you know you not you made a typo
somewhere you don't know what is
going on like right now i don't really
have a question
i don't have a question about svg no
javascript
but something is wrong here
you know maybe a typo somewhere
so xmap xmap is a
search for draw svg okay joe svg returns
a i mean it takes a argument
and this argument is the return value of
compute percentage right and if you look
at compute percentage
it returns a result map which is
a map object so
so go back to draw svg
the way it is called it you know the
argument it receives
the x map is a map object
so a map object
and uh and why
why is it's not working so let's let's
okay let's remove other console log
okay so this is the only console log
we have
compile back to browser
refresh
uh okay close that window let's start
over okay
let's show in browser hey show in
browser
what showing what
show in browser what
showing browser
oh yeah of course javascript you cannot
show in browser you have to show in
browser is
html file no magnify
now f12 console.log
okay so even before even you type
anything
you are getting this error unexpected
value
line 91 passing y attribute
unexpected error so the part about
passing y attribute
here okay let's
let's let's just say start from zero
compile shrink javascript
refresh
cancel out okay no error
but no diagram now where does the x
e x come from it's printing it
oh it's printing it right that's right
so console.log so this is this is
incorrect you know we expect this to be
a number but it's actually ex
so it's actually printing the key oh
of course this should be one
not zero thank god what the
no i don't even need that compile
god of course
now of course yeah uh wait something is
wrong yeah but we can fix that
okay now let's go back to fix the bar
height stuff
so now we got the big biggest
diagram value so the highest bar height
is equals to
[Music]
the svg height times biggest bigram
value
and each bar height equals to highest
bar height times
v
wait
no no
no no no i i think what's going on is
our percentage is wrong
uh we got more and more problems now
i think the problem is the compute
percentage
it's not returning a correct
kind of percentage thing
why is that because
let's see the update code the update
code filter map
let's print compute percentage okay
okay so now we can actually see
the percentage printed here and also by
the way the height of the svg is too big
too big
so instead of 600 let's say 300
compile the code back to browser magnify
refresh
good now let's see okay no nothing
nothing is going on nothing is happening
so
i know because let's go to the update
here
we yeah so this is percentage map is
incorrect
so you it's a map now you want to turn
it into a array okay
use the spread operator now compile
because java's json stream file does not
understand
map it needs array so
refresh now now we got a bunch of
percentage value okay the highest
okay so now so now we are looking at the
percentage data
now now the percentage data
so it's yeah oh okay now i
understand it's obviously incorrect
that's why everything is so small
so flat you know every bar is not
because
so how do you so so essentially our
error is
math error in computing the height
and that is because you are not thinking
carefully
you are just doing trial and error
the typical programmers try and narrow
so this line is wrong highest bar you
know the
in computing the bar height is incorrect
so let's
you really need to think so okay
yeah we're still doing that we kind of
stuck in you know
and we have uh issues
oh that works in a different way than
expected so what you are you guys saying
that's why i love strongly type
languages yeah it's so good it's super
valuable okay so
so so yeah we're still working on the
bar height
we went into fix several problems but
so the highest bar height is equals to
the highest spot height height should be
just the svg
height okay
and each bar height should be
svg height times
oh wait wait wait
i see what's going on guys okay now
yeah our problem now look at the
data of the bi-gram percent you know
so-called percentage values it returns
so ex occurs
0.4 okay like four percent of the
time ht occurs four percent of time
and so on so
and we are drawing our bar chart based
on that that is incorrect
because we actually need to normalize
this bunch of percentages
that is you find the highest number of
them
which is ex in this case and
make the make instead of a 0.04
make it one you you know so you
need to basically multiply a number to
all these values
so they are normalized so that the
the highest frequency diagram has a
value of
one and the rest is you know smaller
yeah you you want to normalize
the this percentage you know so this is
you know the so the problem is math it's
not javascript
our problem has been you know we had
actually several problems so but right
now it's a
math you know it's kind of confusing
concepts you have count
then you have percentage relative to the
sum
total of accounts then you have the
concept of
you want to normalize the percentage
yeah so lucas do you see what i'm saying
we did that like you talked about but
however
our problem is that
you know we we want to normalize the
so how do you how do you do that i hope
i hope in
next five minutes we can get at least
get the po
correctly then actually we need to add
text labels
so this is this video stream is turning
into
like three hours marathon
so we need to get the okay normalize so
how do you do that
then you know again there are several
ways we can
let's just do the easiest way forget
about efficiency let's just do it maybe
here so so
so
you need to rescale each percentage
so okay now you need to think about how
do you normalize it
so uh given
a bunch of numbers each number is a
percentage
of the total occurrences you want to
multiply
okay so multiply so find the highest
value
this value okay this value
times x equals to 1 solve for x
so x
equals to 1
over that okay
so that is the scaling factor okay so
so this one over biggest value is the
scaling fat
factor okay okay so so
so now
so the so the bar
height will be that's right
that's right okay i got it
okay so let's create a new constant
okay bar height scaling is that value
then each bar height will be
will be the svg height
times
where are we so each bar height will be
the svg height times bar height scaling
okay
and do we should we be concerned about
higher scaling
height no forget about that
uh yes predefine the code
okay that is the
should be the correct code now
so here you all you have to say it's
just bar height
well svg minus bar height so you
flip okay compile
back to that
refresh we got something
another error ah god this is no good
wait wait wait okay so oh yeah so
actually i know the math
so bar height scaling factor is equals
to that
oh times svg height i think
that's right times svg height
so in other words svg height divided by
that
svg height divided by
what
ah i'm all confused i need to stop
i need to take a break that's it that's
it that's
it guys need to take that this is not
working
okay
i need to i need to take a break i'm
kind of
i really do need to take a break
and
okay let's
now we need to finish this okay we need
to think
so um
so biggest diagram value
times x equals one
so that becomes one so big is background
value
okay and then
then
then each forget about this one for now
okay then bar height
uh where is this this is not used
let's just say zero for now okay here
let's just say
zero yeah
okay so
so ba height scaling equals to one
so
so each one each bar height will be yeah
obviously we're missing the value
times v okay the value yeah compile
compile
back to the code back to browser refresh
no refresh
no
so back to the code
uh behind standing svg heights
times over
it's
so so each bar height
equals so each card equals to
svg height
times by height scaling
compile computer
compile refresh oh
finally
abc okay let's get rid of the
type error reduce reduce of empty array
shut the up
a b c d e f g
t h t h t h t h th
now after one hour
or two hours of struggle
painfully finally we
got the bar chart correctly
actually not really because
we haven't inverted yet now inverting it
is easy now inverting it now is easy
svg height minus bar height height
compile please back to browser please
refresh please
perfect now we just need to add text
label text
take text labels svg
labels okay it's one one more step and
we done for the day
thank you thank god for
blessing us with
the ability to code javascript and
svg
now you go to text element
svg basics let's see if it's their
ellipse polygon
polyline uh path no it's not there so we
need to go to
text elements we need to add labels
okay uh text element this is how you do
it
you know if you don't know it's pretty
simple so
so so so copy that okay copy
back to javascript code
so for each so we are doing for each
here remember
map entries so we all we have to do
for each then this function
[Music]
uh then okay so that's uh
so this function then we have to create
text element here okay so this is
so basically let's copy that so create
create element this say let's say text
okay then basically
okay so so so this is
a text text okay label okay
l a b l okay create a text element yes
and attribute and x y forget about the
others and style yeah we want style
uh stroke black stroke
red feel red okay feel red
and struck with uh let's say one okay
one pixels so text element
so where do you want to place it oh
that's again
the problem well the problem is
something like you know we've just
followed
this follow the bar chart where it is
oh this is a problem okay x is the same
thing okay
x and y okay
so forget about that so why let's just
say zero okay
let's predefine the code fees
what the
formatting you cannot you know deno
cannot format our code you know i'm
starting to find more and more problems
with deno okay
a pen child that
what what deno cannot format our code
what the
back
yeah okay so
stupid denial what
line 128 what
is that
oh yeah so why do you have that okay
what you don't have you don't
have
what
so that's the
[Music]
you know i am starting to have
i'm starting to not like dental that
much
what
uh shrink
so we have this true svg
[Music]
so this we got syntax error
so this is a function
so
so we have a arrow function and
body so
here is that and
here is that and here is the completion
of that
okay cut right
yeah and here is that
then
then that
then that okay stupid
okay so now no yeah no no no
no compile
refresh no not this page where is our
diagram
refresh fantastic
no okay we got something mistake
[Music]
wait this is a text element oh yeah so
we got
um replace bar
x by text x okay
by okay replace by x uh wait
replace bar x by label x
okay yes yes yes okay
compile please
to browser refresh
now where is the label okay
label is not there
now you you can do
x and y y is let's say
10 yeah drop down a little bit
okay compile it
browser refresh
yeah because you didn't add the text
when you want the text attribute you you
need the text
you know yeah so we let's add the text
so label attribute then label dot
inner inner html
and that will be the actual key
okay okay key
key okay yeah you need to actually
now compile
where is it here refresh fantastic
now finally let's try remove everything
a b c
d e f so we do have a
text now it's not so very good h t h t h
t h t h
so so we do have the text now
let's see now let's
make it better okay so make it better so
so
minus 10 okay then stroke
style let's remove the style compile
refresh
fantastic
now finally after
two hours today and
two hours the previous days
we have a
interactive diagram
plotter written
in javascript and svg
now there's more things to do now for
example the label is not too clear
and also you want to you want to put
this part into the label so
you know so you know user can see how
many
percentage or occurrence is the diagram
okay but that's it for today okay thank
you for watching but basically we are
done and we need to
uh more detailed coding of this
file so let's again let's review open
the file
so it's only 130 lines so
all the first today we did is adding
basically 10 lines
yeah so three hours for 10 lines and
that's actually correct
i mean because if you read you know
report
where they've done study of statistical
measure
measuring measuring how many you know in
in big
corporations google facebook microsoft
how many lines per day
a programmer adds 10 10 is a good day
so we are doing good we are doing a
realistic
thing uh okay so
you know so here's our code it's only
only 130 lines okay to do this spygram
chat but that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
now if you like my tutorial good good
you did it
finally uh
120 when did you make that comments okay
so anyway so
uh yeah okay so we did it you know
some in some form so thank you for
watching uh if you like my
uh for don't forget this if you like my
javascript tutorial so i have a
javascript in-depth if you like my style
and stuff
go buy it okay i go down here buy
javascript in depth
and you'll get onto the road of
mastering javascript
and it includes by the way it includes
all the html you need to know
the comprehensive the all the entire
html
tags case sensitivity allowed characters
in id for example in attributes
uh chart setting in and encoding whether
you should use
utf-8 or what is utf-8 for example
character set encoding utf-8 what does
that mean
so explain here
and so html you need to know and css you
need to master
okay we ran into uh
did we run into a css issue not not
really but
anyways so css uh
and you have javascript okay that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
bye guys i'm shutting down in one minute
uh that's a grueling uh talk show
two hours and and 20 minutes that's the
longest i've done
live okay no more
no more drink i need to get drink
who else is here who else is watching
but
okay so this looks right
the biogram protein bigram okay so
another thing we need to do for the
diagram
is that the vertical diagram is not so
good because they are
you know you want the bars to be
horizontal instead of
instead of vertical because you are
going to have
potentially hundred or so more bigrams
so it's too
too narrow too many columns to fit
together
so a better format is a
a better format is a uh you know
horizontal for diagram
so that we can fix and you know and now
it's easier to fix
after we've struggled so much with the
code
bye bye guys