hello welcome
to another episode of star talk show we
are going to
demonstrate emacs keyboard marker today
so it's going to be 20 minutes or 30
minutes i'm going to demo emacs the
power of emacs keyboard macro and uh
and i'm going to show you how to use it
okay so keep emacs so let's begin key
emacs keyboard macro is the mo one of
the most powerful feature
on the pink window you can see all my
command cores and the keystrokes in
emacs for example i can move cool so you
can see
move cursor by word
by paragraph and so on
um
and i'm using soft light keys and i'm
using
work layout so this is my keyboard okay
so let's go back let's go on to keyboard
marker so keyboard marker what is what
is it basically the feature is that it
just records your keystrokes
and allows it to be played back
and in emacs this is extremely powerful
because in emacs everything you do
is a command
and any command can have a key so in
fact the way emacs works you know the
you know the internal emacs
is actually it just capture your
keystrokes
and then every time you type something i
mean even if i type something like
something okay
something
okay that command if you type s that is
actually the command um self insert let
me show you okay so
you call meta x describe key then i
press s
and you can now see
uh okay let me turn so you can let me
highlight the current line so now you
can see it says s runs the command self
insert command
so even when you are typing you know
just abc df
every character you type every keystroke
is actually calling a command
so that
this fact
makes emacs keyboard marker the
recording and playback keystrokes
extremely powerful because everything
you do anything you do
including delete including split window
or a new window or
copy or new buffer paste or delete
that's all command i mean even when you
type something so when you can record
that and playback it's extremely
powerful so it's
it's in fact
more powerful than programming emac bisp
okay that that is actually true and i
have some examples to demonstrate that
uh but anyway so let me show you a
keyboard marker so
let's start to demonstrate so keyboard
macro
the there are
four commands you want to know okay one
is
key marker start macro that starts the
recording
and the other one is key marco and marco
that ends marco so during this time
whatever you typed it will be recorded
okay
then when you want to play it back
you say
call us keyboard marker okay that will
play it back
or alternatively you can call this
command keyboard mark or end and call
marco that's kind of combining two
commands into one i usually don't use
that so anyway so
keyboard marker start macro
keyboard key marker and macro
and the core last key markup okay that's
the three essential commands
powerful let me demonstrate for now okay
so let's see so you can see today's talk
show you know i'm on this file
and show in browser so this is today's
talk show
so i have some text prepared here
example to work on with emacs keyboard
marker so you can see we have a list
here so let me tell you what i want to
do okay
you see i want to make this add a corner
bracket to the commands okay this these
are
woofing language
function names anyway so i want to add
this so i press the key so that that is
my personal command by the way that's
our insert corner bracket okay
uh let's
um
let's instead of using that let's do
something normal so every so you can
use it
so everyone understand so let's see i
want to insert a left paren
and then right paren
then go to the next line
left paren right paren okay left paren
right paren
and then i have lots of them hun
potentially thousands what you gonna do
keyboard marker okay so let's
let's record this and do this whole shot
okay
so
now start keyboard micro now
start keyboard marker by default there's
a key control x left paren and keyboard
marker n marker is ctrl x right paren
and also by default i believe it's a key
f3 and f4 okay so anyway so let's begin
so let's
start macro you can see in the ping
window you see i call that command
actually i don't want to start here so
every time you made a mistake during
your recording you can
call the command keyboard quick
which is ctrl g okay which i just did
okay so let's start again i want to move
the cursor to the beginning of the line
okay
then
start recording
move closer one word to the right
insert a parent left paren move cursor
one word again
insert the right paren now i want to
stop recording okay
stop
okay so you can see i you know i called
keyboard mark or start and keyboard
marco n okay now i want to play that
command so i move the cursor to this
line
and i call the command called keyboard
markup okay
so
do it
fantastic do it uh oh i pressed the
wrong key okay
uh
cool last keyboard marco yeah do it uh
wait
the cursor needs to be at the beginning
of the line see
so undo undo undo yeah okay so let's
start over here
do it fantastic
put the cursor at the beginning of the
line do it fantastic do it fantastic
now i want to apply to all these lines
you know
so let's select them all
and call
there is a command
called
there's a command um
apply macro to region lines
so it will for every each line it will
call the keyboard marco automatically so
let's do it
fantastic
fantastic no no this block
fantastic okay
okay so
apply
macro to region lines okay
apply macro to region lines you see i
have a key bound to that command so
apply marco to region lines you see so
for me it's a ddr
comma on my work
keyboard kinesis where i layout so
so anyway that is the demonstration of
kibo macro and
okay so i think maybe that's it for
today how many people are here we have a
i had a technical difficulty before
because i was trying to install
i upgraded uh obs you know there's a
giant new version of obs cam came out
and i upgraded and wham it says
it says error you need to upgrade your
video driver card blah blah blah and
then i went into the saga 20 minutes to
update my video driver on windows so
windows sucks
okay so that's it i think for today um
so
if you so i have a tutorial you can just
search for xari emacs
key board marco okay
it's all written out so i have lots of
details you can read about it and
it's a great feature okay
so let me read a question and i think
that's it for today
your boy started me because i was in a
different browser tab okay fantastic
immortality
so you are the guy one waiting okay so
we got four uh
watches so what time is it how long have
i been i think that's it for today
10 minutes okay
short today to the point okay so check
it out uh if you like my stuff buy my
emacs tutorials okay thank you guys
bye
shutting down in one minute
so let me you know meanwhile let me just
undo because this is parenthesis it's
not what actually what i want and let me
show you um
so remove the paren
actually i want a square corner bracket
okay that's what i want
and i so recall the keyboard macro so
start it here
um
yeah
so start recording
insert that
then
go through the
end of the line let's do something
different okay then
jump by word
then
that's it okay then
stop recording okay now call us keyboard
marker do it
right
uh
did we do it
oh you have to
do it
okay i recorded wrong so let's start
over
okay so i want to begin here so record a
keyboard macro
insert the corner bracket go to the end
of line and jump forward by one word
okay now
end the keyboard macro end it
now call that's keyboard marquee
do it
okay
do it again
now okay so i can now repeat it you know
three keys to repeat it every time
okay but now let's let me show you
another command okay so
call us keyboard macro
and now i'm going to instead of calling
the code last keyboard marker i'm going
to call repeat last command because if i
call that it allows me to press a single
key to repeat okay so
do it you see
you can look at the pink window you can
see uh does it show yeah you see the
repeat command in the pink window now i
can just press t to repeat it you see do
it do it do it do it okay
now in this way i don't have to select
you see so now let's call the keyboard
macro
and do it okay
now move here
call us keyword macro
then
repeat then t t t t t fantastic
okay and uh let's just do this manually
okay so
class keyboard marco repeat repeat wait
what
call last keyboard marker repeat repeat
yeah
let's just do that manually
manually
manually you know
the so the keyboard marker the power is
that when you have to hundreds of them
then it saves you
days sometimes even like some something
impossible becomes possible
so so this is just my personal work so
once i have these i press the command
then all the corner brackets becomes
code
so if you go to the browser refresh you
can see they'll become red show it you
see that's what i want those red means
those are function names okay so
do it these are just my personal uh html
commands
and by the way you can also instead of
the corner bracket something
fun
you can also use the
markdown convention so you type fun and
you type this okay actually not that you
type that okay
you see that that's the back tick
now you can call this command and both
of them will be code
highlighted in red okay so let's undo
that
give me that let's just
okay thank you guys for watching and bye
show this in browser fantastic