good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh
today is August 21st and let's see if
I'm alive yes indeed okay
nobody is here okay that's my bad yeah
because hey Z Tron crazy Tony so this is
trunk crazy pick a topic for us pick a
topic for us and let me set the window
correctly starts cuz I'll start coming
out mod Z Tron crazy were you from what
country and what C key pick a topic for
us
Xetra Xetra so I was hoping the Battle
of MU is gonna be here oh yes the Tron
is bathroom in here I mean you are
friend with bathroom you right yeah so
because yesterday he was asking about
keyboard and keyboard layout so I think
maybe we cover that you know yesterday
we went into the topic of okay so we
went into the topic of open source and
free software because of the mega upload
guy you know one thing leads to another
okay so you know if he is here or what
do you like to see you know pick a topic
for us so meanwhile there's keyboard
many interesting things okay let me
cover a little bit about keyboarding
okay oh yeah five random okay so
so random things you know there's
there's this new Mouse which I don't
recommend this is actually cheap
actually I'm not sure it's on sale right
now because on Amazon you only find
actually they are selling the they are
sending the mousepad this one actually
anyway this mouse actually I don't know
how much it cost I mean this trackball
but I don't think it's a good one
Beth Romeo good morning so bathroom you
you you you have some question about
keyboard layout so maybe we talk about
that that yes if so types type type so
okay let's see my boys is working my
head is moving good so this track boy I
don't think it's very good design
because when you have a trackball
you want you want a large ball okay I
mean the larger the ball is better but
if you have a small ball you know for
some reason you know for some situations
small boy is good but however the the
key thing about trackball he said you
want to have maximized you want to
maximize the exposed area so your hand
can drive actually let me show you a
track go
so I have this one this is very popular
and today is very cheap like 25 dollars
you know the classic logic tech it's no
good okay this this one is like I mean
mine mine is like seven years old but
anyway this came out almost like fifteen
or twenty years ago so I do not
recommend it you know you can buy you
know it's very cheap twenty-five dollars
but however when you want to buy a input
device you rather spend you know you
know twenty dollars you know forty
dollars fifty you want to get a good one
because it matters okay don't you know
just oh I'm gonna eat in dollars cheaper
or twenty dollars cheaper I'm gonna get
it because you're gonna use it did you
know for for rather you know several
years at least anyway so this one is no
good because you know it's no good
because I mean come you know the thing
is you you want to compare it to all the
others so when you compare to the other
all the others and and even counting the
price it's not so good okay so for
example know by this section or this
this one no good this one no good this
one is also very cheap twenty dollars
and this design has been out for like
twenty years
and it's no good okay so anyway so you
want to get spend a few you know more
dollars for example this one is also
pretty cheap I think $30 or two forty
dollars but it's so compared or
everything all things considered this
one is good okay okay let me post my
website so if you like to look at them
buy it buy it from my website you know
support me not talk show today is
okay some talk shows so we are here
today chat both reviews okay so let's
see better Amir you are using Commack so
greetings yes 20 what would you mean 20
yes I wondered a lot about your opinion
on Borat Commack okay let's talk about
keyboard layout let me finish about the
trackball so of the trackballs you know
these odd you know they are you know
trackball is unlike mouse for mouse for
mouse almost every Mouse have the same
design you know the except left and
right but basically all the mouse you
use the same fingers you know they'd
they pretty much the same track boss the
design is very diverse you know some use
the middle finger some use the thumb
finger and even all the middle fingers I
mean even the middle finger ones their
design is very diverse you know the
buttons are all over the place
okay so trackball you have to you know
try it if you can but otherwise you know
very different and secondary trackable
they are typically of to the pore size
is a major thing so the huge in general
the larger pore size the better okay but
also they take more space on your desk
so these are the larger balls and and
all these are good and if you look at
all the people's reviews basically there
is no universal agreement you know some
will say this is the best some will say
this is actually that you know they like
this very much some say this is the best
some say you know because I've looked
hundreds of reviews that's you know I
typically like for example this one this
one look I read you know order hundreds
of reviews on Amazon
elsewhere in you know trackball
enthusiasts forums and so on
there's no universal agreement on which
one is best
only on the other hand for Mouse
typically there are few people like you
know anyway the larger bow is usually
better but of course then takes more
disk space and then so anyway so these
are the best large-bore track balls
usually there are $70 or $80 and here
are you know kind of smaller track balls
this one is cheapest this Kensington ok
it's you know because and in particular
these it has a ring this ring you can
like twist it it's like a mouse wheel a
function say mouse wheel so this one is
very good and cheap like $30 the others
like this one is $80 this is new that
came out last year
you know Logitech it's thumb paste this
one also done based on so anyway that's
you know something about track boss you
can read my websites I give you some
details I use my keyboard on the phone
20 was the type of hi good morning queen
tech from Russia
good morning path removed from Germany
and Xetra crazy from Germany great great
good morning
so how many how many audience have 5
people watching so I used my key blue on
the phone ok so ok track bow so back to
this one this one is no good because you
know you want to you have you want to
maximize the expose area so when you
have a small bowl then you have this
veto you know Tiny's exposed area that's
no good also notice how it's flat so
when you have a small bowl like that and
you know with only half of the exposed
area it would be better if you don't
have this you know you know this flat
you know thing on the side because other
because if if you don't have the flat
things then you can actually your hand
can it have more control so this one I
would would not say it's a good one
and Amazon also came up with a you know
Amazon these days they have Amazon basic
basics which I suppose means you know
they produce everything from you know
every electronics and other things you
know just the most basic one and sell it
cheap so this one is like $20 or $30
it's a stamp paste I'm not sure how good
it is but you know it's I guess it's
cheap and reasonable okay so let's talk
about any keyboard layouts any
particular question you have you know
one thing about keyboard layout did this
go to keyboard yeah okay so I have this
page it's all about all different kind
of layouts now if you don't know
keyboard layouts you know for those of
you don't know we are mostly familiar
with Corti you know asdf you know hjkl
that's the layout that's the letter
layout now first so so this is called
keyboard layout this it means the
arrangement of the letter keys okay and
the most popular is Cote and you might
wonder so what's the deal you know have
you ever wondered why asdf why is it
like that
it's like that because of history okay
it's not because for you know logical
design or efficiency nothing like that
just because historical reasons because
in the beginning you have in the
beginning you have let's let me talk
about that you know you have what's
these mechanical typewriters so this is
like 20 years 200 years ago you have
these mechanical typewriters and the one
problem is that they Jam you can you can
see physically you have the jamming you
know when you hit a key the mechanisms
it's actually mechanical you know you
like put put heat to
and see so and you know the other
mechanisms so so the Hammers strike you
know it goes up so if you hit multiple
keys at the same time they they will hit
you know they will jam
so basically originally the reason of
this arrangement is that is to prevent
champ
you know so they eventually came with
this you know quote so-called quality
arrangement it's named Corti because the
top row you have qwe rty okay that's why
that is why we have corty now this is
like 2200 years ago but when computer
you know keyboard is even invented
people are used to this arrangement so
computer just follow the habit basically
so that is why we have CAUTI now this
picture is a heat map
meaning the the more red are the keys
you type the most often you can see that
it's not very efficient you can see so
the so after corty there is a vorak you
know from this heat map you can see that
ball Rockies you know it's more
efficient because you don't have to move
your fingers all over the place I've
been using ball rack for 25 years now
since 1994 you know I was a quality
typist since 1988 or so and now I'm
worked for 25 years and so Borak you
know if you Barack is much more
efficient yeah they they copied layer
from old typewriters so barack is much
more efficient key layout there is a
question of whether you want to learn
more by the way if you are you can
change your layout to varrock or Mac or
Windows or Linux for example I'm on a
Mac you just go here and you can pick
vlag you know you go to System
Preferences you know the that you can
say that yeah
in similar Borak on Windows Microsoft
Windows or Linux okay now as I showed
this many times I'm using a physical
vorak layout so I don't have to I don't
have to you know go to the you know
software-based look all right because
the keys on here it's actually duo
labels you can see the lower right is
for rack you know the Z Z yeah the lower
right is the vorak layout so that's a
physical for a keyboard okay so so there
is a question you know so vorak is much
more efficient so if you type a lot I'd
recommend Barak but there's a question
to use a should you switch or not well
that depends on a lot of factors okay
Neil yeah of course I know about it I'm
a master of keyboards in layout you know
in fact it's mentioned here I have a
dedicated article about that but
actually I don't know much neo so neo is
a efficient layout designed for German
language you know this layout design
letter layout design they depend they
are dependent dependent on the language
of course obviously so for English vorak
is one of the most efficient layout but
that's not the only one because since
like 20 years ago a lot of people have
created many alternative layout each one
of them claims to be you know efficient
you know you know some of them claims to
be even more efficient paintball rack
for example one of such is Cormac you
know this one is Cormac I don't like
Commack okay in general because they
anyway it's up to you to decide so let
me mention a few things so first of all
you know so you have all these layout
you know if you type a lot you know you
don't
to use corty ok you want to get into war
again learn proper typewriting proper
you know proper touch typing you know a
lot of people they have their own ways
of touch typing and online you will hear
them say oh I also touch type but I just
don't do it in the you know traditional
way
don't kid yourself ok there's a test you
can simply say you know whether you
touch type or not like this picture ok
you take up you take a tower you take a
tower put your hands on the keyboard
then cover it if you can walk like that
for ten minutes then ok you do touch
type doesn't matter what's your
methodology ok doesn't matter what's
your fingering if you can walk like that
yeah yes you touch type if you cannot
look like that for 10 minutes no you
don't touch type you go ok don't kid
yourself so you you know I would
recommend you know you learn proper
touch typing so there are two questions
here now should you take the time to
learn touch typing you know proper touch
typing it will take like one month ok
that's one question and the other
question is should you learn vorak or
something alternatives such as you know
Commack and walkman you know Commack
walkman said you know normal layout they
are quite a few invented by people you
nuts
pretty much and kept well mini Mac and
you know car parks qf m LW y now this Y
is supposed to supposed to be
scientifically the most efficient
according to the matrix you know the
measurements designed by this guy
compacts guy you know I have like terms
of details on you know discussing this
on my website so just go to my website
if you want to read about them I have
like tons of details because I've stood
and actually I've been studying them you
know since 1992 back then you don't have
internet so I read read books you know
they are books you know by vorak guy for
example Dvorak has written you know the
book that Barak layout is created by
this guy named Warrick something okay
the doctor of Iraq so anyway I read
books back then then then on the Mac
back then you don't have the rack okay
vorak layout came to the Mac in 1998
something like that man you know it was
on Windows operating system earlier like
1994 something like that but anyway I
was a Mac user back in 1990s
so I created my own vorak layout used
using a tool called rest edit you know
this is history this is 1990s Mac OS the
rest edit let me show you you can pop
you can probably see some pictures of it
so yeah so you see this application in
the 1990s it's called rest edit and
that's the it's icon it's a tremendous
it's very bleeding edge tool back that
at the time it allows you to so what
does it do it's like a Windows register
edit yeah you guys remember register
edit good non-indian so rest edit Allah
allows you to create for example create
key maps new key map layout you know
anyway this is back then so I use reddit
to create a robot layout so I've been
using Balrog layer since 1994 it's
extremely painful to learn it if you
already type touch type corty you know
it takes one month one hour a day to
let's say two hours a day one month and
the experience is extremely painful
because every time you type it's a
mistake then you're always the key my
god you know goddamn key then you you
know this experience is going to last
for one month
during the month you you almost like you
cannot walk normally and you know so
anyway so that's about you know that's
that's how painful it is so if you are
you know you are if you are thinking oh
I took you know I should learn more AG
because I mean to efficiency and I
taught you a lot I type a lot you know
you learn more work but beware this
frustration will come you know so you
don't get surprised because a lot of
people you know they try it then they
abandon ship they go back to quota so
anyway there's a question about whether
you should do it you know whether you
should switch from quality to any of
these alternatives you know any one of
them will take quite you know basically
a month to get fluent and you have this
frustration so the question whether you
should do it or not it's actually up to
you there is no absolute answer okay
because it depends on how much you
actually type and also depends on
whether you use other people's computer
for example you go to I go to a library
then I'm gonna start to hunt and pick
you know everyone will look at me and oh
this idiot you know can't find the keys
like he's first time using a computer
why because you know I'm in a library
you don't have corty you know I mean you
cannot switch to your ball rack and and
you cannot bring your own keyboard you
know so you're gonna start to do that so
there's lots of problems like that also
you know company if you work with other
people you know you know agile you know
pay a program you know there's lots of
these problems like if you in company
with your pair programming you have to
switch you know you either you bring two
keyboards one for yourself one for your
you know co-workers all you have to
switch you know key map every time you
know he types then switch back every
time you types things like that you so
there's lots of practical issues and
everywhere where you go it's gonna be
quality then you might think oh I'm
going to be master both yeah you could
but it's not it's not it's not trivial
okay then you're gonna okay first first
of all you learn you take one month to
to Limbo rack or whatever some others
then if you want to keep skills of
quality it's not easy okay it's actually
gonna be another several month of
dedicated effort to learn touch type on
Cody because typically yeah so it's kind
of complicated I would recommend if you
gonna learn ball rack just forget about
Cody
you know on Cody you just hunt and pick
okay because if you actually take
especially don't try to learn go rack
while trying to retain your quality
skills that's not going to work because
then your time to learn for Ag will be
like three four it will be half a year
and you know the frustration you will
not be able to find the keys because you
are trying to maintain two sets of
muscle memory you know Cody and work so
that's no good
if you want work go cold turkey and
vorak you know pick a vacation time you
know work every day where I can't forget
totally forget about Cody by a keyboard
that's for AG hard way a keyboard
I have lots of you know on my website I
have like I have a dedicated page that's
that list or vorak layout physical
layout where our keyboards is somewhere
there okay and also most of these
economic Wednesday oh oh they off also
feature physical Borak such as you know
these such as this one this one this one
this one not this one but you can
program it and this one you know most of
them to Sony anyway so if you want to
use Virago or alternative layout you
better you know get get you know go away
then get buy a good keyboard and all
that forget don't don't try to you
do Oh master Cody and black unless you
know you already type work for a year
then you find yourself needing you know
for example if you are cysts that mean
you need to go around in the office
visit every coworker and try to set up
the IP address or whatever if that's the
case go back is probably not for you if
you need to go around people you know
use other people's computers all the
time then brag is not for you okay
stick with corty that's probably best
and similarly for comb again orders okay
because quarry is just standard and also
so yeah okay let's be let's wrap up
about that question so that that is
about whether you should switch to
alternative layout that that is the
issue okay
by the way there are some websites you
know online they are the bag of you know
force information some people will claim
Oh Cody's actually more efficient than
Borak like one plus one equals three
three oh one plus one equals through
five you know you know don't pay
attention to those they don't know what
they're talking about anyway so um quota
varrock comment so that's one question
whether you should learn alternative
layer another question is whether you
should learn touch-type now if you don't
touch type there's a question whether
you should learn it again
there's no absolute answer okay there's
no absolutely and so it really depends
on you it depends a lot on you depends
on your situation your your case your
use case because learning touch type you
it will take one month one hour a day or
two hours day you know you take one
month so it's not you know it's not
something trivial okay but you know but
rather I would say it's a good thing
okay
in a case of turning to touch-type this
is more important than learning whether
learn whether to switch to varrock okay
yeah it's actually more beneficial okay
so learning to touch type so it depends
on you
so what wait why because it will take
one month to learn but also what's the
yeah also depends on how much you
actually type you know and on that
question that also is a lot issues
because you know every much many of us
programmers you know we think oh we are
I type all day you know online when you
see keyboard reviews or Emacs users they
talk about oh I'm a programmer I type
about all day
actually they don't type all day because
if you get you know kick get a key log
okay get a key dog let's see like get a
key loud and actually log how many
characters you actually type you know
you lock your keystrokes for months then
you get you then you know software okay
here software Mac key log I have a page
that lists or key lock software let's
see
find log ok key logs security okay this
of a keylogging software you know if you
are unsure how much you actually type
get a key rod then compare the numbers I
have details okay somewhere on this page
like I have my own key rock I show you
how many how many keystrokes I actually
type you know for vast majority of
programmers if you get a key log you
know you're on average your whole days
typing can can be done in five minutes
okay
you don't type much at all good you know
go yourself you know I you know you
if you continue you know if you are a
touch type of continuously type for
average programmer the whole day is
typing can be done in five minutes so in
other words you only type five minutes
in if that's the case do you need to
learn touch type
not really okay you don't need children
touch-type okay so most programmers you
know especially those who don't touch
type they you know each one person have
biased view you know including politics
including you know not just in politics
or religion but also everything else due
to your habit your workflow your
situation you know what you need to do
every day so for a typical typical
programmer even good programmers I'm
talking about you know expert
programmers they created lots of
critical software you know even good
programmers they when it comes to you
know keyboard you know typing they some
of them will say they don't touch type
okay most most people do not most
programmers do not because it's actually
something you have to not so they they
don't touch type so they have a biased
view they will just say oh don't learn
you know touched I mean it's no good
because all the people I know who touch
type that's those people who got
repetitive strain injury you know that's
total you know it's like it's
like in sports are you going to go pro
or not if you don't you know if you are
pros you know football soccer you know
whatever running you know marathon it is
those people who will have lots of
injuries you know if you look at sports
athletes they get injuries you know all
the inspo injuries are from athletes
statistically not from those
non-professional you know if you don't
you know do for a tional committed
competitive sports you don't get
injuries okay so so does that mean oh
you should never get training you should
never you know get training no you know
those athletes competitive athletes you
know they are better they are far better
than you when doing something when you
actually need to you know you know so my
point is that yes you know professional
you know those get training in sports
the proper way to run the proper proper
way to jump
those people they get more injury not
because they have training it's only
because they do it far more you know
hundred times more than average people
not because they actually properly
trained for sports you see what I'm
saying
so for touch typing touch typing is a
proper training okay proper method if
you type you know one hour a day
continuously if you actually average
continue continuously typing one hour
day that amount of work obviously you
know you want to learn proper touch
typing because without proper typing you
get injuries far more often okay so you
know don't listen to the stupid people
so anyway whether you should learn touch
typing or nah it depends on you a lot of
factors how much you type that's one
thing and you have to put effort into
you know learning it that's another
thing okay in general in general I
recommend it okay because you actually
you type a lot also let me mention you
know a lot of people will say oh once
you learn touch typing you will have
repetitive into injury not really there
are details okay because some once you
you see once you know touch typing you
tend to start to touch to type a lot
more then when you don't know touch
typing because now you can start to
write oh you know you know let me show
you because once you know how to touch
type then suddenly you start to touch
type you start to type a lot more than
before because because because for
example for example oh it's my dream you
gonna for example when you see someone
on the
turn ed who is doing things wrong the
end you gonna correct them you see that
you know and lots of things like that
you know you start to type more because
oh when you are chatting with your mom
or your girlfriend whoever or your
boyfriend then you started not now you
know how to touch type you started to
maybe use the right word use the fool
words and things like that so once you
know touch type and also in programming
also in programming once you know how to
touch type you start to write you are
drawn to write lots of documentation or
comments or proper comments you see
because before if you do not touch type
then you you know you try to be minimun
like you have your own like each program
are these idiots you know they have yeah
oh I have my own way of touch typing
then but actually you know you don't and
you know the you know there are lots of
several well-known programmers who has
told who holds the idea you know they
don't touch tag but they they are good
programmers for example the Emacs leader
the previous Emacs maintainer Stephan
something okay that's a he's a professor
in doing research on programming
languages he is a previous maintainer of
Emacs the leader okay
his name is Stephan who you anyone knows
the name type is Stephan something he is
one of the guy who tells you oh don't
touch type because if you touch type
you're gonna you know all the people I
know who gods we've headed stranger is
they are touch type is still stupid and
another guy for example the on on the
Mac there is a fantastic keyboard
utility called keyboard maestro okay you
can you can find it you know that's a
very popular now
you know since like ten years ago they
started to charge you know it's like $30
keyboard maestro okay it's a good
utility but today there are many let me
show you okay it's all on my website you
know I have like a few hundred articles
on these details so software keyboard in
so this page sectionals keyboard
software mac keyboard tools okay Mac
keyboard tours carabiner is the best use
that then you have you have Mac OS also
you know Mac OS X you know that they
also allows you to change keys program
of keyboards get get it okay by you want
a program or keyboards app launcher then
there's keyboard maestro there it is you
know so this guy he wrote keyboard
maestro it's a good it's a good tool and
it's also like it's being around for 15
years so even 20 years and some of them
you know I don't mention anymore quick
key is popular back in 1992 quick key
let's see if I still measure here you
know so I have you know lonely
experience with this qia let's see if I
can find it quicksilver quick kick okay
I remove it I removed it because anyway
quickly is you know back in 1990s is
extremely popular anyway so these are
Mac keyboard tools and I was talking
about typing and injuries hand injuries
you know this I'll go how many
keystrokes programmers type of day you
know get a key log don't give you to
yourself actually measure how many you
then you know how many keystroke you
actually type a day then you can say you
know you type all day or not you know
you can you can get a sense you know
compared to average you know how much
keystroke how much your average
programmer type how much keystrokes your
mom types how much kiss rock gamer types
depending on again you know if you are
in a role-playing game you type a lot
you know like Second Life year sometimes
you type a lot role-playing games like
you have to describe oh I you know I
started to walk towards the north and I
turn right and I saw this monster and
the Masters smiled at me you know those
old wood you know it were playing games
you have to type a lot that you type
incredibly bu a lot because I was in
Second Life for four years I used to do
that so how much then you know then then
the the highest class the people who
type the most is our writers and
bloggers you know it also depends on not
all writers but so some writers bloggers
they actually you know they type a lot
then at the other extreme then then you
have God level which is the data entry
clerks like in court you speak I type
you know and you have to do that for
several hours you know that data data
entry as a profession doesn't exist
anymore
but I was at eight data entry crock back
in 1990s you know the 1992 I worked as a
data entry clerk for a secretary for
like two years so I know the thing there
are entry so dictation you know your
salespeople speak you have to type it
you know real-time type of letter and
also also also some other kind of data
entries that you have to you know
there's lots of computing data like IBM
you know old days you know a bunch of
numbers you have to enter it into
computer that's called data entry that's
why it's called data entry but today
that job doesn't I don't think it exists
anymore because there's a speech
recognition which is actually pretty
good for typical speech but still anyway
then also there are actual professional
data entries where they use the they
used a know type that's you know in
court which is far
more efficient than than any any layout
or any keyboard you know when you
actually want you know go that level
that you want to get into stenotype
or alternative you can you know I talked
about your piano key system there exist
several of such systems for example
piano text
it's a PhD research paper I think master
thesis theses anyway so this there's a
videos if you go to my site you actually
see the video demo using a piano they
have a system then there's also this
mitchler
code system you know they have you know
I've studied them so so if you really
type that much at that level these these
systems are very fast you know a few
times faster than whatever your layout
okay because the physical design you
know multiple keys chords and actual
chords not the PC keyboard code control
or you know that that's the worst you
don't want that at all so these systems
you know that's really good so back to
about the conclusion of our question
whether you should touch type that
really depends on you okay how much you
type you know whether we you know
depends on you and okay so that's that's
finished that question the impact -
maybe we should type it out so today we
could we covered a lot of things right
you know but the main things with lots
of digression is quality quality varrock
I'm getting hungry or layouts where the
shoot you learn odd layouts
okay and another question is should you
learn touch type and I also covered a
little bit about how
tooand Borak code turkey or not and
should you retain 40 skills you know I
have actually saw on my website you know
so how did touch type you know so let's
go back to the layout then you know
there's several articles about a variety
out you know this one is basic it tells
you what it is why is it efficient then
how it's QWERTY designed and my
experience things like cover lots of
things you know we over act make you
type faster know okay there's a myth
going around people think you know most
average people when they hear a rack is
better designed they will think oh well
rack will make you type faster so if I
are done for Ag I will type faster no
generally speaking no unless you are you
know touch typing competitor you know
you are a competitor in speed typing in
that case yes you practice several
several hours a day you know you know
the if you really do that that's a case
but a cue but if you actually actually
want to type fast Barack is not the
answer you you want to go into steno
type or the piano based system that's
much faster okay you know nothing about
steno type is that some people use the
plover plover project you know which is
kind of like emulating stenotype machine
on a standard PC keyboard okay don't do
that that's was that's worse thing than
just using a normal work I mean don't do
that because if you do that you get
repetitive strain injury fast fast
faster than anything you know prova
don't don't don't learn popover okay so
my opinion about prover that system is
no good absolutely don't learn it in any
case you know don't don't know it and
the
only the only situation where you
actually want to learn the prova you
know is get a real stenotype machine
then you think you don't need proverb
because clover is a system to emulate
steno type on a PC keyboard right don't
do that if you really want to know type
get on steno type or if you want a
vision get on the alternative you know
piano key or you know the mickeleh coded
keyboard okay
the prober is don't do crap not not you
know you know some people some probe
offense they stole my message
you know name a disguise they don't like
me anymore but that's my opinion okay
that's my logical analysis of the all
things considered you know the
efficiency the hand health the damage to
your fingers efficiency how fast you can
type and the the physical system why it
is efficient why you shouldn't do it you
know I in my own opinion I consider all
these things you know that's my
conclusion so we talk about then we also
talked about children should you yes I
talked about several all these things so
any any questions type it okay type it
now I'm gonna read the comments let's
see how long I've been talking 46
minutes I'm getting quite hungry and let
me get a drink and so let's talk so I'm
getting hungry you can feel I don't know
how you feel when you get hungry like
really hungry for me like you can kind
of feel it I mean when you actually get
really hungry there's your body not just
like when you feel like eating oh I feel
hungry each time his dinner time but if
you skip lunch and you skip dinner then
your body will you know if you skip
lunch you feel hungry then you skip
dinner you feel hungry but at that point
your body will it's not just you feel
like eating so I'm kind of hungry then
your body I think us
for me kind of start to shake kind of
you can kind of feel it so I'm having
apple juice this is fantastic
one giant ton of apple juice then then
rock star as usual the energy drink
makes me stronger so comments comments
comments or it doesn't exist
okay comment oh so bathroom you though
Cormack so we haven't got into when
which one is more vision Commack of Iraq
okay now as you know Co mag is one of
the alternative layouts and Commack
Commack inventor and Commack proponents
they will it they like to say they like
to believe Commack is more efficient and
then more rack you know they like to
believe that muraki's was invented like
when we was law recommended 60 years ago
by now and C 1987 okay so okay
Oh 20 wait now when is were recommended
1936 so it's like 78 years ago
so the Commack people they like to see
comic verses most efficiently on the
Commack people this page I talked about
you know what is the most efficient
there no Commack people they like to
think you know over Aggies you know 70
years old back then you don't have
computers so but today we have computers
we can do a not a lot analysis of you
know so Copas know a lot analysis of
text corpus so that you know me
that you know a lot data you know you
know articles from newspapers from
Twitter you know so therefore we have
favor we can better decide you know
design a layout that's actually more
efficient then we'll go back okay that's
I tell you right now I tell you
right now because I and I I can tell you
you know reasons my rationale and and
analysis why why Co mag is not better
okay they're about the same okay depend
depends on lots of things just like
touch typing or you know alternatively
or whether you should you know which
ways better and they are quite a lot of
issues I'm gonna talk about so Coco Mac
and by the way you know Copa Scopus is
the you know as I mentioned you know you
might talk show there's a lot jargons in
each community the word copers
is one of the jargon from the kind of
the linguistics community they say
corpus it basically means data data set
of you know lots of you know one medium
books you know them you know when you
need to do analysis on the text such as
in crypto analysis cryptography you need
to know for example which combination of
letters occur the most often which is
shown in this graph for example this
graph shows the most its so-called
diagram to letter sequence diagram or
sometimes it's called teiegram you know
they measure what is what is the most
frequent occurrence of two letters
combination in english you know for
German for French that would be
different so anyway in linguistics
typically in this kind of area community
they call data Sarah's Copas you know
that's another jargon programmer has
programmers jargon mathematicians there
has there's and you know so Commack is
it better no no not not in any absolute
way so when is comic better well it is
better if
[Music]
it's not you know is it's it's like you
have to when you have okay with some
first of all how do you define better
firstly you know that's the thing that
that is a question how do you define
better you know for example there are
lots of studies all these people i i
collected they study which layout is
better you know each one has different
methodologies you know I looked at them
you know I compare them I studied them I
point out each one's flaws so first of
all there's a question how do you how do
you define what is which is better that
depends on how you measure you know
first of all the the most easy
measurement is by by you know the heat
map you look at for example which finger
for example if the most typed key
letters occurs on a home row so you
might think then that is better because
then you don't have to move your fingers
around okay so that that is one of the
most important way to church which
layout is better but there's more than
that for example for AG you can see
everything is most most things happens
on a home row but then on on this layout
Commack it is also true most of the
things letters happen on the home row so
in this case then how do you how do you
judge well there's more things for
example on a home row typically you want
the index finger and middle fingers
because they are the most stronger so if
if the most frequent letters happen on
these two fingers then then it's better
if they happen elsewhere so if you
measure this then Commack Commack is
better but hold on second okay for this
more and and this is quite a lot more
the meeting point out why ko Madeleine
yeah so let me go directly point out why
Cormac is not better okay first of all
let me point it out okay
we said we're a kromagg which okay so
so I'm getting actually I'm getting
pretty tired because I'm hungry and
tired
you know Bernie says Bernie Sanders says
eat wait you're know is your name is so
long I got confused on where to start to
beat you know wait does the comment
begin so Bernie Sanders says apple juice
patricians versus orange juice pissants
indeed I was just drinking orange juice
yesterday this is wait this is Andres
yeah because they don't have you know
typically I don't I like purple juice
the most purple I love bamboo juice I'm
getting tired
okay bohrok let me just let me pinpoint
what is a white Commack is very first of
all if you type English and English only
then then Commack is slightly better
it's not you know I'm a maverick user so
of course I don't like to say kamek
kamek is better so this is my bias view
well I try to be reasonable too so first
of all Commack is not better okay
because consider how how many texts you
actually have to type to actually see
the benefit of Commack even you know
even we assume that all the text you
ever type is English only
you know because first if if sometimes
you need to type Chinese for example me
then or sometimes you need to type
French or Germany or anything that's not
just directly English or programming
languages
another example is programming before
programming if you type programming code
such as Perl not much English word then
then then Vollrath is better I have
studied it okay I have studied somewhere
wait I I must have a vorak versus
Cormack okay I tell you exact this this
page is dedicated page on vorak versus
Coleman okay okay it's much easier it's
in fact if I actually just read it
because you know I have it written you
know concise and summarized okay so so
Commack is focus on rolling fingers like
like like this I'm gonna show you okay
Commack they they focus sound like like
like this movement so for example your
middle your your pinky first your pinky
go down first then your ring finger go
down first time I think I'm kind of
shaking because then you know you you
you have this movement rolling fingers
movement that is usually very
comfortable you know that is very
comfortable so that is the strong point
of Commack and that is how it is
designed they focus they want to put the
letters so that you have all these in
word you know in english rolling
movements against you see like you know
Ted you know England rolling movement on
the other hand ball rack is designed
alternative so if you type for act
typically what will happen is your you
use your right hand the left hand right
hand left hand big you know that's how
the rack is designed so these two you
know there are different you know design
the different way to make the keyboard
efficient so they are different you know
depends on which one you prefer more so
it's a design issue you know okay so
that's one thing but because of this the
moment you switch to the moment you are
the things you are typing is not English
words you know English you know text
then the advantage of Commack the
efficiency of combat becomes drastically
goes away you know because now you are
not typing English you don't so
therefore you you don't have this
rolling movement
anymore you know so I sometimes have to
type Chinese for example Chinese Chinese
ah someone okay so so that's not English
so you don't have the efficient you
don't have the running fingers anymore
so Oh
the efficiency advantage of Commack kind
of get quacked can went away immediately
same thing with French if you type
French Germany any language anything
that's not in English okay so that's one
thing then people say Commack is easier
to learn because command is designed
well I'm not going to go into details
you can read it you know you can read
this article there's are a lot you know
reasons and another reason is for
programmers you know for programmers you
look at vim users vim users you know
check KJ HCl and Emacs users for Commack
is actually worse vorak is better okay
then you also look at you know so the
symbols the main reason is that if the
moment you type something that's not
English the Commack of advantage goes
away drastically on the other hand row
rank is still kind of maintains certain
efficiency because all the vows on the
left hand so it doesn't matter any
language you know almost all languages
you need to have you know most languages
you have vows you know about consonant
vowel consonant you have so you you
still have these kind of alternative
hands advantage so that's one reason and
the other big reason Commack is not
better because it's because even if you
type English for the whole life you know
just how much text you have to type when
you until you you you reach a point
where it is better than
all right you see that's a question
because because they say Barack is
better because they measure all
Shakespeare's text they measure 10,000
books you know but in real life you
don't type 10,000 books you know so if
you your whole life's typing maybe
perhaps you don't reach that much so for
a Coco Mac it's a same thing to you
that's so that is my you know my my
reasons analysis okay okay so I've been
talking for okay what one hour one hour
okay so let me time to read the comments
stenotype I talked about bathroom uses
so Bernie Sanders a bathroom you I don't
know if you know about it but there is
layout specialized for German language
is called Neil yes indeed when it comes
to keyboard layout and key binding I
know everything braggadocio and the mink
a lot more McGraw manniac you know but
it actually I could say this this is
true you know I'm not good at many
things I'm not compared to a lot
programmers you know a lot programmers
are better than me and Emacs Lisp coders
a lot you know a lot better eMac this
food Emmy I'm not you know particular
good programmer and you know but when it
comes to key binding and keyboard
shortcuts you know this analysis study
of about efficiency I'm the top mastered
master okay I'm the top master let me
say that again I'm the top master when
it comes to key binding keyboard layout
shortcut layout you know there's another
to think a different concept is called
shortcut layout because when typically
when people think of layout they think
of the letter layout now key binding is
actually it's it's basically another
layout shuker like control X for cut
control C for copy that's let's lay out
okay and and in fact keep keyboard
shortcut layout is more critical it's
more important with respect to hand
health then the key letter layout
because why because if you measure
statistics you if you get your key log
you'll see for typical programmers or
Photoshop users it is not typing that
you do much it's it's actually things
involving control you know controls
backspace delete open fire close file
cut copy and do
you know things like that that for
typical programmers you do that the
keystrokes you type for those kind of
things are is more than the keystroke
you type for entering text you know just
like normal typing so therefore the key
layout I mean yeah the shortcut layer is
more important so for example if you are
thinking oh maybe I should switch
learned ball rack from QWERTY you know
things like that
maybe you think if you are Emacs or vim
user maybe you think or maybe should I
learn Cote of Iraq okay but before you
can see that it's more important more
benefit to you to consider whether you
should change your keyboard shortcut for
Emacs or vim or whatever okay that is
what you should consider first I have
reasons statistics you know study you
can see on my blog okay so that's about
key binding layout especially this is
particularly you know if you are using
theme Emacs Photoshop you know people so
there are a lot of details and also if
you Photoshop user then you actually
really want is a programmable keypad
okay that's what you really want you
know I get something like for 30 keys
you know program will go keypad so you
can just pick don't don't ever two key
codes like control C control code you
know with option that's the worst so
that's about that so what's the question
me oh yeah so well so so there is a neo
layout okay so neo layout yeah so
another thing about alternative layout
so all these quota for AK programmers
will rack you know mini Mac Commack
Walkman they are designed for English
you know once you switch to another if
you type German German or Russian or you
know they become you know they are not
efficient they are well usually they are
still better than quality
they you know they are not optimally at
all so there are people who design
layout for different languages for
example let's go to where is it
international ok so you know so there is
a german layout standard german layout
then there is a german layout these
efficient german layout so there's Diago
neo ad and w you know there are a few
and I I don't know much about them I
haven't studied about them I don't know
German but I you know I you know these
articles I you know I write them
throughout the years mostly in the past
ten years so little by little I improve
the article so for example for example
in order to study German layout first of
all you have to kind of find you have to
find out a German language efficiency
and you know then but before you do that
you have to actually know the German
alphabet you have to actually you know
start to learn Oh German uses this you
know so so how many you know do they use
you know do they use correct or do you
today you Spanish you know eat a cute
you know like Spanish French German you
know they all have kind of accents you
know so you have to know German okay
German for German language you have
these and you know this you know you
have to learn it then you study the
frequency you get you compute a
frequency by the way I have this
frequency counter you guys should try it
I have these Oh
javascript is turned off let me go to
here let's go there let's see comments
okay comment comment so I have so I have
this app written in JavaScript
that computes or calculates or counts or
something about the frequence when i
typed it wrong
fee fi u qu e and c y of letters okay so
they update in real-time check it out
I like to so you know check out my
website support it if you can drop money
okay drop money so I can again get
something good to eat so yeah so you
have to study frequency counter and this
one is measuring letters you can also
you can post you know for example let's
go to Unicode let's go to JavaScript
okay JavaScript
okay so JavaScript I have so this is
JavaScript code let's see okay so copy
the whole thing so I can go here select
all paste then you get you get the
programming language statistics you know
for whatever language you you code in c
javascript perl python ruby whatever
color you can see what characters you it
uses most often now you can remove the
so no space no digits no actually I want
no AC okay so remove the letters then
you can see different programming
languages you know what punctuation keys
you know like parentheses bracket which
one is used more often this is important
because programming you know languages
uses lots of these punctuation so tip
again depending on what you know so what
language you code if you are C code or a
JavaScript code it will be different
very quite different so it also
so you need because you need to consider
this if you have consider for example am
I going to learn more AK of dope for AK
you know that's so you need to consider
this as well you know
so these lots of issues see whether you
type in German or you know not so let's
go back to the let's go back where okay
so I was talking about German Leia yeah
and so physical German keyboards and
historical German keyboard you can see
they are you know changes his code then
ok so then there's economic anyway so
this German there's also French French
French French standard French layout
this is the standard French layer which
is extremely bad worse them corty when
typing French with this you know I have
details there I got when I do this
research you know you're so I'd you know
I don't speak French so I talked to
French people you know you need to get
information
so there's French layout this then
there's efficient layout design for
French this one actually they came up
with a new layout the French government
actually created a new layout because
they realized this is a big problem the
French layout is very bad extremely bad
so they in 2015 they started to design a
new layout for for French then this year
few months as ago yeah this year they
the final design is published which is
this one the new French layer so it's
much improvement than before but is
still QWERTY wait is it I'm not sure
it's wait so let's see if it's still
quality
Oh No eventually our is based on a
desert e HZ e RT y okay yeah SOT is
pretty much like corty they they switch
they swapped like four keys which by the
way
SOT is another extremely bad lay lay out
one of the standard layout used
SOT is using Europe like German France
they you know East East your Eastern
Europe they have different okay so let's
see what what comments I think I
finished about that yeah so okay how
many people seven okay okay so that two
more maybe two more minutes so type
comments okay questions comments type it
type it and let's see what what I can
say about that
so Dion says have you ever heard of such
a thing as pea mathematics or pear
linguistics yeah no yeah baby pea
program is one the most idiotic thing
it's it's part of the agile and agile
came from extreme programming the the
reason they are there is because
cooperation corporatism it had your
extreme programming agile they are you
know forward time they are thriving the
reason they are popular is because
corporations basically because of these
managers the non program managers you
know you have many managers who don't
know how to program they never learned
it they never programmed single line
code so you have programming like you
know non-programmer managers so they
manage you you know you are programming
but they don't know they don't know
nothing about software the code how they
gonna you know Church your progress like
they tell you know for example do you
have a project and you and you can tell
the manager oh this one is difficult so
it would take 10 days but maybe it takes
5 days but he does I how do I know you
know I don't program AHA ok you know so
it's difficult for me to judge therefore
the extreme programming agile you know
payer program is created why because the
whole thing basically the essence of the
pair programming the agile whole thing
is so that so so now I don't have to
worry about because you programmers
watch each other you you know I make I
make the programmers I manage I make
them like you know spying each other so
you pay a programming you each other
check each other's progress you know so
if you you know lazy I know now I know
because that guy tells me so because I
force I push so there's this ideology
agile you know all the all these things
standard meeting or that such that such
that you guys are supposed to you know
such that it creates a natural
environment so that you guys in essence
becomes you know spying each other
walking you know so I don't have to know
code yeah I can just you know look at
you guys and nobody takes credit you
know you stopped you know it prevents
any programa being good because if you
are really good if you know a lot your
credit there's no credit extra credit go
to you because now it's like teen walk
you know that that's one of the things
they emphasize Oh teamwork oh don't you
know like it instead of you know
so before HOH program you have
responsibility you have skill you know
how how you have knowledge you know how
much you know depends on how much time
you actually spend on that on you know
learning it your skill depends on how
much you actually you package so there's
good and bad you know this good
programmer this bad programmer and you
have responsibility you take on project
if it's good be what goes to you if you
didn't do well it's bad you are
responsible okay that's that's a good
way okay but with agile it kind of it
doesn't like this okay with AD Joe it's
like oh everyone is equal oh you know
it's like it's kind of like you know so
it makes the situation kind of this very
bad okay yeah so that's digression to
agile actually so the new that ok
bathroom you say is the news to type in
different languages a lot was one of the
reason why it was hard to decide for me
to change to a better keyboard layout
the news to typing a different language
okay was one of it yeah so are you using
comic now bathroom you this the distant
gray says most programmers who are
proponents of agile heavens even heard
of never mind
read the agile manifesto so it is an
even implemented
properly in the first place you know
about two years ago there is one of the
agile founder he did a YouTube talk for
one hour and basically he says you know
he himself said at your movement is bad
because because agile has been taken
over by bike by corporations you know
who wants to make money you know there
are tons of cooperation selling books
about agile and there are corporations
you know there's they sell servers at
your service so they go to your company
they tell you how you should do things
you know they make a lot money so so he
says you know the one I'm the founder
you know who wrote the manifesto he says
agile is no good because it's been oh
it's just been taken over by these you
know corporations so yeah and but but
but besides that I mean even if they
have not been taken over by corporations
I do not like agile I mean the manifesto
is stupid manifesto okay so bathroom
uses what you said about the managers
advice just as well for how the
university degree changed here they
shortened the time you are supposed to
study to make everything faster in
Germany okay tell me about yeah I don't
know Jimmy so bathroom you are you
German are you like German you know
German blood is also so to speak over
you America will move to German by the
way you know if you look at American you
know white American if you look at their
ancestry you know whether they came from
France or you know or Netherland so you
know northern Europe or what what which
country or majority I think sixty sixty
percent actually of the German decent so
fathom you say suddenly they complain
that people finishing University
in such a short time don't know enough
about the stuff they studied so bathroom
you say is using quality and don't know
if hold to what I should change yeah
that's yeah you have to that depends on
you you know first so first of all look
at how much you type you know you know
think about it yeah so so bathroom you
say is I'm mostly writing English but
also German in other languages yeah in a
case don't don't do don't do Cormac so
Oleg hi Oleg Oleg are you away are you
from awake are you from Russia or Oleg
says but agile is working organist
o-etca is working at least in my company
okay
yeah bathroom uses 30 years ago he was
perfectly fine to study 12 semesters
because it is supposed to share supposed
to shape you as a human now if you study
a semesters you are looking at we're you
are looking at weirdly by some bosses in
companies so you are in university madam
you are you what you are using
university and you studying computer
science so on
Oleg says also my manager has some
technical background okay so Alexis I am
from Ukraine
okay Ukraine Ukraine I believe you
Ukraine is in Eastern Europe right
let's see Wikipedia Wikipedia is the
answer to the universe oh that's Ukraine
is a big country Eastern Europe it used
to be what okay so it's around there
okay so I think that's it for today I
like to you know normally I like to send
some photos you don't know can you guys
actually post pictures on this you know
chat chat because I always like to see
straight photos of the you know
different peoples faces yeah usually I
would just go to the street my Google
Street map but anyway I think we are
done today so say your last words in 30
seconds we're gonna shut down thank you
guys
okay you cannot post picture okay rain
rain here distant grave where is where
is that distance graves away from
distance way
England okay okay thank you guys for
coming by have a good day if I missed
your questions you can always post
through my youtube comments and you know
the more comments the better subscribe
and thumbs up bye