good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today we are going to do mathematica
demonstration i'm going to show
mathematica
type setting mathematical type setting
wolfan language
uh compared to tech or la tech for
example
and i'm going to show demonstrate
mathematica
notebook and
type setting in wufang language and also
the outline feature
in comparison to emax oakmod
so today is 2021 may
6th welcome guys
uh okay i'm going to begin
okay mathematica type settings so uh i'm
going to show you an article
search for xali search for
tech pestilence
okay this is my article the tech pistons
why tech and la tech sucks
that's download groups uh
technology for typesetting
so you can see this article uh this
article uh
written in 2004 16 years ago
uh this you know here we have type
setting
and here is the code you type in latex
to to show this uh mathematical type
setting and i'm going to show you
how you do that in wolfram language okay
so on the left window for those of you
emacs users on the left window you can
see
all my emax commands and the keystrokes
for example move cursor
right backward by word or move by
character
move down move up any command i
any key i type in emacs
it will show the corresponding command
on the ping window and the corresponding
key i'm using
software keys and i'm using vora
keyboard uh
and okay so vera keyboard let me show
you my keyboard okay so keyword
is so that
is the one i'm using let me let me show
you
uh okay so
so you can see
my keyboard so this is uh
kinesis advantage 2 and that is ultimate
hacking
so you can see you can see reviews i
have
and the video reviews of both of these
keyboard okay
so now let's go back to mathematica now
let's go back to mathematica and
let's talk about the
fantastic features of typesetting in
mathematica
okay
i need to get a i need to get a camera
holder
okay so so let's do okay so so let's see
so let's see mathematica so wufam
language
okay so first thing i we i we i'm going
to show you how do you type those things
in mathematica okay so
sun okay sun and by the way i did
about five or six videos on mathematica
so if you are interested in wolfen
language
uh which is a fantastic programming
language in my point of view
it's the best programming language by a
magnitude
different from all the others including
closure this
pascal erlang whatever golan
python is the best language
by a magnitude so i did five videos
before
uh check them out i go into detail
why i think that way and i demonstrate
why it is so
so today i'm going to show uh
typesetting in mathematica
so for so first of all i'm gonna gonna
show these
sum uh formula okay sum
one over n i'm gonna show you how do you
typeset it so sum one o over n
n from 1 to k
okay evaluated evaluated
okay it's a harmonic number it's a
convergent series
okay so wait it's not uh
it's not gonna i i forgot the math okay
but anyway so you want to typeset this
so what you do you just this is all you
have to type
and you just select it actually you
don't have to select it you go
you press ctrl
shift n i believe so you go to look at
the
look at the cell okay and convert to
uh ctrl uh shift ctrl n okay standard
form so let me show you
shift ctrl n you see
so you just type that and you press
shift ctrl n
you get that now let's try the full uh
full formula okay so let's copy that
okay i don't want that okay
hold on a second delete delete so
press ctrl l to copy whatever the
previous
uh input so there are several formats
let me show you so this is convenient so
you can choose input form okay shift
ctrl
i which will convert it to the way your
the this is called input form in
mathematica which is how you type it
so ctrl shift i to input from ctrl shift
n
to uh standard form this is what ufo
language calls
standard form then there is also a
traditional form okay
actually let's write it down okay let's
write it down
so shift ctrl i
uh then okay let me show you okay so
so ctrl seven yeah
undo uh old seven
no seven is title okay we are going to
start to talk about also i'm going to
demonstrate online mod
so that you have title subtitles
subheadings things like that you can do
that so
actually we are i'm starting to do it
now
uh let me see o7 text form okay
yeah so so input form
and it's input form
press ctrl
shift i okay so that's the input form
then old seven let's see
seven then standard
form press ctrl
shift n okay so that is a standard form
then we are going to do traditional form
so let me show you what that is you
select that
and what is what is a shortcut
ctrl shift t okay get rid of the menu
ctrl shift t
ctrl shift t so you can see
it also renders this in a
two-dimensional format so what's the
difference between
between the standard form and the
let me paste it here
uh control seven yeah okay
yeah old seven not control seven yeah so
and so this is the traditional
form so what what is the difference
between the standard form and the
traditional form
they are basically the same okay the
difference is that
in some traditional you know so the
standard forms
in in traditional mathematical notation
they are
uh ambiguities you know because
mathematical notation
is the way it is is from
evolutionary is is from history okay
historical development
it's the mathematical notation you see
here
they are not created by someone who
designed the whole thing
but rather from historical developments
you know like before we know we don't
have integrals
we don't uh you know we have we have
plus we have minus then
then when the calculus got invented
there are several competing notations
for
derivatives for integrals for example
here you see a derivative
derivative and limit so there are many
competing
notations and gradually eventually we
converge into one
kind of the standard traditional uh
notation
for each so for example this is a
definite integral
and this is a derivative the first order
derivative
of a function f and here is the limit
and here's the sum
and here's the infinite sum so those are
traditional notations
now however traditional notations have a
pr sometimes have problems they are
ambiguous
they are ambiguous um
so it's a flaw and this flaw does not
became
it only became apparent when you started
to use computers
to do mathematics because computers are
you know done
computers are very precise and it it use
algorithms to interpret you know so when
you have a programming language you need
a syntax you need a grammar it's very
precise
so when you have traditional form of
mathematics
sometimes you know it's ambiguous like
the computers cannot decide
just what exactly what you mean but
however to humans
usually we resolve the meaning by the
context
for example so so what's uh what's the
example of the ambiguity of traditional
form
okay let me show you a uh article okay
math notation uh just search for that
and you can see an article here the
problems of
traditional math notation and here is
a kind of a longish article
uh which i began to document uh the
problems of traditional
uh math notation and this is a
well-known problem by the way and this
this article happened to be uh you know
someone posted it to hacker news a
couple of times
so trade so so so so let me give you a
one example of traditional form okay the
i mean the ambiguity the problems of
traditional mathematical notation uh
okay for example the
absolute sign okay the abs
the absolute um uh
negative x okay so for example the abs
the absolute okay so when you have that
okay so let's say let's say x
okay negative x plus
uh let's say plus
three plus
absolute uh times okay let's say
times absolute y
okay so you
have a notation like that
you see the problem with the absolute
symbol is that
it's not a bracket notation so when you
have absolute
you know kind of the bracket they do not
you know there are several ways to
interpret
and interpret this expression it could
it could mean
the absolute uh value of this
x variable and then the absolute value
of the y
variable this is the common
interpretation
you know by context we understand to be
to mean that but however it could also
mean you know the absolute
uh the absolute
thing of this expression then you take
the absolute of the whole thing
okay that that is kind of a forced
interpretation but
it it it it can um
let's see let's just say this okay z
okay so let's
modify this okay so this is so for
example in this notation how do you
interpret that you know suppose y
is a variable in a programming language
that becomes an operator that evaluates
to an
operator you know in most languages you
cannot do that but in mathematica you
can actually do that
so if y evaluates is a variable that
stands for an operator so
so then you have this you know this is
one of the possible expression then
you know then the interpretation becomes
ambiguous
because you can say the absolute value
of x
then and absolute value of z or you can
say the absolute value of y
then you take the absolute value of the
whole thing so it's ambiguity
so this is just one of the many examples
of the
uh flaws and ambiguity
and big ambiguity of traditional
notation okay and i
have quite a lot um let me give you
another example okay just
for the fun of it x equals to three
okay now if you are a programmer you
know it's common to have another
expression
using double equal but however in
mathematics you don't see that you only
see
equal sign so equal sign let's say let's
say y and let's say not three okay
so equal sign in traditional math
notation has
multiple meanings it can mean an
assignment that is you assign the
variable
you you assign the value y to the
to the variable x or
it can mean equality a predicate kind of
in logic it's
called predicate you know
which means you know uh in in
programming language it's also predicate
anyway the predicate in logic and and
the predicate in programming language
they have
entirely different meaning but anyway
let's let's forget about logic for now
so so the traditional
notation of the symbol equal sign can
mean assignment
and but it can also mean equality okay
so when you have this expression that
means x is identical
to y so it's ambiguous
but but in math you know in math papers
you you see a lot of
but you don't you don't use double equal
sign you just use equal sign
but how do you know which what does it
mean equality or assignment
you usually know by the context you know
human we read it we
we can tell by the context
so these are some of the examples of the
problems of the traditional math
notation and there's more okay for
example i
you know it's quite this is actually a
non-trivial problem this
this problem actually is non-trivial to
the degree
it touches upon the fundamental problems
of
computation and mathematics
the connection the relationship between
math and
computation for example you might have
heard
of if you are headscarf programmer
howard curry howard correspondence or
hurry coward isomorphism
so this this this is a theory
that connects computation
with mathematics okay so
so anyway we are getting a bit far so
the reason i'm mentioning this is to
support
my uh the idea okay the the claim that
the notation the design of a notation
in fact is a non-trivial and
deep problem that has connections
to the foundations of logic and proof
theory okay now in the past 10 years i
i have a great interest in proof theory
proof theory homotype type theory
you know they are all about proofs how
do you do proof
proofs in mathematics what does it mean
things like that and uh
and i i just want to say
you know without too much explanation
that the
design of mathematical notation is very
critical it's very
is very much tied to the to the
proof theory the foundation of
mathematics and the
computation okay but let me tell you why
okay let me tell you why in a
single sentence the reason the notation
is important because in computation
in computation okay uh for example
you guys probably heard of um lambda
calculus which is the foundation of
uh of computation lambda calculus is one
model of foundation
and there's also uh combinators for
example the hacker news comp
y combinator that you know they use the
name
y combinator is white y combinator
is a specific combinator which is a an
expression
and what's a combinator combinat
combinator
is a a particular way to
model computation okay so
and you mo you also have heard of tuning
machine okay tuning machine
combinators lambda calculus they
are all equivalent
models of computation okay sometimes
called universal computation
uh universal uh computer
so they are equivalent models of
computation
so what's the point about them you know
they they are equivalent but however
they kind of take different
um uh
different approaches for example y
combinator and lambda calculus they
both very much depend on syntax
essentially that's what they are
formally it's called
formal languages okay let me let me show
you some of these
articles
okay so you can see a wikipedia about
formal languages formal
language the study of formal language is
the foundation
of theoretical computer science is i
would i
you know i would actually claim it's the
the most fundamental foundation of
theoretical computer science
so passes compilers lambda calculus
uh combinator they are all
based on formal languages okay and
computability of
all those problems you know for example
whole team problem
uh they you know they are all studied
by using formal language and formal
language is very interesting by the way
because it's
basically us just a symbol it's
basically it's just a
string replacement you you you
you create uh rules of string
replacement so this is related to
password passes if you studied passes in
a computer language or regular
expression
it's all formal languages about
uh string replacement replacement in
short in a practical way to explain it
you can just think of it as theories
theories about string replacement okay
so that includes lambda calculus
and combinator okay so look let's look
up
okay so here we have the y combinator
the famous
company's startup uh incubator started
by paul graham
one of the great least programmer
okay combinators so let's look at
wikipedia okay
so you can go read about combinatory
logic that's you know that so why is it
called logic
because combinators and lambda calculus
both of them
why did logicians create them they are
created by logicians they are created
lambda calculus and combinators they are
created not
to study computer science okay they are
created to
investigate investigate the
the foundation of mathematics
in other words proofs and logic so what
when can something be true can you
create a systematic way
that autumn automatically find out
all possible theorems you know if you
have that that's that would be wonderful
you know because then then that means
you can create a computer
and just let it run you'll you'll find
all possible theorems of the universe
you don't
you don't need einstein you don't need
newton you don't need
you know you don't need mathematicians
anymore because you just let the machine
run it you'll find all possible theorems
of the universe
but it turns out it's not the case so
that's why it's a
lot of study so let me get back okay
combinators lambda calculus they are
they were
created to to to study investigate
foundations of mathematics or proof
proof theory
proof proof systems and and and by
chance in turn
they turns out to be fundamental to
computer science
okay so combinators and lambda calculus
they are both
part of uh let me let me go back they
are both
uh they are both formal languages okay
so so when we talk about
formal languages it's essentially in a
practical sense it's a string
replacement system
now that get us back to the notation so
what's a string
if you're a programmer you know you know
what's a string you know you have a
string
in purple python c c sharp c plus plus
in every language go like
uh javascript string and you can replace
string you can usually you do
usually do that by regular expressions
okay let me show you some
regular expressions um
kassadi python rejects
okay so i have a article that shows you
uh this is a tutorial on python's
regular expression
and you know tutorial regular expression
basics
and uh regular expression flags
and regular expression functions okay
so that's a tutorial for python regular
expressions
find and replace strings okay
now let's go back to javascript so i
also have an article about
articles and tutorials about javascript
regular expressions so you can see
javascript expression flags or syntax
or functions java or tutorial and
tutorial
so a complete tutorial and reference
about
regular expressions in javascript
and i also have a tutorial on e-max list
regular expressions so you can see
there's a tutorial there's uh
you know um for a regular expression in
images
so anyway so let's go back to where we
were so we were talking about
um we were talking about
close that combinatory logic formal
languages lambda calculus y combinator
so i was saying they are all
in a sense a string replacement system
instead of using string they call them
symbols a sequence of symbols
so you can think of it as a sequence of
characters in a string
if you are a programmer so
string replacement system uh so it
it has you know it's basically it's
deeply tied to computation and
foundation of mathematics
so when you do string replacement so
that's why
you know the that's why i say the
notation
becomes critical
because a sequence of symbols is just a
string
and and you eat and you want to do
lambda calculus or combinators of any
formal language or passing
you you replace strings right so
which how you you know how you design
your syntax
you know what what you start with you
know so that's why
it's uh critical the notation okay
that's kind of a giant digression to uh
formal languages and string and
okay i i think i should write it down
today's topic so today's uh
today's talk show i think uh let's write
it down okay
so that's kind of a big digression
so let me write it down
traditional math notation
has many problems one of
them is ambiguity okay
the design of notation
is critical and the
the design of notation or syntax
is critical and none trivial
they are deeply tied
to foundation of math
proof theories and
theoretical computation okay
that's a second point then
then why is that
okay why for example
formal languages lambda
calculus
combinators they are
all essentially string
replacement
and a string is essentially
a
sequence of symbols
all in terms of
of industrial
programming its
stream
okay because when you and they uh
and for another
practical example passes
okay so what does a pastor do a pastor a
primary language parser
it looks at your source code which is
input
then it basically reads every character
and it has to
basically transform them
into a into basically another string
okay
so uh
more or less okay i'm not gonna let me
go back to let me
let's we are getting far okay so let's
go back to
uh okay so let me just say for another
practical
example passes and
regular expressions okay so i'm showing
you
how come why do i say they are tied
together
and also let me let me show you a
let me link to the um
curry hardwood correspondence okay so if
if you don't know what that is
you know try to read this uh article it
is it basically says
every mathematical proof has a
corresponding
program algorithm in
uh you know in programming you know they
can
uh they you know they are kind of
equivalent
so so so back to the notation so so i'm
showing
i'm trying to tell you why there are the
problems of traditional
notation and i gave you two uh
two examples the absolute sign or the
norm
and the assignment versus equality
that's
ambiguity in traditional math notation
so that's why i'm saying the design
design
of the so go back one step i'm trying to
explain
what's the difference of the standard
form and the traditional form
in in ufam language
okay now i'm now let me explain that
the difference is that in traditional
form
traditional form that basically emulate
traditional mathematical notation
but however when creating the wolfram
language doing
you know mathematics
because there are many ambiguity
problems therefore
wolfram language will find stephen
wolfram created the standard form
which avoids the these ambiguities in
in in the traditional uh notation for
example
for example let's do integral okay
let's do integral let's say x squared
okay
with respect to x okay evaluate that
okay we got it wrong okay syntax zero
uh not integral integrate okay integrate
okay evaluate that so you integrate x
squared
which is the result is x third power
over three
uh plus a constant okay but let me show
you
so let let me make this into uh
okay let's let's do another another okay
so
here we make it into
traditional form okay ctrl shift
t so here this is what you see in
traditional calculus you know or math
textbooks this is the traditional form
but
let's so what's the problem there's a
problem because
you see you you see this d
thing so you have the integral sign
then the expression where which is the
part you want to integrate
then comes this dx thing
you know so what is that d you know if
you are you
if you are a programmer it's a puzzle
like
where does this d come from you know the
d here
is simply function as kind of a
comma or separator you know to a
mathematician the d
means differential so it basically but
from a function of from a programmer's
point of view
the d only functions is as a separator
of arguments
you know we are trying to tell the
program that x
we want to integrate this expression
with respect you know to some symbol and
that symbol is x
so the d uh kind of function as a comma
or separator
so so it's this so so from a
programming language syntax design point
of view
this is not a good notation because you
have this mysterious d
so why is it not h why is it not you
know a b c
d e f g why is it d well yeah because
historically you know the d to
mathematicians you know they
they don't have computers they just
write dd stand for differential it
reminds them oh
with respect to x so so that's why in
mathematica
wu from language you have the standard
form okay control
shift n
okay it's dlt okay yeah okay so
anyway i
okay this is not a good example so so
but i can i i can tell you why they they
still use the i mean
so this the mathematica type setting
system
is created in 1996
okay then around 1997
also 1995 you know they were working on
this and
uh and then when when
in 1997 also mathematica version 3 came
up
then you you have uh the
the complete typesetting system so
back then when this was designed this d
is a big problem i mean there's a huge
debate
between you know ufam you know you know
fam company
because okay let me tell you uh
kind of uh story okay i don't
i may not be accurate you know i kind of
know okay this is just uh
you know stefan wufang he doesn't like
these nor do i you know when i see this
this is a problem
this d is a very illogical it should
should be banned
so stefan wufang wanted something more
like you know just
comma d or something but however
that's a problem you see the force of
convention
tradition is very powerful just like for
example
keyboard computer keyboard quality
layout versus
nobody know what what the is right
they are so the force
of convention for example the let's go
to keyboard let me
let me uh let me kind of ramble
in my usual way and tell you about
things
for example in uh in keyboards
most people are familiar with this kind
of keyboard
you know they are comfy comfortable with
it but
why is it keyboard this way why the keys
are kind of slanted
why the letters are arranged in a weird
way a d
asdf you know it's all weird why
because history because typewriters type
typewriters mechanical typewriters was
that that way due to
it must you know there's many
constraints engineering constraints
therefore it becomes that
you know the staggered layout the you
know
you know so so and also the
the you know i talked about this many
times the
quality you know the quality the the way
the letters are arranged it's that way
not because
this is the best design but rather it's
due to historical reasons
so however my point here is that
traditional tradition
the habit human habit tradition is
a tree is
is tremendous powerful tremendously
powerful you know most people to this
day
they have no idea what's a work and if
you show them
a weird keyboard for example let me let
me show you some you know
some of the weird keyboard these are
designed efficient efficiently you know
these are well designed but to
average people your mom or dad
this is weird this you know they cannot
get used to it
even including many programmers today
so the power of convention is a very
powerful force
and and for good reasons too because
you know when you have new design even
though technically it's better but you
have to spend all that
you have to spend time to learn it and
you have basically throughout our
history
all the textbooks
you know if if we started to change all
traditional math notations then that
means we have to
all the textbooks millions of of them
will be no good anymore because
this is oh no you know you have to
relearn everything you have to re-teach
all the teachers you know it's a massive
problem
you know in the same way just like the
in united states we use
a imperial measurement system
for example miles inches you know
so why don't we just change them to
kilometers to the metric system the
whole world is using
well there's a huge cost to pay because
then all the highway signs you have to
change to miles all the cars you have to
uh change to
kilometers and other people they are
used to miles you know
americans you know you have to
they have to relearn what the kilometer
means then
it's prone to accidents so
traditional the convention convention
and tradition
it has tremendous power you know the
the the uh force
and habit human habit therefore
it's not you know so therefore in
wolfram language they
eventually decided to stick with the d
because if you some use something else
let's say a comma or a uh let's not do
it here okay hold on a second
if you use something else a comma or a
or even a parent you know something
weird
you know parents doesn't make sense so
maybe you want to use
that you know anything you do
that's different from this form all the
people will find it weird and basically
nobody will use it so that's a
force of convention so eventually that
is why
we found language they you know they
they gave they gave way to the tradition
so
this is the standard form this is the
traditional phone
so anyway back to my explanation so this
is not a good
example to illustrate the difference
between traditional foam
and the standard form but let me show
you
an example that does illustrate so
for example absolute value
okay norm okay so norm let's let's do a
norm of a vector
uh so norm so you have a vector
one and one you want to know the length
so in
in math note in math terminology that's
called the norm so
okay evaluate it so the length of a
vector
x1 y1 is
uh square root of two okay
now the norm you can now there's a
traditional notation for the norm
which is the double vertical so let's do
that
ctrl shift t okay
so that's a traditional form for the
gnome okay
but however we can make it
uh the wolfram language standard form
ctrl shift t
ah no not t ctrl shift n
what okay that's not a good example ah
i i should use absolute
uh wait okay this is not good
let's see
ctrl shift n for standard form
okay i i i give up uh
wait so so right now i'm trying to show
you an example
where the traditional form and
the standard form differs in a
significant way
and right now i'm failing
i failed in giving in in giving you an
example to show their difference
okay let's skip that okay so you know i
can find the example but that'll take
another five minutes
so let's check how long have i been
talking and check
is watching and see we need to move on
so i've been talking for 43 minutes
lots of digression okay so let's let's
let's continue okay i
i need to show you the um the
mathematical notations so we are kind of
so let's just get back to uh
instead of all the digressions let's go
back
to
to the
to the tech oh is it
oh yeah so there so let's get back to
typing these things in mathematica okay
so let's forget about
the gnome i'll i'll find i'll do that
another day
so
so back to wolfen language language so
you we have the input form
that's like that it looks like that then
we have the standard
standard form looks like that then we
have the traditional form okay
oh yeah now i do remember difference
between traditional form and standard
form let's do a derivative okay
let's see if we can do that
what derivative with respect to x and
let's say
x squared so derivative
of x squared with respect to x is 2x
okay so let's copy that and now let's
show this
in traditional form
okay yeah that's the traditional form
now let's show that in standard form
ctrl shift n there it is
okay
yeah so so okay so this is uh not
okay so here is an example so in
traditional form
the derivative of x squared is written
like that
but in a in a un
ambiguous way in ufan language standard
form it's written like that
so you can see the tradition of notation
for the derivative
is ambiguous because you have the
fraction you have the
divide so this can be seen as this you
know the top
expression divided by the second
expression which is completely
idiotic so that's a some of the problems
of
uh problems of traditional math notation
okay
and here is the example of the
traditional form
and the mathematica standard form which
is very different from the traditional
form okay
so that's a that's a good example
so now go back let's go back to uh to
how do you type this in mathematica so
so we've shown we we have shown the sum
so the integral um okay i think
uh we need to do it fast because um
i already talked for 40 minutes
so we showed the sum so let's do an
integral so integral we
already showed so this is how you do the
integral so you just press
ctrl shift
ctrl shift n to get you know to get the
to get it rendered in standard form
or ctrl shift t for the traditional form
so that's an integral
so we've done integral we've done so
what about fraction so
fraction is pretty easy okay so let's
just say fraction
x divided by y okay enter
so let's copy that so let's do this in
standard form and in traditional form
now i'm i'm not going to do standard
form anymore so
i mean the the i'm not going to do the
traditional
form anymore because most of the time
it's uh
identical to the standard form so anyway
fraction
okay so fraction then
uh you know you just type x over y slash
y so
integral so what about definite integral
so
here's the example
so integrate some expression this can be
anything times f or whatever then
you want to uh so here you say with
respect to x
then from a to b or a a and b can be any
other expression
okay so evaluated that uh
oh it's it actually symbolically it
actually evaluates the whole thing so
let's see
let's not
wait how do you
hold on a second so let me see what's
the syntax for integrate yeah so
okay i'm i think i'm kind of getting too
slow
and so let's let me check the comments
hello luis uh
cool never thought of that uh do you
think that is fundamental to give type
to the values of the string or
do you prefer a dynamic type system okay
that's a programming language design
question uh we can talk about that for
an
hour but it's not related to
our topic today so ask me another day
okay
uh you are starting to have a
shuffle chauffeur for hair
greetings but
km and meters yeah so anyway let's get
back to the
integral okay so so what is going on
here
okay so anyway so let's
so let's show that so this is how you uh
type
you know uh this this is the syntax for
the integration
so ctrl shift n
okay so you can see that it's typeset
you know in general the traditional form
is more beautiful
so here is the traditional form okay so
integral
so we got definite integral then
derivative you can
derivative actually you uh you can type
it
like that okay then for example copy
copy then
ctrl shift n standard form ctrl shift
t traditional form okay yeah so here's
another example where you can see the
difference between
traditional form and the mathematica
unambiguous standard form so why is this
ambiguous
because you can see in a traditional
form they are using parentheses
but however parenthesis has multiple
purposes
in traditional math notation one it
signifies
the grouping you know the precedence of
expressions
two it is used as a bracket for the
argument of a function
so it's ambiguous so how do you know
what does this mean exactly so
that's a problem of uh traditional math
notation so
in wufang language they decided you know
the square bracket is
always used for the arguments of a
function while the parenthesis is always
used for precedence
okay so so what about limit okay how do
you type
limit okay so limit is okay
obvious some expression uh
we uh so uh
so uh h goes to
x okay let's say a okay
so that's how you do limit
uh oh yeah so
so they they actually evaluated this
limit
and reduced it to just expr symbol
why because when when you have a limit
and when the variable does not appear
the in the expression
the result is the expression or
something like that i
actually um anyway so so let's do that
again
so ctrl shift n for standard form
so here we see and here ctrl shift
t for traditional form
wait do i actually did i type this right
yeah yeah i got it right
so but why is the limit not showing
correctly
let's let's change the expression to one
over x
now i don't
anyway yeah so anyway so so that's how
you do limit
okay so
uh so limit so for example if you want
to
let's do a more complex example of this
limit okay so
so you have the this is the this is the
traditional meaning of of
a derivative
minus f a
divided by
h and h goes to zero okay
evaluate wait i don't
understand
i mean this has to do with math why is
it evaluate to
f yeah this is making some assumptions
about the function f
because if f is not
a well-behaved function it doesn't
you know it doesn't become f anyway so
so here's here's the expression
in standard form
and in traditional form
okay did we get it right oh yeah wait
wait we got it wrong
this yeah i got it wrong
copy paste
okay so traditional form
standard form
traditional form okay
okay that's limit how do you do square
root okay
here's a square root
okay
ctrl shift n for stat
standard form ctrl shift t for
traditional form okay
now what about matrix now here's the
example of matrix
uh for let's let's make it complex
square root two plus
uh y squared okay
copy paste paste
and traditional uh
standard form traditional form whenever
you see a traditional form
you'll notice here it shows you know
kind of
dot dot you know kind of uh saw here
okay what about matrix okay so let's do
a matrix
so a matrix is just a nested list in
mathematica so
here we have one two and three
4 so the first row is 1 2
the second row is 3 4
and and the dot
zero one
zero zero okay let's see if that
evaluates
to yeah so it
evaluates to zero one and zero three
okay but how do you format these two
okay so let's do copy
let's do the standard form
it doesn't change let's do the
traditional form there it is
yeah so in traditional form the matrix
is typically represented by a square
bracket
but however sometimes it's also
represented by
a parenthesis now i don't know why
mathematica use parentheses as default
yeah because i think the most common way
to represent matrix is with
square bracket so anyway we have matrix
so let's see uh okay so hold on a second
let's try to typeset this full
expression okay
so here you say is equals to
that and
okay that's actually
okay that's not what we want
nah yeah
anyway i uh that's not forget about that
so anyway so i have showed you know how
do you
type what's the syntax for these
renderings in mathematica you know in
fact you can select the whole notebook
and just press ctrl shift n to to
transform
uh everything to the mathematical
notation
or you can just select part of it for
example this squared
this y squared i can just select that
expression
and press ctrl shift n to make that part
uh rendered as a uh
you know math uh two-dimensional
way okay that's about mathematica
uh ufam language type setting
capabilities
and in fact you can do this you know for
example let's
let's do nested square root okay
square root x
let's say next
okay let's say next list
okay what's the syntax for nest list
function expression n okay so function
square root expression is x uh let's
repeat
four times okay enter so you get that
okay i was i was trying to show the
nested square root
but it actually uses uses this
fraction power uh which is equivalent
but i was trying to show the
anyway i i haven't used mathematica for
a while so i
right now i don't know how do you show
the nested
nested you know the radical symbol so
let's see
now i'm not doing this right
yeah i don't
okay
this is not what we want oh yeah we
forgot that
oh there it is there it is let's see
40 okay oh god this is gonna be
humongous
okay 40 is too big uh
you know i why is it taking so long
because the rendering
i think it's the rendering is taking so
long 40 nesting
nesting you a bit we are basically
nesting the function
square root of a number plus that number
it's taking too long control period to
cancel
wait wait uh what how do you cancel
evaluation oh it's period okay
old period to cancel so let's
just say nine okay so we got
huge yeah the rendering is taking the is
the most the biggest problem
so now is too big to to see what's the
structure let's say
three okay so if you just want the last
part you don't want the whatever
previous so
you use the nest instead of nested show
it
okay so let's say 9
okay so here you got this huge
expression
wow even nice it's really big okay so
that's the
you know so that's par that's the power
of mathematica
um typesetting capabilities
okay now imagine if you are going to do
this in tech or la tech
you know so if you are doing this in
tech one of the most idiotic things
all the nerds you know the unix
philosophy the unix people linux
you know the tech geekers uh
they they would you know they would get
excited about tech and la tech
which which is the worst design possible
you know
donald gruth went went the wrong way and
created that that's what
this worst design possible so in
mathematica you can
you can do this you know just just a few
lines you know and it's
so in math so one thing that's very
different from tech or la tech
of in mathematica is that in tekko latex
all the you know the syntax they are not
compute they are not computable computer
computable expressions
so when you do square root of two in
latex
i mean let's just say you want to do x
uh two
two squared okay two third power you
cannot
evaluate it so two third power is uh
you know two times two times two is
eight
but in tech the syntax only allows you
to
like render it it doesn't allows you to
do the actual computation which is which
is
a very bad design you know you since you
are using a computer you should be able
to
have you know have it evaluate and why
do you have to type you know
underscore you know how do you do square
root here
do we have a square root yes you know so
this is how you do square root
backslash square sq rt and blah blah
blah
you cannot actually evaluate it we you
know
but it should be able to since you are
using a computer
so in mathematica
you you don't have to you don't have the
syntax
to do the formatting
but instead you simply type the
expression
it format it by itself it renders it in
in the two-dimensional notation by
itself so that's the huge
difference between you know the tech or
latex
design uh compared to mathematic
mathematical
wolfram language design for typesetting
okay i think i talked enough today for
an hour and six minutes so i think
that's it for today
um and uh
you know i was going to do today i was
going to
do star talk show i was then continue i
was going to do
uh talk about the
the outline features of mathematica in
comparison to ogmod
but i think we'll do that uh
another time so thank you for watching
uh yeah so if you are wondering so what
is a
alternative a better system for
typesetting
uh yes of course mathematica but you
have to pay you know
student version 300 hobbyist version
three hundred dollars or a professional
version two thousand dollars
uh but if you want the free so
check out read my articles okay i give
you several alternatives
besides mathematica you can possibly
explore
the you know just you know my advice is
never ever use tech never ever use latex
stop propagating this crap
okay you know start being a tech geeker
because this from the point of view this
of design
this is the worst possible uh
system for the needs of
two-dimensional mathematical expressions
the worst possible system
and why is this system popular why is it
you know this is part of actually this
is part of tradition and convention
in physics or in mathematics you know
very common
why is it very popular because one the
most
fundamental reason is that it is free
you know it is free everyone wants free
stuff like free pizza
three when when a computer programming
language
or a protocol when it's free it
tends to wipe out everything that's
better designed
that's not free okay when when a better
design system is also free
then the lousy design free one will go
away
like tomorrow if mathematica open source
you know don't doesn't even need to be
open source if wufang language
becomes free and without any ties like
you can just use it to
wherever without ties to from research
then the tech and latex will
will just disappear overnight
okay by the way mathematica is free so
so you can just go to my website uh
okay so let me show you
so that's it for today so you can if you
want to
just play with mathematica uh it's
officially free
you can just go to my website download
language for free
there are several ways one is buy one
one way is buy a raspberry pi
uh forty dollars or you can download the
wolfram engine
or the wolfram script uh basically
essentially do everything mathematica
you know what i've shown today
uh actually i'm not sure they do type
setting
i don't know but anyway you can try them
okay i haven't i haven't uh
studied what what's the differences in
detail but anyway those are free
you can download today so you can play
with then
i would actually recommend you know
mathematica i bought it
i bought it in 1993 because i wanted to
be
i i wanted to be a great mathematician
and
and i wanted to have the best tools
okay thank you thank you guys
bye okay so
you know if you like my stuff donate buy
my uh emac
this tutorial or the you know i have
the quite a few tutorials
um
curry howard correspondence that's uh
fantastic so i'm
i'm trying to you know in the next few
years i
and now i'm trying to study for more
like i'm trying to study
uh proof's theories uh much more so i
want to
you know explore that so again so i have
my javascript in depth tutorial covers
everything you need to know javascript
and there's also python tutorial and
they are free on the web too so
but you can buy some of them
bye guys