good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh today is July
15th 2019 Monday 3 o clock
3:20 p.m. San Francisco time and today
we are going to talk about math mostly
mathematics forget about that I was late
for 20 for 20 minutes or something okay
so let's talk about math mathematics you
know some interesting things okay so
yeah yeah okay I'm going to show you
some interesting things about math a
spark Bach music close it
so so let me show you some of the I want
that you I'm waiting for people to come
on when you know one people one people
is here great fantastic yeah God just
close that by mistake one people is here
say hi we are going to today start
today's topic is math math stuff I'm
just going to talk about math stuff wait
why does this a offline what's going on
whole life okay
today's topic math okay so it's needs
begin talking about it math in
mathematics so let's go to my math blog
and let me show you let's see where do
we begin
okay let's just begin with that so so I
have this page you can go to this is a
collection of wonderful math software
free they are online and you can
sometimes are there for Windows some
some are for Mac and you know and you
know just you know you go to my math
blog like Sally math you'll find it so
this is math software this is my
collection of math software you know
correction of the of them that I started
to do this since 1997 so many of these
are great you know fantastic software
you can prop surfaces this is
differential geometry this is very
advanced and you know you have come to
these are code come to ISIL
I saw something surface anyway usually
it's called contour plot okay and then
you can differential geometry again
no so collection of math software and
great ones and this one is spectacular
you really should try curved space it
shows you it visually oh these are
visual geometry software visual meaning
it's fun you know you don't have to like
when you eat rice these software's some
of them are really advanced for example
this one this one is about ciphered
surface I don't I don't understand it
but it's it has to do with I think
topology and not theory cipher surfaces
so this for example this topic is very
advanced you know you have to it's kind
of graduate math but but most of these
software and this too is like graduate
graduate math this one is talking about
curved space like for manifold three
manifold yeah curved space things like
that anyway they you know that the cont
the math subject of some of these
software may be very advanced but
however the software is fun to use like
you don't have to like when you try this
you don't have to like oh I need to
learn some math no you can just play
with it this one is this one lets you
fly through space in a typical like
three dimensional space we live in we
perceive it as Ukrainian space so called
Ukrainian space it's like a flat flat 3d
space you know three dimensional space
flat but this software shows you three
dimensional space that are not flat so
what do you mean a space is not flat
it's it's that's that's the you know
very interesting thing about math so
that's why math is intriguing you see
when you have a line you know if you
have a line
or if you have a surface like that means
let me show you like for example I have
a paper here and that's surface you know
flat now if I can bend it or you know if
i hack I can have a growth you know like
this this is a surface you know like a
flag or tower you know they can paint in
you know they can be pinned but all
these surfaces are two-dimensional you
can see they are just you know
two-dimensional even though they can
paint but they are still two-dimensional
but you see okay two dimensional
surfaces there's something interesting
for example this piece of paper I can
bend it and I can let's say I can paint
it like into a row like a joint you know
a cigarette joint or part joint you see
now I becomes a cylinder I and now it
was a flat surface now it's a cylinder
now but if you imagine if you are aren't
crawling on the surface if you go
straight you will come back to where you
begin now that's an interesting thing
that's an interesting property you can
observe that on a piece of paper you
know two dimensional space you can
easily observe it because you have you
we are from a freedman three dimensional
space now you can you can see there is a
concept of flat versus curved when it's
curved you you you might have this very
interesting property where you go
straight you know in a direction but you
will end up you know coming back to
where you begin that's an interesting
property that does not happen when you
have a flat you know space to these
space so that's very interesting now if
you go in three dimensional there is
similar things happening because you see
we are infinite dimensional we cannot
see it like a you know meaning that we
cannot see the whole 3d minute
dimensional space but just like the flat
two dimensional space three dimensional
space can also be bent they can be they
can be bent in quite a few ways for
example one one over the way our
two-dimensional space spent is you know
for example you can bend it into a
cylinder another example is a sphere you
see a sphere is also a ball you know
it's also a to limit two-dimensional
space but it's curved
you know it's bent so that imagine if
you live on earth for example Earth you
go all the way straight you will
actually end up you know at the position
where you begin you see and in fact
doesn't matter what direction you go
doesn't matter you know East waist or
what direction you go if you keep going
straight you know straight and you will
end up at you know the place you begin
so that's an interesting thing about
that's a you know about a
two-dimensional space so this is a
example of curved two-dimensional space
and as we mentioned another example of
curved two-dimensional space is like a
you know a cylinder but now notice they
have different properties on both a
sphere or you know a cylinder you can go
straight and and arrive at where you
begin but however on a sphere you have
it's such that you can go in any
direction you will always come back at
where you begin but not so for the case
of cylinder on the cylinder there only
there is only one direction you know
like a boat you know one direction like
a straight line that way or that way
that you will you know if you go
straight you will come back to where you
begin so even though both you see both
of these curved two-dimensional space
has this special property where you can
actually go straight and come back to
where you began
but unless fear you have it's kind of
deep you you know this property applies
to any direction
so we have just explained you know a two
dimensional curved space you know and
some interesting properties that does
not happen with a flat 2d space now so
far we are all talking about
two-dimensional now so the interesting
thing is when you go into 3d even though
we cannot see it but if you do the math
you can easily see it that in 3d the
space can also be curved so that is to
say imagine you have a rocket you know
we should you know NASA should fly
rocket to space if you shoot a rocket
and the rocket goes straight you know
does not turn it just goes straight it
is conceivable you know it is you know
it may be the case that it keeps going
straight you will actually come back to
where you begin you know come back to
earth even though you are going straight
if the three dimensional space is a
curved space so exactly what you know
how does it curve you know that that's
that is the math you know that is how
you want to study that's you know you
study you study differential geometry
and topology you know these are the
relevant you know math branches you you
go study so so this application is
called curve space and there are many
different you know great software's for
geometry math so this one for example
this one it does face part very very
fantastic let me show you face plot most
of all these software are most most of
them are interactive so it's very fun to
use you see this is fantastic let me
show you so you move your mouse anywhere
then you can shrink you can see the
whole thing you see this this is a face
pot now I'm not sure exactly what is
face fraud you know but you can you can
you know if you know
if you know complex numbers you know
it's not difficult you know you can at
least you can understand what face prod
is this is face fraud you know you can
start to read Wikipedia so it's you know
all these are beautiful fantastic math
software I've collected and this one is
also interesting so many of them there
you got fractals you know so check it
out many great factor software so good
morning cat 42 44 44 not 42 so okay okay
I got three people watching so let me
read the comments cat 44 says have you
tried any of the factors software around
yeah of course three diamond or bulb up
offices factories yeah you know I've
been changing in fact I've been true a
bit I have been obsessively trying all
fractal software that exists out there
that you know that you know you can find
since 1990 since 1997 so that is why I
have this collection of software and a
you know so it this is been 20 years
since 20 years ago so 20 years things
come and go you know I so I start to
have this page in 1997 then and then
after 10 years have 20 years you can see
you can you can see you get old and you
can see the society changes you know
like some of the software author you
check some of them you know they're long
time outdated and you know in fact I
have another page old math software let
me show you okay so this page is a bunch
of software that's no longer there
you know the people people get old you
know it's 20 years people people get or
some of them you know maybe some of them
still update the software you know most
of them can for example this job are
written in Java they are dead all these
lots of them you know
so it's like 20 it's like history you
see the history of the software you know
so anyway this so factor software in
fact you know so I started to do this
you know 20 years ago in fact today you
know I haven't spent much time on you
know check out where you know because
today actually they are quite a lot I
think you know I don't have time to
maintain that go to into detail and keep
collecting you know what's the best
factor of software but I did that anyway
so so that's great great math software
so let me talk about some other math
stuff okay so math stuff and let's go
through math let's go to math blog
okay great math software a course in
universal algebra now universal algebra
is now this is this is very advanced
this is like a graduate
I don't know Universal jabrai but I'm
learning it so if you are interested you
know it's a textbook it's a free
textbook by these I think they are
professors you know so universal algebra
so what is universal algebra is
basically is you know it's like you have
a group theory being really really you
have abstract algebra you know algebra
theory in algebra theory you now you try
to study all this algebra you know
theory in back vector space all these in
a in one coherent setting so you you and
also you study them using kind of
equation instead of the using using
equation using operators instead of you
you try to eliminate things like there
exist
you know the
condition the axiom there exists an
element identity identity element such
and such that you know so huge you
remove such such axiom because when you
do programming those kind of thing like
there exist they are not computable they
are so anyway I don't know very much
about this I'm learning it so this is
universal algebra you study you know
ring grooves vectors you know these are
G break structures in a coherent context
so in a more generalized context and you
know if you are into category theory or
proof systems they are related related
so that's a textbook on universal
algebra so let's see the next topic yeah
let me show you three books that's very
interesting math books these three books
are fantastic for beginners
you know programmers if you are a
programmer so the one of them is graph
theory this one this is a great
fantastic most wonderful introduction to
graph theory you do not need any
prerequisite you know you don't need
calculus or anything you can you know
graph theory is very much applied math
especially for programming so I read
this in 1990s you know 1990 was
something 1995 or something and you can
buy on Amazon it's very cheap let's see
how much five dollars you know it used
you know this anyway five dollars six
not six dollars paperback you can also
learn graph theory from Wikipedia you
know Wikipedia is very rich you can
learn it but but sometimes you know but
if you are new if you are a beginner if
you don't any you know you don't have if
you don't have math background
and you try to read Wikipedia usually
you get confused because Wikipedia has
lots of things they have some of some of
them are you know graduate-level some of
them are research level but they are all
together and you know graph theory
article because they are you know they
are properly under the graph theory
title you know but then so that's you
know so books sometimes is very good for
that so this book I become highly
recommend graph theory you don't need
you know background and also this book
group groups and their graphs I
recommend just go to Sally math blog
you'll find it and the Edition I read is
this one this book is also very old 1964
originally so if you this edition you
buy on Amazon it's like ten ten dollars
yeah ten dollars used but there is a new
edition you know typically these newer
editions they don't do much okay so if
you can get it with a cheap Edition
that's totally fine the new edition is
like you know twenty-five dollars you
know and you know they don't they don't
add much actually they change the
writing style a little bit they you know
and you know usually it's marketing
stuff in fact if you want to study
calculus any calculus textbook from
1990s you know 20 years ago or 30 years
ago we are doing please you know
perfectly fine you know just you know go
to a used book store two dollars you
know get those 20 30 years ago calculus
textbook instead of otherwise today you
you go buy a math textbook calculus
textbook that's like $200 $300 yeah it's
it's extremely expensive and why is that
because it's almost like a scam and
corrosion
between you know the professor's you
know our age you know American education
system you know like this calculus
textbooks stupid you know
this one is $250
you know latest edition packing
you know 1991 you know they I wasn't
using what 1991 there's also this book
back then it's $90 and now it's $250 and
if you look at the content it actually
the math content do not change at all
they just add you know they they pump
out additions because to prevent people
from using old books you know using free
being people's you know they can resell
you know that the morning Danielle so
this article explains why textbooks are
expensive in it in a nutshell is that if
you say our textbook you write it once
you said after you said nobody will buy
it anymore because you know the books
are out there you know once student
graduate you know they throw it away
like they did you know they sell it back
to bookstores or bookstore so then
people can buy the old edition so you
don't make money anymore so these
publishers or authors they need to like
they need to like create a new edition
out of the blue so what do they do even
they even if there's no need to change
so what they do they try to change you
know change a little wording change the
exercise you know they do that
artificially just so that you have a new
edition then the professor will require
the new edition so that you know your
Edition you cannot you know use the old
edition from bookstore you know from you
know old bookstore so that is the way
they artificially control you know you
always have to buy the new edition and
for most people you don't know like oh
oh this is new edition that addition is
you know three years old oh I must get
this new edition you know you don't know
but actually the math content data
actually do not change
in the past thirty years or even longer
you know a speech you know for beginning
for beginning calculus at least so you
know when you buy math textbooks you
know you can you know remember you can
get the old copy so math textbooks so
I'm talking about group theory so this
is a great book on group theory group
theories is what is the most fundamental
math part of math so this is a thin book
you know spend a you know you I would
say if you really try to study in detail
you can finish this book in a week you
know two hours a day you know read it
you know in three days in four days then
you will know the real you know the hard
group theory which is which is
fundamental it's more even more
fundamental than graph theory okay graph
theory you see I'm about to digress you
see in when we talk about the math
curriculum you know what causes you know
what you know first of all what subject
what kind of branches are there in a
math that's one thing then what do
University teach you know what what
exactly what kind of math branches they
teach what they don't teach that's
another thing yes actually they are
something they don't actually teach but
you know it's for example logic they
usually don't teach that and groups
graph theory by the way also they don't
usually teach that if you are a math
major
yeah I'm digressing because that's a let
me just cover a little bit so anyway so
first of all they are you know what
branches of math are there you know
that's one thing you have algebra you
have geometry you have you have discrete
math then then the other thing is what
courses do colleges actually teach
that's another thing by the way the cook
the kind of subject they teach it comes
and go it's like a fashion in fat you
know
in in in this decade some topic is hot
in like today in programming for example
machine learning is hot everyone is like
machine learning every unit University
we are like oh we teach math machine
learning you know but then next decades
is something else you know so so so what
University teach is another thing we
gonna talk about that
so in general graph theory if you are a
math major also of course depend depends
on what what is your subject of study
what's your intended specialty for
example if you are a programmer computer
science student you will likely learn
graph theory in your undergraduate
degree now if you are a math major you
know you may not you know you you may
not have you know taken graph theory but
however here's what I want to say group
theory if you are a math major group
theories absolutely a must it's a it's
it's a must it's actually it's like the
first dish okay so so I'm trying to give
you a sense you know what what are the
difference is you know between you know
the different subject of math in terms
of what they teach in University for
undergraduate so the new angle Anglo he
says textbooks are expensive but open
source is free yeah yeah yes very very I
have also I have a collection of free
open source math textbooks so they you
know I talked about this in few months
ago in my video so you can you know oh
these are free I collect it and I
verified you know they are solid you
know they are quality material they are
almost you know every one of them is
written by professors either I have read
them mostly I have not read them but I
have verified you know the the professor
the content is solid so so you can check
out my
collection of math textbooks these are
free for example this is calculus you
know we I'm going to talk about these
like I'm going to next I'm going to talk
about what they teach in college so
anyway so this you know you have number
theory probability calculus linear
algebra V analysis complex analysis you
know in you know so let's go back to
some of the great books on math so I'm
top so graph theory good theory and this
one complex analysis this is also a
great book now let me go back so I have
three books here now this graph theory
book and this group in their graph they
are introduction to the subjects to the
graph theory and to group theory they
are and they are written such that for
non professional like for if you don't
know anything about math you don't know
calculus you don't know anything about
programming these two books are
fantastic they are good so they serve as
an introduction once you read them after
you read them you know they are thing
very thing you know after you read them
you can just go to Wikipedia and you can
you you have sense what to look for you
can you know you can actually go on and
actually obtain a PhD level you can well
you know undergraduate level of graph
theory or math or group theory by
reading Wikipedia and links from it
actually yeah it's possible today
because you know info is all a lie so
anyway this to book our introductory no
this this but however those two books
are not in depth I mean if you are for
example if you are I mean they are great
intro okay but they if you are in
Stanford University for example you are
taking half a year to study graph theory
then this book is not enough they can
serve as the first three
two months for example same thing with
this book first you know two months
cause course you know to two hours a
week they work but not for the fools you
know have a year but this book visual
complex analysis that's a full in depth
you know rather you know come to to
great extent you know course textbook
it's a full textbook complex analysis
and it does require you you have to know
calculus okay you you must know calculus
and you must know let's say some linear
linear algebra
well calculus is necessary at least so
this is a full text book I have it here
it's a fantastic book so tenuous a is a
question what is not a ripoff like cable
television for example what is not a
rebuff what do you mean what what is not
a revolve with respect to like anything
yeah so what is the context so anyway
this is a great book this requires you
know calculus you know you must know
calculus so anyway that's textbooks and
then let's talk about this so I have
some pretty mathematics pretty math
collection I have here so this you know
knighting Chinese knots and great theory
you know when you have weaving like that
they are they are extremely for example
this one you know this how do you call
this young or a sweater how do you like
if you have a sweater like this how do
you call that how do you guys call that
so you know but look at the patterns
they I mean they are extremely complex
and you know so they are like to in
order to have the I mean this pattern
it's like
a pattern within pattern for example the
on a hole you see you know they are like
braids you know like hair braids but
each one is actually also braided and
the question is how do you make these
how do you even begin to make this cable
night oh okay so that's called cable
night so this is you know like so to the
you know you guys math oriented people
nuts you know that
so this is just amazing and and
mathematicians have studied this though
and you know I've I've seen papers you
know III have papers actually a
mathematician I asked him to send me and
also look at these let's look at let's
have a look this you know the this you
can see this kind of thing it's very
common in China or Taiwan I don't know
if in USA it's in common and how do you
call this so you know look at this table
cross you know so this intricate
patterns you know it'd be something to
like you have to design it like you have
to think about how to design it then you
have to Knight it yes like you know is
it's like a human artifact it's it's
just amazing so you have these kind of
things you know this you know weaving
and great theory and you know and they
the you know in China Chinese has this
traditional
decorative thing called Chinese knots
you know that's interesting
oh and then you have this basket weaving
yeah this this is also so I it's you
know the proper word is weaker weaker
work weaker works yeah this they are
like made of your tongue like you see
them in chair they are you know these
things are very cool when in summer it's
very cool to sit down
this one is no good it doesn't look very
good but anyway because the desert
doesn't illustrate them the intricate
math patterns but let me show you some
of wait let me show you some of the
returns okay so let me see let me show
show you sorry the House of Flying
Daggers there okay there I have a photo
of a girl with this hat weaved hat and
yeah okay so this is not so great you
see the pattern you know they make this
hat and you have to weave it you know
bamboo overtime or whatever but this one
it doesn't seems is too regular but mo
you must have a hex hexagonal pattern to
it but there are many let's see if let's
see if we can find some beautiful ones
so how long have I been talking 35
minutes six people watching
hi guys say hi okay post comments
opinions just post it okay so these are
not good you see when you do kind of
searches like this the key thing is to
is the right word you want to find the
right word once you have the right word
you'll find what do you want so let's
see wi c ke r wicker walk let's say week
ahead okay we're getting close so we
have this one okay it's still irregular
though let's see i want to find one
that's very regular and
oh hey we got this beanie beans how do
you call this beanie yeah I think B
kneecaps that's not well anyway so you
see there's this intricate patterns
anyway that's not what I trying to find
but anyway let's go back to so yeah so
nineteen and patterns so these are you
know interesting and and wikipedia has
oughta go on that break theory then we
have projections you know these lamps
fascinating lamps beautiful projections
and you have this kind bottle opener you
know a made it she this girl this woman
path Sheba Bathsheba she makes this you
can buy it anyway so this page is about
interesting things so the the thing
interesting about this you know I
categorize them into the proper math
area they are studied under so these
kind of thing is you know not theory or
big theory or I don't know if there's a
term for weaving theory so and this you
know this this one-step spectacular this
hyperbolic geometry this length you can
see this lamp let me open you see so
someone 3d printed this thing you know
this this you know this this lamp you
can see it it's a it's actually it's
called hyperbolic surface hyperbolic
surface is such it's a manifold
hyperbolic space is such that in
I think any two lines will meet each
other in in in one way or multiple ways
I forgot you know then anyway so it's
actually more than that but anyway
hyperbolic geometry you know it's so you
have us you know this is this this this
you know so we call them models of
hyperbolic geometry you know it says
this one is a hyperbolic surface and
it's such that you know it's it's the
very flamboyant you know it's like wavy
it grows and in case it gets more wavy
and more wavy as it grows you know so so
it's a model of hyperbolic geometry you
know you study these kind of things when
you study have a hyperbolic geometry
then then these are projections they are
you know we studied I mean on the
projective geometry bent but then you
have this Steve EO graphic projection
there's a video it's very good by this
guy Henry Richmond
Harry's settlement
so he made this video model it's it's
fantastic it's a stereographic
projection so Steve your graphic
projection is you know when you shine a
light on top of a sphere and project
whatever patterns to from the sphere to
a plane this is called stereographic
projection and you know just like this
and it's a model you know and you know
in math this boy this fear is called
Riemann sphere and it's actually it's a
model for for the complex plane so the
whole thing you know the math of this
subject is complex analysis so that's
what what this is about complex analysis
which is you know that book was about we
showed before and you know that about
you have this Klein bottle it's under
topology then you have these tiling and
timings and patterns and then you have
this roller coaster which I classified
under calculus you know this is most
typical of calculus you know you you
want to study the the speed you know the
pot you know the inertia that you know
kinetic energy and it's like that when
you build a roller coaster you know if
you make if you make you know then you
have to do derivatives and integration
so what happens if you made a mistake in
derivative
the consequence is death you know so
calculus roller coaster you know then
linguistic from linguistic point of view
its roller coaster it's interesting
because you know today's how this works
is that you just you know you you pull a
bunch of seeds you know hi then you just
drop you know you just drop it and let
it guide you
red coast so that's called rollercoaster
but in modern modern was you don't you
don't you don't coast they have they are
driven you know they are powered you are
driven into sinuous Ness so that's a
roller coaster you know that's calculus
so why so you know then you have this
you know water curtain this is a photo
of a fountain you know so I think he's a
mathematician mathematician he took a
photo and he actually analyzed why this
pattern happens you know if you go to
his Twitter he he kind of he does some
explanation on why it happens it takes a
while to load so anyway so yeah so you
can see you know so and this I
categorize it into chaos theory you know
so this is actually chaos theory you
know this there are many ways to
categorize this photo you know like you
can put it into you know you can put it
into cellular automata or you can put it
into dynamical systems so what is they
are they are kind of all related
dynamical let me explain what is
dynamical systems dynamical systems you
know you can search Wikipedia so
dynamical systems is a branch of math
what so what is what is it about it's a
when you have a function you know of one
variable you you know you're putting
your number and another number comes out
then you take that output feed it back
to the function you know and another
number come out and you repeat you know
you do a recursion so in programming
this is called recursion in math they
don't call it recursion this is this is
called iteration okay so you have a
function you know you you're putting a
number a number comes out and you take
that number
and feed it back to the function so by
this process
you got a sequence of numbers this whole
it's called iteration in math in
programming we call recursion so in this
iteration you got a bunch of numbers
then what you want to study is that you
want to study the the properties of this
sequence you know how for example if you
recurse a function what will happen for
example let's say the function takes a
point as input a point in the plane you
know then it comes out so another point
somewhere else in the plane so you if
you plot the sequence what will happen
you know where they like repeat with it
will they become a loop or where we are
they you know like behave you know how
the point you know where does the point
move to so that so this study is called
dynamical systems basically you study
the iteration or recursion of a function
now when you study this you'll find many
interesting phenomena like you will find
sometimes a function will behave in a
strange way then that then when you
focus on that particular property that
is called chaos theory you know that
that is what chaos the chaos theory is
about because when you study you know
function iteration because if you know
function you will find you know there
are certain you know interesting
behaviors that that's that's you know
that's that's the beginning of chaos
theory so this thing you can consider
the whole thing as dynamical systems
where you know essentially from in terms
of physics you know in these molecules
they you know they have forces they have
you know surface tension they have you
know good you know grandfa odd you know
I don't know physics you know but do you
have the intrinsic force between
molecule but anyway but eventually you
get you know so
essentially what pattern you know like
when you have water drafts on window
sometimes you know which drop will merge
with other drops it's unpredictable
typically that this process are
unpredictable so you know that's part of
the interesting thing mathematicians
want to study so you know there's this
chaos theory then you have polyhedrons
look at this one this one is a fun one
somehow I made this then you have
factors this one is also a beautiful one
you know where you can you can cut paper
and make this pattern factor pattern
anyway these this one is for my airport
where you have these beautiful
octahedron structure let's see yeah so
let me read the comments so group theory
is fascinating linear algebra is
fascinating come to think of it
calculus is quite fascinating I think
the way it is taught is maybe shameful
boring
yeah that is true you know like when you
read math actually in general when you
read this is true for a lot of things
when you read like for example I read
math you know I look at a lot of lots of
math textbooks or sometimes you know
even on textbooks math books and all I
read online
many of these math topics they will say
oh group theory is one of the most
important in math then you read calculus
then you'll say oh it's the most
important in math then you read you know
then you read complex analysis you'll
say oh this is the most important in
math like when you don't know the
subject matter like when you are
beginner you know you you try to read
what they are on Wikipedia you tend to
see you tend to see that it's almost
like every subject they will say this is
the most important or sometimes you say
this is the most
elegant math you know good theory or
graph theory or actually for complex
analysis and group theory sometimes you
see that or you know this is the most
beautiful math but the point is like you
know if you don't know the subject you
tend to like every almost like every
subject is the most important but just
exactly which is most important you
don't know similarly by the way this
applied to movie applies to movies as
well like if you look at movies so
they'll say oh this movie is the first
to one
you know this award you know this is the
first to feature you know something
something you know it's like then
another movie this is the one of the
greatest movie because it's this or that
you know after you read a few you you
get confused it's like every movie so
firstly so that you know so just
interacting which one is actually great
one way to find out is actually to have
a rank you know is you know instead of
you know this is the first this or that
because everything can be first like I'm
sorry the first two you know this is the
first person to be named Sally you know
the first doesn't matter anymore like
everything is first everything is the
first of something so instead you want a
ranking now so if you if a movie says
this movie is is considered to be you
know the top ten in in a decade then you
know you know you have some sense how
important or how great it is in your
seemingly similar way math you know when
they say this is important you have you
know my group theory is very important
complex analysis is very important graph
theory is very important they are all
like fundamental but but then if you say
okay if you say if you have a rank or
like like between comparatively speaking
which of these is you know more
important then you know goofed
I can tell for example group theory is
more important complex analysis in graph
theory they are like the gap like they
are secondary depend like ok then
between complex analysis and between
graph theory which one is more
fundamental that depends
like like that depends on what's your
you know what's your feel what's what's
your concern what's your study for
example if your let's say if you are a
fittest then complex analysis is
absolutely more fundamental than graph
theory but if you are a computer
programmer if you are you know a
programmer graph here is far far more
important you know you don't you don't
do anything with complex analysis you
see so that's how you know but however
but if you have a math major in general
you know if you intend to be a
mathematician good theories is the more
fundamental then complex analysis is
more fundamental because graph theory
they are they are not the main dish of
math anyway so let's move on to the
other subject so let's look at you know
just exactly what math major study in a
university so here I have a you know the
courses I tried to you know verify so
what university actually teach for a
undergraduate math so I actually went to
Stanford University website so you know
I get a list so anyway so let's see what
ok so I get at least you know so so you
can check out you know the least
you know you can check out but basically
I can tell you I can tell you what it is
so if you have a magnet well first of
all depends on what major you are if you
are a physics major if you are
engineering major if you are chemistry
you don't take you know your math the
math you are required to take is
typically calculus and multivariable
calculus now if you are a computer
science major then you know you also
typically need you know basic calculus
and maybe graph theory and linear
algebra okay anyway but if you are a
math major you know you are a true math
major you intend to focus on math
typically so you know University
typically four years the first year you
need to take calculus you know basically
introduction to calculus everything and
yeah that's almost enough for you
calculus and maybe some statistics okay
in the second year you might you know
and you know calculus and multivariable
calculus you know basically calculus
with multiple variables including this
you know calculus subdivide - you know
differential calculus integral calculus
then you know analytic geometry and
multivariable calculus
that's a thing and before that you take
precalculus and intro to analytic
geometry and trigonometry you know
that's kind of like high school
so first year of college you know
calculus in multivariable calculus
second year is usually introduction to
linear algebra and introduct
introduction to differential equations
and yeah linear algebra differential
equations and maybe statistics you know
like different
University they you know the cost varies
they vary very spa basically that's it
the third year for a math major that's
usually the beginning of real math major
so the third year is typically the most
the two most important are abstract
algebra and analysis okay that's a two
thing two main thing abstract algebra
which includes group Theory field theory
being theory you know a combination
thereof you know that's abstract algebra
that is the the most important abstract
algebra for a math major in third year
in third year of University study and
equal to that equal importance to that
is is what's called an error analysis
analysis is basically calculus but in a
math in a mathematicians way so so you
have you know abstract algebra and
analysis this is the third year study
for math major now for the fourth year
fourth year of math major study it can
be you know quite a few things usually
okay you can take graph theory graph
theory you can take in third year you
know it's in in the independent you can
take you know it's actually you can take
you can study a first year of University
so like I said before they are not you
know the main thing in math for math
major so for example there's also
combinatorics now combinatoric square
theory group theory they are all kind of
related but they are all independent
they they belong to discrete math they
are not the main dish of math majors
mathematicians you know they are like
you know you computer scientist go study
that they are not they are not
considered usually you know they are in
a sense they are treated treated
you know like you know that will not be
a mess you know like computer science
you know they are actually I mean they
are we your math but they are not the
main thing of for mathematicians so so
in the fourth year you study you know
differential geometry topology analysis
on manifolds that's like differential
geometry yeah that's basically
differential geometry and differential
topology algebraic topology which is
basically algebra more advanced
elementary of theory of numbers now okay
theory of numbers again that's not
that's not the main dish kind of anyway
so you have set numbers yeah I mean
there are many so many ways and
economics mechanics they are not you
know main dish of math and light and
heat and fear your probability again
probably the probability is not main
dish the main dish is about analysis in
algebra and anything that sub-branch out
of it
analysis algebra topology that is that
are the main things of for
mathematicians then you know sub branch
they have you know differential
differential geometry differential
algebra algebraic topology not what
differential geometry there's no such
thing as differential algebra I don't
think maybe there is you know anyway
differential geometry for analysis
differential topology algebraic topology
you know you know things like that
that's you know that's basically if
fourth year of graduate course courses
so that's kind of introduction that's
kind of introduction to math courses so
I think that's it for today that's
that's what I'm gonna talk about
yeah some interesting math topics what
do you study so any comments questions
opinions I'm kind of tired and I'm going
to go to sleep
any comments shown Danielle
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching hope to see you next time
bye
I