hello everyone so today I'm going to try
to do wink off I'm trying to I'm still
expert experimenting with my video
making so you know I'm gonna try
different video styles and stuff okay so
this this is my Linux tutorial let's do
a box I'm gonna talk less today and just
do topic edge okay get rid of that rid
of that this is me okay
that's good
job control put it there so this box
needs to be looked and removed if
there's a duplicate remove it if it's
one of the link is not appropriate not
duplicate I have to think about whether
to remove or not but let's just leave it
there
so open and go to the button it's such
okay search for that then paste that's
good
okay so let's Rico let's try out let's
record Marco
okay show you start Marco hoping such
bottom six five nine zero zero okay
go here hey paste yeah yeah let's try
again
Scott recording hoping and spot them go
to the beginning such at bottom yeah
it's ads we call tomorrow go open the
file go to the beginning such ads bottom
okay go to the beginning of the line and
paste that's good
close it save go down
stop macro so I have the mark already
now dread macro again okay run run run
run run run okay
so let's see they said mean bottom
that's good PS go to the bottom top go
to the bottom edge top ramstad using
groups alpha mission it's good open file
how sof shadow and steep so that's all
then so what I'm doing is just adding
these navigation box to every page so I
need to do that for Bastion terminal as
well it's it's look at them batch
terminal topic
okay actually this already one okay
let's stop that let's change something
let's go to let's go to do a themed golf
you know I think I I think I claim
Sophocles is the most efficient
keybinding so let's try something called
open being of challenges remember lines
containing a word header easy stuff okay
let's just try that one it's increased
the found picture okay start file
go buy a new file paste that save it
today's date so it's not file in file so
you're gonna end like this copy so what
is the situation start file and file
like this line this line is the same and
this time it's the same water so it
just deletes this deletes I just basis
basically delete a few lines
this is kind of silly copy new buffer so
we want to keep this line let's make
sure we want to keep that line and the
second line and the sixth line
okay so assume that cuz I say the top
the second line and the sixth night did
the TV that's it it's only that's just
TV guys what's the deal solutions the
best way to learn through is to practice
below you will find some of the
solutions so that other golfers have
entered to unlock higher ranked
solutions submit your own entry which
does as well or better than the solution
you can currently see climb the ladder
and lock it's annoying you know they so
now they start to lock the solutions you
cannot see it unless you submit your own
this greedy website state all the
websites become greedy every day even
the open source beam golf stuff kind of
open-source community but basically I
just want to see am i doing the solution
or not so this solution number eighty
anak 81-82 she global find replace Vita
he pressed by and save okay replaced by
T TV lines return
lowest score wins so look lowest score
means the least number of keystrokes I
suppose so leaderboard so nine
keystrokes okay I can't I can't quite
get the problem it just read a few lines
one two three four five six seven eight
I need eight strokes oh eight okay then
I need to save the file does that if I
save the file then it's it's yeah if I
save the file its Nike strokes
now this guy's go is 17 keystrokes and
that's not good I don't want to script
aloud
I don't want to submit my solutions I
don't I don't you know these websites
you know for most people for average
normal people you know it doesn't matter
it's fine
you know it don't be paranoid but these
web side want to it's you know it
because it's you know intentionally
using these psychology gaming tactics to
get you to use their website I mean I'm
surprised that wim HOF web site would do
it because we think of web site is you
know typically the open source community
these people well I mean I cannot hit
community as well these people generally
you know are very anti commercialism and
stuff but anyway the first the first
such website using the gaming tactics is
Stack Overflow anyway so okay that's it
that's it for today
you know you know well I should try
another game think of this this is just
TD lines easy stuff make it look better
okay simple practical common let's start
let's do it next day
by