hello hello hello good morning good
morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound talk show we are going
to code wolam language
today uh wolam language uh coding some
geometry if you are here say hi love to
see your comments keep them coming if
you are not here play at 1.5 speed and
Skip around okay because I ramble uh so
we so I'm going to Let's double check
I'm live yes video check audio
check okay so I'm yeah so uh start wolam
language coding and uh show today's talk
show page you know there's a nasty thing
with uh YouTube with the Google Chrome
browser and uh Firefox browser so for
example you go to one of my YouTube page
it's say um let's say this one you know
yesterday so we did yesterday or two
days ago so you see I have a link to my
website but if you click on that link
that's HTTP not https if you click on
that link Firefox will say security
connection
failed so because it automatically
change your link to
https even if you have the
settings of that turned off so for
example let's go to settings and uh then
um let's go to privacy and
security and you can
see aut field history permissions
Firefox data collection no no no website
ad uh website advertising preference no
security there it is HTTP on only https
only mod so click do not enable however
neveress nevertheless it still do
it uh this began about a week ago so
even if you do not enable the
automatically change to
https it does it
anyway so that
means you know the billions and billions
like more literally a billion websites
more than a billion websites now they
will become
inaccessible because for average people
they have no idea what is this you know
HTTP versus https protocol so they will
just see this errow so effect
effectively this is a massive massive
scale
censorship uh and this so this happens
in Firefox browser and it also happens
in Google Chrome
browser uh you know Google
Chrome so for example you go to
YouTube and
uh uh go to YouTube go to casadi search
for casadi
emx and uh you know click on one of my
old uh okay so let's say the most
efficient emac workflow
start playing and there's a link to my
website can you
see
uh let me set so you can see there's a
link to my
website there click it Google will say
error so this is a very nasty censorship
so what you have to do instead whenever
you want to visit the website that's not
https you have to type it manually so
for
example you know so Google automatically
Chang that to https so instead you want
just HTTP so copy that back to Google
Chrome browser new tab paste that just
HTTP then it'll
work uh you see so massive scale
censorship pretty bad Google started to
do this about 10 years ago uh so let
me you know I have a document of that so
you go to cali. info and let's say why
https why no
https so I have a documentation of the
fact you know in the beginning like 10
years ago it started mild Google will
say oh we are helping security we are
helping
uh you know for security of the website
so uh we recommend everyone upgrade to
https which is
encrypted uh then they say then after a
year or two they say oh uh now if your
website is not
https then it will not rank rank high
you know they started to uh remove
basically massive censorship and also
magically at the same time there pops up
this um encrypt let's enpt organization
so that gives you allows you to have
https free you know
magically magically someone organization
create this offer you free so that makes
this Google move move easier to accept
you know so how is it possible that
someone just you know create this
organization and give it things for free
usually you know if you are organization
that creates H https the
certificate you know you you make a lot
money so but magically you you got this
let's equipped free
so but then after a few years Google
only like you know so their ranking only
shows https website
then you know now today both Firefox and
Google Chrome they stop they stop you
from Reading any HTTP website you see
why is this censorship this is massive
censorship you know it's it's kind of a
trick you know uh
because the
https is for encrypted traffic that
means if you go to website the SE as
Amazon or any shopping website you have
to give your credit card when you want
to buy things that traffic that needs to
be encrypted so that is why that that is
called secure you know if you are giving
out uh personal information such as your
bank or credit card number but vast
majority of website are not that you
know like my website you know people
don't need to uh have
password encrypted when they you know
like most website don't even have
password you know they you just want to
read about what your friend did last
week what your mom you know or watch a
video of your mom's birthday or see
what's your friend's opinion on
something or some any other thing so
vast majority of
websites the vast majority like billions
and billions they are not https
encrypted why because that is a standard
that's a normal way you know if you want
https you have to kind of you have to
pay for this certificate and you have to
install it and it's it can get very
technical you know because I was you
know as a Prof professional uh coder for
the one of the earliest e-commerce
website back in year 1998 1999 web
order.com we create e-commerce engine
then we sell it to like giant we sell it
to
um to that um phone com Verizon you know
like then then they they run this
e-commerce engine then the merchants can
go there and sign up so basically you
create we we we are creating the Amazon
like the engine then Merchants can go
there upload their you know items they
want to sell and uh you know in inv
inventory and things like that then
users Shoppers can go to the site and
buy stuff from this you
know uh millions or you know hundreds of
thousands of merchants so that's a
e-commerce website so if you are
actually doing you know like Bank
transactions credit cards then you need
of course you need https and back then I
was the you know I was responsible for
creating for in soing https with the
certificate you know back in so this is
1999 so back then it's even more
difficult you know you have to create
you have to buy the certificate from the
certificate
organization uh I think it was like4 $50
uh Year back then I I don't remember
exactly yeah and and you have to update
so one of the common problem is that you
go to a website and it says the
certificate expired you know so anyway
this is not a trivial thing to do this
is fairly involved and also the
certificate organizations they are
there's a lot of you know uh scams among
these players because they can how do
you know they can you know how do you
know they are not creating fake
certificates you don't know unless you
are the like uh professional in that uh
field and in fact there is you know for
example the uben 2 Linux the guy who
created u 2 Linux uh a black guy from
Africa he was doing the cert he he was
in the certificate business
um and and and many other uh
corporations and they there are several
scams over the past decades about how
they cheat or you know things like that
so anyway certificate is when you get
things becomes very uh complicated and
uh
critical okay because this involves
encryption which drags in the
entire huge government uh you know
around the world because you know it's
critical information so anyway so Google
started to you know so today back to the
topic today Google and uh um Google
Chrome browser and Firefox browser both
both um basically sensor
websites okay that's about that
digression hello I don't know hello
mhv
uh okay so yeah you can get free self
signed you know yeah that like let's
encrypt that's what I'm talking about
but what I'm saying is that this is a
movement of massive censorship because
now if you only allow https websites
that means the control the information
you know internet is supposed to be free
information but now if you always
require https that means the
internet for the you know 8 billion or
so people people on earth now they are
controlled by a few certificate
organizations you know so that's a key
Point okay so that's that's about that
uh let's um and uh yeah so it becomes
more and more serious today you can you
know like vast majority of websites they
are not
https the the point is that you should
not require
it you know because most of websites are
not shopping websites you don't need to
type your credit cards or login at all
you just want to read some in you know
some whatever jokes memes or
whatever okay that's about that let's go
to so today I'm just coding wam language
let's go to what I need to do okay let's
so let let's start
um
uh let's
[Music]
see let's open this
notebook so
is so mostly this is my wolam coding
wolam language coding session I need to
do things um that I need to do okay so
if you have any questions about wolam
language or stuff ask
me yeah so this you know so I don't know
I'm not sure what to do about that you
know
I'm I don't really want to upgrade my
website you know I have to look into
because when you if you upgrade if you
follow their rule you know you do what
they
say
then it's not very good okay I mean so I
mean I could you know I could say oh
okay Google and Google Chrome so by the
way so if this happen to you know in
Firefox you click on that link you gives
uh gives you get an error
so you can use Brave browser which I
recommend very much okay Brave like you
are very brave brave browser bra browser
don't have this problem for for example
let me show
you so for example let's copy this
connection failed actually I have it
document documented
here uh
there Firefox Force
https beginning this month
okay uh yeah so let's do the screenshot
of the connection
failed okay but if you do this in Brave
browser no problem Al so let's let me
let me show you so paste the link go to
YouTube so that's one of my YouTube
start
playing click on the link
here click you see it goes to my website
no problem so this this error is just a
very scum you know practice like scale
tactics like most people have no idea
about this technology so just say secure
connection failed an error or something
something and if you click on learn more
then it's just a bunch of
incomprehensible thing you know secure
connection failed they're going to
mention technical jargons you know they
they what they can do you know you can
you can you can observe people's
behavior and make a judgment by by just
simply looking at people's behavior so
for example some people will say
uh this is not you know they are
actually good intentions why why do you
claim they are bad you know look look at
what they
say they could simply say the website
you know on in your
browser the website is not secure
meaning that if you type any personal
information such as bank or credit card
then those information could be uh
viewed by hackers okay they could simply
say that so if you are seeing this error
if you if the website is not uh
requiring your credit card or login
website you just want to read what my
friend is eating for dinner whatever
then you just you know you can just you
know uh use https like in this aror page
they could say uh go ahead and and you
know
it could simply say this you know the
website you are trying to go to is uh
does not require credit card or things
like that so if you don't type your
credit card then you can just click the
link and go there they can do that but
they do did not do that and also then
you look at the their error page like
for more learn
more then you know they say this very
complicated and you know very
complicated technical detail like this
this like you you can if you are if you
know what this is you know the
certificate https like
me it's very simple you know then but
but you see the this error message they
go into table of contents secure
connection cannot be established then
subsection secure connection failed and
did not connect potential security
issues then website issues TLS version
unsupported hsts required you know this
this is a
intentional fuse
station they want to scare you not
average people you know they have no
idea what what is this era they want to
scale you they just want to tell you the
website you are trying to go is no
good okay so these are scums you know
and
Firefox this old news you know Firefox
they donate to antifa they have like
millions or 100 millions of dollars that
goes to mysterious organizations you
have no idea what who they are you know
they're supposed to be open source you
know they say we are open source we are
most trusted but
actually there hundreds of millions or
something like tens of millions dollars
going somewhere you don't know you know
so so the so today since the past 10
years it becomes very extremely
corrupted and and and also by the way
Google is the I believe Google is the
main main uh fund funer don't you know
to
Firefox why Google do that because you
might think oh Google is so nice Google
is a very a great person the CEO uh of
Google is a Indian guy you know but
actually because Google doing that
because
Google um
well so Google can you know escape the
um Monopoly
Monopoly accusation you know so Google
kind of funds Firefox anyway they are
all very deeply deeply corrup
corrupt okay so let's go back to so
that's about that
um okay close that close that
close that okay so let's let's go back
to coding wolam
language uh close
that okay so let's see closet showing
browser okay so we want to code so let's
look at Parabola okay let's see what
um okay let's do these two let's update
these two images these are old actually
I I think I should replace them
by something
else uh okay let's just copy
them
cette
cette uh
so wol language let's paste it
here and uh let's see the code
so we got some code here okay let's copy
that
copy and uh let's go to talk show let's
open let's create a
new block of code for Wam language paste
it now pop it out to K Wan mod so this
this definition is is returning a unit
Vector uh so this is 30 years old code
but unit Vector wam language now has a
building function for unit Vector so I
can show you what this does for
example uh so for example unit Vector so
let's let's try to call it unit
Vector unit Vector let's
say uh
one and one so Vector at you know one at
one and
one uh x and y coordinate so the unit
Vector is going to be like a circle of
you know it's like uh it's going to be 2
* square otk of
two so anyway let let me show you okay
so if I evaluate this region let's run
it
there it is you see so that is the unit
Vector of one and
one so unit Vector means a vector of the
same direction but however has a length
of one okay and the formula is just just
that you know each compon component
divided by the square root of the sum of
the squares okay something like that you
know this this this syntax is very
powerful so that actually means uh let
me let me try to
explain
youit Vector okay in fact you can just
actually you can just read Wikipedia
okay but let me just explain it so if
you have if you have a vector X and
Y the unic vector means
a vector of the same direction a unit
Vector of a
vector v means a vector of the same
direction as V but has length of one
okay that's what the the meaning the
definition of unit Vector so how do you
compute it
so if the vector is comp uh coordinates
is X and Y let's say A and B
okay then
the
unit Vector is uh uh is
is a ided by a divided
by square root
of a s
+ b
squared okay and uh also
similarly for
B okay that is the formula for the unit
Vector for two-dimensional unit Vector
if the if the vector has three
components three dimensional unit vector
or fourth dimension or whatever it's
exactly the same formula okay so you
divide each one by their uh length so
so so that so if you have the vector if
if that Vector is AB b c then this part
is square root of a squ + b s + C
S so a
short abbreviation for this part you can
you know it's just V Dov so V Dov is a
DOT product dot product okay so this
definition is a very condensed way
to express the formula of a unit Vector
of any Dimension you know it can be 2
three 4 or 10 or
20 so that's the power of wolam language
okay so um let let's do this again
so let's run
it okay that's a
result okay that's about unit Vector now
but in wolam language so this is 30
years old but now in wam language there
is a buildin function for unit Vector so
that is called uh they don't call it
unit Vector because the the normal the
traditional math name would be
normalized gome okay so I think no so
question mark uh
what question mark
gome okay Enter gnome
gives the norm of a number vector or
Matrix so for
example so let's say Norm okay now
evaluated uh no okay so that gives the
length so that gives the length uh so I
want to so the you so the univ vector
would be uh normalized I
think yeah nor is the length or the
absolute
value so this subject are about linear
algebra very interesting uh the abstract
version of it it would be called a
vector space so you're dealing with a
vector space nored Vector space
okay a normed vector space means a
vector space that has a uh length
defined mind
basically but you should always just
check W check Wikipedia okay check w
wikipedia because so you can see the
formula right there so anyway normalize
gives the normalized form of the vector
v that's right so you know instead of
Nome it should be let's copy let's do it
normalize okay normalize the
vector computer
it there it is okay so you see identical
to my own custom definition so if we do
this in wam language we can do it you
see uh and the nor is just the length of
the vector so do it you
see so that's norm and normalize so so
you know my old code uses unit V now
let's replace all unit V by normalize
okay do
it replace it
by okay so do it and do it
here okay so this is my code so I'm
trying to update this code you
see okay so I need to look into actually
so uh so the code is actually doing
negative pedal
okay oh God so here is the inline
definition any comments and
questions if you have a wolam language
question ask ask me okay or about uh
linear
algebra okay so so you see what I'm I
want to do is this Parabola page at the
top there is two Gallery about the
parabola so they are showing the
negative
pedal negative pedals of the parabola so
all these black lines are the negative
pedals uh what does negative pedal means
neg negative pedal means
um uh so you got positive pedal then you
got um
yeah so given a curve and the fixed
Point O draw a line from o to any point
p on the curve then draw a line
perpendicular to line op and passing
P okay then repeat the step two and
three for every Point p on the curve the
envelope of the lines is a negative P
Okay so
I um do you guys do you guys know what
I'm talking about uh I can demo a you
know using a interactive Graphics uh do
I have it here
somewhere uh no I don't have a
pedal interactive
Graphics um anyway I want to code this
okay so
anyway so basically given a curve and
given point so whenever there
is you know for any point p on the curve
there's a tangent line then the line
perpendicular to the tangent at that
point is called the
normal
so so the pedo is um
wait that's not you know anyway I I'm
not like in a mood to
um to talk about this now let me just
focus I'm I'm kind of
um going all over I want to focus on
updating this code okay
so yeah okay so this gets complicated
then you know I have have to explain
each one of these then it's going to
take an
hour
um so let's not explain you know then
then there's also this
um this is very old code they have
updated it so you don't do this
anymore yeah so updating this code would
be quite involved because then I have to
explain ped then I have to
explain you know each one of these
construct
uh okay so but let's not explain let's
just make it run let's see if it runs
okay let's try let's
not explain anything let's just try to
run the code to see if it runs okay so
okay let's do that shift enter run the
code okay it run and make this type set
shift control
n so now it's easier kind of easier to
read now just plot it
shift uh okay hold on a second you need
to remove the semicolon otherwise the
graphics won't show okay now
shift enter there it is so the
code still
Works uh beautiful and now let's make
this control shift n to typ set it and
now let's try this one control shift n
and remove the semicolon at the
end and shift enter to run it beautiful
so you see they are drawing these black
lines they are the negative pedo of the
curve NE ped is with respect to a point
so you can change the uh ped point to
something else so this part I believe so
let's see the documentation negative
ped
uh yeah so you see this this is
not anyway
so uh
draws the negative ped of lines of the
parametric curve XF YF at points XF
YF uh at what points
okay oh okay so with respect to that so
the third argument is the pedo okay so
the third argument there so this curve
this picture is with respect to this
blue dot now let's change that
so for example change that okay let's do
it
here shift enter okay that's that now
this one let's say
02 shift
enter okay you got a bigger hole so
let's if we change this to 03 shift
enter yeah the hole gets bigger now
let's say at 0 0 do
it now you got a different thing and Ne
negative Infinity encountered so there's
something in the code I need to fix now
but if you say 0 negative
1 you got intire you you got this
interesting uh thing okay now let's
remove the plot
range so
that oh very interesting okay now let's
put back the plot
range contrl Z to
undo
uh control Z to undo yeah so plot range
X from stive 7 to 7 let's say let's say
-1 2 1 * 10 and uh the Y AIS will be uh
let's say -9
to 30
shift
enter
fantastic so adjust the plot range -9
to uh
20 shift
enter
beautiful okay and the parabola you see
we need to extend the parabola so let's
say from negative 10 to 10 okay shift
enter
now it's beautiful
complete so this is about negative pedo
so but I need to explain negative pedo
okay
so
um okay so let let me explain negative
ped
okay so make a screenshot of that whole
thing and uh open this
in um open is Snip and sketch okay so
negative pedo let's let me just explain
that actually
um actually just let me just do it
here so actually that's pedo the
negative pedo is this
okay and open that in snip and
sketch okay so given a
curve let's say given a curve and a
fixed Point O So this point O Okay then
draw a line from o to any point p on the
curve so okay so let's say there is p
draw a line from o to P okay so it's
going to
be like that okay we got a
line then draw a line perpendicular to
line op and passing P okay so a
perpendicular passing P to that would be
this line
okay now repeat the previous two steps
for other point points p on the curve
okay so let's say uh let's say let's
say
P2 so draw a line from O2 P would be
like that and a line perpendicular to
that passing P would
[Music]
be like that okay now do this again for
another one another point on the curve
let's say p three so first of all draw a
line all to P3 then draw a line
perpendicular to P3 so that would be
something like
that okay so for every point for each
point p on the curve you got this you
know so let's change color let's see you
know you got
this you know okay you know you got this
this
line and for P2 you got this line and
for P3 you
got this line okay that's a p do lines
with respect to these three points now
you just have to do this for every point
on the curve basically infinite number
of points okay now when you do that you
start to see this uh you start to
see this
this you know this so-called envelope
they form a curve you see so that for
this one the curve is the red one it's a
parabola and the blue point is the the P
point the O and then you follow these
steps then you got these black lines and
you can see they kind of form a curve
here and form a curve there form a shape
okay and this one if you put a point
here
they form this curve okay and for this
one they you know so that is the P Point
that's I mean that's the PED curve so if
you put put the point in the middle you
got this fish tail or tear drop kind of
new shape okay so the negative pedo this
is called negative pedo okay so
this is a way is is kind of a way to
generate at a new curve based on a
existing given curve the red one here
and a given point
okay um what is the use what is the
properties I mean what is so what what
you know one common question what is the
use of
the uh the pedo I don't I don't know
actually the idea of positive and
negative ped curves occurred first to
colen
mcloren uh a famous mathematician for
the mlen series in calculus so in
1718 the name pedo is due to turum the
theory of costic Curves includes pedos
in an important role the oromic is an
enlargement of the PED of the reflecting
curve with respect to the point source
of light okay
yeah I don't I don't understand it I
don't uh I might have 30 years ago but
you need to refresh it now costic is
interesting because costic is basically
the reflection of rays you can see in
this photo okay like the reflection of
rays so so what it is saying that the
history of ped curve is related to the
costic
the notion the notion may be enlarged
upon to include locai formed by dropping
perpendiculars upon a line making a
constant angle with the tangent namely
pedos formed upon the normals to a
curve okay yeah the details I don't I
don't know but here is a book from like
a 100 years ago about the pedo okay so
you can see
um about ped
curves uh I
wonder now I wonder what Wikipedia say
okay now ped curve Wikipedia now have a
lot information so so actually I don't
know much about the PED curve so there
it is PED curve in mathematics a ped
curve of a let's enlarge it
a pin curve of a given curve results
from the orthagonal
projection of a fixed point on the
tangent lines of this
curve
uh H so it relates to tangent well okay
so what I'm doing here is negative ped
which is different from pedo okay so
but so the pedo itself has relation to
tangent which is anyway I
um okay so
Wikipedia have some details so showing
you
examples right so that is a ped
curve the red one the the red curve is a
ped
curve and the blue and green lines are
the constructions of it okay
so okay let's see what I mean so what is
the point of this ped curve what is the
purpose you see very
interesting W so I didn't know about
this
um very rich uh
Wikipedia so geometric properties
okay
uh um well okay so but it doesn't really
tell you why is it important
okay okay does I guess somewhat a little
bit uh it's the envelope of circles
through a fixed Point whose centers
follows a circle through let formed by a
circle uh we have we also have shown
that the catac costic of a circle is the
evolute of a lion
okay you know this this table is mostly
like copied from my website
let's see uh number Resource number
seven well by now they removed it
because this Eric W
Westen website originally copied a lot
of information from my website we were
friends kind of back in
1990s until one day I criticized the you
know his CRC Encyclopedia of mathematics
then he removed all links to my
websites so but
anyway yeah so I mean since about 1999
or something he he started to work at
wolam research so not so his website
becames the wolam research math
World um you know I talked about this
like two years ago and I have blogs
about it if you search you'll find it
so in summary you see my
website you know so you you see you got
this uh table of the relations of
very uh several curves and they are pedo
so for example the parabola if the PED
point is on directrix then you you get
Str forid um so for example this one
Parabola if the P point is on the vertex
of Parabola then you got then you get
this cisoid of dios this blue one okay
another famous
curve so many curves has these
relations you know the PED of of some
curve at some point is some other curve
okay and vice versa so I got this table
and you can see
Wikipedia also have this table
and then it references
to to number seven number seven Edwards
okay page
uh which one is the
Edwards oh okay so it it reference okay
so it references to this
Source differential calculus so this is
189 92 that's right so this this type of
um topic is kind of popular in
1800s okay so so this curve an
elementary treaties on the differential
calculus okay 1800s 1892 close to 1900
so that's that's like okay so that's
like
calculus already fully developed so in
1900s you have you know the Delta and
Epsilon and limits concept so anyway
interesting this is a calculus book back
in
1892 okay but but however then it also
references to Eric Weinstein so for
example let's look at it P curve from
math world so Eric
Weinstein was was my acquaintance back
in
1990s and his his web page for example
this one has linked to links to my to my
website you know for example then he got
this table which is which is similar to
the table I
have but around 1997 also
he he published his you know book via C
CRC press
then called you know like Encyclopedia
of mathematics then I criticized it you
know it's sold on Amazon I I made a
comment I criticized this is not really
a
encyclopedia this is rather just one
guy's you know
notes
then he removed all links to my websites
you
know then later on like back so so then
like this around the same time then he
he started he joined wolfan research he
started to work for wolfan research then
wolfan research published his so-called
in
encyclopedia as wolf math world so
that's a short story about this it was
known as Eric's Treasure Trove of
mathematics okay this wolfi math word is
was known as Eric trasure tro of
mathematics now if you want uh you
know history of that or receips you can
look up you know you can easily look up
um for example mathw on Wikipedia it'll
tell you you see math word math word is
an online mathematics reference work
created and largely written by
Eric Weston
it is sponsored by and licensed to wolam
research okay around
1999 okay so before that it was known
history it was known as uh CRC press
Eric Eric Treasure Trove of mathematics
there there it is you
see so that's a you know then there's a
CRC lawsuit in year 2,000 you know
that's all related
so you know I criticized him and he
removed all links to my website not
really good but it's history it's long
time
ago okay that's it for today thank you
guys for
watching
bye so yeah I think so that's it save
this this explanation of P already exist
uh uh yeah
yes okay and uh save
this
so so the uh so we did these Graphics um
so what
I wanted to update the graphics okay so
copy the p
cup I need to update this code actually
yeah not a very good video
today uh what what am I doing here
so paste that link yeah put it near the
parabola there okay
then then
this with a language code I need to
update but I
didn't let's let me just continue
updating this
okay so well um but we explained
normalize yes okay so we kind of
explained that uh
let's
um yeah
yeah okay so we have a copy of the
screenshot of that and then we we don't
need it okay so just say normalized okay
so we don't need this unit V yeah Del
delete that unit V okay delete that now
this is a uh update I mean so we need to
update this code so let me yeah let me
start to just work on my stuff let me
think about what to do so save this
Untitled one okay wait shift control s
where is it saved to desktop okay so
now what we want to do is so I have a
custom function here that plots negative
plot now why is this custom function why
is this not in my
packages
um because negative pedo is
normally not common I forgot let's look
at um planker plot
okay now list all lines containing the
word
pedo okay so you
got you can plot
pedo but why do I not have negative pedo
so let's try
negative okay so I don't have negative P
for some
reason uh this package is planker plot
package you can get it on GitHub and you
know it allows you to plot tangents
normals
uh and uh many other
features tangents normals
secants uh you can see beautiful
graphics secants and cosics that's the
optical
property and uh costic and culating
circles kissing circles and uh
evolute and
involute so anyway that so that's a
package which includes pedo so you'll
see so you got conco then you got
inversion then you got
um that's inversion like then you got
involute then you
got parallel curves so this red dots
this red is a parallel curve over the
sign
curve and then you got ped so you can
see
ped now but why didn't why did I not
have negative ped as part of this
package I don't remember
why I don't remember why I
don't have you know this as part of the
pl curve
plot but it's separately defined here so
I have to think about it
so I might want to move this function
into the
package yeah I don't remember why is it
not part of
it okay uh yeah so
you know then then I also you know I
need to update this code right now still
works fine however after 30 years
there's you know you know there's quite
a few improvements I can
make
um yeah but then coding this would
be kind of
esoteric yeah you wouldn't be interested
well I mean it would be interesting to
show how do you actually create this
function you know so basically for each
point in the plan you need to
find you know like our illustration
here you need to you know given a curve
and given a point you need to draw this
green lines so you need to find their
position and draw it draw it so that's
essentially what this
does yeah but uh we could you know it
would be easier actually to just to
write this from scratch and explain
it but if I update this code is
not then I have to uh explain on out of
the syntax and
stuff
yeah yeah I'm going to go do this
offline do we have um Nostalgia
hello yo show the small boy
going I don't have much information I
don't have new information about the
swab board okay
so I just haven't started to use it I
haven't start to practice
it uh
just because I'm doing a lots of other
things
so you know it's you know so you have to
wait okay so that's I think that's it
bye guys
and I can
continue uh so it's been 1 hour now let
me just continue
okay not feeling so organized today
like anyway
so so what what am I doing now so I want
to update the code yeah doesn't matter
whether I'm going to integrate this code
into my package or not I need to update
it
anyway so okay so let's let's let's
start to update so first of all about
the documentation because without
knowing the
documentation you wouldn't have any idea
what you're
doing so the first step is to know what
your function is supposed designed to do
okay so negative pedal plot uh takes you
know
this you know remember this is 30 years
old code so lots of changes in wam
language so you see my documentation
they are using this shortcut
notation uh I wouldn't do that today
because because people don't understand
this is like more advanced wam
language so my style also changed after
30 years so anyway this negative
negative pedal plot takes three
arguments the first one is a pair of
functions for X and Y parametric
equation okay the second one is the
variable uh is the range
so you know for example if we are
plotting a
parabola from 7 27 uh so this first part
this first part by the way means that's
a parabola so yeah you see a lot of Let
Me Explain
okay so this okay where's the code so
let me copy
that copy that
copy so let me do it here so you see
that's calling the negative plot I mean
negative pedal so let's recall this so
this part is just a function okay this
this part is actually let's rewrite
it okay let's rewrite that to to a more
understandable syntax okay so let's just
remove that this would be just
function x x this does nothing this
basically identity function
okay and the second part would be
function X
then uh X then just
X that
okay so this is equivalent to that so
this the first component is the function
for x x equals to itself the
second component is a function that does
x² ided by 4 so that is the formula
parametric formula for Parabola
okay so you see this shortcut is much
simpler but let's just change it that
okay so that's the first
argument then the second argument is
arrange that's right
then AIS then range okay so for example
we can plot that it will be identical
to to that you
see okay so that's one
thing so similarly in my documentation
I'm doing um
what am I doing anyway I don't I don't
feel like doing a video right now so
okay that's it bye guys