good morning welcome to another episode
of s talk show today we are going to
code emac disp three task to do so it's
just pure emac disp if you have
questions ask me okay so my keyboards
this is glove 80 glove 80 ultimate
hacking keyboard and this is slve board
data hand magnetic Swit is fantastic I
have reviews of them on video on my
website or search for YouTube okay let's
begin coding emac
disp uh nobody is here okay so we're
going to code today's task there are
three things first of all we going to
write a calculator
pad so I press a few keys I press two
keys or three it pops up a python or
JavaScript or whatever your favorite
language
and you can use it for calculator okay
that's one thing then we're going to
code uh write a command that use Arrow
up to increment number so if we have a
number here for example episode 553 I
just press Arrow you know Cod the
command and press Arrow it'll increment
the number or holding down down arrow it
will decrement it's very useful it's
especially on date for example uh
you know so here's the date I can press
up arrow and you'll increment the date
that's uh that's available in
ogod uh so that's second thing to do and
another thing to do is write a command
to add HTML attribute for example I want
to add attribute here uh for example
class class uh you
see class uh equals to something so that
is usually tedious so you can
now I want to press a key and it
automatically go there if there's also
already attributes like ID class style
and it will just automatically add it if
it's not there I don't have to move the
cser there and so on so okay let's begin
okay let's write a
calculator uh pad calculator
pad now why do I want to write it so
let's begin emac this the reason pop it
out and on the pink window is all my
command Calles and key strokes on the
left and command names on the right in
real time as I type delete insert uh
scroll or whatever or switch window you
can see all the command names on the
right and the key stroke on the left I'm
using SAR fly keys and I'm using vorak
keybard
layout so you can if you you can search
the command and you can find usually you
can find it on the web for example let's
search for this command name beginning
of line or block so there is the code
and you can
use okay
so so let's go back so let's write a
calculator pad okay so let me tell you
what to do so first of all Define
function s
open uh calculator okay let's just say
calculator open a template file
for to use a calculator you know this is
convenient
um
version
uh version give it today's State this is
convenient when you let me explain so
you know typically on Windows you can
use use the
calculator you know on available on the
Mac or Windows you can go scientific or
you know so you are calculating your
groceries or whatever your Finance you
know um but you know if you are using
emac if you are a programmer you prefer
to do it
programmatically now in emac you have a
cc which is a calculator
uh which is fairly powerful for example
three two then I can do plus then it's
five and on the left you can see it the
history but it's not so good okay uh it
was great in the 199s it was actually
bleeding edge technology but today it's
like very lousy um I I I do not
recommend it a lot emac fans emac
fanatic will say oh you should learn
this and also it's hard to use um so
anyway I do not recommend it why because
for example let's go to python mod print
um save it py okay let's just just say
temp
XXX you know so if you want to do
calculator the easiest way is in fact
just use a programming language okay you
can run it it's seven so you you know
you can do minus
uh something something number and plus
you know if you are doing your monthly
income whatever um let's see a random
number you know you can you have all the
emx power and you can you can start to
set it to variables for example cost
equals to that and so here cost and you
can have
income in you know some some random
number and you can cost minus income
something like that uh
income Minus cost minus expense you know
you so you can you have variables and
and every history is fully detailed
unlike
the calculator you know the small you
know small screen
and and if you want to do more advanced
math such as
Vector uh Vector you know or Matrix list
of numbers python you know you you can
load the library if you are a programmer
you know if you can load the library
it's far more powerful and advanced than
emac
calculator okay the emac calculator it
has many features actually it can do
some limited solving equations and stuff
so people are very emac Fanatics are you
know they'll tell you to use it but in
my opinion no so you just use python or
JavaScript or goand whatever is your
favorite language FSH hascal they have
math libraries so um so it's more
convenient and you have the full emac
power you don't have to
learn you know special keystrokes and
special how do you do a sign cosign you
don't have to learn that okay so that's
what I recommend
um that's you know just use Python okay
python JavaScript or whatever your
favorite language but what we want to do
is we want to write a command that
easily open this calculator so I don't
have to every time open new buffer uh
then save it and something something. py
I don't have to do that so I just press
a key and it pops up okay so that that
is what uh we are doing open a template
file uh for users calculator okay so
let's say uh
um file path let's let's
say
uh you know I already have a temp file
path so let's say that
okay you can you can set it to your home
directory or whatever
um let's say that okay
so uh
cyy okay let's say that's the temp file
name clean it up and uh now let and uh
then you just say find file find file
XT
uh let's say XC
path okay and basically I think that's
it okay eval it eval the buffer now we
you can just call that command meta X
call it do it fantastic and over here
let's put a print so that okay save it
close okay let's call it again
calculator fantastic so doesn't matter
where you are right now for example in
this file today's talk show so I can
meta X calculator you'll do it so you
can calculate your grocery or whatever
so that's one thing done now close that
let's pop up uh so that's a example
let's put it back syntax C it showing
browser so there is the code and uh
let's put
this
cut uh where is this okay so
cut let's go back here and put a sample
okay open a new python code paste it
here make this a paragraph syntax color
it showing browser so that is a first
thing okay now let's put a section sign
so we have more organized so now that's
the first thing
uh we need to put this
in here okay that's the task so I have
it written up so this is emac
calculator uh and you know if you want
to use emac calculator you can read the
emac this documentation so you do
control
h then you see all the emac manuals
search for
cc there it is it's fairly complex
uh you know you have hundred hundreds of
pages of documentation data types stack
and Trail mod settings arithmetics
scientific functions Matrix functions
algebra units you know it's fairly
powerful but but a programming language
is far more powerful than this and since
emac is suitable for programming
language is fairly fully integrated so
uh so this is a thing of the past okay
in my opinion
so that's one thing the next any
questions
comments Edmund
hello Okay so let's do a next task write
the emac command that use Arrow up to
increment number
okay okay let's do this task
um there it is is Select select okay so
we don't want to go there select make a
section showing browser there it is so
now we want to write a command okay
let's do it emac pop it out Define a
function uh what's the function name
SAR
increment number okay dark string or
important
so in increment the number
under
Cruiser okay on
called
press up Arrow to increase
PR down arrow to decrease
okay that's what we want to do okay so
let's begin so first of
all
uh so first of all you want to make sure
the character under the character under
the curser is a number okay so you uh so
first of
all uh when
uh so you want to grab the current
character in the cruiser how do you do
that I forgot what's the command so you
go to emac list
Basics uh so that would be grabed the so
that's emac list Basics practical emac
this writing commands text processing
get perer string there it is get string
from region get current
word get current line get current URL
file path get text between brackets get
current Char CH before that's right CH
before and CH after so you You Want U CH
Char after okay
so so
when let me show you how uh Char after
okay
uh now CH after it returns it Returns
the character under the Cru
so in emac in emac a cursor the the
cursor is considered between characters
so in above buffer you have curser
position so in the beginning that curser
position is one and that cursor is right
to the left of the parent so you can
see you know again remember it's between
characters that's a curer position so
when you say CH after that will will get
you the
character right after the cruiser to the
right of the C cursor okay and in iMac
so that's one thing the other thing is
in iMac this you don't have a character
type every character is actually an
integer that is the unic code ID for the
character for example for example right
now we
are at the a character so you know the
emac shows a rectangular block the
actual cursor position is to the left of
it okay so you can call describe
character okay call describe character
and uh expand the window you can see the
command is describe character on the
pink window so you can see position
203 that
means that means let's go back okay
let's go back here that means this curs
of position is 203 out of 220 so there
are total of 220
characters and in column six okay and
then you can see code point you see code
point is an ID in unic code that
uniquely identify this character so this
character is a you see so it's its ID is
97 so in iMac this a character is just
integer okay there's no special data
type it's just
integer so once you get the character
this returns this returns a integer you
need to uh let's convert it to string
okay so chart two string okay so chart
two string a character is that okay now
that's a string and basically it was
going to be
a so once you get a character as a
string then you want to check if it's a
digit or not if it's not a digit say you
know
error so so how do you check you use a
regular expression to match okay so
string match regular expression 0 to9
okay and what do you want to match
against that would be this thing okay so
cut that there and start we don't care
okay so uh uh okay so wait now we should
before we clean it up hold on a second
okay so this so
when
when when this is not
true uh you say user
error CH under cursor is not a digit
okay uh
okay now we clean up the code there it
is now it's it's better okay uh so let's
shrink the buffer smaller a bit am I
doing good so far so good hello
guys uh question from Rusty hello Rusty
I your name is familiar to me how do you
learn to learn things and establish
Behavior
change I have hard time achieving good
score in school system despite having
wide range of technical stuff I have
knowledge of that's very interesting
question let's talk about that uh after
we finish this okay uh Edmund says just
starting to learn thank you for all your
videos thank you again uh you know if
you guys like my stuff pay me okay
because money is really get things
going uh printing a rectangle overlay in
a way it would work on Terminal emac is
a challenge for me just because POS is
not XY but this but this number
way okay I'm not too clear about what
question is that if you want to ask that
elaborate please so let's let us finish
this command then let's talk about how
do
you get yourself to learn things like
Behavior change okay that's not
technical question but anyway let's just
okay let's call this okay so first of
all we check if that um you know we
check if the current character is a
digit or not if it's not you know stop
error okay now it is an
error uh now we all we have to do we uh
is to see what character it is so let's
define
c
c current digit okay current digit is
actually chart f
okay that's you how you define a
variable and give it a value there
current digit and now we we can just
replace this by that
okay uh
actually current digit yeah let's change
it to string so uh so okay
so this should
be there so current digit is a string a
single character then okay
then okay then okay we got the digit
now now now current
digit is a string remember now we need
to increase it so first of all we need
to in uh change it to a number
so uh string to
number okay now that's a number now you
just increment so that function 1 plus
will increase
number okay that that should be what is
going to be okay so you increment number
now you just need to
replace that character so you
do uh Delete
chart okay let's see delete chart delete
to the right or delete to the left I
always got confused delete chart delete
the following and charts okay it deletes
the right so delete chart uh let's see
do you need a option so you need I mean
you need argument so delete Char
one then insert just insert
that oh you need to turn it back to um
do you need to turn it back to string I
forgot uh yes you do because if you
insert that yeah it doesn't work I mean
it you see when you insert 33 uh let's
say 96 96 is the character a okay so if
you insert that since it's not a string
emac will consider that integer to be a
ID for a character so in the case of 96
that's a so it will just insert a for
example we run
it oh we got a that
uh but I thought a is 96 let's see a is
97 oh right so for example
97 run it you see it inserts a so you
need to convert it back to uh convert
back
to string okay
so I mean convert back to string yeah
number two string there it is then that
okay there it is I think that's it for
our
function now we clean up the code
actually that's
it but we haven't done the we haven't
done the key binding yet but first of
all this is
the uh command Okay eval the buffer now
let's try it something
okay uh something okay now copy the
function name now meth
x s increment number do it you see error
CH under Cruiser is not a
digit correct
Behavior now let's say we have a number
three put the cruiser there
magnify let's call
it increment number it become four
fantastic now there's a issue we need to
move the curser back to there because
otherwise when we increase again uh it
would be in the wrong position so now we
move the cursor
back okay where do we add it check the
parent okay here so backward chart
that's how you move the curer okay clean
the code
evaluated do this again increment five
increment six increment Seven
Fantastic
um uh now eight nine now there's a
critical moment do it again 10 okay this
is actually not we want so when it's
nine it should um it depends on what you
need to do it should go back to
zero
or or something okay but let's leave it
for now okay let's leave it now let's do
the key binding so press Arrow to
increase and press down arrow to
decrease how do you do that okay so you
can you can add the key binding
by first of all let's add a global key
binding
okay
Global set key okay now I forgot what's
the uh the syntax is like
that so we need to pick a key I haven't
used let's
[Music]
see uh I don't want
F7 f8
no let's try a key I have not used F9
no
uh okay so
F2 uh F2 you see all my function keys is
running key
maros now I need a easy key that is not
used uh let's see F5 F5 F5 is
undefined okay we can let's use
F5 so let's see the Syntax for Global
set key Global set key command Okay easy
so that's a command and uh the command
needs to be a symbol so you need that
apostrophe okay so eval the buffer eval
the buffer let's did we do it eval the
buffer now let's say five now let's just
press F5 increase increase increase
fantastic okay now we now once the
command is called we need to make the
Arrow key active so Arrow up and down
we'll do the increment and decrement so
in order to do that uh I have a tutorial
for it I believe so you go toel emac
tutorial and emac keys everything you
need need to know about key
binding uh and key sequence key priority
of minor mods mini bu Keys minor mod
Keys major mod Keys mod dependent key
meta key Super Hyper key menu key repeat
command by key okay
um one of
these uh repeat command by key let's see
there it is trans set transient map
okay so let's copy the code so that it's
easier just to copy instead of so let's
see now hold on a second shrink them a
little
bit so the main part is this okay so
let's delete that so you set transum map
that means you create a new key map okay
so you create a you make spot key map
make you make a new key map and name it
X key map
then you define key up Arrow so you want
to define a key for this key map an up
Arrow key so what is a Syntax for up
Arrow you just do describe key and press
up Arrow so the syntax is just up there
okay and what the command the command
will
Bea increment number okay and uh
similarly for
down down arrow is that syntax and here
will
[Music]
be decr okay we need to write this
command okay let's write that
command uh we can make a c cleaner code
if we combine this two command into one
and use the argument like increase or
decrease
but but for this live stream let's just
write a different
because that's simpler conceptually so
here is a decrement
number de decrement the number and the
cursor one called press up Arrow to
increase down arrow to decrease yes and
uh okay so this uh this so what we have
to change is this change this to
decrement function so is there a one
minus I don't think so let's try
describe function y minus oh there it
is I didn't know okay so let's see if I
have a shortcut DC oh I do so anyway so
here is the
command that's it that's it for this
Umar decrement number okay so we got
that we got that okay so oh and we need
to put this key inside the function okay
so yeah so cut
it and back to the first
function put it
inside uh
let okay I think that's it and do the
same thing for this
and okay and now I think that's
it eval the buffer now put five here now
press F5 to call the command it BEC six
now I'm going to press up Arrow let's do
it seven Great eight you see now I let's
try press down arrow 7
65 up Arrow again 6 6 7 8 9 10 1 2 3
fantastic how do you exit just press any
other key for example space that exit so
now up arrow and down arrow becomes um
their orental um functionality okay so
fantastic so let's pop this
back and uh syntax CCT showing browser
fantastic we did write that function um
okay that's it that's it for so now we
can another task but for now let's
answer the question so far it's 37
minutes uh so Russy has a question how
do you learn to how do you learn to
learn things and establish Behavior
change okay I have a hard time achieving
uh good score in school
system and let's let's magnify
this wait I want to magnify wait why is
my control key doesn't
work okay you can't true control scroll
up so let's try
control
okay so anyway so I have a hard time
achieving good score in school system
despite having wide range of technical
stuff I have knowledge of okay so let me
tell you my story I was the worst
student I never graduated high school so
in Taiwan back about 40 years ago when I
was 10 13 I was the worst student so bad
that I didn't even graduate Middle
School okay so you know I'm not good you
know I like I have no interest okay but
gradually somehow through turning events
in life you know I moved to parai and
mid Mid America I mean Central America
then Canada for three
years um I uh started to have interest
in learning things and basically that's
all I do I just read encyclopedias all
day
so but however I'm still very bad
socially as you as many of you guys know
I I mean uh I've gone through extreme
poverty for for 10 years like almost
about to kill myself because hunger in
America I mean that's like like you um
you know I don't imag most people you
cannot imagine Americans that's even
even poverty you know like you don't and
so I'm at a level
that's suffering actual
hunger meaning
that you know I I I I I'm hungry and I
don't have like $1 to buy a banana two
bananas also something like that okay uh
so so some some things changed because
become good because I
become and for you know I become kind
of a professional programmer and also a
amateur
mathematician uh but some of things uh I
didn't do so well such as the
practicality of make a
living so there are things that changes
so and in this this question relates to
a lot uh it's a common question for
example a lot Americans they want to
lose weight but they can't you know they
go there's this diet you know there's
like 10,000 diets you know they're
trying to lose weight and and also
especially women women's got their own
thing because women want to lose weight
because that's their power you know to
be a young
girl and you know so but you just can't
do it because your environment you know
because you are comfort you know you
have money to buy so many so many food
so you just can't do it so how do you
that's I mean I guess that's the gist of
the question how do you
change and for example right now I have
the issue of smoking I really like to
quit
but I've been saying that for a while
yeah um but I just I just I just didn't
I mean you know I'm not quitting why
because I can I can I have money to buy
a cigarette you know I just you know
so the desire to quit um is a like a
logical you know yeah it's good to quit
oh I should quit you know because cancer
is not good for your health and but
there's no
you know there there's nothing that
that's pressing that nothing that's
pressing me to stop like you know after
you know I after I do a live stream I go
out and have a
cigarette
so how do you change okay so I
think the the the most CR critical thing
to to make that change is if there is
something that happens to your to your
mind like something clicked that you
really really desire to change that is
the most important thing once you got
that you're going to change it no M no
no matter what okay I think that's the
most important so as to how do you
actually get that that is a
question uh that depends on each person
I don't think there's no magic pill you
know so whatever is your issue or
whatever you want to change you know you
want to get into studying or whatever
there's no magic P just first of all you
have to realize
that okay
so so I think you but so but
fundamentally the the thing is in your
brand your software in the brain when
you want to change then you can change
but
the question is where does the wheel
come from you don't know so maybe you
moved you know you moved to another city
maybe you met different friends or maybe
you watched s talk show too
much and maybe you know there's
something started to CH in your brain
you make a change okay and maybe but
maybe not maybe you just maybe you don't
really do you actually need to change
that's another question you see many of
us have complaints you know we
have dissatisfied with life or whatever
you know issues we think if I quit
smoking I'm going to be a you know I'm
going to be fantastic but actually maybe
not you know it's just something you you
you you feel you you know you imagine
that's something
good uh so we don't know okay so I I
think we don't know so just I think just
you know if you want to to change
something just keep that in mind and
look for it and you know and
not you know be practical not think
about fantasies and maybe you will um I
think that's my advice about
that and uh you know that reminds me
like a lot of zumas today like I despise
the zumas you know the zumas they are
you know on YouTube you know doing like
they are intonation the the the they you
know they don't know nothing they view
of the world and some of them become
YouTube Stars you know one medium but
they they they create crap you know like
full of lies and idiotic
opinions but Zoomers watch it like
because the all the Zoomers they don't
know they you know they go to YouTube oh
this this is you know this thing or that
thing especially on Twitter you know uh
on Twitter I'm not going to click but if
you click around you it's
instantaneously you see lots of
controversies conspiracies food you know
food like Diet oh you should do this
diet because nonstop and or gender and
you know this Zoomers you know they they
know nothing
so so so often I feel that you know and
also a lot of you guys on on my on my
Discord you know I chat with you guys
all the time you know especially in the
spory room you know I think what the
idiots you you know
like the view like you don't know
nothing you have no depth like every day
you do is like C Chad virgin or whatever
you know the drios like like you know so
I thought how come you can just like
code you know do a programming language
or mathematics whatever you know but
they can't you see they are grew up they
grew up in this environment since they
were born all the fake news clickbait
you know the YouTube gft us you know
they they don't know what what is you
know so they
can't so you can't so I you cannot
expect for people to change or for
example fat people you know there's a
lot especially in America you know a
be many you know they want to change too
but they but they can't because there's
no no one to help them no one to
encourage
them uh and you know and then the the
Deep State politicians you know the the
social justice warri you're saying oh
fat is beautiful and you
know so it's a
mess so what so anyway what I'm saying
is that there environment issues that
you you cannot just expect people to
change uh and so
if you really want
to
change you you you know possibly you can
so just think about it you know be be
be uh reasonable and uh you know do do
things are good for you and uh
eventually I think you get better and
maybe you don't even need that change
you know you I think that's um that's my
view okay that's that's it about it and
I think that's it for today an little
Excursion
into you know these things you know when
I talk about you know these
non-technical things the viewership
increases that's that's another well
it's a common trait of
humanity okay that's about that
uh okay I think that's it for today
let's see there's another task but we
can Skip it's already 48
minutes anything
else since Super Chat is evil do you use
any other
donation that appear on the stream uh no
sorry yeah the thing about Super Chat is
that CH Ching you know people can see it
that's the you know that's and YouTube
but YouTube takes like 50% of it it
really blood you know really blood
suing in a sense because I mean after
all but YouTube you know you have to
imagine you know we can just blame
Google Google is extremely evil since
about 2012 okay extreme like like huge
lies nonstop and you know extreme evil
but however for the donation you know
the Super Chat you can't be like a
Zoomer you know like a lot of Zoomer
will say oh you know they take 50% yeah
but they are comp you know you I'm not
paying Google to use YouTube YouTube is
their service so they provide the
service right they don't owe me so I'm
using YouTube right so and they they
provide you know that you know it's not
easy to create YouTube you have the
infrastructure you have to pay the
programmers you have to pay the
electricity you have to pay you know the
lots of things so you don't want you you
do not want to demand things for free
like the richest soulman and open source
you know they that's they
created the situation they demand you
know this website that Twitter you know
the alen x or Facebook they want it free
and they want they they want to tell
them what to do oh you cannot this is
immoral you know gender whatever you
should you know Google you know you
should do this or that you know you have
activist you know this white
people and then the open source Fanatics
they want to pay so what can Google do
or other companies well they move to
Cloud they start to get your info and
sell it what can they do I mean they
have to survive either they shut down or
they got do something right so they they
move to Cloud so all your information
like the YouTube you know it's on the
cloud then then they they they they sell
your information
you know so it's going downhill by these
Fanatics and zumas you know you you you
around it doesn't benefit you in the
long run okay so anyway back to the the
YouTube you know Super Chat you know
yeah they take 50% which is Hefty and
you know what I
realized recently I've been looking at
chatter bit it's quite it's very amazing
okay and they also take
50% uh yeah but you know what can you do
so anyway that you know that's about
that uh I don't want to talk too much
about these issues because then then
Google is going to censor me you know
like
strike
uh so anyway yeah if you want to pay me
you can uh do by PayPal so but it's not
you know Interactive
opinion on Kendrick versus Drake um I
have no idea what that
is okay about cigarette about quitting
cigarette I have my own ways okay I can
quit code turkey like I talked before
I'm a I'm kind of a monk
mentality like uh you know like
sometimes you see those monks or uh
Indian fakers you know like they are so
thingin they they have certain
thought you know self mind control I'm
kind of like that so that is why I'm
able to suffer hunger for like 10 years
actually most of my half of my life is
in poverty and uh
and I'm a a schizoid personality so I'm
very extremely logical and uh uh uh less
of
emotion so as as for quitting smoke
my my strategy is just cold turkey I did
that before you know if I really wanted
just make up my mind the the thing is
you have to make up your mind if you
really want to you know then go turkey
nothing is going to stop me you know
that that's where I look at it you know
it's like there's this thing can you do
it and you know you really are serious
about that question if you decide that
you're going to do it then you can do it
chi ching thank
you live stream installing and
customizing Solaris Solaris is like long
dead 20 years dead okay that's it for
today thank you guys for
watching bye guys 20 C viewers okay um
yeah that's it we shut down in 2
minutes fantastic fantastic ch ch ch ch
ch
[Music]
Ching they want twoyear Solaris
management what Solaris solarus is dead
for like 20
years it's nothing much too Solaris I
mean all the units are the same you know
the and also as far as I know the C
admin job is already is gone it's dead
instead they call it you know the op you
know the what they call it op
something UK nuclear energy company oh
okay maybe some oldfashioned
company y bye