good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is 2019
December 19th 1 o clock in the afternoon
San Francisco time and today is Thursday
and we are looking at the phantasmagoria
of flower view and this is Emily's
favorite thing this game and today we
don't have a topic so let's cook up some
topics ok and let's stop this thing and
we have a poetry people number people
watching poetry
number three people oh my god I'm losing
I'm losing audience I'm losing fan
because well let's see okay so poetry
so let's look let's let's the word of
the day okay first of all saw start
command log mod so you can see all my
Emacs commands on the left window okay
all of them all of them
wipe them out all of them all my Emacs
commands on the left window and so that
is prepared and let's make it pretty
pretty pink it's okay let's say pretty
pink let's say set background color good
morning crash hacker
sit sit background color pink okay
we love pink because Emily loves pink
well Emily loves purple so let's make it
purple L CD let's see what are the
colors are purple okay pop Oh Oh violet
something like that okay three so let's
try this lethal thing thing okay let's
try set background color and three so
yes this is perfect
Emily's favorite color and we need to
have a Papa
but well max you cannot have colored
emoji so so good morning a bunch of
people magpie and magpie is from gee I
forgot yesterday nee aqua Nia Nia koala
that's a country in Central America is
that correct
Oh Central America that's a country
where you go to vacation with Nick Nick
walk how do how do you how do you say
the name okay so we have to go to Google
Maps okay let's go to Google Maps yeah
let's go to Google Maps and let's look
at thee the place where Mac PI came from
now that's a place where you go to
vacation okay so hold on a second
shrink shrink so now we have United
States of America okay and you go to you
fly to Mexico and below Mexico you have
kata mala where I stayed for half a year
25 years ago
then you have nickel Nicaragua okay this
where you know you have lots of these
how do you say the as blue as the lake
something okay you know that is that
like so Nicaragua in Central America
right in the middle yes indeed you know
basically I'm thinking Caribbean islands
now where is Caribbean islands Caribbean
island somewhere here okay oh kuba kuba
is the Communist something the Bahamas
yes the Bahamas
okay well let's go back to NIC NIC
Nicaragua can you say which town
so let's look at so what is the country
Nicaragua like what what are they what
what kind of people live there so Nabi
young good morning go to Google
Translate just type it in English
section then pick the speaker icon oh
yeah that's too much trouble though
nikka nicaragua in Central America so so
Rocco okay crash hacker good morning to
Japan and India Sheriff
good morning I hello Lee I forgot where
you from Freddie Freeman
I forgot you from Emily the money to UK
Eduardo good morning to Brazil I think
the money to Allen California sunny
California Emily and papa hot and
Justine good morning Justine to Canada
Oh Canada and and we don't have a topic
today okay so we miss so magpie says
okay so Navion says and good morning
Nabby from California Southern
California now there's a slight
difference between Northern California
in Southern California slight cultural
differences wait in my life make sure
that I am NOT talking without audio okay
check check Houston status check okay
you're good to go
so Nicaragua
so I want to you know let's drop down to
look at some of the sceneries of the
Nicaragua so where can we drop down so
magpie subject that suggests a place
Nihao neha good morning this is Good
Morning America well this is good
morning China good morning Chinamen good
morning can hear okay
so Matt pie says I live in the capital
city of Managua Spanish speaking third
world country Oh third world country
Managua so let's look at are you a max
user how did you find me so here is the
capital of Nicaragua okay something like
that and here is Managua and they speak
Spanish here okay and now as you look at
Google Maps you can also get certain
information you see they don't have
street maps I mean they don't have the
street view except a few you know
selected faces meaning now that has
significance if you are studying if you
are observing the world the significant
well one thing you learned from this is
that apparent so for some reason maybe
political that Google you know are not
allowed to drive around in his face
something like that okay so that's what
I see so the map path is okay he lives
in Managua and the spanish-speaking and
it's a third world country I was
fortunate enough to have good education
and native English speaker and I do a
bit of Japanese and French oh good okay
so let's drop down to some of these face
ok let's let's drop down to Street View
and see what it is like Oh Oh cause Oh
cuz cause we must have dropped into some
honda toyota dealer array of shiny car
so is this a motel or something okay you
have panel panorama
okay so magpies says software engineer
I've been thinking about learning
I use Linux and different IDE said at
the moment oh that's interesting
software so you are not a Emacs users as
of now and that you are thinking about
it so anyway we are looking at this oh
look guys look another interesting thing
now this is Google Maps and here we have
license plates they are not censored
okay this indicates to me that this
either there is a bug in Google software
or there is something you know some
feature they still need to add all this
panorama is created by people but Google
don't have you know the censorship of
the car plates for some reason so anyway
that's an interesting thing we looked so
let's let's pick another yeah it's back
to Mountain View again Mountain View
well that's it's back to Nick Nicaragua
okay I think maybe we should change your
subject change to something interesting
let's see what other people say so we
don't have a topic okay so guys so you
post programming or whatever topics then
we can talk about it like so beautiful
face just not very well of economics
economically if you want nice tourist
face check out Kong Island and Grenada
oh ok ok all those cars are white yeah
that's interesting yeah I don't yeah
what's the deal
so Grenada so magpie says Canada is kind
of a tourist race so that's dropping I
have a look
Grenada but can we see all the reef you
know reef Beach you know that you
those kind of places okay they don't
have street maps so it's just dropping a
random phrase random good morning cool
for school says do you use oak mud not
really I talked about that many times I
use just raw HTML I don't use oak Mart
oh c'mon is great but I used raw HTML
because I've been I've been writing raw
HTML since 1996 okay so we are looking
at Kannada which is a city apparently a
tourist city in Nicaragua
okay so they speak Spanish here and we
see some sort of okay so that that's
that's it okay so that's it Nicaragua
interesting and it's markdown and let's
go back to turn on auto click what's how
do you spell the place hold on second we
are back to the word again
okay so it's Nicaragua okay okay okay so
that's one of the topics and what's next
so we've been talking for 12 minutes
without topic so this is random chat and
the guys join discord okay join this
code we have vibrant discussions on
disco discord vibrant including
including certain things I don't like
okay but you know but you know different
people have different opinions and
different of styles of expression of
expression so you know I don't want to
go nutty about it but yesterday there is
a guy who is kind of insincere you know
the end I pen him anyway so so let's see
do you use augment no okay Mac prices
for Reeves look at Combe island okay for
Reeves right those beautiful peach where
you see Asia
yes lake as blue as Asia now by the way
that's a reference from the Clockwork
Orange you guys know that what you guys
know now this is getting sensitive sorry
Clark
walk orange this is getting into the
Forbidden Zone now if you click that
you're gonna see several screenshots of
the movie A Clockwork Orange which is a
classic movie and it's it has a some
kind of code following movie the subject
matter of that movie is pretty serious
it's about society and and how do you
explain that
you know punishment society reform
education of problematic people like
like street gangs that is movie
Clockwork Orange have you guys seen it
so I don't know if I should click that
because if I click that that's a
screenshot of that movie and Google is
not going to like it so anyway so el
mundo so yeah so Asia so I was talking
about Azure the word as sure a Z you are
and it's a line from Krakow walk a [ __ ]
walk orange violence ultra violence
that's what that movie is about Freddie
says do you like to travel yes yes I do
but I don't have money so have you been
to Europe no I have not been to Europe
but there is a plan upcoming that I'm
going to visit Germany so let's go back
to Google Maps so I'm gonna tell you
guys I'm going to visit Germany in
February or in March
probably ok it's up to me and it's a
free trip so it's going to be my first
time in Germany and I'm going to visit
in the area around :
ok somewhere close close to that and I'm
going to visit a math professor it's an
invitation for so I'm going to stay
there for two weeks
and you know it's gonna be first time so
have you been to Europe so do you drink
alcohol no I well I like to sometimes I
do but in general I don't which CPU do
you use which CPU do I use I use a Mac
among a Mac um I'm on a Mac Mini ok
so let's show so you can see so you turn
around this Lodi that's me talking and
you go down you look at my I'm drinking
coffee milk first coffee beans press
honey okay and there it is my cleanest
keyboard so imagine my camera is a space
is a spaceship so it's gonna fly over
then over to my mouse and then there it
is it is my Mac Mini and then there is a
smarter given to me and you zoom out
then you then you go back to my visit my
mug shot
woohoo so visit part but is in his body
in colon area well and there is Matt
Matt is also there Mary is not here
today you know I I it's nice you know
when you are younger I can I can do that
but now I'm older when you are older let
me give you guys a tip okay when you are
younger you can sleep in a couch you can
go around Europe or whatever America if
you are in Europe you go to America go
to Canada you can stay at my place for a
few days you can stay at you know your
friends online friends face you can say
you know online friends you you know you
talk to them hey I'm going to come be
over there do you have you know you know
you can ask people so they will invite
you to stay at your home for you know
one day or two so you can travel around
but when you are younger you can do that
3d but when you are older you are less
welcome okay so
that's that's just the way things are
and and so so infinite sauce so I'm in
the same latitude as Cologne by the way
just way west okay yeah so do I you know
I could visit but the other thing is I
don't have money like like like
literally like consider me as a hobo you
know someone leave you on the street a
little better a bit better but I don't
have money so if I'm going to go to your
you guys if I'm going to take invitation
from you guys yeah I can visit for a day
but it's gonna be me going there and I'm
not gonna pay a thing because I cannot
that's that's a sad sad but true so and
I don't know if I'm gonna you know do
that
topics about topics well the thing about
topics in my in my in my livestream is
that is that like today we don't have a
topic it's you know it's is it's instead
of thinking of it it as you know I need
some topic and you gonna post some time
that's not it because I know a lot of
topics because I can start to talk about
computer science I can start to talk
food in a SIA or keyboards or anything
you know tcp/ip or Linux tutorials Linux
in general or the history of HTML is you
know it's like I can start to go random
but that's not that that that does not
like kind of the that's not the thing I
mean that's that's not a thing I can you
know I can start to talk about camel you
know but but the thing is like when you
watch it's like this okay like when you
are chatting with a friend you have a
friend you know this who visited you or
maybe your coworker a workplace you
don't begin you know you say hi hi how
are you a ho hey I haven't seen you for
a while and you guys start to talk right
and you obviously you guys you know
don't have a topic like it's nobody have
a topic but topics topics happen
naturally you start to talk about
something then one thing leads to
another
then maybe you start to talk about the
culture or the some programming
technology or well tech industry is
going oh what what happens with AI or
talking about math you know things
happen naturally you start to talk but
you don't like hey how are you and they
hey we don't have a topic yet can you
suggest like least ten topics and we're
gonna start to talk about that so that's
what I'm saying
so like you I mean it's great you you
know so we have to get kind of like if
you have a question oh yo or if you have
made some comments then I read it then
oh yeah I have some opinions then I
started to say something about that then
maybe you disagree or you you
you want to add something about that
then we started to have kind of like the
conversation quotes right but it's not
but but when you meet a friend or group
of people you don't you know let's say
you have a party or something you don't
gather together and say hey we don't
have a topic can we start to list of
topic and in someone should give you a
list of topic that's that's kind of like
meeting you know that's like a
conference you do that well yeah I can I
can you know that
I mean that what's that that's what I'm
saying it doesn't it you know if you
gonna just give me a list of topic I
cannot it doesn't start the conversation
yeah there's no spark you know you need
a schmuck to start the engine so that's
that's what I'm saying that's kind of
how I feel so video conference podcast
yes there is a delay yeah 10 seconds
very annoying I think it's 10 seconds so
what are you going again when are you
going again
sometimes in February or March undecided
yet basically now I have to make a
decision you know I'm kind of like
procrastination that's that's my
decision and uncertain and undecided
because I hate you know filling out
forms and then also it means I have to
go out and apply for get get a passport
passport you know I think my passport
last time I used is like 15 years ago so
I have to go you know do it get a
passport and all those kind of things so
Emily so Emily where are you Emily Emily
say something Emily Emily's off work and
Aaron says okay so ask you suppose
I would like them again so what Alan
what question I mean do you like what
something interesting you know okay let
me let me tell you guys this okay so we
we have this discord which is great and
I'm thinking I always wanted to I'm
thinking let's let's have some kind of
mini - Toby Oh like mini presentation
mini talk of each of you guys okay each
of you guys you can for example Emily
she knows you know she knows many things
we don't know she knows all and
programming she knows keyboards happy
hacking the details the hacking of the
happy hacking keyboard you know she's
gonna take it apart
reinstall the key switches and things
like that and you know she has you know
take it apart replace the firmware and
we map the key so she has a lot to talk
about so she can give us for example for
example mini mini lesson okay like 10
minutes or 20 minutes and she can you
know it's up to you if you want to go on
video but she can like you know talk
about you know tell us about that topic
so we can actually learn for those of
you interested and I know a lot of you
are interested in keyboards on how to
you know especially happy hacking
keyboard you know where to buy things
how do you replace the key caps for
happy hacking keyboard because happy
hacking keyboard is not the Cherry MX
keyboard okay sorry happy hacking
keyboard block okay that's good let's go
to keyboard rock so you so there are
many interesting things she can tell us
about like so it's like lightning talk
in today's jargon in San Francisco we
have lots of meetups so you can you know
she can give us a some kind of talk
about happy hacking keyboard by the way
there's a new version coming out new
brand-new from Japan this is just
announced last week and it's already out
in Japan you can buy happy hacking
keyboard it's I think it's $300 u.s.
dollars and I think it's not available
in USA yet so you can fly to Japan oh
but you can fly to Japan and buy it by
the way a shocker
did you finally go to the Akihabara yet
cuz you need a you need a keyboard you
need to join the keyboard Club so anyway
so this happened new version of happy
hacking keyboard you can buy in Japan
right now and so what's new about it
well they added finally the happy
hacking keyboard is not programmable so
you know you can you can reprogram the
keys you know by firmware so so so back
to what I'm saying so Emily can talk
about these kind of things or networking
or or give an intro about a line why is
it great Alan you know Alan is kind of a
functional language and you know she can
talk about that and Alan for example can
you know Alan can talk about you know so
I'm you know Alan can talk about
linguistics or you know what
introduction to to linguistics or what
is the academia like in the linguistic
department or anything anything you know
yeah I think you know people will find
interesting things you know other people
don't know
so Alan would you be interested you know
I kind of I started to ask people about
that so you know you would you be
interested like giving a 15 minutes talk
on some topic you know linguistics or
whatever whatever you like oh what's
what's your what is what is your coders
you know programming life is like
working in California oh you know
anything so we're gonna you know we can
do that in the disco channel like I
would set up a time like oh we we set up
a time like
so today 10 o clock you know for 20
minutes Alan is gonna talk about
something something you know we have a
schedule though then on that day people
just swamp swamp into that voice Channel
and we listen to Alan talk about these
things and next day you know Emily is
gonna talk about this this topic and we
go there and we listen to it and in a
similar way crash hacker can talk about
you know AI technology in image
recognition or what is India like what
is India technology industry like things
like that you know in anything that's
that that that that you know other
people don't know an Abby okay guys we
smart okay guys Nabi can you know tell
us about his work you know at this giant
gaming company and what is skimming the
different type of games you know she
Navi plays Final Fantasy 14 and now he
introduced us you know what what is a
game like well why is it interesting you
know so many so many things and Navi has
also a fancy patter sation you know he's
got he's got a go ducks and he's also
got a razor fancy razor gamepad and he's
also got a 20 button 23 button 25 button
Mouse from razor and Nabi is can tell us
about he set up you know he has his
elaborate setup so so that's what I'm
thinking you know we can talk about this
he says I don't know about anything okay
so I'm thinking about that you know and
of course and Justine
adjusting heaven being on discord much
but just Cain can tell us about has cow
likened introduction so anyway that's
that's that's just you know some ideas I
have you know because I always I want to
learn you know I want to learn many
things I don't know you know many things
I don't know for example Olin I don't
know but in Emily's learning it so it
will save me tremendous time if she's
actually did give a you know a mini
introduction a mini course for example I
know a lot of things you know you guys
don't know I know eMac beasts for
example I know I know about efficiency
of keybinding layouts their history
things like that I know about this
history the list culture the hacker
types of the among these cultures you
know so why all the history of
JavaScript you know many of you guys are
not there this is 1995 so when you don't
know I mean you can of course for
example let's say eMac B's let's say
JavaScript history you could go to
online Wikipedia you then you can start
read but you don't get you know you
spend 10 hours you don't get what's
going on you know rather if you have
someone who actually knows it in 10
minutes you know beat one hour of
Wikipedia reading or research you know
the links and historical Docs you like
you don't know what's going on so you
need someone to give you an intro for
example has cow for example math
mathematics for example what is Scoob
theory what is Archer what what is like
like for example if you don't know any
math at all wouldn't it be great someone
gives gives you an overview like in half
an hour you get overview what is the
whole entire mathematical branches what
they are doing what you know what
in fact I've done that in the past few
videos so that is the power of teaching
that I mean you know the
she grows so fast exponentially and each
day we become we become know nothing
each each one of us we know nothing like
whatever you think you know it's like
nothing here about history they like you
know nothing that is that's what I found
out that's my experience I you know I
read encyclopedia every day basically an
hour so on average statistically since
you know before internet I go to library
you know the Encyclopedia Britannica and
American squirrel coitus encyclopedia
and there's quite a diffuse you know you
look at them so what I found is I
basically each person you you know
nothing doesn't matter even if you are a
professor you know nothing I mean that
that's that's not an exaggeration that's
that's that's actually true you don't
and like is it almost like absolutely
nothing about [ __ ] it doesn't matter who
you are unless you are a professor being
very in something very specialized field
then you know that thing where for
example you guys okay you guys if you
program and see if you are a C
programmer for ten years then there is
one thing you know and you know where
that is how to program see the technical
details but the important thing here
here is a consolidation okay the
important thing here is that you don't
know nothing about programming languages
okay most hackers think they do they you
know they okay for example Linux
programmers the Linux kernel hackers or
others FreeBSD or others quite a few
then you start have to have opinion so
what what what operating system should
be no no you know nothing about
operating systems okay you know nothing
you you for example if you use Linux for
ten years this and this one thing you
know that is how to use Linux okay well
you don't know nothing about the
operating system designer architectures
that I got like [ __ ] okay
they are only not many people who knows
it that's that is professors who
specialized in this field you know I'm
talking about the general my my general
Angus again is the hacker types because
when you talk up to these hacker types
on Hacker News on reddit everyone is
like they throw jargon so Haskell
Oh monad Oh everything should be no mana
because these are then they know [ __ ]
okay
so especially I mean this well so
anyways that's becoming a rant so let's
see what else so now we can talk about
Nabi setup that would be great yeah so I
think we're gonna I'm gonna try okay I'm
gonna talk to you guys and I don't know
how it goes and and also it's you know
you should I don't have a goal like it's
not like this is something I need to do
and so that therefore my channel will go
it's nothing like that
but I think it's nice so we'll let's see
you know maybe I'll talk to you guys and
get that set up okay
Justine don't like this code much okay
so yeah so discord you know is one of
the big corporations and they'd be
called everything you type on it it's in
their database permanently as far as I
know even messages you delete it and
including private messages you send to
other people but what can you do that's
the nature of things and that applies to
basically everywhere every online
website any anywhere so and even you
know if you are thinking oh I have my
own server no chances are everything you
said on your own server is in a database
of CIA okay
don't think don't think you are oh I'm
open source or something you you know
not not likely unless
like I said before unless you are a
professional spy or you are a
professional who works in the
cryptography industry then if you are
such a person then I can trust that you
know a thing or two about that but you
know like like like this guy the guy
Snowden Snowden who lives in Russia he
has a talk on interview on and on this
idiot guy Geoghan Snowden okay Snowden
Rogan what yeah what's that guys the
radio host okay Joe Rogan yeah that
idiot so Snowden for example he whatever
he say about crypt analysis about this
security in the industry I would put a
high trust on it okay so so you listen
to what he said and in pay attention
carefully and only on things that's
related to you know like what he know
like his field specialized field then
when he talked about those kind of
things you can kind of trust it okay
that's how I judge so what I'm talking
about here
hold on a second so this guy's Snowden
okay so as you know yeah I mean he's
very famous you know because he so you
know so so so what I'm saying here is
when you church people you Church on
what is he experiences now you know what
have he done in the past 10 or 20 years
not not the [ __ ] you know type of
hacker talk you know oh I know about our
insistence I know about networking I
know about everything this Lisp
programmers this Haskell programmers
this this type of programming languages
that's considered elite or Emacs users
they tend tends to give a huge huge
bunch of garbage
they tends to tell you you know what how
how language should be designed this is
all [ __ ] okay and this also includes
famous people like for example let's say
Bo gates okay Bo gates that reaches
person in a word for for the past you
know for for like forty years also Bo
gates so what does he know he know he
knows visual basic okay
he knows the 1980s visual basics he's a
expert but after in the 90s no he
doesn't know he doesn't know programming
okay so when he talked about when if Bo
gates talk about visual basic of 1980s I
would trust it okay
when Bo gates talk about how to run a
company how to manage your company I
trusted okay when Bo gates talk about
anything else about about politics about
how the word should be that's all
[ __ ] okay that's how I judge that's
my that's my point of view that's I hope
it's useful to you I don't know but but
that is how I look at things okay
so Richard Stallman so what what does we
chose storm and no well so so rich a
storm and when he talks about Lisp
history what this is like in 1980s I
would trust it when he talked about
history of MIT the artificial
intelligence industry in 1980s I would
trust it okay anything else it's pure
[ __ ] garbage okay that's Richard
Stallman he's opinions about license
about economy about how society should
run
that's pure [ __ ] okay Richard
Stallman so my point here is that you
that's how I judge things you you want
you you know first of all everybody on
this earth everybody including you know
president of USA or whatever you know
actually police politicians they know
even less they know nothing okay
partitions everyone in this earth don't
know [ __ ] to begin with you have to
memorize that in your mind embedded in
your brain today every person every
human animal on this earth knows [ __ ]
about nothing including of course
including yourself you know [ __ ] about
nothing even including what you think
you know you know you know you've been
working on this for ten years you know
[ __ ] begin with that thought in your
mind then you actually might know a
little bit something that's that's that
is my opinion overview about what people
know you know things like that okay
okay I don't know how this livestream
went and maybe that's it for today we
don't have a topic so okay so let's go
back so what about your opinion so what
do what do you think you know counter
count arguments and counter-arguments so
do you think Oh besides [ __ ] or do
you think what what do you think so
so Navi says they know how to talk
without saying anything they are experts
on that politicians yes
so this is saying he went nice friend
okay so so you know let me since I'm
talking about that topic okay let me
emphasize you know what a person know
when you evaluate person even if he's
famous like Nobel Prize winners for
example I instant okay I mean this this
is one of my you could say pet peeve
okay in modern society there's a jargon
pet peeve American jargon huh how do you
UK people what is the UK's analogous
jargon for pet peeve so so it is my my
pet peeve you know like you know you you
like every day you hear you know people
on Twitter on certain networks video
every day they'll say oh I instance say
something oh something I enjoy anything
this this is that every day [ __ ] they
know nothing that I mean they don't even
know the basics of physics but but every
day is the court iesson instance said oh
imagination is more important than than
than knowledge [ __ ] [ __ ]
crap he logical total complete [ __ ]
you know then then someone will say Oh
Bo gates be okay say something well Fame
and say something you know the feces VIN
you know they then then the Linux view
out that yeah this is this particular
Linux people or the hacker types these
programmers these programmers say oh oh
HTML XML is just a stupid version of sex
[ __ ] idiot okay then the Haskell
people oh the word should be monad every
programming language is should be mole
and monad okay then the roast roast
idiot so these are elite you know code
you know these are code phenomena coat
the drawers people I know many of guys
you know loved roast okay that was rows
people will say oh colon is no good
because we because they don't have
memory management is [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] the entire league [ __ ] you
know nothing you know nothing about
nothing
so when you talk I mean so in particular
when you talk about you know that let me
put it another way so what do you know
it must be very very very very specific
okay so what is your name
that you know okay and you only know you
know it well what is your age you you
know what's your sexual preference
you know I don't know he you know nobody
knows you know that well that's an
example very very very very very
specific and wow there's some huge noise
in my neighbor's some machinery god this
happens every day
you don't hear because this microphone
is like noise blocking I need to cross
the window okay hold on a second
so actually let me give you a view of
this edge of my window okay so you
looking at my mug so let me show you the
so you see here is my computer and that
is a very old computer connect monitor
connected you know it's a dust it's all
dust I haven't turned on for like two
years now
it's a connected to a old PC running
Linux and then there it is my window and
here is the village of outside let's see
and you can see Walker there you know
some kind of they are digging the Kadena
trees okay they are cutting a trees so
back to the Nommo broadcasting and how
long have I been talking 48 minutes okay
maybe that's it okay and then we're
gonna talk about all this this this
phantasmagoria of flower view that's
another topic fantastic topic okay so
almond says spending so much time
looking at the wording a particular way
so so yeah so so what I've been saying
is that you you you know the word is the
word of things it's really huge it I
mean if you you have to I mean you
either yeah I think you don't get this
you know like there's a common quote
there's a common saying there is a
common saying that when you are a
undergraduate when you are suffer more
you think you know everything
typically young people are like the
you think you know a lot oh you started
to study computer science you started to
study the history of Western philosophy
or history of the world history of USA
used you know you learned names you know
historical figures you think you know
everything you know you are educated so
formal
then when you are PhD student now you
are not sure anymore because the more
you learn you the less you think you
know that's you know that's a common
saying when you are you know graduate
you know a professor or postdoc then you
know this a lot you don't know it you
know this it's like that okay so but you
but of course
statistically they surprise to people
you know when they age
we like younger people tends to be like
they think they they do things they
without you know they they are brash but
when you are older you'd you know a lot
more things but then you are unsure I
mean there is also a quote from Bertrand
Russell or someone some philosopher okay
right like they say you know being wise
is like you a fool a fool is someone who
is sure of everything then a a wise man
or some something like that a genius a
wise man then he is unsure about
everything so that that's some of the
common wisdoms
you know so that is my that's what I'm
saying - and this you have to experience
it - no you can't just like you hear me
saying it by tomorrow you you you forget
at all you don't remember a thing yeah
you have to you know this after 20 years
when you get old then you become like
that I think there's a interesting thing
about what happens you know in vampire
movies where vampires they live a
thousand years you know I wondered what
will actually happen if you live a
thousand years
very interesting thing to go into you
know to think about so Alan says so what
what is so Alan says counter-argument
so-called experts often get caught up in
their own models for instance chemists
might only see the word in terms of
chemistry yes indeed
usually these experts when they predict
the future they got it wrong because if
you study futurology which is
predictions about the future you know
the very popular among notes you know
you study what's going to happen
especially today we have the big
question of AI artificial intelligence
what will happen will it be bad we read
you know you know and but you you study
in the past 50 years all the famous
people you know experts in computer
science in math or in physics or
celebrities PDAs the billionaire
businessman who controls the world they
have made predictions about the future
you look at history usually they are
just wrong they are all wrong they are
all like totally wrong but rather those
people there are some opinions which
turns out actually correct but but those
kind of opinions usually does they they
are not from these these experts at all
you mean this this is a phenomenon like
you can you can go online and do
research about that ok so just in gonna
go so hammer the world looks like nails
so it's counter argument for trusting
people are talking about their own
domain
yes but I'm saying I mean if you have a
chemist expert you could trust him about
chemistry I mean like I said it must be
very very very specific you know so if
you have a chemistry expert you know
then you can
you know let's say he won Nobel Prize in
something chemistry then he know that
very specific part think very well that
we know for sure but however his opinion
about let's say related things such as
chemistry education came how government
should sponsor chemistry research what
should be funded what should not be
funded you know that I would I would not
trust it then you know that that's what
I'm saying that's that is that is my
point that is actually my point you know
it must be very very very specific so
you know yeah so that's what I'm saying
so yeah so Alan says a person that
studies biology nutrition might have
some ideas about what is the best way to
eat based on their science however an
athlete traditionalist might have more
practical knowledge yeah people don't
distinguish opinion from fact okay army
uh army says okay I'm about done okay
fifty-six minutes where are you guys
people I'm always looking for people way
so al so army amry anime am I am I says
okay so Emma says actually science is
most mostly based on trust
especially with tribalism in science act
scientists tend to bias experiences and
observations okay satisfying on the
workers what workers oh yeah they are
cutting trees huge noise I thought I
knew so much about computers when I was
20 so so I'm I say it's true even most
associate even most seasoned researchers
only know
specific narrow topic okay
what are we doing now are we going to
shut down are we going to shut down
let's see
so Snowden okay you can go go watch
Snowden's video you know and listen to
him talk about very specific things and
and also money you know this another
thing about conspiracy theories you know
they fly off all over the place it's a
mess it's kind of a mess you know and
this this problem how do you get society
so that how do you how do you manage a
society so that each person actually you
know we have solid good information as
opposed to you know insane or crazy
ideas or UFOs or conspiracy theories and
how do you define conspiracy consider if
conspiracy theories things like that you
know there is no there's no absolute
answer it's not like there's a magic
pill that you can just there's no magic
formula you know on these kind of things
you know what is conspiracy what is not
it's it's it's it's a permanent eternal
problem okay and I'm just giving you my
take that let's say I'm just giving you
my take today about how what things you
can trust how do you judge upon a person
you know you know how do you judge what
he knows therefore you can trust once
you have this idea what he knows then
you can trust that specific thing he
says and there are so many things today
today in society I mean even just in
programming there's game programming
even came from I mean there are ten
subfields you know this AI engine
there's a graphics engine there is a you
know character design there's a gaming
architecture there's a you know so many
nobody knows nobody knows anything [ __ ]
you everyone knows [ __ ] about nothing
you see because the you have to
understand the exponential growth of
Sciences that's what it means
so so you web programming for example
everyone knows JavaScript you have like
10,000 libraries and it's changing every
day
nobody knows like nothing yeah anyway
that's kind of that's that's what I'm
going that's what I'm saying about these
things okay so let's look at this code
okay what people are saying so George
okay Georgie is wake George says a lot
we call Western philosophy is actually
Near Eastern philosophy Western
philosophy is pretty young largely based
in Near Eastern philosophy but divergent
sorry replying to way old messages okay
but I don't know what George okay the
other thing is you see I'm talking in my
live show so I can talk about a lot of
things and you know I can express myself
I can articulate about many complex
issues such as philosophy but since you
guys are you know textual you guys are
using a technology of text so other
people I mean you gonna you are not
doing a good job of expressing yourself
compared to me using voice and my facial
expressions so usually if you give some
opinions you know on complex topics like
society and philosophy
oftentimes I don't get what you mean
because you know a simple sentence
cannot express it so I can you know
nothing I can do so so that's why I'm
thinking you know we can do a you know I
you know you guys do a talk and we can
start to talk to each other and learn
things learn things learn things and
so we don't get beaten by AI and
technology and these things like that
okay that's it that's it for today I
think what else so George for example
George says a lot of what we call
Western philosophy is actually Near
Eastern philosophy like what what do you
mean I don't know what do you mean yeah
you know like to me Western philosophy
is has roots in Greek philosophy you
know Greek you know when we think about
Greek philosophy that's agent from 2,000
and 3,000 years ago quick philosophy
which became you know ingrained into
Rome the Rome Rome Empire then you have
Christian arity you know so that's what
I think about you know that that's what
I think
that's that's that's that's that's
Western philosophy but George says you
know as George says George you always
have very interesting ideas and I like
George's ideas but George says a lot of
week a lot of what we call Western
philosophy is actually Near Eastern
philosophy hmm so what do you mean and
George says Western philosophy is pretty
young you mean American philosophy so I
don't get you know I don't get what do
you mean and George says largely based
in Near Eastern philosophy but divergent
okay so near Easton what do you mean by
that you mean Indian the ancient Indian
civilization you know with the sand
script sand script you know script 3,000
years old script also so yeah so I don't
you know so so what I'm talking about
here is that there is a problem when I
go on to say talk show and when you guys
expressing opinions you guys opinions
don't have much power
you can i yeah you know yeah you know
unless you guys go on voice and so go on
voice is another thing so okay so George
says quick Greeks aren't Western okay so
as yeah but then then that becomes what
how you define Western you know because
for example for example you know the way
I'm thinking right away is that quick
for example Europe is named after Europa
which came from quick-quick
mythology Greek Europa Europe so so if
you say Greek philosophy is not Western
philosophy then they becomes I you know
to me then it's a issue of how do you
define Western you know so so maybe we
you know so that the so that so that's
the direction we have to talk so anyway
that that's about it today okay so yeah
no I think yeah that's one hour yet
let's see let's go back to Google one
hour okay good bye guys have a good day
my and go to my website and by myself by
keyboard spy surf okay and this girl let
me tell you she's got oh my god looking
at this girl this girl with huge boobs I
spent hours digging a two into the
history of linguistics and gaming
industry in Japan and the mythology of
ancient mythology of Chinese and
Japanese culture about these flowers the
story you know the her background story
and lots of things and also Western
Western Greek mythology you see she
holds this weapon this is faith this is
form we
you know kind of the Reaper you know and
then then you actually I actually went
to YouTube to look at what exactly is
this site how do you use it so I went to
YouTube these videos and indeed there
are people using it today you you use a
site to cut the floor so or weeds or the
or grains you know weeds you have to eat
you you so I actually learned what is a
site like in real life because the site
always looked strange to me you know the
Reaper and by the way
Reaper which is from again quick
mythology most mostly they Reaper do not
always hold a scythe you know you
started to read you know Wikipedia for
example in other places you started to
read and you know the Soul Reaper you
know you started to read about the
history of Reaper so actually so there's
a lot of things about this but anyway
that's it for today no no scythe is
ergonomic Oh George don't get it wrong
site site is very open economic the
straight site you see here that's that's
not reality you have to go to youtube to
see the real site they all by the way
they make it in Australia George your
country like this this this company
hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo is famous for making
site so they are in Australia that's
what I seen you know there's a YouTube
it's a site you have to check it out and
it is ergonomic ok so ok ok bye