Good evening. Welcome to another episode
of Exile Talk Show. We are going to talk
about emac coding stuff and randomish
and artificial intelligence. The the
artificial intelligence AI writing um
programs is getting amazing. If you are
watching offline, play at 1.5 speed
minimum because I ramble. If you are
here, say hi. Love to see your comments.
Okay, say hi.
So you know so a lot of people are
talking about AI coding. So you know you
see fancy code but I I'm not sure I
believe it. So for example this guy
asked Grog to create a visualization in
JavaScript uh for the oiler's identity.
So this equation so so you know
apparently it did it. So if you can look
um for example let's see uh go to talk
show and uh so I'm not going to talk
about that today but that will be
tomorrow for uh so for example
opening brave
and uh magnify okay so this guy asked
Gro so and Gro apparently generated this
application it's amazing you know even
if you don't understand the math but but
I doubt it because I doubt it will
generate you know um the code correctly
if it generate the code I believe I mean
if if you are um
today if it it generate the code but you
needs to be JavaScript expert and uh SVG
expert in order to fix it to get it to
work that I believe because I have asked
a lot work questions and it's amazing
ing answers artificial intelligence but
however if you ask it uh the AI bots to
create a game I I'm not sure it works uh
unless you are expert then you can try
to fix it then you'll work so I'm going
to try this tomorrow and George in our
in our forum kasar discord just asked AI
bot uh Germany
to generate uh what's what is the prompt
uh here? Using only HTML and JavaScript,
create a visual that helps me understand
Pascal's theorem. The page should have
an overthe-top Barbie girl aesthetics
use 3D animations and it created the
code. So, I have to try that tomorrow.
It's this amazing. This is just this is
just incredibly amazing. like
unbelievable.
So, but anyway, that's not what we're
going to do today. So, um because we
already have a topic. So, uh today we're
going to do close close back to Emacs.
Uh we're going to do some Emacs stuff.
So, for you Emacs, the best the best
coding editor. Okay.
Uh hey, George. So, hello Talid.
So we're going to uh so there's uh so
George you have to wait uh I'm going to
ask AI bot some emac questions but but
most of this is kind of esoteric you
know hasht it can generate hash table
for sure if I ask gu you know I have gu
here
uh for example let's say uh
generate code of hash table
in Emacs Lisp. It'll do it because I've
asked many similar questions in
different languages. But let's see.
Okay, it's pretty long. Well, it's
actually writing a tutorial
the implementation. So, it generated the
code. We we'll have to verify it. Then
it says uh the implementation tries to
explain make hasht correct function
equal test. That's correct. That's
particular to EMAC bisp uh create table
h#put. This is incorrect.
There's no function um hashput but you
have put hash. So you know let's this is
outright in incorrect. This search
function does not exist. Okay let's try
uh so emac this mod is not highlighted
means it's incorrect. So copy describe
function hashp put no match okay there's
no such function but you have put hash
okay so this is incorrect outright so
even a simple problem like this it's
creating incorrect um answers so I doubt
if you ask you know that's why I find it
question questionable like some people
are asking it to generate 3D games and
it it generated prototype and they show
some screenshot but I
those those are grifters okay
because I don't think it can do it one
shot and and whatever code it produces
it requires someone with expertise in 3D
game programming in in order to fix it
for example if I ask to generate a 3D
game like a like even a ping pong I'm
not I'm I'm I don't think he'll actually
do
Uh, and I'm a JavaScript uh, expert, but
I don't even know if I can fix it
because I've never coded games before.
But anyway, let's try the let's go with
the lisp. Okay, let's try see its
answer. Okay, so hashport is incorrect.
What is this? Create hash table.
This this oh define it actually define a
function of creating a hash table. Okay,
this is uh well this is also incorrect.
All size uh oh okay this is wait this is
correct uh hashput. Oh
so interesting it created it its own
function a wrapper hashput to
to add a key to hash table. So it is
correct. Jesus
get get hash hash get okay table key.
Okay, it actually rewrote you know it
could this you know the get hash is a
function but it defines it its own oh
Jesus remove key value pairs from hash
table. So the hash table it uses uh
string keys. Okay. Uh in eag you need to
specify the equality test in order to uh
if you want to use string keys as
opposed to uh uh you know others other
like symbol keys uh integer keys. So you
it also define remove hash. Okay. So
those highlighted words that means
that's building function. So this I can
see it's correct. hash contains okay if
equal uh if if equal
get hash key table and uh otherwise
return not found if wow if this is
correct so it seems to be correct from
what I see so that's hash contains then
hash keys return a list of all keys in a
table
map hash that's correct lambda the key
value push key and push push it to um
so you push to the keys and return keys.
Okay, that seems to be I think it's
correct.
Hash keys get all keys. So it actually
defined a function like generated a API
by itself.
Amazing.
Hello ACP. Why do you have a ACP? Why do
you have a like uh
like the crown sign? Oh, that's my most
top fans.
Top top fans.
Am I going well? Am I like are you guys
watching me? Let's see. Check check
check.
Okay. So, so um let's get get back to
the code. So it actually created a API
entire API by itself. Hash size. Okay.
Let's just try the code. Okay. So it's
got sample code here. Define hasht
example. Demonstrate hasht usage. Oh
god.
Wow.
So what does this do? Uh this this is
the main thing. Uh hasht example
demonstrate hasht usage. Okay. It
creates a hash table by its own
function. Uh then hashput that's that's
all its own functions. Okay. Then print
some values message name hash get my
table name edge. So what is this uh
hasht hash get my table.
So query for the name. So the name edge
city is already added. So it just print
name edge and check has city. So it's
checking the hash content function. Then
keys get all keys get all values get the
size of the table and remove the entry.
So it's testing the remove function it
defined here and then print it if it's
successful. hash
uh after rem removing edge after
removing age size is now that clear
table. So this is seems amazing. Let's
run it. Okay. Run the code. Save it
first. Okay. Uh xx
hasht test
AI hasht. Okay. So now put the
underscore in the file name and name
itel. So now open it. So now it's uh s e
v smart. So let's run the code. Run it.
Wow. No errors. Okay. No errors. Now
let's just call the function. This you
know it
uh
let's call the function hasht example.
Okay. then show the output in uh let's
show the messages buffer. Okay, right
here. So now
show my pink window. The pink window
shows my all my command course on the
right and the keystroke on the left. I'm
using keys and vor keyboard. Okay, now
let's run this run.
Wow. Can you see that name John H is 30
has city true keys CT age city edge name
values New York
uh New York 30 John that's correct size
three after removing edge size two after
clearing size zero
wow perfect 100% perfect code
Jesus
I'm out of my job. My eaglist [ __ ] My
eaglist tutorials took me 20 years to
write. Now I'm out of my job. Perfect
code. Not a single one, not a single
part I can say is incorrect.
Not a single part.
Okay.
Well, okay. So this and and also emacisp
is one of the less used language
compared to say python javascript. So it
actually generated completely correct
code.
Okay. And uh it actually created a
function wrapper by itself creates
creates its own API hashput hash get
hash remove hash contain and they are
well named you know because the emac con
convention you start with a keyword like
the library name.
So this is very impressive and then then
to use this in Emacs it tells you what
to do but anyway and then it explains
the hash table uses equal as a test
function which allows allows for various
key types string number symbols that's
correct the implementation is built on
eag native hasht function for effic
efficiency that's right
so so it is 100% correct Correct. So I
would score it 100 this AI answer. Wow.
Yeah. Fairly impressive. Okay. So let's
copy the code. Let's go to today's talk
show. Let's create a section on what we
talked about.
Uh yeah. So create a section uh and uh
create a EMAC this code section. Paste
it there. syntax color it go to the top
and the title would be
ask AI to uh what what is our question
generate code of hash table in emac this
ask guac AI to do that okay showing
browser so that is the first thing we
did fantastic stick.
Okay. Well,
that's kind of that's kind of scary and
disappointing. I mean, it's exciting,
but Jesus,
nobody needs my tutorial anymore. And
and and whatever tutorials, Stack
Overflow, you know, they all collapsed
basically.
Se, you know, quite serious
consequences.
And then it relates to the question
whether programmers still going to have
a job. I always deeply believe so. AI is
not going to replace programmers. But um
because well the main the main reason is
that you can you know if you have a
specific question it like that you can
always it might be able to answer but
however most of the time when you
working a job you don't know what is the
question you know you have to talk to
your manager several managers get a feel
what they want and you know talk to your
client clients whatever then you know
then you know you you don't have a exact
specification and they change all the
time. You never have exact
specification. So
uh so usually in real world jobs it's
not just one language I mean create a
hasht that's like a toy uh toy puzzle
you know that's not even a toy it's just
in the documentation
but in real life you have you need to
touch on not usually not just one
language but several other things some
of them you know protocols technology
you know uh networking you know
basically you need to formulize what is
the problem. So and uh you can't and
even if you know what is the problem you
cannot you cannot make it into a
question like usually
the things you have to do
it is hard to turn it into a actual uh
concrete question so I think so I don't
know so you know nobody knows what's
what will happen so that's that's that's
impressive so but let's go on okay there
are several other things I want to do.
Uh, okay. So, let's see the comments.
You ACP says, "YouTube recently created
the crown icon and applies it
automatically to encourage engagement
the chats and super chats." Okay.
Cat 09 Tails. I remember that name.
Hello. In one of your video, you said
that Wolf Mathematica is free as in free
beer nowadays, but I I go to their
website and it's not free. Well, you
just check out my website. Like every
time I mention it, I mention my website.
So you go to wufam language, search for
wam language tutorial on.info,
then click on the download, then there
is download wam engine. So on Wufam's
website, you know, don't be tricked into
some spam websites, you know, like there
are probably quite a few spam websites.
So on Wufam, www.wfam.com wufam.com
official website they have. So turn on
JavaScript refresh. So they have Wufam
for software developers you know about
you know they they are like lots of
marketing. Okay. So but anyway on this
page
uh you download fast intro uh download
there. Okay download they're going to
ask your email and some questions like
do you work or whatever. So remember
this free download is for personal use.
you know if you are a Google and you try
to do this if you are you work for
Google that that that that would be
illegal anyway so don't don't do any
tricks okay like I know you a lot of my
followers they are like Unix Linux
hackers you know the free software open
source [ __ ] okay they're going to
be announced okay oh I'm just going to
create a new email for this because I
don't want to be tracked you know if you
have that mindset wam language is not
for you. Okay, just forget it. You know,
go to your Python, go to your Python,
whatever, numpy, okay, JavaScript. But
if you really want to try the
technology, you know, you click
download, follow instructions, give your
email. I mean, just email, okay, just
that's all you know and and your work.
Okay. So uh ACP says Han after 20 years
you have uh earned the title of EMAC
this master is no master.
Well
not sure about that AI is you know AI is
surpassing humans. Um but what I know is
that you know it now because of the AI
you know it devalued
uh you know almost all tutorials
um book writers you know um so anyway
that's that's AI okay so let's copy that
let's um
so wuam language okay copy that wait uh
download wam language okay so wuam
language not not to Do language
download. Copy that. Close that. Okay.
Go to talk show. Uh today's talk show
and uh
Okay. So
they are download WAN language. That's
what we talked about. Okay. So there's
some other things I want to talk about.
Let me tell you. Okay. So recently I've
been busy. You know in the past two days
I've been working on Emacs list my
tutorial. So a new page about the
keyword symbol. So this is kind of for
advanced immacoders
you or liver. So
should I go over it? Uh because then you
know few people understand. So anyway
Emacisp is a symbolic programming
language. So it has a symbols concept.
Now one of the thing about so symbols.
Okay. So you need to be a eacisp coder.
If you don't know anything, you know,
you might learn it from my Emacs basics
from the beginning, you know, basics.
Then then the EMAC list section. So I
have several like over over 100
tutorials
uh writing EMAC list. Okay, there's
there's one uh EMAC list for beginners.
Search on YouTube, you'll find it and
quite a few by others other people. So
anyway, in mag you got the symbols but
but you know so basically means what it
means is like the identifiers in other
languages in Python, JavaScript, C, C++,
Java, you know you have uh so-called
identifiers for variable names or
function names, right? But in EMAC this
those are called symbols not just not
just called symbols but they they
actually they
uh the identifiers can be held
unevaluated.
So for example in Python so okay so I'm
starting to explain what is a symbol
uh okay so let's do that.
Oh god then then I got other things I
cannot finish. Um so
uh
so okay so what is a symbol in Mac?
Okay. So, so uh Python. Okay. So, let's
go to Python. So, v let's say this is
python. Okay. Print xx, right? You
run it. The result is three. So, that's
then purify the code. Okay. So, that's
so xx is a variable. It has a value of
three. Whenever xx appears, it becomes
three right away. you know there's
nothing else to it. Similarly for
function names you know if you define a
function that function name just just is
a function body. Okay but in in in lisp
that's different. Okay so in lisp you
any identifier is actually a symbol and
you can kind of manipulate it. Okay so
uh so eag this for example. So, so let's
do the same uh set QXX3.
Okay.
So, now it actually uh wait. Okay. So,
okay. So, you can see it's three or you
can see it in the message buffer. Okay.
Three.
Now, so xx is a variable and the value
is three. However, you can get xx by
itself. So, uh for example, xx is is a
symbol. Okay. So, meaning that meaning
that for example um uh okay so
okay you do that then evaluate it. Okay
let's do it again. Evaluate it and put
the output here. So it returns just xx
meaning that it return just the symbol
itself. So mean so so what what that
allows you to do. So every identifier
can be uh manipulated.
So this is the meaning of um
symbolic programming languages. Okay.
They they just deal with symbols. Okay.
So syntax color show in browser.
So it's you know to for much further
explanation you got to go to read my uh
my uh tutorial about it because
it takes sometimes to uh
to to see the actual details and because
of its symbols that allows you to have
the immacro
um feature. Okay. Uh I'm not going to
talk about that.
Okay. But symbols but another thing. So
there's there's a spe a special symbol.
So whenever a symbol start with two
colon in front that means that symbol
uh cannot be assigned. It's it's
so-called self self evaluating symbol.
Okay. So this this is most useful in
hasht for hasht keys. Okay. So that's
why it's re related. That's why I wrote
this new page.
Okay. I uh kind of so and and and this
this so when a symbol start with a colon
that symbol is called keyword symbol.
It's called keyword in short in EMACSP
and I think in common this as well.
Okay. So why is it useful? It's useful
in hasht keys
uh and it is also used in functional
functional uh function parameters named
parameters. Okay. So here uh is example
where you call the function you know my
test three and uh something something a
value something something a value those
are named param par parameters. Okay.
So it's a convention. You start the
symbol name by colon colon. Now it's not
just a naming convention because when a
symbol start with colon colon it has
special meanings. It cannot be assigned.
It it's basically it's it serves the
same purpose as kind of just a string.
Okay. Uh a string that can never change.
Immutable string. Okay. that that's what
this colon colon symbol means.
Okay, so that's that. So that's you know
I wrote about this. This is also new
page function keyword parameters for
emacisp and uh and here's a hasht
tutorial. So that gu just demonstrated
correctly but here is my tutorial about
hasht in emacisp
and uh so I updated a lot a whole lot
yesterday and today to so now there's a
example for example uh for example gu is
going elaborate you know he's doing he's
creating a entire API for hasht but but
the whole thing hasht for example copy
that you know let's let's show the code
hasht
uh hasht
so we we talked about symbols and the
emac this paste the hasht code so we
talk about we talked about symbols so
let's
kind of uh meaning of symbolic
programming lang uh meaning of symbolic
programming language Okay. Cut cut cut.
Make a new section. Paste it. Delete.
Delete. Delete. And uh and uh where is
the like these symbols? Okay, let's put
that there and put that there. Paste
showing browser.
So a new section meaning of symbolic
programming language. Okay.
The better name would be meaning of
symbols in Elis. Okay, that's better.
Not too advanced. Wuam language by the
way also also is like uh is symbolic.
Okay, so then we explained keyword. So
let's go here. So let's move this
keyword.
Okay. and uh and also function
parameters.
Okay. And then now let's talk about hash
table.
Uh
okay. So wait uh what? So that goes
there. That that that that that that
syntax color remove that showing browser
meaning of symbols
of okay then hasht okay hash table so
there's a example let's run it
okay very simple so you create a hash
table and specify the equality test is
going to be equal. Then you add hash
push hash A1 B2 C3 then return the value
of the hash table. So if you run the
code, it returns this thing. Okay. And
comment it out. This is a literal
expression for the hash table. You see
hash table test equal data 1 2 3 ABC.
Then you can get hash
C from XX hash table you get three.
Okay. So that's
that's the example simple example of
hash table. So put it back syntax call
it.
Okay. Hash table. And what else? Um
so there's something else I want to do.
So let's see.
Okay, nothing. No comments.
So, seven people watching. So, how long
have I been going? 40 minutes. Okay. So,
let's see what's the next I want to do.
So, uh let's talk about uh softly keys.
Okay. So, let's remove that.
So you see recently I made um changes to
safely keys. Um
how should I should I go explain the
whole thing?
So what do you guys think? Maybe I
should uh that maybe that's it for
today.
Hasht.
Hello Hank.
you know the next thing
I don't think go answer so this is
getting into more practical issues okay
but in order to explain it um because
you see what happens is that I have this
safely keys right I talked about many
times it's a uh you can go there see and
there are quite a few videos I've done
in the past. So, Soundfly Keys is a key
binding system for the Emacs editor. So,
when you if you use it, you don't have
to press control or old keys much. So,
it's like Vim but more efficient. Okay.
So, it's a key binding system.
And uh so there is a problem. Okay. So,
um I mean what is the problem there?
There is a problem. I mean that I mean
so you want a way so inflight keys you
have command mod and uh and uh uh insert
mod. Okay. So let me remove the
highlight for now in order to explain
this.
Okay. So uh let me let me do that. Okay.
Okay then. Um,
okay. So, right now I'm in softly keys.
Okay. So, hold on a second. Let me do
something. So, I removed the highlight
current line. You see that's was kind of
weird, but that's um because I made some
changes, but let me do something first.
Okay. So, let's uh let's let's remove
that. Remove that. Okay. So save it.
Okay. So you can see right now I'm using
SFY keys. You know your cursor uh cursor
is Wait. Uh God, wait. Why you turned it
on again? Uh hold on a second.
Um
remove the hook. Remove the hook. New uh
it it turned on. You see the highlight
came back
because Oh yeah. So global highline mod
you need to turn it off. Okay. So now
close new buffer something. Okay.
Okay. So in South keys you have insert
mod. So when you are insert mod
you can type and L just insert. Okay.
But when you are in command mod like
right now anything you any key press you
press is going to be a command. For
example if you look at the pink window
if I want to move the cursor to the
right to the left one word I press this
key G on on Vorac U on quoty. Watch the
pink window. Okay. Press.
So you can you can see press
and it says backward G. You see? Press
again. Press again. So I move the cursor
by one single key. No control, no meta.
Okay, that's when you are in command
mode.
So you can move to the end of line,
beginning of a line or delete a word or
undo. So you can see the in the pink
window you can see they are the commands
and the keys or single keys. Okay.
But you need a way to indicate whether
you are in command mode or insert mode.
So the cruiser will tell you. So you see
right now there's a giant red cruiser
that means you are in command mode. So
if you press a key to switch to insert
mode the cruiser becomes an Ibeam.
Insert mode. Command mode. Insert mode.
You see now there's another indicator
you can see at the lower left you know
when it's in insert insert mode the
first character is I when it's in
command mode the first character there
is C in this bar this bar is called mode
line okay the EMAC technical jargon for
this bar is called called mode line or
you can think you can call it status bar
I used to call it status bar because
that's familiar to most people.
Basically, it tell you tells you which
you know the current buffer what major
mode it is in and other information like
number of lines in the buffer.
So you have command mode, insert mode,
command mode, insert mode. You you need
you need this you need some way to
indicate
which mode you are in that will help you
otherwise it's kind of like it's kind of
confusing. Okay. Now there's a problem.
Now if you go to uh terminal
uh fail load setting
uh
okay my Windows terminal just failed.
What the rock?
Wait.
Oh god,
my Windows terminal failed.
Uh, because I was tweaking some
settings and now it just failed. What
the [ __ ] Let's close it.
Close all tabs. Okay.
Okay. So, Jesus
very annoying.
This
I think you know something because I
started um OBS that's why there's this
problem. Is that correct? If I quit OBS
then the problem goes away. I'm guessing
because you know before I started before
I did live stream everything is fine but
let's see if I can maybe something um
You know this is really annoying. Do you
want to close all tabs? Yes.
Okay. Why is that Windows terminal?
You see this is not right.
Oh, that's Windows PowerShell.
I'm starting I'm supposed to start the
PSWS not Windows PowerShell. Okay.
What I want to do is I want to start
Emacs from terminal but something is
preventing you know but my PowerShell I
mean this this is the Microsoft terminal
application is not is somehow starting
PowerShell instead not the not the
PowerShell the crossplatform one.
Okay. So what can we do is that we can
try to quit OBS and stop the stream for
a few minutes and see if the problem is
caused by OBS.
That is just my guess because OBS it is
related to the graphics card and there's
some you know complex magic going on
there.
Or I can just start Emacs here and uh go
on with it. Okay, let's try to go on
with it. Okay, because we don't need
PowerShell anyway. Actually, I want to
de you know I want to show Emacs
in terminal with Safly keys. Okay, so
let's let's do it.
Okay, it's not working. Oh, it is.
Okay, fantastic. So, so now we are in
Emacs
running keys in terminal. For example,
let's go to um close that.
Uh let's see what a Python output. Let's
go to talk show.
Okay, talk show. Close that. Close that.
Now go back to terminal. Now
open talk show.
And uh today's talk show is right here.
Open it. Okay. So it's kind of terminal
is kind of ugly.
And uh but you see
when you are in EMAC, you are in command
mod or insert mod, the cursor shape
changes. But that does not work in
terminal. You see I switch it doesn't do
nothing. So this is very confusing.
Okay. So you want be able to
to to to have it uh change the cursor um
shape. One way to do that is via
kind of a hack
is via this this uh
this
highlight
highlight line mode. Okay. So what it
does what it does is it just highlight
your current line. Okay. So if I turn it
on,
okay, you see it highlights the current
line, but but it doesn't highlight the
whole line right now is because I define
this thing. Okay, so I actually
customized it. So let's let's change it.
Uh if I set it to Neo, uh that just
won't work. Okay, set it.
Oh, now it works. Okay. So if if it's
Neo it re reverts to its own highlight
current line function.
Okay. So so basically we are turning on
let's close that we are using the
highlight
highlight line mode to highlight the
current line. So we if we are in u in
insert mode we can turn off this mod.
Okay. So that is the trick I'm using you
know I I you know I'm I I want to use
you know I have been using
so that way in terminal
so that you know if you highlight
current line so can we do that yes okay
so so what you do is let's see uh let's
stop that so here is my customization
actually
you can see my custo customization at
my Emacs blog.
Just go to Kafly Keys,
Emacs tutorial,
then Kasar Emacs packages, Kasar
packages, Karly keys,
customization,
and uh the section
mode status indicator. Okay, so there
are several uh things you can do. So all
you have to do is copy this line, this
part. So copy it back to terminal, start
a new buffer, paste that, then
eva buffer.
Okay. Now you see
uh now you see it highlight. So command
mod I mean insert mod command mod. So
you can see
insert mod command mod.
So when command mo command mode is on
it'll highlight the current line. You
see on off on off
but why doesn't highlight the whole
line? That is because right now I have
some settings that's [ __ ] it up. Um I
mean not not [ __ ] it up. So that
that's this this. Okay. So So if we
restart Emacs here, that'll work. Okay.
Restart Emacs.
Okay. Now
uh
oh uh wait you need to so that then
then add hook. Okay now back here. Exit
restart Emacs. Uh why does it uh
NW means no window runs in terminal.
Okay. So there it is. So now
command mode, insert mode, command mode,
insert mode, command mode, you can move
the cursor and stuff. Then insert,
insert mode. Okay.
Okay. So that takes 10 minutes to
explain what's going on. Now the next
step is to explain what I want to do. So
right now, you see we when it's in
command mode, it turns on the highlight
current line. And when insert mode the
the current line is off. So you can type
something you know but still it's
confusing you see when you know then the
cruiser is um
the cruiser now is a single you know
thin line.
So that is why I want to set it so that
when you highlight the current line,
don't highlight the entire line, just
highlight the part where the cruiser is.
Okay? So that way it's a work around of
the problem that in terminal the cooer
shape cannot be changed by the by
whatever is running in the terminal.
Okay.
So that was that that is what I'm going
to talk about. So that's that's about
all these all these lines. Uh so I think
that's esoteric.
I don't know if anyone is following me.
Is toggling insert mod and command mode.
just a matter of swapping key mapping in
and out.
Yes, that's the idea. But the implement
implementation kinds gets uh kind kinds
of gets esoteric because
Emacs key binding system is very
complex. You have major mode, you have
minor mode which takes priority. Then
you have all sort of other kind of
remaps. Some of them has priority you
know remap and key translation. So it's
fairly complex.
Okay.
So when you just naively you know set a
key map
you have problems because some in some
mod some key will not work. So
eventually what we did is we made softly
keys to use trans to to set up transient
key system. Okay. So this is getting
into like very technical detail. So you
go to EMAC tutorial
Emacs tutorial and go to the
uh Emacs keys everything you want to
know about setting up Emacs keys.
Okay. Then you can find an article about
about about
um about transient
map which is also how you what you use
to make a key to repeat for a command.
Like once you press some key to call
that command then you press certain keys
it will repeat certain commands or or a
subset of commands. So that's this what
this page is about repeat command by key
transient map. So it is implemented
using using this what's called transient
map. Okay. So what it what it means is
that it's a key map. You know emac
convention is it you know whenever a
function or variable ends in dash map
that actually means a key map. So when
so transient key map basically is a key
map that only last for a while. Okay. So
so so the way stuff keys use it is that
whenever you switch to command mod it
set up the transient
map
for all command keys.
Then if you switch to insert mod it
removes the transient key map. That's
how that's that's how it is implemented.
So this way
this way
other mo modes major mode minor mod this
way guarantees that safely keys always
work in any mode you know it doesn't
matter whose package you know you are in
whatever package you download is you
know works the way expected
because transient map has highest
priority.
Okay. So that is uh that is why.
Okay. So this is uh [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] up. You know I don't think this
is a good video because every time
because because
I was planning to talk you know every
day I want to do a you know talk show
but the so so these are things I have to
do like every day I spend few hours you
know like right now the task is to set
up this
you know this this setup so that uh
works well in terminal for stuff keys
using this highline, you know,
configuration of high line mode fairly
complex. You have to dig into the
documentation, you know, for example
uh
what
describe
function
highline
highlight line mode. Okay, the name is
fairly uh complex. Okay, so you go to
the you go to the source code. So it's
300 lines of code. Okay, then you have
to read it, of course.
Then you can you know you read the
documentation then you can figure out
you know what are the configuration how
do you how do you control the highlight
color how do you control how many
characters to highlight and things like
that. So you spend several hours on this
then
then you've noticed you know the the
background the theme doesn't work well
you know like then then you started to
look into the powershell configuration
you know like one hour two hour becomes
three hours okay the powershell
configuration
then like right now all of a sudden
you know my powershell doesn't work
anymore because this this is not you
know this this is Windows PowerShell uh
exit.
Okay, like this this you know no the key
the key I press that usually starts PWSH
which is the crossplatform PowerShell
not the Windows PowerShell you know so
that's another difference you have to
know
um so now that doesn't work
so anyway so I have so the thing is you
know I have to work on this so I thought
why don't I work on it and meanwhile
I'll do a live show so I can tell you
guys what I'm doing every day. But but
usually like right now
I I cannot actually do any work be
because before I do any work I have to
spend 20 minutes 30 minutes to explain
you know what am I doing why do I want
to do it things like that so usually
that's um anyway anyway random chat
Okay, I think that's it. I like to do
more. So, so there is um
Okay, that's it for that for today. Uh I
got to go figure out why PowerShell
doesn't work. But let me quit OBS. Okay,
maybe it's OBS. So, let me just quit it
and I'll be back in, you know, within
two minutes. Let's see if it works.
Uh, are you sure you want to exit? No.
Stop streaming.
Is my streaming back?
Okay. I Okay, I think my stream is back.
How did How did you discover that you
cannot customize a cursor in terminal?
That is that that is just normal. Okay,
that is that is the case with terminals
because terminals is Asian technology
like 30 40 30 40 years
uh like 40 years technology.
Okay, that's it. Bye guys.
Bye Hank. Bye everyone.