good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of
talk show you are watching xatv
and today is 2021
april and april
12th and today we are going to
do wufan language coding okay
let me show what i'm going to do so
there is
my exotic show topic notes okay that's
my random notes on things to talk about
so today i'm going to do probably an
hour or 15 minutes
no more and i'm going to code
mathematica
wufram language okay so if you have
questions about wufam language
just shoot okay and uh
am i alive check voice check video check
yes my hands
uh look let me show you my pen spinning
non-stop
so this is kinesis advantage 2 keyboard
it's a fantastic
ergonomic mechanical keyboard and
programmable
on the fly programmable this is my
favorite
350 my friends and the other one you are
looking at
is ultimate hacking keyboard i use as a
macro
pad for example last window back to last
window last window last window
and let's go to a browser and
look at these two so previous tab
previous tab previous
previous previous so i can just all
single key press
now if you see if you look at this web
page you know one single p press to
magnify toggle toggle magnify window
and you can see algorithmic mathematical
art
now this is very related to what what we
are doing today mathematical
mathematical coding mathematica can code
all of these in fact
why don't we begin with that okay uh
it's just for
you know i'm coding the mathematica of
i'm going to do some of my
i need to plot and write some programs
for my website but for fun let's just
let's do this one okay
so for example let's see how mathematica
does
okay so this is a implicit plot 3d let's
see if uh
implicit region okay um
contour plots 3d i believe
okay i believe i'm not sure
i believe this is one yeah this is one
last time
we yeah last we haven't showed this one
but so let's do this one okay
contour plot 3d and
what is the stupid
you know mathematica i think you know
they should have a feature where
when you just press tab and it um
you know gives you all the template for
the
arguments so come to plat plot 3d
what what's going on so you need that
so let's plot that that
that equal i believe
uh in mathematica it's two equals three
equal
to equal yeah so x x means x max
okay and i don't want those sub
okay let's do this okay hold on a sec
copy let's go back to what is this let's
go
back to uh emacs
okay i in fact i'm thinking of writing a
uh what reference link
what's going on what's what's what's
yeah pause it knew what that
okay i don't want that contour plot just
let's just
plot it myself okay let's write it so
that's uh so
x from uh
0 3 2
3 okay and do the same
for y and z
okay so that is our expression copy that
and let's go to mathematica let's see
what it does
try it options expected oh yeah so we
got extra comma that's not allowed in
mathematica
now it's plotting
okay i don't i don't think this is
working oh
yes it is fantastic
now you see let's let's see the full
glory of this
okay so you can see
so you know i call this thing a bulk
cube
like uh 15 years ago mathematica cannot
do this i believe the first
version that does this is around 2006
yeah so this is fantastic actually i
want to you know
i want to increase the resolution so
uh increase let's say three to six okay
change three to six
okay let's read of that
okay this this way it's easier to see so
let's plot
another one do it
okay again you got the extra comma here
mathematica doesn't like that
do it good morning potato eater good
morning
grim system admin
where are you from grim system admin in
usa i think
um so let's so let's see let's look at
this
it takes a while
so this is mathematica you are seeing
what
oh oh oh okay now it's done now let's
let's see the full glory
yeah what's going on i want to yeah
toggle window yeah so i want to
make this big
okay so you see isn't that beautiful
this is the beauty of
mathematics you see you know you can
just
plot random kind of uh things
and
you know you can observe their structure
so this this
is called technically in mathematics
this is called
implicit part of a equation of three
variables
and any points on the surface is a
coordinate
x y z and they are a solution to this
equation
so in mathematica you call you know this
is done by contour plot
okay so that's uh you know that's power
of mathematica you can
you know if you are industrious
you can write this you can try to
implement this in python or golang or
whatever
with a graphics library this is
beautiful
that do that to be a nice cube hello
bass
bass haven't seen you for a while okay
so that is
uh you know one of the things and again
this is uh
done by mathemaker this one is by
michael trott
who is the i would say the top
expert you know let's say let's put a
number the top
100 uh among the top 50
let's see uh top 50 okay
or even top 20 uh
master of mathematica programmer michael
trott he works at wolfram research
you know since 1990s i met him when i
was there
and he is known for the you know this
fantastic
this is this is done back in back in
1995 but by the way
so today you look at this it may not
seem that you know great but this is
done in 1990
1995 and in fact
yeah so he's um you know he wrote
several books but he's not
you know if i may say he's not a great
uh writer he's
you know yeah his book 1999 you know
this graphic card
is like three volumes huge and
the code is impossible to read
anyway but this you know it's old book
20 years ago it's probably not worth it
i don't think it sold much anyway
back then anyway michael trott okay
michael trott is the
top expert mathematica programmer
and he was you know he's a physicist you
know he's a
russian i believe russian yeah he uh
physicist
uh that's his background you know uh and
also
anyway so i was i'm starting to talk
about lots of these
um random topic well that's today's
you know i'm not doing something uh
specific today let's try this one okay
now remember you see you see the graph i
have here
you see this one which i call this one i
call borg
cube this is created this one is plotted
by
uh this application called uh
graphing calculator it's simply just
called graphing calculator it's
fantastic it's um you know if you search
for it
there's a a very weird wonderful story
you know this is an application that
apple macintosh
included in their power pc around 1990
you know it's uh part of the mac os uh
yeah when when apple
switched from motor roller chip
to the uh power pc chip around 1995
or 1994 or something like that yeah so
then apple mac os included a
application called graphing calculator
and this
to this day it's a best graphing
calculator to this day okay
you can find and and and there's a okay
let me let me talk about it okay so
let's go to
so you go to sally math okay go to my
website math
okay go to math then you see
a bunch of these things
then you want to go to
[Music]
um math software okay
then you go to curves and surfaces
now these are a bunch of great software
i haven't checked for them for a long
time i mean this is
from a professor my friend professor
richard palace
and this i haven't checked
uh anyway some of them the link might be
dead you know last time i checked this
one
is there it is you know the person on
home side you have requested has been
retired
okay you know usually they are phd
students or professors
so okay the link is done
but usually you can find
uh you know the new url by
okay so yeah so here is the new url
speedvac uh it does differential
geometry this application
oh internet archive gee okay yeah
so people moved on you know from
yeah yeah this this website actually
cites my website for it yeah anyway
so you go to you know you go to uh my
website
sorry so i need to update this but
anyway so here is the graphing
calculator okay
uh okay the new name is new cac
now there's an interesting story now
this this application is created by
wrong
avatar uh a kind of weird
uh a weird programmer you know it
doesn't
who doesn't work 925 incorporate you
know incorporations he
he's a how do you say hacker hacker
types
so he wrote this application
it's not official but eventually it
became you know
he he's got a story somewhere here
if you search for let's see if i have a
link
yeah yeah i think i don't have a link
but you know
he has a sorry about how he got his
application
included in apple and he wasn't even
paid by
apple that what that was back back then
um you know not like today's whole
cooperation works uh
let's see if i can find the story maybe
this one
the graphing calculator story okay so he
actually he did the talk
yeah okay anyway so he did a talk at
google that this
is uh 2012. i mean
today's google is something else now
so anyway he you know so that is
a uh that is one of the great you know
this application
the the home page is not very good you
know it's kind of silly but
this is uh one man's product you know
one weird
programmer hacker type product anyway
that's one of the
it's a i would say it's the best
graphing calculator okay
anyway because i have tried you know i
have literally
tried hundreds hundreds literally
of softwares that does math since 1990s
so this is my compilation of it and
today i haven't been maintaining name
that much because there are so many you
can i cannot keep up
and there are a lot of javascript ones
but anyway this is uh
uh used to be popular anyways
so i was saying so how how did i mention
yeah so i was saying this is plotted by
graphing calculator and you can also
rotate it in real time
and now let's go back to some math okay
now let's go back to
what i was talking about now
uh
okay let's restart over
math some math
algorithms where algorithmic
mathematical art now let me explain
about this article again this
article hello how are you i'm good
how they were just in sci-fi so what
math have you been doing
fuzzing hello fuzzy no i'm not are you
are you do you have a job offer for me
post you know private message me
so justine scofie is a mathematician
at a canadian university of vancouver or
something right
anyway so back to so i was talking about
uh by the way this article
algorithmic mathematical art i wrote in
uh which which i consider this to be one
of my great articles
it does two things one it
gives you a overview of mathematical art
you know of different different types
different approach for example geometric
surfaces
that's what you're seeing this is
raymond sphere let me show you my this
is my professor
uh you know raymond sphere so you are
looking at
uh raymond sphere let's let me show you
not
not that's not raymond's fear that was
the uh
this is raymond surface okay uh which is
let me show you
so you have a bunch of beautiful uh
mathematical surfaces
ah where is it uh wait
surface minimum surfaces okay that's
uh raymond's surface is a minimum
surface right yeah
so you can let me turn on javascript so
you can see so if you want to get
get serious about this you need to study
uh
this these are part of differential
geometry okay
so this surface you know you are you are
only looking at part of it
you know you know it's cut off so
imagine i have always want uh i wanted
to do this
imagine try to implement this thing
in a gaming engine you know like you
guys gamers unreal engine or whatever
engine try to implement this so that
so that you can for example become a fly
and fly around the whole surface
now remember this surface you are seeing
here is cut
it's only part of it it should be like
you know it should like partition the
plan into
into like infinite rooms you know
so it's not like round it doesn't have
edges like that it just
you know in order to draw them uh
practically that's why they
you know it's cut like that but actually
it should just
like feel fill out the 3d space
uh and you know so what is this one so
this one
shows how they uh how they how different
um surface of this family
uh changes
so this is raymond's surface and there
are so many others
okay these are called mineral surfaces
so what i was saying so i was saying
yeah so back to this article so
the first part is a outline of all the
different mathematical arts
so you can see here's another type they
are related to
regular polyhedrons or polytopes
you know you can see then you have plane
curves you know different
fascinating now this is not the boring
trigonometry
you see in your math classes when you
see this
it makes you you know want to be a
mathematician
but it's basic it's trig trigonometry
this you know for example this one
is a trig equation so let's go back to
mathematica let's try plot that
okay so uh so
[Music]
so let's uh
okay let's go to contour plot
this time not 3d just 2d okay and the
equation
is that instead of that comma
and x y okay so let's try that
back to mathematica paste it
run it
loading will find research server i
don't know why that happens
now i don't know why is contour part you
know i hate that
so that means you need to you know
because contour
should be it should be part of the core
mathematica as opposed to
you know requiring to connect to
ufam so i thought you know anyway
so you see this okay so let's try to
change the parameter this is too small
so 6 let's try
16 okay
okay so this is mathematica's rendering
now i might i want to make some
you know you might you know this doesn't
look so good you might so you want to
increa
increase plot points and things like
that
uh you know let's say 2050
that should make it uh yeah now it's now
it's beautiful
so this is an implicit plot you know
each point
is x and y and it's a solution
that makes this equation true
so beautiful you know so back to the
so and this image this this one is
density plot this is done in mathematica
okay
uh and this one was plotted in
yeah actually it's also plotted in
mathematica i think i forgot anyway
so first of all this article gives you a
outline of different type of geometric
artwork these are inversion
you can study them in geometric
inversion which is not very popular
topic
you don't usually learn this in you know
in if you go through
a math major in college you know
yeah inversion but but you know they are
certainly
part of math you know or
if you have done complex analysis then
inversion is basically one over z okay
one over
uh you know the one over z that's what
geometric inversion is about
so okay so inversion so these are
different inversion pictures
and here is a transformation of the plan
and here is a recursive turtle graphics
or our systems
uh beautiful this is uh done in
mathematica
uh and this is famous
uh a famous curve called uh
a snow snowflake and another famous
titan
pink wheel tiding and this is in
australia
uh let's see so i kind of um
okay i kind of lost my goal like
i'm just talking random okay nobody's so
let me okay let me finish giving you a
description of this article so this
article first of all give you an
introduction
a a survey of all different kind of
a um wait uh
different kind of math artwork okay then
you have fractals
uh and you have uh plotting functions
these are functions of
norm q on a unique on a unit
disk so i don't know what is norm q and
this is a
plotting of complex function then you
have titlings and patterns
okay celtic knots
uh very fascinating because carded knots
you know historically
it's just a culture you know decorative
artwork
from north north and uh
europe you know uh you know scandinavia
those
people you know their artwork their
culture cultural artwork
but if you study it mathematically uh
you know so it's part of not theory and
linkage theory so if you look into
um you know
and not theory has a very interesting
history because in the beginning
it's kind of you know it's about nuts
right uh like
if you don't know about math you think
wow yeah not
so yeah you know if you are a boys uh
boys scout
or something you know you study this you
know it's very interesting
for a lot of people but it's surprising
you know it's amazing that this is
actually a proper
subject of mathematics very deep okay
and it in the beginning uh it aroused
because people wanted to study quantum
mechanics they
you know they i i learned about the
history from stefan wufam's talk
so apparently people wanted to study
physics you know model the quantum
mechanics or something
then they thought that you know the
space
you know at some level is made of knots
so you have to study all the possible
configurations of knots
so that's that's kind of the origin of
the history of not theory let's see
you know we can check history here
archaeologists have discovered not
tying blah blah blah okay that's a
different uh but anyway so
hyperbolic geometry topologist
uh yeah there so in 1860s
lord kelvin's theory that atoms were
nuts
in the ether led to peter
gundry's tales creation for creation of
the first not tables
for complete classification there that
is i would claim
this is the beginning like the beginning
of
uh not theory like stephen wolfram uh
told so this is the first time in 1960
you know people started they they want
to have a classification of all
different type of knots you know
that's one thing mathematicians study
and this is part of
uh you know a classification is a big
big type of activity uh in mathematics
so it's amazing you know so when you
study fix physics you think that
you know atoms were nuts in the ether
you know either is a
non-existent thing it's a old idea that
turns out to be city but you know one
thing leads to another then
he then we started to have not theory
which is a complete
you know now today is a complete a
branch of mathematics you study not
uh and and and now theory then you have
then you have ties to
to geometry to topology to group theory
you know
uh like the typical how how math is
very you know very advanced i mean but
but not theory you can study by yourself
actually you don't need you don't need
calculus it's part of
uh it's kind of part of a discrete
mathematics like i talked about
last time so in my professor friends
uh project 3d explorer math virtual math
museum
you can see several of the interesting
notes
you know for example this one is called
uh
let's see oh yeah oh yeah this is
actually javascript oh yeah you can turn
it
fantastic this is created by uh
caution herman who is a
the words one of the top
experts in differential geometry uh
and it is he who created most of
the minimal surfaces you know he because
he's the one of the top expert
in minimal surfaces uh german guy
hermann
casher you can see if you click around
you know this is written by him
a friend he taught me a lot math so but
you go
up so but he also do you know
kind of interesting other math things
not
you know this is not really you know his
focus of study but anyway so he wrote
this
let's see we can what is this
this is the size
so this is what inner radius
you know the this this knot is called
taurus not because
it can create it imagine it's a line
going around a donut
so that's why it's called torus not so
let's change this okay so you can change
you know you so you can change um
you know that thing anyway
okay back to so you know knots many
uh many things many things interesting
about knots
uh and here is a curve vbn curve okay
so let's see so back to uh you know
counted so
originally it's a decorative arts
but if you are a mathematician you look
at this
your your you know you might look at
from a different perspective that is not
theory
and link theory linkages now
great it's called ray theory okay let me
show you uh
search for b-r-a-i-d okay
braids do they have a link they do
you know wikipedia is the great um
resource so here is a great theory you
can see
so this is the mathematician study of
braids
you know so it's kind of so you guys
programmers you
these topics are something you would be
interested you know if you are beginner
you know like what what do i study how
do you go about studying math what made
you interested you know
so i'm giving you i'm telling you that
very theory not theory is something you
can go to
and group theory okay you don't need
calculus because typically you go to
university it's calculus right
and calculus you might think oh it's
boring you know it's trigonometry it's
like
but here so you have great theory let me
let me show you some other thing about
braid theory because uh it's
you know let me give you some incentives
to go
into uh braid theory because you know
you read wikipedia it might seem boring
but let me entice you with some pictures
okay why braid theory
why for example i myself
is so fascinated you know why it
fascinates me
why it makes me why do i want to study
braid theory
so for example 19 you know 19 is again a
human
artifact very ancient you know 2000
years old or something or even more so
you see this
beautiful amazing you know uh
weaving and stuff you know cable night
so
women you know women do this right yo i
mean you used to be your mom or your
grand grandma
but today is much lots of these are done
by a machine but anyway look at
the intricacy i mean imagine i mean
imagine even this is a puzzle how do you
possibly figure out you know which
you know how the thread go you know
where it goes so that you form
this pattern how difficult you know
imagine there's such a
incredible and beautiful
you know human creativity you know this
wasn't invented by a mathematician like
a mathematician sits down and designed
this no it was you know after centuries
you know trial and error almost like
your other mostly women you know they
moms you know they created this uh
amazing thing
and here's a more elaborate one you know
cable so it's called cable knighting and
then look at this one okay this
this is a again something a bit
different this is a
table cloth okay now but but look at the
intricacy
okay so it's magnified so you can see
you know you probably have seen this in
real life amazing you know
it to me it's just amazing how is it
made
and and more so how mathematically you
know how
how where does the you know
the lines should go under or over to
make to create this
coherent uh one piece and pattern you
know so
and then you have the chinese cultural
stuff called chinese knots okay it's a
thing
you know like today if you are american
you probably heard of
origami you know how do you pronounce it
origami you know the paper you know
artwork made by paper
and uh and so these things are kind of
similar but it's
a different uh and also there's a
hyperbolic you know surface culture you
know
amazing so amazing okay so let me show
you
yeah so uh great theory okay so that's
uh
that's that's you know you might study
very theory you know
begin by go go read up wikipedia very
theory and not theory
okay and okay so let me go back to my
article
algorithmic mathematical art so first of
all a survey
of all the different artworks surfaces
polyhedron
then curves plane curves then geometric
process
okay so we have inversion but also you
can
you can have projection from higher
dimensions to
2d to a plane this is uh one such
example
so it projects higher dimensional
spheres to a plan yeah
so and also when you watch this in in
animation in real time it's amazing you
i i don't know i've seen this before but
i think it's
if you look around yours you'll find it
you can see this picture
in animation so what you are actually
seeing
is a projection from from a higher
dimensional sphere
into a plane yeah
yeah i don't know you know you might
search for it
and plant transformation you know fish
lens
or kind of thing and air systems total
graphics
uh fractals recursion artwork made out
of recursion
then you have uh plotting function
processes
okay uh then you have kelted knots
knots and braids and and this is uh this
is a i believe
islamic yeah islamic style uh kind of
artwork
uh and you have weaves and
you know that patterns and
this is this is a modern thing uh
penrose tithing
also the history of penrose titling is
amazing okay
if you have not yet go read it up on
wikipedia
the history of penrose tiding
then you have uh hyperbolic titans or
some
other you know hyperbolic geometry uh
yeah those and then you have a you know
computer generated um
uh computer generated
geometric tithing you know amazing you
know
if you look at this in detail you see
some goes up
some goes down so it's a
not you know it's a not a linkage grade
network however
the each of the weave you know each of
the line
they must be positioned in certain way
so that so that you form
you know stars you know it's quite
amazing
so that's why i find this you know
amazing this this one is made by
nodplot.com
which is ancient this website is the one
of the most popular
around 1997 okay when
i had my website you know this like
award winning all the
you know it's a history so it's internet
history so this website is one of the
top visited website around 1998 okay
late 1990s to
even up to 2005 because he has
lots of uh non-works you know today you
look at this
kind of city it's small you know small
images
found is too small there's no css
there's no javascript yeah because the
web technology changed
but back then this is this is like a
great you know
great website and in fact your whole
screen is no more than
than than this picture that's your whole
monitor is just that big
that's that's how things are
so anyway so so that is from these sites
okay so you have nuts then you have
fractals
proper okay fractals now again if you
have
not studied um you know this is part of
complex
analysis okay i'm trying to get you guys
to
you know introdu introduce you to
uh mathematics you know because myself
i'm mostly self-taught and it took me
you know like a decade to actually begin
to know what are what
you know i'm not a math professor so i
don't really know that
deep but i can you know for you
programmers i can give you
kind of like a guide and telling you
what what is
uh about so if you want to study factors
this kind of thing you want to get start
to study
complex analysis okay that's the
that's the branch of the math that's the
name of the branch of math
mando broads set okay now
i want to also make a rant you know like
most of you my audiences are programmers
right
so in fact you have seen
you know if you have seen the fractals
on the web
most of them are created by programmers
okay for example this image is created
by programmer
this image beautiful you know even
though it's very beautiful
it's created you know some here's some
more examples it's created by a
programmer okay
now these programmers typically they
know nothing about mathematics okay
they are just programmers like you and
me
okay so these programmers you know you
you can learn what it is how to create
this plot but
you don't really actually understand the
math
okay so this is so why am i mentioning
this
it's an interesting phenomenon because
almost all the
all the fractal images you know you have
like back then around the year
year 2000s you have like 10 000 millions
of these
very popular you know but however they
are not created by
mathematicians they are just great
programmers
so what's the point the point is that
you know the point uh what i'm trying to
say is that
there's a kind of difference a big
difference between the programmers
mentality
and mathematician okay so
okay one thing i'm trying to say is that
if you you are
um you guys are programmers right so
when you see this you might start to
study it in fact you can do it right now
you know and you started to
create write a program which generate
these images
and very beautiful and very fast right i
know that because
all my friends are like that you guys
but
it's almost always the case these
programmers you know
you know even they spend a year or two
in factors they
they never picked up any real
mathematics okay
let me go to uh
mandelbrot set okay okay so for example
let me go to wikipedia let me tell you
i mean what's the difference between
math and uh programming okay
so for example again you have these
fantastic you know
actually this is animation you know you
have these fantastic
imageries these are almost always done
by pro
you know very great mostly professional
programmers many of them work at google
or facebook and so on
but however if you read wikipedia you
can see for example let me tell you
which part are the math
okay so definition whenever i said is a
set of values
of c in a complex frame such that
critical point z equals
zero under the iteration of the
quadratic map okay
that okay and remains bounded blah blah
blah
so let me tell you like then i'm trying
to tell you
uh so you have a
main cardiod and period bulbs
hyperbolic components local connectivity
okay this okay yeah so these are math
okay but i'm trying to
um find more of the
generalizations okay so
yeah so this page half of this page
actually talks about kind of
superficial things okay uh
i want to
am i getting boring okay so okay so let
me go
let me let me finish this and actually i
got go i gotta go
uh i'm i'm right now i'm trying to
pick out part of this article that is
very
mathematical and uh usually the
programmers just ignore it because
that's very interesting because you know
there are certain you know
mathematicians the way of thinking and
looking
looking at things are very different for
from programmers programmers they get
excited by you know just trying to plot
this
and make it fast but however when true
math no of the you know programmers
ignore it like that's it for them
so okay anyway that i i'm not i'm i
didn't find the part you know i want to
find lots of like
equations and deep theories but
basically let me tell you okay
mandelbrot set is one of the most
fascinating and arguably difficult and
wonderful
part about math it represent let me show
you okay that represent almost like
the deepest question about humanity
about the universe you can find it in
mathematics okay
almost in a sense okay i mean this is
not
in any absolute sense for example you
wonder about
how far you know the stars how many
stars are there how many then you
then we understand there are galaxies
then we understand you know
you have uh solar systems then you have
uh different
other star systems then you have gala
you know and then you have you know uh
star clusters then you have galax
galaxies then you have galaxy galaxy
clusters you know as we
advanced in the past 100 years we know
more about the
the universe cosmology okay that's one
thing that's one you know one aspect of
our wonder you you wonder about life you
know
another aspect is like what's the
meaning of life
you know can we live forever you know
what happened if we die things like that
now in a in a in a different
in another aspect that's mathematics
okay and fractals
uh in particular mandelbrot said
represent one of them you know
it's like you have this thing that's
made out of equations you know kind of
recurs
recursion and this thing so happens if
you know it has this extremely weird you
know
what we call factors now you know
self-similarity
and you can zoom in and you'll be
infinite you know it
you'll be infinite and they'll still be
very similar to itself you know
so that is one of the most incredible
fascinating uh you know the heart
why mathematics captures so many
people's
uh you know eternal attraction for
humanity
even though it doesn't give you any
money you know you just
you just want to study kind of look into
you know that's
uh that's what i'm trying to say and one
of the
uh great question about this mental set
you know if you look at the definition
let's see if we can find the definition
you know this this article is not very
okay formal definition okay
uh yeah so here is a formal definition
okay
now now one of the question is whether
this
set is connected you know it's like it's
part of the question in topology
and that question is just um that's very
deep okay
you see i'm trying to find um
now i remember someone proved
that matter broadside is a connected set
and that's not easy i remember somehow
it doesn't show up here
i remember i read it on wikipedia like
uh maybe 10 years ago
compact set you know closed this and so
on so
disconnected so who was it okay this guy
there also
exists a topological proof of the
connectedness
that was discovered in 2001 so
yeah so this kind of thing these
things okay so it shows you know it's
connected yeah so
here let's look at let's look at that
link okay
so yeah okay so this this page is a
general
uh discussion about what it means to be
connected
well anyway you read you'll find the
name who who was it first proved it
and things like that and let's look at
jeremy kong okay who is this guy
mathematician okay jeremy khan and vat
ma
something so this
is uh it's american mathematician he
works on hyperbolic geometry riemann
surfaces in complex dynamics okay
so yeah so anyway anyway so
so back to uh so we talked about
fractals okay
mandelbrot said the wonders of
mathematics the deepest
uh attraction of the universe uh
and back to my artwork you know my
algorithmic artwork page so then you
have higher dimensions this is
a higher dimensional regular polytope
okay which is
a polyhedron but regular polyhedron but
in four or five or six
dimension you project it or you slice it
into 3d
and it becomes like that okay he's got
you know this
most of these people i've contacted you
know
or emailed in 1990s or or 20s
they have a website but unfortunately
it's written in java which is dead today
so you cannot run it you have to you
know you have to install java and do
you know stuff to get it to run uh
anyway so
this is a slice of a higher dimensional
thing
into 3d and then you have this
fascinating
this this one by jeff weeks okay he's a
cosmic cosmologist okay he's a physicist
in cosmology i i went to his lecture one
one time at uc berkeley about
15 years ago uh
you know he is talking about the shape
of space okay
so you can go to his website and you can
download the program
for mac for windows for you know ios 2
io ios these days so he's got
you know you go to his website he's got
quite a few fantastic
um yeah he's got quite a few fantastic
uh
uh programs written for geometry okay
so uh so jeff weeks okay and back to my
article so
actually my article is long i haven't
started to talk about
then okay so you have higher dimensional
space you have fractals
which is different type of mathematical
art the higher dimensional space
then you have evolutionary programming
now this is the famous stefan wolfram's
cellular automata it forms this kind of
thing
also again fascinating computation the
nature
you know if you're a programmer you are
you'll be fascinated by the nature of
computation what happens
if you if you create a random
programmage
and just let it run forever what happens
to it you know what kind of
what what types are there what's their
behavior
you know that's what stephen wuffed his
interest his primary
focus and so that's called cellular
automata and other
including other systems then you have
asia okay s
asher you familiar with then then you
are
you have the transformation the
how they call this um uh okay okay asia
is the
probably the first one to create this
but now it's popular now there's
there's a guy a mathematician i'm
kind of acquainted with he's a canadian
he
um he have done you know project
and thesis about this so and he has also
written a program
that tells you how in general how to do
this kind of
uh gradual transformation okay
so you can see
okay i gotta go i uh my alarm clock
come on so this is a this is uh ashes
you know gradual transformation from one
shape to another
it's called i believe the it's called
parquet deformation
or something maybe they have a new name
these days
anyway so the first part of my article
is about
um a survey of different kind of
type of mathematical art now the second
part i define
what constitutes an algorithmic
mathematical art
first of all i talk about what is
mathematical art for example some of
them are not
mathematical art which a lot of
programmers love okay i despise
for example ray tracing you know if
you're a programmer in my circle so you
know you if you love c
programming language c plus plus rust
you know in float
java you know long double short code
stack
if you are into these kind of things you
are
you love this ray tracing because
everywhere you see these type of people
talking about ray trace
now that is not a mathematical art okay
that in my definition this is not
mathematical art okay this is just a
you know computer-generated image okay
so let me show you some other examples
that's not a mathematical art um
okay anyway my i gotta go so my articles
too many so anyway i want to tell you so
i define i give you a definition
so what is mathematical art mathematical
art is a art
work that has a mathematical structure
okay
that's inherent inherent inherent
in it okay if you look at this artwork
and if there's a mathematical structure
now then it's mathematical art for
example this one obviously
this is a you know the structure it's a
it's a sign it's made of cyan cosines
okay
and this one it's a you know it's a
rayman surface it has many
properties okay it's a minimal surface
that means
in okay i'm not going to explain what's
the minimal surface but anyway you
and this one for example is based on the
symmetry of
uh poly uh
uh octahedron no not octahedron uh
data cohesion okay symmetry of nautical
hydrogen a very mathematical structure
okay
same thing for all these all these uh
polyhedron and this one is you know
again it's a
solution to a you know embodies this
uh equation so it has has mathematical
structure
similarly for this you know inversion
of circles or projection of higher
dimensional
circles or spheres to 2d you know
they all have mathematical structure and
this transformation of you know the
fish eye lens you know it's a
transformation of the plane
very mathematical structure because how
it transformed the plane is very
regular you know it you know and this
also mathematical structure because it's
a recursive and this the whole
graph is made of a single line
you can see i i created this you know
the whole thing is made of single like
single
line uh so in that aspect it's uh kind
of interesting
and okay so all of these have a you know
the artwork
itself the visual artwork itself has
a inherent inherent mathematical
structure
in it okay that's a that's a key thing
you need to remember
so if that is true if the artwork has a
inherent
inherent mathematical structure in it
then
that is a mathematical artwork so same
thing can be
can be said for these fractals or newton
factors this is a newton
so called newton factor because it's the
graph of trying to find the root of the
equation and this is a mandelbrot set
defined again by a recursive formula so
this is actually
a visualization of you know of a
recursion you know of a math formula
a function and again all these two so
this
this is the shape of space this is a
higher dimensional polytope or regular
polyhedron
again okay so all these so
you know and again if you look at ash's
artwork for example this one
it's very you know it's uh why is it
mathematical artwork
because it has a inherit uh it has
because it has a math structure embedded
in it okay
why because you see those you see you
can can you recognize these four
uh circles symmetric in the middle but
however you
use you also see these four yellow
circles
they kind of you know in a pattern then
this pattern repeats you know so you
have a
blue circle blue circle blue circle blue
circle
and then you have a red circle you know
it kind of repeats forever
in inwards or outwards so that's a
that's
a inherent mathematical structure so
so this one classified you know qualify
as a mathematical artwork
in my in my definition okay
and and this one the same why does it uh
is why is it math because
you have two uh mathematically defined
curves
these curves is is called equiangular uh
spiral you know i show i talked about it
the other day
okay so that's mathematical you know
when
artwork has a mathematical structure in
it that's a mathematical artwork
but not uh so that's why
that's why this this is not artwork this
is not a mathematical artwork okay
and sometimes you'll see a bunch of
others let me show you some others okay
that's not
mathematical artwork but somewhat
popular too
uh let me show you okay so okay so go to
my
professor friends website then you can
go to
uh math art okay
uh so this artwork okay these are math
artwork okay these are but however some
of them i don't
i don't consider them to be for example
the the
this one uh you know these they try to
mix
factors with some kind of humanistic
mystic
touch okay okay you know okay this
artwork okay so that's fractal art okay
so you see
they try to you know mix mathematics
with
you know you like you started to do some
painting on it
so i don't like i i think i think these
not do not constitute
uh mathematical artwork in fact i don't
like them
you know i i don't like them at all
then you have you know pope book is also
very
famous he is a very great uh geometric
programmer but this one
you know if you look at that is it
mathematical does it have
inherent inherent mathematical
structure in this artwork i wouldn't say
so
okay does this one yeah
maybe maybe uh yeah actually it is this
is a calabi yaw surface
in from string theory okay you okay so
you can
consider that to be your mathematical
artwork
okay invert inverted charged titling
okay this is also qualified i guess
okay okay actually his work mostly
qualified
but i want to show you some of them
that's
common but uh very uh not mathematical
okay we started to see them you see so
you know yeah it's artwork but this is
not a mathematical artwork okay
it's based on you know some math ideas
okay this one again it's
it's an artwork but i wouldn't call it a
mathematical artwork
it's just a artwork that's uh with heavy
metal
influence influences you know
you know you get my idea i think and
uh these ones in the same way i don't i
don't consider it mathematical okay
so that's my mathematical artwork
that's you know that's my definition of
it uh now let me go back to my article
and finish
explaining my article okay so that's how
i define
mathematical art that's the first part
very important
now the second part is even even more
important so
what do you mean a algorithmic
mathematical artwork okay
so this article i'm trying to define
the concept i'm trying to define the
concept
algorithmic mathematical art okay
so first of all i define what i defined
what is mathematical art
but what do you mean by algorithmic okay
uh that takes some time to explain so
but i gotta go but but
basically um
so imagine suppose imagine you have this
artwork
okay this one is asia very famous and
it's very beautiful and it's also
mathematical because
it's it's 100 symmetric you know it's
purely with a pure mathematical
structure
that means with this artwork there
you know it there is an algorithm
like in embodied with with the whole
thing i mean like like
the whole thing can be generated by one
single
sing sing single and simple
algorithm okay that is what i mean by
algorithmic mathematical artwork that
means you
have to write a program you
if you write a program to generate this
work
your program may not be a algorithmic
mathematical artwork if you if your
program do not follow
do not capture the inherent
inherent algorithmic process
that is in the artwork for example for
example if you draw this one
if you are like asia you know you
started to paint it you know
for example if you make a photocopy of
this and you started to
write a program that start to draw each
pixel
you know from the top to the bottom so
you obtain a computer program that can
generate this picture
however it's done by drawing pixels per
pixel you know that that's
you know you so in your program it has
no
you know it doesn't have a the beauty of
you know it doesn't
capture the algorithms at all so if you
do it that way
then that program is not a algorithmic
mathematical odd okay even though the
result is
is the same that is essentially my point
so
you can write a computer program here's
my point you can write a computer
program
to generate every single one
mathematical artwork on my page here
okay however
you your program the algorithm used in
your program doesn't matter
how what program language programming
language you write it in c
golan c sharp scheme list mathematica
okay
your program must use the algorithm that
inherently
capture the embedded structure of the
artwork
if you do it that way your program is a
uh i would uh i would say
uh algorithmic algorithmic okay okay
thank you for watching if you like my
stuff donate patreon okay
i gotta go uh yeah okay i'm gonna go
thank you
bye guys patreon me paypal me
don't forget i must mention that