Hello, good morning. Welcome to another
episode of Talk Show. We are going to uh
talk randomish. I'm going to work on my
website. If you are watching offline,
skip around and play at 1.5 speed. And
uh if you are here, say hi. Love to see
your comments. Uh I typed so much in the
past month. I have hand pen, you know,
both. Now it's right hand too. So, let
me show you my keyboards.
Um, so this is SWAR board. SV A L B O A
R D. So, I'm going to start to use
it. SV A L B O A R D. Fantastic. Okay.
And uh this is
my uh glove at keyboard. Fantastic.
Ultimate hacking keyboard. Fantastic.
Fantastic. Newly attractable. Fantastic.
And that's uh well-known
Logitech with a mouse with spin wheel.
Okay. So, let's start to talk
randomish. Suspicious. Unsuspicious. Hi.
Rice wine. Hi. Cheers. This is grape
juice with one shot of tequila.
So I'm working on my website tremendous
you know I've been working nonstop so
many things to do you know end endless
um writings writings to do so let me
show you some updates on Emacs blog so
you can see this is my Emac blog
uh let's
Okay. So, hold on a second. Yeah.
Anyway, so this is my Emacs blog. So,
you can see in this section there is
like 20 to 30 custom commands you can
get. I have updated them. So, all these
are HTML commands. For example, add
paragraph.
Uh you can copy the code and use it.
Fantastic. So that's related to HTML.
This is format CSS code. Fantastic.
Another CSS convert RGB color to HSL. So
you got this
command. Then you got uh add brackets to
capitalized words in current line or
paragraph. Then change brackets. We
talked about yesterday also.
Insert bracket by pair. This is
efficient. The most efficient efficient
way. Fantastic. Check brackets balance.
You can do that. And so many others.
Okay. So, you know, if you just go
through my, you know, so these are
update. So, what's what's new about
them? uh most of them I removed a
dependency that so typically when you
call a command you want to the command
to work on the current text
block sometimes known as paragraph okay
but Emacs doesn't have that built in so
you have to code it yourself so if you
want that code there it is this tutorial
get positional block that will give you
the beginning position
like go over there and end position as
integers. So many of interactive
commands you know work on the current
block. So you need to get the beginning
and end position and Emac doesn't have
that built in. So you need to call this
command which is a external package.
That's kind of annoying because then for
every of my commands I put on my web, I
have to tell people, you know, oh, by
the way, this depends on this package.
Click here and download that. Then this
command works. So that's kind of
annoying.
So over the past 15 years, I've been
like
sometimes put the dependency inside like
like the code just put it in line.
uh then I after a few years I move out
and you know back and forth but now I
put them back in the code again so it's
in line for example to select the
current paragraph that's this line this
kind of long line of code that's returns
the beginning and end position of the
current text block. Okay. So inline so
you don't have to like download another
dependency. So that applies to these 30
or so commands. Okay. Now for any of
these command for example this is move
cursor by text block. Extremely useful.
For example I can go down. I can just
hold the key to go up or down. Every
time it move uh moves the cursor by a
text block. A text block is defined by
having two new line characters you can
see. So you see so this command
basically substitute replace the page up
and down you know so your hand and if
you are using safely
keys you know it's all built in most of
these command are actually all in safely
keys. So download download it get it.
It's on GitHub. It's the most efficient
supreme key binding system for Emacs.
Okay. You don't have to press control.
You don't have to press meta. Not that
much. Vast majority of them are removed.
Just single key press. Okay. Sound like
keys.
So So that's about Emacs update. So
close that. So and this is today.
Um, that's about the Emacs update. So,
let me put a link here. Today's talk
show keys
there. So, yeah. So, let's go back to
Emacs blog. So, that's the update. So,
go there and get these commands, okay?
It's free. If you like my stuff, pay me,
okay? Just go to
kasari.info. kasadi.info. all the way
down you can see my Patreon, my Amazon
gift card and PayPal. Okay, copy my
email address and paste in the credit
card or whatever send to
section. Thank
you. Cheers. So that's about the Emacs
update. Let's see what else I want to
do. Okay, I want to you know I you know
massive working on my website
mathematics f l proof systems geometry
plane curves differential uh
differential
geometry uh then then python python
really sucks so I'm I'm going to talk
about that okay so there's a about wufam
language logo let me show you okay
uh so actually just search for logo
So you can see Mathematica logo history.
Let's go back. Lisp needs a logo, lambda
logo
tool, lambda logo tool. Purpose of logo
and principle of logo design and sambar
logo. One of the best design and SGI
logo. That's one of the best tool. So
let me show you some of them. and uh
website logo and erggo Emac logo. Uh so
and GNU Emacs logo, GNU logo, latte art,
lisp logo, chi logo. So there you know
has got so many so many and kas java
logo. So you see I have a uh I like
logos a lot the design aspect of it
because I'm into design you know
symbology unic code mathematics
programming languages uh and logo
okay so here is wuam language
mathematica logo history so um you know
they are represented by these what they
nickname it to be spiky okay so I have
kind of a history of it. Uh beginning
with version one. Version one is this uh
I don't have a big image like 1988. So
that's 30 40 years ago. You know, you
have to remember back then the memory is
like one one gabyte. I mean one megabyte
is the biggest memory you can get. So
you know so then 1991 version two logo
that's when I started to use wuam
language and version three four five and
so on. Okay. Uh and wam Stefan Wuam
himself has written uh history you know
a lot like his blog one of his blog is
usually takes few hours to read. So he
details
the you know fairly very ind depth every
one of his blog you know
he tells you why this is chosen and the
history of it over the past 20 years and
uh you know like historical uh software
you know this is Mathematica this is
when I bought it year 1992 or so it come
with a box in manual back then, you
know, today you don't have manuals
anymore. Then
t-shirt. I have a t-shirt I worn for
like 30 years. So, it's all worn out.
Eventually threw it away about five
years ago. Uh I have one of the shirt
but not this one. Um I have like two or
three of them of different design. One
of them is this one. So remember all
these are done in
1990. Okay, 1990. And this one is
designed by Scott Kim. I believe this
interlocking
uh interlocking tetrahedrin. Okay. Very
intricate. So back then when you create
graphics like that that is like cutting
edge. Okay. Like there's no software
that allow kind of allow you to do that.
Um so anyway so then history of the all
the logo design. So we are only at you
know so it it goes on on and on you know
the the the complete documentation of
the uniform polyhedra also in the 1990s
there's a giant poster about 1993 you
can buy back then so so now remember the
all these for example this chart uniform
polyhedra in 1992 this is cutting edge
because if you are a mathematician you
study the uniform poly polyhedra.
There's no Wikipedia. You know, today
you go to Wikipedia, you need uniform
polyhedra. There's like tons of
information and nice graphics. But
1992, you you don't even have a book.
You can go to the library, you spend
hours to find a book on uniform
polyhedra. Some, you know, sometimes
it's Asian. You know, they don't have
nice graphics. Sometimes they are
missing information because some of the
mathematical information we still don't
know yet but I think by 1990s we all
know uh all of it. So anyway so you know
the wuam article okay historical details
and also involves uh social history and
social issues. For example, this this
logo
spiky apparently was known in Brazil. Uh
so he talked about it uh you know so
there's also uh back to uh history of
mathematics. So polyhedra this
is I uh
Isaka
um Iicasahedra I believe that's called
what what do you know I always confer or
I
Ias so anyway this one is like 2,000
years old that that I believe that's the
first one found
okay from ancient Egypt so maybe
uh 3,000 years old. So anyway, so then
there's his history history of
mathematics. So that's typically the way
Stefan Wuam writes a blog. So when you
have a topic such as, you know, logo,
you know, you might say, oh, we choose
this logo and that's it, which is the
case for vast majority of tech
corporations, you know, Python logo. Um,
uh, uh, okay. I started to uh like
giving a lecture about logos. You know
there's tremendous things to say about
logos. For example, this is Guth's book.
This summation which I use as my
website my website signnet you know
uh you know there's a lots of logo
design. So but anyway so let's go back
to one thing at a time. So Wuam language
I mean the wufam logo history. So you
can see and it so happens in Brazil. So
here is a history of mathematics. This
by um this this one is back then like
300 years ago or was it 400 that it is
thought that the universe is structured
in a way of nested regular polyhedrron
like this. This this is kind of famous
graphics. Okay. So he talks about that
Kepler. Yeah. Yan Kepler uh one of the
great
mathematician and uh then uh you have
sphere packing problem uh very advanced
mathematics. Um so anyway so so this is
illustration back then.
Um then let me show you. Okay. So scroll
up. So then there you got the crystals
actual uh micro scope photo of crystals
I
believe. So tremendous fascinating
subject. Then you got Penrose titing and
how it relates to all this is zanohedra
or something. Anyway, so you you know if
you want to read one of these blog save
three hours for it minimum just to have
a scan. Okay. So then yeah then he
mentioned where this apparently this uh
this thing is in Brazil culture you know
so someone you know uh told him so he
showed some of that you know so then he
started to search the history of you
know of this thing in Brazil. So it's
quite a story that's a case for most of
his blogs.
Okay, that's uh Stefan Wuam's article,
but you know, so I just have my own, you
know, a little experience about
it. Uh I started to like ramble all over
about this topic. Uh there's more things
to talk about. 11 people say hi. Okay,
say hi.
Uh there's quite a lot you know if I
keep talking about logos then it's going
to be one hour. So for example, let me
show you some um for example this
page logo design in software industry
you know the programmers the typical
programmers especially the Unix C
[ __ ] in Python you know they they
don't know anything about society okay
like 20 years ago you know they call me
a troll you know they say I'm a troll
you know they argue with me then they
ban me because I don't I don't conform
to their thinking
You know like and I I'm not polite. I
just tell them you are a [ __ ] idiots.
For example, Python logo. You know today
it's very well known and the Python
fanatics they love, you know, they they
will promote Python by these two double
snakes Python logo, right? But back in
1990s and 2002, you don't have a Python
logo. Okay? And whenever if you know but
you have some un unofficial ones. So for
example these these these are unofficial
logos and sometime and and I believe
some of they use on Python website I
forgot but anyway the Python fanatics
you know they started to use these are
popular ones. Okay. and Python powered
back in 2005. You know, back then this
web badge web badge thing is popular. So
if you write a blog, I go to your
website, you'll have this, you know,
Python powered, you know, I this website
is is powered by Python, you know, I
love Python. It's kind of promotion web
badge. Okay. So in 1990s, they don't
have logo. So then but then I tell them
you know you should have a logo because
logo is you know logo is a uh graphical
represent representation of ID okay like
my name is Kali each person has a name
but sometimes you have a visual
representation so that's what logo is
and today you see logo everywhere like
you go to any website like Hascal then
at the bottom you know they are like
framework framework websites It's at the
bottom you'll say you spy IBM, Apple,
Microsoft and one bunch 10 you know 20
other logos of small companies you never
seen but just like each each one is a
logo sometimes they don't have a name
you know there's massive number of such
website created by the framework
[ __ ] so so today logo is popular well
known but to these people whenever I
mention you you need a logo or your logo
looks ugly. These tech nerds, these
[ __ ] especially from the Unix C,
they'll say uh and including Lisp, you
know, I had a huge argument with them
like on on news group, they will say we
don't need a logo. Why should we be like
they they are thinking like if you say
you need a logo, they think you are a no
me in today's jargon, you know. They
they they despise you because you are a
nomi. You you wear suits or whatever,
you know, because and they want they are
the real man. The Unix and see
[ __ ] They think they are the real
man. They are the elite. We don't need
logo. Logo is for kids. Uh if you want
to a logo, go to
PHP. That's the thinking, you know, very
common [ __ ]
So then eventually in 2005 Python
started to have a logo you know so
that's double snake snake you know
Python the term why is it named Python
is because there is a comedy show a a
great comedy from Britain you know
Python called Python you can you can go
to YouTube and see some of it is very
funny so the Go van Rossam the guy who
created
Python he named his language um over
that show because it's you know great
comedy then
eventually but then but the word python
to most people it just mean a means a
snake right so he doesn't really want to
you know like you know like you know he
doesn't really you know it's supposed to
be a comedy not not meant to be a snake
however The word means snake. So
eventually he gave up. He adopted the
the snake logo like double snake 2005.
Okay. The python [ __ ] You know
this Skid von Rosome the most the most
comparatively the most stupid guy among
the among the language creators. And he
is not just that you know like the PHP
the the the guy who created PHP or lots
of small
languages. PHP is not small. It became
the most popular
but but you know many language you know
but but Pomang Rosam is one of these
arrogant like passive aggressive
arrogant you know let talk about it. I
talked about it uh in my past videos.
you can see uh like at least twice just
search for Python sucks on my YouTube.
Okay. So anyway, that's the history of
Python logo and I particularly
remembered twice I besides Python, you
know, not specifically Python, you know,
the like twice I argued about logo with
the lisp [ __ ] That's one thing.
Then another incident is I argued about
logo with the with a lobb logebang.
Okay, you guys don't know what is
lobbang
uh wordy. Okay, let me let me bring that
up
quickly. So you go to
kasali.org you'll see a wordy English
section. So this section is about
vocabulary, English, linguistics,
writing, literature,
uh those issues from the hotty emotions
of lexicon, stylistic
concerns, decipherment of grammar and
idioms,
linguisticality, literature and
logicality. Okay, those are kind of the
summary of this these group of topics.
Okay, they are all related literature,
linguistics, writing, writing style,
idioms, grammar and uh uh and logic
because logic is a fundamental part of
linguistics when you study
linguistics you know for example
computer languages is kind of belongs to
that group. Okay. But so you go here
world English ethmology then there is uh
lojang lojang is a artificial language.
I did a video back you know 2021
uh by now so that's four years ago
constructed constructed language so it's
a language created art
artificially so
that language is called lobban and its
precursor the history of lobban the
precursor is called
llan standing for logical language so
this language is designed to be total
pure
logical you know it's based on logic so
it's a human language but based on logic
so suppos supposedly the goal of the
lang of these languages it makes your
expression your thoughts to be purely
logical like the
vulcan guy from Star Trek you know
logical
so you know quite interesting to study
so I did some tutorials back in
2004 but this logic uh I mean, but this
language has a uh logo.
Okay. So, you can go to Wikipedia.
Wikipedia has a lot of information. Back
in 2004, there's none. So, you can see
they got this logo. Okay. So, this
language uh let me
magnify. So, am I am I doing good? What
do you guys think?
Let's
see. Good evening. The daylight saving
in Europe are killing me. So stupid.
Yes, that's true. Same thing in
USA. Uh question. Do you recommend
company mod Emacs to get
completion? Uh yes and no and probably
no. So let me answer that question
quickly. Okay. So if you are using
packages, no because I never use any of
the company. So for example, if I want
completion, well in the case of HTML, I
just press this uh you have uh any kind
of tag, you know, uh and I can do that
in Python, in wam language, in PHP, in
whatever, you know. Here's a code. HTML
mod then there is um you know Python,
PHP, Emac this you know you have seen me
do it. So if you use my packages, I
don't use that comp company mod or that
kind of that mod kind of pops up a
little uh menu right at where you want
to complete you know so let's close
that. So you know for example I want to
insert a tag. I can choose dive undo. I
can choose P undo or I can choose uh you
know there are so many like DL uh
H4 you know and if you have something
here then you call it P wrap wrap it
around your word. So anyway this is
completion in HTML which is done in a
particular way unlike typical languages.
uh but I can also do Python. Okay. So
let's not demo but
anyway
so for myself I don't use company mod
because I you know the the way company
mod I don't have it installed. What they
do is they when you complete tab, they
pop up a little menu just like other
idees that let you select a word, you
know, as you type, right? But okay, I
actually I need to demo.
Um, so let's go to talk show. Let's uh
let's do uh JavaScript. Okay, so uh so
JavaScript. So let's say I want console
log. So I just
cl you got console lock. Uh but what if
I have something I don't remember. So
array you know then a r a there are so
many methods. I press confusion then
this is how my completion works. This is
standard emac way. Okay. Then you can
type form to narrow down to a choice or
you can use arrow to select right range
arrow. So let's say range zero range
zero doesn't you know I don't uh let's
say array
again completion array length and uh
clear in okay not many choices
[Music]
um yeah not many choices because array
this is technicality of JavaScript array
is a function so this array function
only have five methods if you want array
methods then
That's that's that's not that's not
methods of the array function. That
would be methods of the array object. So
that but for for example JavaScript is
[ __ ] Okay. For example, for each fe
there it is. Okay. So you can do array
three
four five dot for each. Let's let's you
know let's print it. So console lock
which means print x then let's say x
plus uh plus f where is my plus key
uh plus one.
Okay wait let's press a key to pretty
format. Okay fantastic run
it undefined. Oh yeah, wait why? Oh
yeah, because for each it doesn't it
returns undefined. Uh so you can print
here. So actually so cut that. So
instead use console lock here. Okay,
then uh then run it. See four
456. Okay, I digressed over.
So, so let's get get back to the topic.
So, completion, okay, we were talking
about completion. This is my method.
Okay, this is standard EMAC
way. Now, how is this implemented? This
is implemented um well okay so you have
to implement it okay via the normal EMAC
standard way. Okay. So you can if you
want to learn
that if you learn you want to learn that
just go to Kasa Emac tutorial you'll
find it if you search then then this
create a major mod. Okay everything you
need to know about creating a mod of
your own language or or Python,
JavaScript, whatever. Then there's a
section keyword confusion. So read this
page you'll know how to do that the
confusion we have just shown. Okay
that's the style. Okay standard Emac
style. So I do not use confusion you
know then there's I mean the company mod
okay because I prefer the standard Em
EMAC interface. Now the other thing
about the company mod is that that they
pop up that little thing that is a major
hack. Okay, that is a majorish hack.
Emacs is not designed to do that because
Emacs is from like 40 years ago. It
doesn't use the framework the Gnome
framework or the Windows framework or
whatever graphical framework of the
operating system. Emacs is its own. So,
Emacs doesn't support you know pop-up
menus or you know buttons. So, Emacs
support them but Emac's own
implementation. Emacs does not rely on
the operating system, you know, the
graphical
framework. So, Emacs does not support
this little popup, you know. But how
they do that? How does company mod do
that? Well, they hack, you know, they
hack to have some kind they hack to have
a um you know, they they they hack it
up. Okay. To to to use uh what what was
it you use? They use they use um
overlay, I think. Okay.
So, so they use overlay there. they they
use this overlay to hack it to to
emulate these popup, you know,
boxes. So, I don't like
that. So, that's the
reason I don't use company mod. Okay.
There's a newer reason. Okay. Another
reason is because in EMAC
um in the latest version of Emacs Emacs
30 released about last month
there there is a
um building support for popping uh for
for for completion company M
something. Okay. building support
completion the completions buffer now
always accompanies I complete okay I'm
not sure but mini buffer okay
uh I don't know for sure but I kind of
remember I read something about it okay
so anyway that's why I don't use company
mod so but for you guys
um you know if you are not buying my
packages um I suppose you yeah I
wouldn't you know I suppose you can use
company
mod. Okay, so now we digressed so much.
I I let's go back to the
um let's go back to the logo. Okay, the
logo discussion. What I want to say?
Yeah, I was gonna Okay,
so hold on a second.
So I wanted to uh um so I was I was
talking about logos but what I wanted to
do is updating the my wuam language
logo. Okay. So let's go back here. So
uh we talking about bunch of things. Um,
let's see what is this page word block.
Okay, copy the URL back here. Uh, paste
that's
um, paste that
here. Okay. What the English Emacs blog?
Yeah, copy
that. Paste that. Okay. Then Emac 30.
Okay. Then what is this page? This is
text overlay. Okay. uh technique in
Emacs. Basically what this do is to
highlight text. Okay. Then we talked
about logebang. Close that. Yeah. So I
was mentioning Logebang because about 25
years ago, 30 years ago, I had a huge
argument with these people, you know,
online. They have a forum about, you
know, logebang language and I say the
logo sucks. you know this is their logo
and they they say well I we disagree we
think this is great these are bunch of
idiots extreme idiots you know this logo
you know if you want to know about the
quality of logo you have to ask people
who are who know something about logos
for example artists they design logos
now there are some rules and principle
principles about designing a logo okay
so when so but these programmers or
these nerds they know nothing about
anything other than programming. Okay,
but they have strong opinions. They tell
you what you know they think they know.
So when I attacked their logo, I say
this is the worst idiotic logo. Then we
started argument. Then they banned me,
you know. They they banned me. The
[ __ ] Okay. I I still, you know, if
you search online, you can probably
still find the original ma message about
happened in uh maybe 2003 around there.
Okay, my my argument with him that's a
loge bang logo. These extreme idiots,
they they don't know what they are
talking about. You know, they think this
is a great logo.
You know, you you ask you survey logos
in any corporation or you ask any
designer of logos. You know, this this
is the worst [ __ ]
possible. But these people don't know.
They insist. Okay. So, this is one
example. I have I had a huge fight with
these nerds. I got banned. I got kicked
out of the forum. Uh eventually
uh I I think mostly due to this
argument. Then another incident, let me
tell you guys, another incident is about
lisp logo. Okay, this is when I argued
online with a bunch of the lisp
[ __ ] especially the common lisp.
Okay, the common lisp [ __ ] back in
2006. This is the reason they call me a
troll, you know. So this is a excerpt of
part of the argument among like tens of
posts. But this Ken Tilton is actually a
nice guy. Ken Tilton. I like him. Ken
Ken Tilton. He's by now very old. I
think he's like maybe 10 or 20 years
older than me. He's on Twitter
still. So we had arguments not with Ken
but with you know others. I mentioned
you know we need a logo. at least need
need a logo and I think the best one is
this one. Okay, this one you can use I
recreated. I mean originally what looks
like that from 1990s. So I think
originally this is from
1980s. So I updated into a SVG and I
tell people this great and someone uh
about 15 years ago Duncan home printed
out as a sticker so you can actually buy
it. Fantastic.
Okay. Uh, you know, so you can Yeah, you
can buy it. I'm not sure it's still
available. Let's click. Oh, there it is.
Still available, you know. So, you you
know when if you like this logo, you
have to you have me to thank for. Okay.
So, anyway, back then I was telling I
was saying how this logos are so bad. We
need a one. And they say why do we need
a logo? We are not uh kitties. We are
not script kitties. We are not nomies.
We are like elite. We are great coders.
We are this. We don't need a logo. If
you need a logo, go to PHP. These
communist [ __ ] Okay. You can still
find the message. Do I have do I have a
link to that my argument here? No. But
maybe somewhere you can still find the
message. Okay. About 2006 or
so. Uh where is it? Uh where is the
um let's see history of Python logo.
Um where's is that article lambda
logo uh list logo here. Okay. So wait
not here. So you scroll down scroll down
scroll down scroll down. Then there's a
latte art of this logo.
Then and and let me tell you about the
others. Okay. So, hold on a second. Uh
there's an article called Lisp needs a
logo. Where did it
go? I was just showing
it. Okay. So, let's click the link. I
mean, go back here. Let's see if we can
find it. This blogo, purpose of logo and
principle of logo
design. Go back.
Where is the Mathematica logo? History
this logo, Hascar logo, Java logo, GNU
Emacs. Okay, not here.
Uh there is a article called why Lisp
needs a logo. Okay, let's see. I'm
pretty sure I'll find
it. Lambda logo too. Okay, maybe here
there. Okay, so let's reopen that. So
this article you can still find it 2000
2006 also you know huge argu argument
with these common list [ __ ] you
know these people these people are nerds
you
know are like today you know today you
guys you know on Twitter you sometime
you you have arguments about programming
languages it's you know it's like you
you know many of many of you guys okay
like you don't know nothing about
anything but you think you know. So
anyway back then so they so some people
they also see the need for logos. So for
example then they started to create one
you know for example this one kind of
popular and this one these are not very
you know kind of subsided 2005.
Okay. Today, you know, okay, when it
comes to this, I have stories to tell.
Okay. So, someone created this alien
technology, this, you know, fiveeyed
elephant something that's idiotic. Okay.
Conrad Bosi. Okay. [ __ ] stupid logo,
you know. This this this, you know. So,
he is this coder. I believe he also
wrote a
book. Okay. He also wrote a
book. Not a bad I mean a good guy I
suppose. I don't know him much but I
suppose he's a good guy. But however the
logo he choose is like
um distasteful to me you know. So to me
this is not a [ __ ] cartoon. This is
not to be trifled with a cartoon.
and to like use the cheap dirty trick of
associating it with some UFO or aliens.
You know
this. So that's distasteful to me. So I
want So my favorite this logo is that
okay this
clear
succinct austere okay not not a cartoon
or with an animal or a dragging drama of
some alien you know like like like like
using the tactic of seducing the
populace you know look look this is a
cute alien we are associated with alien
technology ology right you know you see
a lot of parenthesis that's why we are
so odd but actually we are you know fun
you know this kind of
demeaning you know to me
okay so this
guy I do not share taste with this guy
okay but now let me tell you guys today
today for some reason the
Wikipedia they adopted did this logo for
lisp. I'm not exactly sure what is the
history. Okay. But I kind of know why
they do that. Okay. Usually this is not
normal because usually in Wikipedia
articles do not have a official logo. So
if it does not it you know you don't add
a logo to it. Okay. So this is some
someone added I I don't know when. Okay.
like I don't I mean I don't know who it
began about maybe 10 years ago ago.
Okay. So someone added this logo. So
this is kind of common. So today a lot
people think that this is a lisp logo.
But however as far as I know I know
quite a lot about lisp history and this
community. There is no official adoption
of this logo anywhere. I don't I mean
not it's not even a popular list this
website like none like like some someone
just just added
this supposedly to be a list logo like
doesn't
exist and this logo is also kind of
annoying to me. Why do they choose this
one? Because this is kind of similar to
the you know Chinese yinyang taii thing.
you know the Tai Chi like Tai Chi gung
fu you know go round about
so and the origin of this association of
lisp with the yinyang concept which is a
philosophical concept in of China is uh
because I believe it's because the six
uh sik book that's the full name
is structure and interpretation of
computer programs in that book there's
four chapters and I believe the last
chapter is called something like meta
evaluation or something or uh so so you
kind of got this idea of a loop you know
like recursion you know lisp is very
into that these people lambda calculus
so that's how this logo that's how lisp
is some some somewhat attached to the
you know taong inyang
philosophy and meta and then somebody
somebody I don't know
who you know it might take some time to
to look into who began this maybe this
guy okay you know like who just like
added this to represent this this
doesn't represent my this you know this
to me is not like tai chi taichi tren or
tai chi kung fu or y in young stuff
anyway they they did it and this is out
of character of Wikipedia.
Okay. So I talked about 50 minutes.
Um so we were going to yeah I rambled
all over. We were going to talk about
why Python sucks. You know Python is
extremely insulting the kido
vrosa. Okay let me show you this page.
Okay like uh so you guys still watching.
So let's see how many people 20. Oh, I'm
popular for so let me talk about the
Python GTO vanrosum extreme idiocy you
know GO von Russam is kind of this
guy the IQ is not too high okay you know
among the programming language creators
no one of the among them he's ranking
the kind of low okay at the bottom in my
opinion so gan rosam then then here is
is some articles from Python FAQ. Okay,
I believe most of them are written by
him. You know, you can go there is you
know one of the annoying thing is that
they don't specifically mention author.
Okay. Like some some sometimes you can
see the you know Gido von Rosam said
this this but but there's no author like
you know but from what I can tell most
of it is written by Gidto von Rosa
because he has a particular style of
writing and thinking pattern you know I
kind of know you know his his uh his
way. So he's this guy brain is not too
big but um but he's haughty you know he
believe he knows the best G Russam he
believe he knows better than
you know better than like or better than
other professors or programming language
designers he think you know he's kind of
haughty but in a in a passive aggressive
way
okay and let me tell you so let me give
you an example example. Okay, like every
time I read Python documentation, it's
like infuriating and
insulting. For example, let's see this
one. Okay, simple one. So, for example,
here, why does Python use methods for
some functionality such as list index
but functions for others such as length
of the
list? Right? That's a common question
because in
Python do we need to get get show
example? Uh let's
see. So you have a list uh let's say
three four five. Then you can print
length of that list xx. Okay. Run it.
You see you got three because you got
three item. Let's say three, four, five,
six. Okay, run it. Okay, you got four,
you know, because you got four items.
Close. Run it. Right. So that's length.
But however, for some other methods, so
length is a function both. But for some
other methods such as what?
Um, such as what?
Index index two. Let's say what you get.
Print
uh trace back. No. Okay. You got you you
need to find an item. You need to find
the item that is three. You want to know
what is its index. Okay. Zero. Correct.
Okay. So, let's copy that. Paste that
there. Okay. So, the question is well
some some functions are function you
know length. Some of them are methods.
So you you start something. So why is
that? Is that not consistent? It's a
very common question. And the GO
vanrosum idiot
says, you know, so so he says, well,
basically he just says, well, I like it
that way. Okay. He's trying to give some
uh reasons, you know.
So he drags drags in uh mathematics like
for example Gido Gido said
a item a for some operation operations
prefix prefix notation just reads better
than
postfix. Prefix and infix operations
have a long tradition in mathematics
which likes notations where the visuals
help the
mathematician thinking about a problem.
Compare the easy compare the easy with
which we rewrite a formula like x * a +
b into x * a + x * b to the clumsiness
of doing the same thing using raw op
notation you know so first reason he
dragging mathematics he says that length
is a function but not a method because
mathemat because mathematics this
follows mathematics way and it's easier
to read you know then then he say B the
reason B when I read code that says leng
X I know that it is asking for the
length of
something so basically this idiot he is
trying to come up with some
pretext to say that why somehow the way
the way Python it is is the mo is the
best is the most
supreme extremely idiotic does you his
his reason doesn't
stand there. There is no way there's no
way that this somehow is you know for
example let's let's write it okay
so so why can't you just
say xx dot
length you know this is common in
JavaScript in Ruby in just about every
other language who follows the
op right so
Well, you could you could simply say,
"Oh, it just that way, you know, it just
so happened and you cannot change
it." You know, no, nobody's going to
think you are stupid or your language is
bad, right? But no, he's going to cook
up uh, you know, he's going to cook up
elaborate reasons, you know, dragging
mathematics.
Oh, by the way, the long tradition, you
know, like pay attention to the way
specifically his style of writing, okay?
You know, for some operations, prefix
notation just reads better than
postfix. You know, prefix operations
have a long tradition in mathematics
which likes notation where something
visual help the mathematician thinking
about a problem. You see this [ __ ]
scum is trying to cook up a way you know
reason explanation and does that apply?
Does does it actually true? Is it true
to vast majority of people
where where if you have a OP language
this is easier to understand than this
or or even just that you know you know
this this is a you know like a data
um member okay and this is a method so
so you are saying that to vast majority
of people they You'll find this easier
to read than this or this in a OOP
language. That's what he's claiming. A
[ __ ] Is it true? No, it's not true
at all. Or is it he saying if you are a
mathematician then you like this better?
Yeah, sure. But then then what the [ __ ]
is this? Why can't you make this a
function? you know like like index you
know
index xx is a list then three so let's
change the this xx to a list okay
so you see you you can just have that
index means get the index of the list of
this this item get the index of that
that's much easier to read why are you
doing op
Gido von Russom [ __ ] Okay, so
that's just one example. U but actually
I wanted to show this example. This this
one is more insulting, you know, like
more insulting. But I think that's
that's it for today. I'm running out of
time. So this you know so so these three
pass passages you know this this
this is a kind of very typical writing
from kiddovan Rossam I can I can tell
because by you know you read you know
the way he say things you can tell it's
written by him you know like very
pompous pompous is a word you know very
pompous he pretend pretentious and
pompous and
worthy okay that's a characteristic ics
of of Gidov von Russam. Now if you want
to know why Python sucks, it's one of
the worst designed language. You know
there I have like 20 30 articles about
it. Okay, that's it for today.
Um there are there were other things I
was going to do but you know that's it
for one you know. So next we going to do
Yeah, that's it for today.
Hi Kasan, love your stream. Thanks for
doing. Thank you. Choker man. Charlie
track says meta circular evaluation.
That's right. I I forgot to
um link to my you know to advertise my
website articles. This structure and
interpretation of computer
programs. Uh, by the way, they have a
Oh, this is funny cartoon. You know,
starting about 15 years ago, they
started to have a fashion or a meme of
showing, you know, [ __ ] Japanese anime
girls reading this book. Sometimes other
books, you
know, it's [ __ ] stupid. And you see
this this book mentioned on 4chan all
the time, like for some reason, but it's
it's a good book, okay?
And there's a JavaScript version. Okay,
there's a JavaScript version. Um, then
there's the history of the cover. You
know, someone dug it up in CCP
conference 2020. So, I borrowed it and
gave credit by Conor
Hostra. So, anyway, that's the book.
Okay. So the metaircular
um evaluation I didn't read that chapter
actually but the metaircular evaluation
that's kind of associated with lisp not
in the beginning though I don't know
when I mean I haven't read that chapter
okay but I don't I'm not sure I'm gonna
be too too fond of it you know why I
like lisp I like lisp the number One
primary reason is because it's a
functional programming. Okay? [ __ ] op
[ __ ] side effects. [ __ ] the lisp meta
object system. [ __ ] you know, I want
functional programming. I want pure
functional
programming as as practical, you know,
practical practical. uh you know I I
don't necessarily go for like strictly
pure like Haskell but basically I want
functional programming okay so I like
lisp yes I like this pretty much wam
language is also this uh because they I
mean so I like this because it's
functional programming unlike Richard
Sman you know the richest stoman idiot
he has a blog somewhere I found out few
month ago you know I you at least, you
know, like he he he's making some
comments about Closure like someone
asked him, "How do you like Closure?"
And he he he goes his way, you know, oh,
I don't know Closure. Of course, he
doesn't know because he's living in a
cave. He don't know nothing about
Closure. But then he made a comment, oh,
but I we don't we don't like Closure
because it it's not Lisp because it
doesn't use cons and uh we don't like
functional programming. You know the
this this tradition is not like going
for functional
programming [ __ ]
idiots you know so you know he's old
that's why he's you know he you know he
he has um that's not why I like this I
like this the primary the most important
primary reason is functional programming
then another important a good reason a
good reason is because the nested
syntax. Okay. But then there's got
problems because in this the nested
syntax is not pure. You got lots of
exceptions. But the the common list
these idiots, they don't know, you know,
like you got the, you know, back tick or
tick or a pound sign or a semicolon for
comments. You know, you got this
exceptions. I don't want exceptions. I
want everything possible or just nested
pure parade. in pure the most simple
syntax
possible. But these people, you know, of
of since the 90s, they they don't
understand. They don't know this this
these
idiots. Okay, that's that. Uh let's see
next
comment. Bye. That's it.
Why Python
sucks? Yes, I tell you why. There.
Close. Close. Yeah, we got to do, you
know, we got this like this.
This somebody decided this logo is going
to represent our lisp.
somebody out of
nowhere, you know, that's a crime. Can
we sue Wikipedia? Like normally that's
not Wikipedia doesn't do that. You know,
if you have Python, you know, Python is
well designed by this guy and they they
have a official organization then they
their logo is that that that then you
know then you have a logo. But not Lis
doesn't have a logo. Like who the [ __ ]
just put it put one there? Does you know
the McCarthy guy, I think he's a great
guy. I don't know him too much though.
Does
he approve that you random [ __ ] Zuma
[ __ ] added this to represent this?
I don't think
so, you know. So, so these
people and the lobbang idiocy extreme.
That's it. Bye.