thank you
hello guys welcome to another episode of
sun talk show so today we are going to
call it wufam language a geometric
inversion with a stereographic
projection okay so let's show my screen
so
Wolfram language coding geometric
inversion with stereographic projection
now you are looking at geometric
inversion now there is a relation
between geometric inversion and
stereographic projection now I'm going
to explain all these okay and I did
several videos on geometric inversions
in the past so you can search YouTube
you'll find it
so this is will be about an hour so
you're gonna learn geometry and you're
gonna learn wolfam language coding which
is a term rewriting system okay it's a
term relating system fantastic so here
is today's talk show
so let me show you what is a geometric
inversion okay show in browser Now video
check audio check okay we're good to go
and the keyboard I'm using is the
uh exposed today today I'm using exposed
keyboard fantastic okay I recommend it
so uh back to so let me let me show you
what is a stereographic projections
projection so here it is we did a video
on this one as well live coding so we
coded uh stereographic projection here
is a code so let's start Wolfram
language
uh let me let me start wolf and language
and just show the code
okay so if you have comments and
questions posted okay I'd love to see
your comments and questions so first of
all let's copy that shrink the window
back to the wufan language paste it
begin okay there is the result so you
can see let's magnify the font
okay so you can see here's the grid you
know this is a graphics programming so
let's make it typeset
control shift n Ctrl shift n so you can
see it's a typeset
you know you can just press Ctrl shift n
so and and watch it was those as the
window shrink they will be formatted in
a Smart Way automatically so this is
fantastic much better than Tech love
Tech you know it's a Wolfram language uh
and okay so here is the grid we just
created and then we just created the
ball you can rotate it
then we just created this image you know
we did a video of that last time so that
is a stereographic projection and and
then there's a relation in fact the
the stereographic projection you can see
how it works you just draw a line
passing through a sphere so any figure
on the plane can be projected to the
sphere in or vice versa and uh so in
other words any points on the plane
corresponds to a point on the sphere and
vice versa so you can for example the
the image on the plane can be a photo of
you or someone you know a photo of you
or whatever house then you can project
it to the sphere and so it's very
interesting and
um
you know and then
there's a relation so to do the
stereographic projection you use certain
formulas for example here is the
projection formula as simple as that
okay so let's see we can and projection
Works in any Dimension so let me let's
just try it okay so project
for example X and Y you know uh
a point on the plane and it becomes a
three a point on a sphere okay and uh
actually can this function do three uh
yeah it doesn't work for higher
Dimension this function but anyway the
the idea can work for higher Dimensions
as well
so anyway you can see projection
function is just a formula that takes a
point you know two numbers and return
three numbers okay these three numbers
are the coordinates on the sphere that's
projection Geo that's called
stereographic projection okay now
there's a connection between that and uh
and the and the
geometric inversion so for example we so
geometric inversion again it's also a
function
that's very interesting okay so we did
the video of this you can you can watch
it I recommend it
so you know it's beautiful so
essentially it takes a point from a plan
to a plane
that's a 2d case or it takes a point
from a three-dimensional space like here
uh and for example we start with the
rectangular cage and uh
and apply the the geometric inversion of
three-dimensional case so it takes a
point and returns another point so this
the grid points of a cube becomes that
okay so that's uh that's the geometric
inversion three-dimensional case now for
two dimensional case it's similar so you
for example let's say let's begin with a
simple one you start with a grid on the
left and you apply the function each
two numbers a point we you know gets a
new two numbers that's a geometric
inversion two-dimensional case so you
got the image on the right so
so that's then we can use tubes to have
more better visual effect you know so we
did that so all these so and 2D case in
3D case and here is another
three-dimensional case we begin with a
bunch of Cubes then we apply the
function and becomes that so so all
these uh geometric inversion okay 3D
case so there is a connection between
the
between the stereographic projection and
geometric inversion so in other words
you know in other words before we use
this projection function you know to
convert a point on the plane to a
three-dimensional point on the sphere
you know that's a formula for
stereographic projection
but because there's a connection to
inversion you can also use the inversion
formula to arrive basically all right
you know arrive at the same answer
so in fact the formula is going to be
the same English you know so that that
is we are what we are going to do
basically we are going to do today is to
create a pretty picture of the
stereographic projection using the
geometric inversion formula okay so I'm
gonna show you how it works in you know
the mathematics aspect
okay and let me mention about wolfam
language okay so if you just search for
Wu fam Language tutorial fam Language
tutorial you'll find it you know I did a
lot of you know like 30 videos 40 videos
in the past two years you know lots of
videos you can watch uh and there's an
introduction as well within language you
know introduction to fam language
um
uh symbolic computation and term
rewriting system that's this one 2022
July 15th uh that's a good intro so you
can read that you know it's a term
rewriting system so open language is
very different from all the other
programming languages hello guys hello
Nguyen
my
um pop-up pop out chat you and my my my
number one fan from 4chan and hello
Louise
uh I got one sentence I did not
understand well it's very easy it's it's
very very easy to understand you know
actually so you know if you watched one
of my video about the inversion you're
you know it's very easy to understand
especially for programmers because it
doesn't involve
there's nothing this is not math this is
you know we are doing this although it's
a topic in geometry and Mathematics but
actually all you have to know is just uh
you know you can just
ignore everything just just know that
there's this function that takes two
numbers return three numbers that's
projection you know projection is very
easy to understand you know the because
you can just look at the the graphics
inversion is also very easy to
understand I explained before
um
so okay let's let's get into it so I
want to show you so here's wolfam
Language tutorial so for you programmers
you know if you are you know I know you
guys uh have you know
are expert in JavaScript in Golan in
Ruby in Python you know that's the
domain of programmers but the wolfam
language
um
you know the wolfam programming
languages is uh is very different from
all the others it's act it's kind of
like lisp okay it's basically a lisp I
did a video covering that Wolfram
language is exactly
a lisp like every every concept you know
about this is is the same in Wolfram
language
um including the nested parent syntax
but now there's a shortcut so that's so
you don't see the too much nesting but
in fact it is I did a video on that so
anyway that it's a term rewriting system
so it's very uh very different from all
the languages
the the way you code it you know is
quite different okay and it's a
functional programming language so I
want to show you here within Language
tutorial of course I have everything uh
you know introduction you know
30 uh Pages you know you can read that
but also I want to tell you how to how
to get it so download rule from language
for free you can
you know go to this page and click
download and you know it's for free for
personal use what you get is a wolf and
uh
uh Wolfram script in Wolfram engine you
don't get the notebook anyway so I
talked about that before so you can just
read it or you can buy a Raspberry Pi it
comes with it free The Notebook so it's
uh fantastic okay so that's the
introduction so you can download it and
play with it now let's get to the
um let's see what we want to do now okay
so Wolfram language
um
yeah so okay so let me copy that and
paste the link here so we get a so what
is this okay copy that close that
uh
paste the link okay so here's today's
talk show notes okay so let's begin to
code it okay
uh
there's one more thing I want to show
you just search for
xahle dot info
and you click on sorry
info search and xpow
okay X
Dash pow so exposed keyboard night
that's a keyboard I'm using currently so
it's a fantastic I recommend it
okay so uh yeah so copy that close it
back to emacs well back to that back to
that here and paste the link here okay
so we have the notes so let's begin
coding this thing so first thing I want
to explain what is the relation between
this geometric inversion uh and the
stereographic projection let's see about
evaluate this again so that
you don't get grayed out thing so
so we draw a ball and we draw the plane
last time we did it didn't really finish
the graphics because what you really
want is
uh hold on a second so
so you can magnify an image like that
okay so then you can see
uh what we last time
yeah we should we should have drawn uh
the
you know join the square color it and
draw the line projection lines that way
it's
visualization so when you see it you
understand it you know visualization is
very very extremely powerful thing
so what we want to do is yeah we want to
explain the relation between geometric
inversion and this so so so let me
explain okay so first of all
stereographic projection is very easy to
understand you have a sphere you put a
point from the top of the sphere and you
draw a line to any point on a sphere it
will intersect the plane so that makes a
association between a specific point on
the sphere and a specific point on the
plane so in this way any point on the
sphere is connected to a one precise
point on the plane except the top of the
sphere okay so in this way you have you
know this Association this map so this
is called stereographic projection okay
so that's that now let's let me let me
explain what is the geometric inversion
um
so again we did the video on this
multiple times but let me explain
geometric conversion
geometric inversion is
again in the 2D case is
you know so so so let me let me let me
um let me make a copy of this let's draw
and so geometric inversion
in the two-dimensional case is that you
have
uh so first of all suppose you have a
mirror so you can understand a mirror so
a mirror
so you cannot do that here so you have
to
open with snip and sketch okay so if you
have a mirror and you have a point that
mirrors here if you have a point here
that mirrors here so if you have a let's
say uh
let's say a triangle and it becomes a
triangle like that
you know if you have a
Square then it becomes a
trapezoid you know a trapezoid become
you know it's a trapezoid becomes a trap
so that's a mirror everyone understands
now geometric inversion is very it's
actually just a mirror but except a
straight line you have a circle so given
a for for example given a axis so you
have a circle here with radius of one
so geometric inversion is that every
Point outside of the circle
becomes a point inside the circle any
point inside the circle corresponds to
one point outside the circle so again
it's a map so it Maps the points inside
the circle two points outside the circle
okay very interesting so how is it done
how how exactly is it mapped you know in
the mirror case you just draw a
horizontal line and you see that's how
they you know each of the point map you
know the same distance so mirror is a
map in the plane such that for every
point on the right side become you know
Associates with a point in the left side
and vice versa that's a mirror it's
called reflection the the mathematical
terminology is called reflection okay so
geometric inversion is is the same
similar concept of reflection except
points outside the circle gets inside
inside circle map to the outside okay so
the the way it is exactly done
is that you draw a line
suppose you have a point here okay so
let's say this is p you want to know
which point this P corresponds to you
know it this P will become inside the
inside the circle so what you do is you
draw a line from the center
to to this point P then
basically the so the
the
further the p is from the center they
become closer to the origin so basically
in this case here is Q okay so this P
Point Q they correspond to each other
the closer P let's say if you have a
point here let's say a
and that point will become here B
you see so the further away the P the
closer it becomes to the origin the the
closer the p is to the circum
circumference of the circle the closer
is the cross running point so so just
exactly just like mirror okay it's just
like reflection
like further way away to the right
becomes further away to the left in the
same way here same same thing so let me
show you a
so we have
um so close this save it
uh okay save it let's uh
it's it's open then so let's uh let me
show you so
there is a lot introduction on my
website let's see where is the link okay
so here is the page that explains the
concept
the code
uh you know history description so you
can click on this Geo GE algebra let me
show you this very interesting
application so G algebra so you can see
here is the point p
and you can see the corresponding Point
Q you see so that's the geometric
inversion now if the point p is inside
the circle it's you know it just reverse
it's exactly the same thing you see
so it doesn't matter where this point
raised so this is a geometric immersion
and and we are this map this function
this you know given a point two numbers
remember so if you are a programmer you
can think of it just a a function takes
two numbers returns two numbers okay
that's that's it
so these via this inversion geometric
inversion that's how you get uh all
these pretty pictures you know so here
for example you have a bunch of blue
circles
then you apply the geometric inversion
you get this kind of circle circle
actually becomes circles so it's a very
interesting property circles become
circles and lines also become circles
so here is many you know various uh
geometric inversion and also
there's a lot of applications you know
in for example in robotics in Trend in
mechanics you know you want to convert a
rotational
motion to linear motion you can you know
you can build a mechanical linkage such
that you you know it does that so for
example train train Wheels Locomotion
you know you want typically piston you
know they create rotational motion you
can turn it into a vector linear motion
that's some of the application very
interesting and especially today in
robotics for example you you want to
create a robotic dog you know so so how
does the leg move well that's via this
mechanics linkages you know so you can
constrain the arms or legs to move on
only in a certain way
uh okay so that's that's the geometric
inversion uh okay so this is a
two-dimensional case now 3D case is the
same thing you know you start with a
sphere any point outside the sphere
becomes inside and any point inside
becomes
the outside the same same thing by
drawing a line okay
so and uh
and the the okay so that's the geometric
inversion so now what is the
relationship you know between how how
the geometric inversion and how the
how the stereographic projection relate
okay let's let me explain that one okay
so let's make a copy
um
uh
okay so let's let's do a
screenshot
and let's open it in um
sketch
okay so we can draw here
okay so here is how um
they relate okay so in a stereographic
projection in 2D case what we have is a
line
and we have a circle above it and
suppose we want to know what is this
point P correspond to you start with a
at the North Pole you draw a line to p
and this P you know this line passes the
circle here so this point is q
so in other words a point on the line
becomes this point Q on the circle
so this is a two-dimensional case of the
stereographic projection 2D case Okay
simple now 3D case obviously very easy
you can you know it's similar it's
exactly the same
now so how does this relate to geometric
inversion so let me explain so first of
all let's start easy with a 2d case okay
am I doing good
am I doing good guys say something okay
let me check my uh good fantastic Mark
says North Pole where is Santa
okay so so okay so let's go back to the
um
yeah so we want to so
here is a 2d case uh to the
case
of
stereo
graphic
projection
okay so that is a 2d case now let's talk
about the two-dimensional case of the
yeah you have to use the mouse the
two-dimensional case of the geometric
inversion Okay so
so again so
so let's let's review so here is the
okay let's
uh
2D case of g o
inversion okay did I spell it correctly
I forgot
s s i o n yeah
so in 2D case of geometric inversion
remember you start with a circle in the
center and for any point P you draw a
line to the point p and
and then
it becomes a point inside
so this point is q
okay
now how does these two relate you know
it doesn't you know at first it doesn't
seems you know
they relate because one is a point
becomes a point on a circle the other
one
the points outside the circle becomes
inside the circle so they don't you know
the only point that goes onto the circle
is if you begin with a point on a circle
you see
so but but here is how they relate okay
so here is how they relate very
interesting so if you want to do a
stereographic projection okay so again
you start with a X and Y so let's say
you know stereographic projection you
put a circle there right
now you want to know so let's say this
is a point p
and normally you would just draw a line
to P then you can see this point is q
right this is the normal way to do to do
the stereographic projection
but now you can use geometric inversion
to get this point Q
so okay the way you do that is that is
this you draw a bigger Circle centered
on the North Pole so you got a circle
like that
okay so you got a circle so you want to
know
so so you see you draw a big circle
two times larger
than the stereographic projection Circle
okay now you do a geometric inversion
with respect to this large Circle so now
you can see you can see this p and Q
they are actually
geometric inversion now so
you see so that that is that is their
relation okay between the geometric
inversion and the
Studio graphic projection okay
so save it
and now let's start to code let's let's
create some beautiful
um Graphics am I doing good so far so
good
three people watching okay
so let's start to code uh okay what do
we so let's begin to code we want to
okay so start the wolfam language okay
I'm coding Wolfram language in
emacs
by this package Xavier mod okay so this
is uh
emac this code that allows you to code
Wolfram language in emacs visp and you
can get it
from this URL and it's on GitHub okay
just search for subwoofer mod emacs
you'll find it on GitHub
there's a download here GitHub
okay so anyway so we are coding it in
emacs inside Emax because inside emacs
is it's much more efficient you can you
know for example I can
uh I can type a matching bracket by you
know always type a matching bracket and
so on
close that okay close that close that
close that wait uh don't close that
reopen okay let's start with code
uh so now so how long I've been talking
36 minutes oh my God hello nwin
fantastic
so now what we want to do let's do a
fancy Graphics first first so you see
this one is based on lines okay now
let's do it with tubes
uh okay so where uh where do we go here
uh wolf and mod okay copy that close it
uh let's go back to talk show
uh okay paste the link here then we want
to do cubes yeah so cubes
what we want to do is now using this
these cubes okay I mean tubes to
represent those lines so it will be
beautiful uh but before we do that let
me show you this one you know this is
the power of Wolfram language you see
these Graphics how many lines is that in
Python okay in Wolfram language one
single line okay
copy that go to Wolf fan language and
let's just paste it there and let's make
it pretty okay then let's run it there
it is you see fantastic
fantastic okay
uh and you know this seems complex it's
functional programming and it's a lisp
and it's you know it's actually much
easier than you might think it's a
function of I mean it's a term rewriting
system but let's not focus on that today
I mean I want to let's just do this um
this okay so we want to do this thing
but now instead of lines we use cubes
okay cubes not Cube Cube okay all we
have to do is let's paste that okay
we're gonna modify this code so actually
let's copy it let's go back to the Emax
here
uh paste it yeah here's a code
so
very easy okay so let's just um so I'm
going to first of all
not explain and just do it okay it'll
just be two minutes okay so
and show the show the result then maybe
we can dive into how it works so all we
have to do is so here is you see here is
a graphic 3D and Graphics 2D that prints
out the graphics okay
so all we have to do is just take that
okay
take that and here we want to do a
replacement
replace anything
that has a pattern just a line we are
doing pattern matching okay that's what
terms rewriting system is about you know
in normal languages in Python Ruby you
have regular expression right regular
expression what does it do
ultimately you know in a sense it
basically just do text
find and replace it finds some text you
can replace it by some other text and
the way you find can be a pattern can be
you know a pattern that represents email
address or a phone number you know
so you can do find and replace with
regular expression
and what is it um you know and the thing
the regular expression is applied to
Strings okay that's a key that's a key
concept of regular expression the
Practical Keys concept okay you find and
replace strings
by a pattern that's what regular
expression is okay now term rewriting is
exactly exactly the same term rewriting
but instead of string you work on the
the whole language syntax so what we are
doing here is that we want to find any
pattern
that is the literally l-i-n-e okay then
we want to replace it by
so you you just type an arrow here
replace it by tube
okay that's it okay and let's do the
same thing
let's do the same thing for the
um
so for the yeah so for here
and the whole Graphics okay it's just
these two lines let's hope it works
let's do it I don't know it will work
but should
run it fantastic
fantastic uh yeah it worked great
fantastic
so I'm I'm happy
um
Okay so
yeah so so that's that's it um that's it
for you know as far as turning these
lines into a cube you know the way it
works let me explain a little bit how it
works okay so
well the the the the way this works we
already expand we just do
find and replace you find all you know
all names in this
you know in this data that that that is
a line you know literally l-i-n-e you
just replaced by the tube function so
and this works because line and Tube
they have the same syntax so let's first
so for example let me show you
so you
um you uh so you look up the
documentation for the line function
there it is it's magnify I mean that's
done JavaScript
um
and let's magnify so here is
line so you just say line
curly braces then inside that it just
bunch of points then it represents the
line just like this you know it
represents a line in 2D or 3D
you know passing those points that's as
simple as that then you just slap on
Graphics then it just you know just
print it okay so for example let's do a
very simple example
so lie
and let's say point the first point is
zero zero now is this uh
yeah so the the first point and zero
zero at the origin and the second point
is let's say uh two three okay so that
represents the line then we can evaluate
it in Wolfram language it doesn't do
anything because that's
that's what it meant to be it just
represent the line now if you want a
graphics of it just say
okay graphics
then then whatever above okay so Ctrl L
to copy the input from above okay so
there it is that's a line and if you
want the axis you know X Y you can say
X is true okay
okay so it you know so now it shows
access now you can also show the grid uh
grid let's see grid quit
I think uh no that's not
options so
quit
lines
automatic
Okay so
simple line now if you want the three
dimensional case very easy you just add
so let's say from zero zero zero to
let's say is two three four two points
okay
uh that's incorrect okay so because yeah
because now you have a line
where each point is a three-dimensional
point so you cannot use the graphics you
need to use graphics 3D
okay to represent so let's do it again
so there it is
you know this so this is a line now
now
um now this option is not good so let's
remove that
okay so now
uh what we want to do now let's do tubes
now tubes are exactly just like
the the Syntax for the tube is is
enzymatics semantics of the tube is
exactly just like line okay so here is a
documentation for tube you know just
exactly just like a line
the only difference is that it now is
use a tube to represent the line okay so
all we have to do is just um let's copy
that okay
so let's copy that
copy
okay so these two things now let's just
replace line by two okay so let's just
do it manually so in Emax we can say
find replace line by two okay
do it do it do it do it okay so except
here is wrong okay
um no yeah so there
so tubes now let's run it
uh okay the first case is incorrect
uh where is the first case incorrect
but the second case Works 3D oh yeah it
doesn't work for the first case because
the first case is a two-dimensional case
now the tube
can only be used for three-dimensional
if that makes sense because it's a
three-dimensional thing
yeah so but
the point here is that you see it's
exactly the same you see now it's a tube
and before it's a
you know before it's line now we can add
thickness to the tube by
by just add a second argument
let's say thickness 0.2 okay do it
now you see you got a thick Cube so the
point here is that the tube
function
is exactly the same as the line function
the syntax is exactly the same so all so
you can simply replace any
you know line literally just by two then
you'll become tube so that's how this
works now the replacement we did here is
manual you know we manually did find
replace but you can do it program it
programmatically by for example
so here's a line so let's make this
pretty so
um
you know typically in programming
languages you format it this way in
Wolfram language you don't do that you
don't do oh where I need a tab here a
tab oh is it should be space or type
character or how many space represented
cat tab like python you know idiotic
in wolfen language you don't do that you
know in fact the whole thing
for example the the whole thing can be
just uh
single line let me show you okay
normally you don't format at all so make
the whole thing a line you know that's
valid code you know copy that
paste it there
uh it did seem valid why is that I I
um
I did something oh yeah it's invalid
because I forgot
uh
wait
I forgot to add a semicolon okay so you
need semicolon here let's add semicolon
here
okay now let's put the whole thing into
a line
okay copy it
paste it there it is oh yeah when you
put semicolon it suppresses the output
so you don't so you you you don't want
the semicolon
at the end here
okay so you can see now you can see
they automatically format in a smart way
as you adjust the width you know the
window width or as you type That's The
Power of Wolfram language type setting
okay and you can press a key Ctrl shift
n it becomes becomes typeset okay
so again you see this is supreme okay
so that's an advantage of Wolfram
language that's why I love it you know
I've been coding it since 1992. uh far
more advanced than the industrial
coders in the industry you know coding
Community C C plus plus C sharp even
heska you know they have nothing they
have nothing like this you know and in
the industrial coders they don't
understand they've never seen this
before you know they kept you know they
have Indian idiomatic guide python
idioms you know they tell you to how you
should you know manually format or
configure your emacs you know it's a
it's a very complex so this is a power
so
anyway so
so now we so we got this you know so
we can program
programmatically replace the line by
tube by just this these syntax so let me
show you what this means Okay so
so
um okay so let's
so so this
this code uh this line let me just paste
it okay
so this code can be rewrite can be
written in a more nested Way by like
this okay so let me do it so you just
say
replace
or okay so replace or then two arguments
the first thing is the thing you want to
replace that would be X4
okay the second thing is is is the
the thing you want to find and the thing
you want to replace that is represented
by a rule okay like that
oh wait
okay so the rule takes two arguments the
first thing is the fine pattern
the second
argument is the replace pattern so the
fine pattern is gonna simply be a line
literally and the replace pattern is
simply going to be a tube literally so
now we don't need this part anymore so
you see
so now remember this line that's a
syntactical shortcut okay is exactly the
same as this line here is where you see
you see it's fully nested there's no
special syntax like the C4 Loop while
loop you know I plus plus there's no
special thing like that everything is
purely nested just like lisp in fact
more regular so this is one of the
reason ufang language is you know it's
at least it's basic it is at least it's
derived from lisp and APL programming
language okay so anyway let's we got
this and let's run it
okay
do it you see
and now if we remove those
um
let's say let's change the tube to line
uh line so it actually doesn't replace
anything I mean
if we do this line becomes line itself
so it doesn't affect it effectively it
doesn't does nothing okay so if we do
this
then it's uh just lines
okay so I think um
so I love using C plus plus work very
good at office my friend okay I think
that's it for today 50 minutes yeah so
um yeah that's it for today thank you
for watching if you like my stud uh my
if you like my stuff donate okay the
patreon me PayPal me
uh you know I have you can go to my
website saudi.info uh and uh lots of
interesting things and at the bottom
patreon Amazon gift card PayPal okay
thank you guys
okay we shut down in one minute or two
any questions
any questions you find interesting uh
you want me to explain or anything
okay so here is today's code it's
fantastic yeah we demonstrated this uh
basically
you know
some aspect of the
term rewriting system you see that you
know what what this what you are looking
at today what we did today is actually
that that's the that's one of the a very
good example of thumb rewriting
power
you know in other languages you you
can't really
do that and this part of the power came
from you know for example in Haskell in
our camera in F sharp in the functional
languages or today even in Python and
Ruby you have some form of term you have
some form of
Pat imagine okay which is similar to
what we are doing today
but however the Wolfram is a real-time
writing why because
um
it's the difference is that the Wolfram
language term relating pattern match in
terms writing it's a symbolic
okay so it's just like lisp you know in
this every variable every function name
is actually a symbol that stands by
itself
it's not just a you know a byway to a
value
it's actually a symbol so you can
manipulate all this symbol symbolically
okay so in wufam language combined with
pattern matching and replacement like we
are doing today you know replace so so
what you become so so it becomes a term
rewriting system
effectively what it means is that every
syntax
it's just a sequence it becomes like a
string so you just all you so when you
want to do computation you are just
doing fine and replace
by a pattern
for the for the whole language so in
other words you can think of for those
of you these coders this is least macro
okay this Marco
but with a power a magnitude more power
so the whole language that's that's the
fundamental way you do computation in
Wolfram language is term rewriting okay
so essentially every computation you do
is just finding some pattern and replace
it some with another
you know sequence of symbols and do that
again and again
and again and so on you know when in
fact when you define a function the way
function works is that you just Define a
pattern so whenever a Wolfram language
found that pattern it just replace that
pattern by the function's body
and and so on until no
rule matches so that's the essence of
term writing system
okay thank you guys for watching that's
it
bye guys
so you know close this
code is so let's pop pop the code back
to
um
yeah so
let's clean up these paint
okay syntax color it showing browser
that's what we talked uh today