good morning everyone
uh welcome to another episode of son
talk show
today is 2020 august 21st
friday and it's 4 30
in the afternoon san francisco time good
morning guys
good morning bots alan and informatic
so today we are going to do a uh
concentrated
emacs list tutorial i'm going to show
you
how to create a command that highlights
text
okay and so first of all today's
background
image is this keyboard fantastic hey
danielle
so this is this keyboard you see there's
hyper
super meta control this is one of the
lisp keyboards this
is uh rocco norsk
kps10 lisp prototype keyboard
this one is actually a prototype it's uh
never made this is
at the end near the end of
a.i winter you know that's the death of
lisp around 1990 i think what wins this
keyboard
uh 1984 okay so 1984
so anyway so that's today's background
and you see back then we have this
optical mouse
you know 1984 this optical mouse unlike
today's
where so back then you have you use this
uh mirror pad uh
for it to work without that pad it
doesn't work
so okay that's the background image and
let's get it get started we're gonna
talk
we're gonna do this tutorial and this is
just going to be a concentrated tutorial
so we are going to write a command that
highlight
text uh let me show you okay so you go
to
let me show you some default emacs
commands so you this you you go to my
emacs tutorial just search for xr
emacs highlight highlighting commands
for example so
let's magnify mac magnum by my buffer
for example
let's say i want to highlight all the
words
emacs okay let's see so emax
so i just call the command highlight
uh lines matching regret rejects there
are several command
commands highlight phrase okay um
there it is uh wait highlight phrase
then you type emacs press enter
it asks you what color so yellow is fine
so now you can see
yellow now let's highlight lisp keyword
so
highlight phrase lisp and what color
pink
you can see so that's a highlight
command so how do you do it how do you
write a command to do that
i'm gonna show you okay so here are some
of the commands
highlight regular expression uh
highlight symbol
at point uh very useful if you are
programmed
if you are a program programmer doing a
source code sometimes you want to see
some
function name highlighted highlight
highlight lines
matching regular expression highlight
trace
highlight regular expression so there
are these commands
so i'm going to show you how to do them
so what you do you go to my emacs
tutorial
then you go to emacs list
writing a major mod okay then you go
down um
then you go down then you look at um
text properties okay so that's my
tutorial where i tell you
you know you can read it i tell you how
to do it but we are going to do it from
scratch
i'm just going to explain and do it um
live
so highlight command so let's start a
emacs lisp okay so just
open the empty buffer any buffer will do
but since i'm um so anyway so
here is my emac list define a function
and so let me explain so in e-max there
are two
mechanisms to highlight text
for example you see these red
lines comments in html that's syntax
coloring
obviously right you see you see this is
blue
this is blue and for a string you have a
red
then normally it's black this is syntax
coloring
so in general syntax coloring
in a major mod programming language mod
they use a mechanism called
text properties i'm going to show you
that now
okay text properties
now that's one mechanism there's another
mechanism called
overlay okay uh i think we are going to
explain that
we need to do this fast but let's do
let's focus on text properties first
so in emacs you have something called
text property like in a buffer every
text
every text for example in any text if
there is you can actually attach
a property to it and so for example over
here how does emacs know that
this you know part should be read well
it's because
in this section in this region of text
there's actually a text
property that tells you
that it should be color red that's a
reason
so so how do you do it so okay so let's
see
um let's write the code to do let's say
highlight let's say let's write the
command highlight kernel word okay
um
okay hi light
current word the word under cursor okay
let's see um type type the
dot string highlight
the word under cruiser to be
red okay and let's
give a version number today's date
it's my convention to always give a
version number of date
for command so okay
so how do we do it uh
highlight the word highlight the
the word under cruiser
uh wait so am i doing good oh it's
always good
okay highlight what under kusa hold on a
second
let's see okay so highlight what under
kuza so
so first of all we need to find out the
beginning position
and end position of the word under
cruiser so how you do that
um there's a word there's a command
a current word there's there are quite a
few ways to do it
uh but one of the simplest way is using
a command something called current word
i forgot the command name so let's go to
my emac this tutorial
and we'll find it
stream functions text editing um
there is a let's use just use thing at
point okay
uh that's because it's um it's more
general
thing at point so there is this command
thing at point
and you just say a single word and that
will
let me show you how to how to do it
first of all
position one position two that's the
beginning and end position of the word
we want so
um found a thing at point so that's the
command
that's a command you want to call bounce
of thing at point
then let's just say word okay
so what that will return is a vector
this will return a vector so let me show
you how do you do these
bounds okay let's say boundary
so we have three variables so first of
all
set set
boundary okay then this command
bounds everything at point
so what it will return what it will
return is a vector like that
uh some way
wait what am i doing
yeah it will return a vector like that
two numbers the number
are positioned cruiser position in a
buffer
that's what uh sample return value okay
so we not once we got the boundary
then we want to set position one and
position two so position one
is going to be set
position one um a ref
okay when you want to get
a element of a of a array you use a ref
wait i think it returns a list instead
of array so
let's look up the documentation
describe function so here is the
documentation
so determines the start and end buffer
location for the thing at point okay
blah blah blah
uh return a con cell so that it returns
a con cell that's what it
returns data type so in that case a
car if you know it returns a con cell
like that
like that so to get the first element
you just say car
okay then set position two
to get the second element you say cut
the okay
uh cdr that's just um the
strange names you see car and carder is
just
historical don't worry about it
uh you can you know you you might find
online articles about why they are named
that but basically
it's a console any anyway so car you get
the first point and kada is the second
point
a second element in a con cell console
is just basically
it's just a at least like
thing with only two elements that's a
constant
so we we've done that so okay so that's
that uh
now the next step is
so now we have the beginning and end
position now we just want to highlight
it so
so what do you do you call this command
text properties okay let me show you
uh okay let's go back to my talk show
you go to text properties
i'm gonna explain to i'm going to
explain so what you want is the text
properties
here let me copy it
it's easier so you see so we are going
to
this command text properties put text
property
what does that mean so this function
takes two elements uh takes several
arguments
the first two argument is a position
beginning and end position
so in our case it's position one and
position two
then the rest of the arguments
is going to ask you what kind of
property you want to add to this region
to this position one position to be you
know the region between those two
positions
so what is the text property you know
you can read
my tutorial i explain in detail but text
property is basically a
list of pairs so it's actually just a
list of pairs
you know key value pairs so in our case
we are going to add
one of the building key is called font
lock face
okay uh found log face so we are going
to add
a text property with a key font lock
face
to this region then then then
the value of that is going to be this um
this list expression foreground red
yeah foregone red
so let's make this pretty fire so that's
it that actually that's the code that's
all there it is
so we are so what we're gonna do is
going to we're gonna to evaluate this
buffer
okay now copy the word copy copy the
command name
now let's say let's go back to my uh
talk show okay so my talk show
let's say i want to highlight the word
modify
you see that that word modify so i put a
cursor under that word
called the command we just defined
highlight current word okay enter
you there it is you see it's red
so that's how you do it okay let's go
back to the code uh let's go back to the
code
you know that's how you do it it's so
simple
okay so so far so good comments guys
okay
comments let's see do we have comments
say something hi
uh guys uh
let's see how long have i been talking
there's something wrong with this um
pop-up let's see how long i've been
talking then let's
let's move on to the next topic uh
14 minutes okay it's pretty good
so that is how you highlight uh text
you know might you know you read my
tutorial you explain the whole thing
uh but now okay now let's copy the code
and put it in my this tutorial okay so
um
a second
okay paste the code here show in browser
so we got a code that's today's code and
make it
syntax color refresh so that is our code
for highlighting the current word now
let's move on to the next um
thing we want to do so
so text properties is one of the way one
of the mechanism
in emacs to highlight you know to make
coloring of a text
and this this the thing we just showed
text properties
is actually the the more fundamental
because
every major mod every programming
language my javascript java
c uh uh python
ruby perl any any programming language
mod
you know when they highlight words they
are using
text property mechanism okay
that is what they are using this is the
kind of the most efficient mechanism to
highlight text
uh text properties okay now let me show
you there is another mechanism
as kind of secondary mechanism it's
called overlay
so so it's also
you can see the code here it's actually
pretty simple as well
you know you you all you have to do is
uh
all you have to do is look at that lines
of code you know
overlay put make overlay then
face and bolt and beginning and end
position you you know you give a
beginning and end position of a
buffer then you just call this command
then you say uh what kind of color uh
what you want bold or
you know what whatever so overlay so
what's the difference between overlay
and text properties okay so for
text properties you know it's a it's
it's kind of a
list of pairs that is attached to any
text
in a region in a buffer so when you copy
and paste
any text the color the properties also
go with it
so when you copy your piece of text in
emacs
you actually copied you know for example
this text
you see this color if i cut it
the text properties go with it so if i
paste it here
you know it's again colored actually so
if i open a new buffer
magnify paste it you can see the color
is still there
uh wait okay so let's try again so open
a new text
new buffer and let's make this
fundamental mod
so there is no coloring no coloring in
this in this buffer but however now
let's paste it you see it's your color
why is it color because the text
properties
come with the text okay that's the text
so so what's the difference what's
overlay now overlay is something
different
overlay is kind of just like the english
word overlay like you are laying
something on top of the buffer so it's
not
fixed to the text uh
so what's you know what's the point of
overlay
for example you've seen two tips right
you you've seen
two tips like right now you see the two
tips
the two tips in in css you know the web
technology javascript css
is is kind of overlay you know or in
photoshop photoshop you have layers
you know in photoshop you have layers so
what's so good
for that well that's advantageous in the
sense that
you can modify one layer without you
know modifying
the other layer so that that is what the
overlay is
kind of like so
so overlay there is a cost though
because when you have you know when you
have like
hundreds uh color it's
less efficient so in general you don't
want overlay so when do you want to use
overlay overlay is when you want to
for example when you highlight words
when you call the command
uh highlight phrase you know that
building emacs command let's say
what do you want to highlight let's say
you want to highlight the word keyword
okay and highlight green
now you can see the keywords are
highlighted in green
those are overlay overlay so overlay is
general
in general it's used for ephemeral
purposes like
you you might want to remove the overlay
later on
things like that so that's overlay
okay so actually we are going to do um
so that
so that actually finished the
explanation about overlay we can try
this actually
um let's try it okay so
let's let's let's let's try the code
let's
uh emac this okay create a new buffer
paste the code here i'm just going to
use the
you know copy and paste so this this
command will
highlight the region using the overlay
mechanism
and it will make it both you can see uh
both okay
eval buffer now let's go back to the
html buffer
and let's say i want to overlay this
word figure okay
so so i select it
now first of all it's red right it's red
here so i select it
call the command xsa
make overlay bold
region enter okay you can see now that
that word figure is now bold so that's
overlay
okay uh copy the paste code paste it
here
make it that lag uh put it into our uh
talk show page so that's overlay
okay so that completes my uh
explanation and you know demonstration
of these two
uh text highlighting mechanisms these
are the two
uh mechanism text highlighting
mechanisms
now let's go the next thing we want to
do is let's let's use a practical
example because
i'm going to write i have a command that
does something
and i need you know it it transformed
the buffer text in the buffer
when it's done i want
all the places that has that changed to
be highlighted so i can
easily see it okay so so this is an
application
of the text highlighting
uh okay so far so good where is my uh
uh good morning guys uh you're not good
okay thank you
uh people jason good informatic
it's off topic but why no https in your
website
well that's partly because i'm lazy
you have to do it you know and usually
you have to pay
like 40 a year
anyway so let's go back let's let's make
a practical example okay close that
reopen so this is back to my talk show
now i want to show a practical example
let's see
um okay here
so i have a command that's html remove
or wikipedia link
okay let me show you so for example i
have this
page uh this
is one of my blog about parallel
programming
problem s as asciify
string uh so what the what does this
problem what is the problem basically
when you have a text that has lots of
these
um european language characters
sometimes you know sometimes you want to
remove them
so you want to replace e or cube with
the accent
remove the all those accents
so that that is the task that is the
problem
so on this page the issue is how do you
code it
uh it turns out there are so many ways
to implement that
you know you you can implement this in
in imac list
in commonly speaking scheme in golan in
in javascript in perl
many ways to do it i mean you can use
any language but however
the algorithm turns out it's suitable
for parallel
parallelism so this is a good exercise
for
uh parallel programming
so i mean we are not going to do that
but what we are going to do is you see
there is some
text is green they link to wikipedia
so for example this id and homograph
attack you can you can read it later
and for example duplicate characters in
unicode
so in unicode there are
many characters that look similar but
they are different
okay
so why am i mentioning them because they
are related to these
um you know ascii
they are you know if you want to
implement them they are related to
parallel programming because you can use
parallel programming to do those things
to do these tasks in your algorithm so
anyway my concern
my our concern right now is you see
there are links to wikipedia okay there
are links to wikipedia and also here
so you know anyone want to try it
perhaps in fortress fortress language
siso language urlan language is language
alice language x10 language all these
languages there's one thing
in common they are all designed for
parallel programming
and also closure you know they are all
for parallel programming
but anyway what i want to do is i have a
command i want to remove all these
wikipedia links okay so let's go back
so i have a command let's go to this
page okay copy
uh back to emacs open that page
so this is the this is a page
programming parallel programming
so you if you let's say uh list matching
lines
pdr you can see
all these lines matching you know all
these links in wikipedia
so you have you know uh fortress ciso
erlang
is you know for example let's go to
there
you see this section hey they are or
wikipedia
links now i want i so i have a command
that removes them all so let me show you
let me call the command
um okay so call the command
html remove wiki remove all wikipedia
link
okay so that's a command call it
you see open you see that you see
you see over here it's all the wikipedia
links is good
but however it shows in the message
buffer
so here's the message buffer here is all
the
links that has been just deleted
okay okay
but what i want is i want to i want to
i want the command to highlight here you
know highlight
it so i you know so i can
i can know in the buffer where they
changed
okay so let's let's write that command
that that's what we're going to do
so let's look at the source code for
example remove html
uh source code for
html remove a wikipedia link okay here's
the source code
um so that's so good any questions
comments questions okay uh
where is my where is my
leonato says how can i list the entire
supply keys uh well that's
off topic but you can do it you can do
it by space
control edge okay that's how you list
that's how you list all leader keys okay
let me try it again space
control h okay so now expand this
buffer so that's all the commands for
leader keys
okay so back to our program so so this
this function this command cannot remove
uh all
wikipedia links let me explain what they
how it works
so go to character go to the point
minimum go to the beginning of buffer
then a while loop then search for word
search for word for wikipedia link you
know that's a class you know string so
basically that what that does is it
moves kusa
to a um let's undo
it moves kusa to a
to a wikipedia link here
then okay then
then it sets flag
okay sets flag
okay so what it does is
so it calls another command so here so
then it calls another command
html remove wikipedia link which which
just
removes that one single link
but what it does it return it returns a
flag
then okay so
so this command size we remove wikipedia
links
removes the link at the at the cruiser
position
and it returns the whole link
as flag then what it does
is um
you push that value to a list
removed text list okay then
what it does is you print
you know you you map then
then you map the print function print
basically you want to print
every link you remove to the to the uh
to the message buffer so that so that's
what it does
then just return the list of removed
text
link okay so now what we want to do is
we want to color
color the removed part okay so
so the the main function is this one
this this is a function that removes it
so let's go to it
so here is a function so this function
removes the current
link the cursor is
under okay okay so i
have to i have to explain this um
code okay so let's let's explain the
code then
okay so
so let's then when so it starts to
search for words remember the cursor is
inside the link you search forward
for the end tag of the link
okay when if it's found then it's set
p2 position then
it sets then search backward to the
beginning of the link
the anchor link then sets p1
so py and p2 is the beginning and end
position of the link
then set text to delete
you grab the text you know buffer string
no properties
you give it two positions then it
returns the text
the string under that to position so
save
save that to text to delete then you
search for word
you search for word for the wikipedia
link then
oh my god so this this uh this this
code this thing calls another
command
so you once you move the cursor to the
link then you call another command to
remove html tags
yeah yeah i should have just coded here
uh so
html remove html tags so you call
another command
to remove html tags
that's no good
well you uh
so you call that command that commands
remove the entire link
but what actually what we want to do is
um
let me let me explain okay go back to
the html page
let me explain
so for example you have a wikipedia link
here
you see you have a wikipedia link here
now if you remove the entire link
what you let what what is left is the
you know the link text
this is this is a text we want to
highlight
and in order to do that we need to know
the beginning and end position
okay that's that's what we need but
however
in the current way it works
you don't have that um
you know you cannot you cannot get the
beginning and end position of the
link text because this command
this command actually just removes i
mean this command removes
every possible attack in the region
yeah so it's it's it's getting complex
so we don't want that so let's let's
let's modify the code then
okay let's back to we are back to the uh
let's narrow to region we are back to
these
let's let's code our own okay
so let's quote it quickly so how long
have i been is it so so far so good
feedback uh yes yes type yes okay
let's see how long i've been talking 34
minutes not so bad
so let's code this fast so now remember
right now
the cursor is under a link under
wikipedia link
so now we what we do is search search
backward
search backward to the beginning of the
the html bracket okay
then set p1 okay
let's say p3 p4 okay
position three position four okay
so let's set p3 and p3
is the beginning of the link
actually we don't want to
yeah let's say search for p3 okay
then search for word
uh the end bracket okay i'm going just
going to code fast okay
then set p4
okay then
what we do is we delete region
p3 p4 okay delete region
then search forward
delete region yeah then search forward
search forward that for that
then set p3 then search backwards search
p4 then delete region again
that should be it prettify the code okay
that should be it
okay when
okay that's that's our code
um
it should work okay let's try it
evaluate go to html
undo so we have a we have a wikipedia
link here
now i move the cursor somewhere inside
the link
then call the command start remove h
excel remove wikipedia link code
works you see now the link is good
undo let's go back
okay so far so good now we just now we
are going to do the highlight
okay uh
now we are going to do the highlight but
before we do that
hold on a second let's we need to
let's use begin
link text begin okay
another variable
links text link text end okay link text
begin position
and here will be link text begin
and and here will be link
text end yeah that's it
if i click and i correct
no wait
uh no that's not right okay hold on a
second
so so this part this part
deletes the beginning of um
that part deletes the beginning
beginning
link the beginning tag of the link
let me write it so it's it's clear
okay this is the beginning tag dvdn
tag and link tag
okay now
in between we are going to do
set
link text begin
okay so that's that is the position
where the link text begins
then
then the link tag text end is is here
okay so
yep that's that okay so far the code
works exactly the same
we just added two more positions link
text begin
and link text end now
now what we are going to do is overlay
add the color remember we are we want to
add the color
so um so let's go back to our code
so how do you do overlay you do it this
way
uh wait
yeah okay all right so i don't have a
overlay put describe function
uh describe functions so here is the
documentation for overlay overlay put
property value okay
so here's a function overlay put
make overlay begin end will be
[Music]
okay link text begin link text end
then property will be i want it red
you know i don't i want it read so for
red
you can use this code okay
property will be
here is our property and here is the
value
there let's make it so
there and facebook we don't want
facebook
okay
so this code this code will uh color it
red
let's let's try if it works okay
eva evalda wait uh syntax zero
unbalanced parent somewhere i got it
uh wrong back trace
wait
okay yeah i copy okay so now it's good
uh
let's pretty fire this a little bit
yeah yeah
evaluate the expression
then back to the html
shrink a little bit delete that
let's go down so we we go to the
position
where there is lots of wikipedia links
you see so there's a lot of wikipedia
links
now i'm going to call the command html
remove all wikipedia links
so all these links will be done but
but the words the words like you know
the link text will be
read so let's call it let's hope it
works
it's not remove or wikipedia link do it
yay it worked
but we got a problem you see this word
is highlighted red
but apparently something went wrong so
uh
you know something is uh went wrong
but but that's ideas so uh we just now
undo
let's we need to fix the bugs so wait
undo again so why is that
how did it happen so that
you know it highlighted in such a
strange
way
okay i know now remember before we said
that
if you use overlay mechanism to color
text
it doesn't stick with the text it kind
of floats
you know it marks two position and
and but if you change your buffer if you
delete lots of
text before it the overlay coloring
doesn't change
it doesn't move with the text that's the
reason i think that's a reason
so so i haven't
logically thought about this but we can
actually go back to the code
so instead of using overlay let's just
use
the you know put text properties you
know just let's just um
so actually we improved our code so
instead of overlay let's say
put text properties okay i don't have a
shortcut
so let's copy the code here
there it is put put text properties
position okay position will be
this position will be that link begin
link end
then the property will be found face
foreground red
okay um
yeah so let's comment out the overlay
thing
that's it so let's make this one line
okay so
uh whoops
so we evaluate the code
back to html back to this html
close it reopen it so we got a fresh
html show in browser
so you see this is the this is you know
that page
uh you go down you see all these links
now we're going to call the command
remove or wikipedia link
call it done
uh okay so the it's still incorrect
okay so debug again so apparently
the problem is not due to overlay the
problem is due to
our mark position is incorrect
so i mean so the code here the
so we have to think about that
okay so let's see search backward search
forward
uh so this is the beginning tag then uh
set oh i know why okay
so you cannot you you have to
okay should we explain so far so good
should i explain what's going on you
guys know dude
okay let me explain you guys are quiet
say something so let me explain the code
so what
so what's going on so
so what's going on is um
undo
i'm not sure do i still make sense say
something guys
so at this point does that make sense or
getting
more complex should i explain or should
i just go ahead and just
make it work and everyone is happy
okay so what happens is that you see so
so let me show let me show okay so let
me show let me show a code
for example so here is a wikipedia link
so what happened is that when the
cruiser so we are moving
so cruiser is inside the link somewhere
okay so first of all we switch backward
to the to the angle bracket
then we search forward to the closing
anchor bracket so the cruiser is
right here now we want to delete that
that part so we delete it
and we want to know the beginning
position of the word
the link text so
we have to you know what we have to do
we have to delete this first
then set the position because otherwise
if you set the position now then you
delete it
the position is wrong and you you and
you know because
you already deleted you know some text
above so the position will be incorrect
so what you need to do is you need to
delete it
then set position okay so that is why
our code is not working
properly so let's go back to the code
so you see this
setting should be
should be it should be here okay wait
and we got
that wrong so so you see we delete the
position i mean we delete the region
first
then we set the
uh position similarly here
similarly here okay
okay let's just run the code let's use
the overlay again
okay evaluate the buffer
now let's go back to the
let's go back to the html page
call the command custom remove or
wikipedia link
do it hey fantastic now you can see
success it becomes the text becomes red
and all the removed links
shows in the message buffer
okay so that is that that is what we
uh wanted to do today how long i've been
talking 51 minutes
so i think that's it for today thank you
guys for coming by
uh yeah so if there is there so
so now we are back in browser let's
refresh once you refresh all this
wikipedia link will be good do it
good so it's good back to the talk show
so let's clean up we and we shut down in
three minutes okay we shut down
we clean up the code a little bit uh
yeah here's our code
copy the code actually this is part of
html
part of html mod so actually
let's uh modify it let's
update the version name and let's say
let's update the version name and go
back here
and update the version name of the mod
okay so i want to add the date stamp
and wait wait
okay add a date stamp
not that
i want add a date stamp version 8.12
then something okay save it
magic
i want to sync to the edge uh my github
so here is let's see what we changed
so we changed uh quite a few things
okay let me let me uh actually there's
more than one change
so so
split buffer speed buffer
okay hold on a second so
so this command now highlight
change
and also
now
let's describe variable
describe variable major
uh describe variable
major mod that's how you find the
technical name of the mod
okay so the technical name of the mod is
html mod
so now html mod is based on
html mod i'm writing the commit message
and html remove wikipedia link is now
we are now uh highlight change change so
that's my
commit message cut that
delete that close magic close it
do it again magic status
and
type s to stage
the file uh type cc to commit
they ask me a commit message okay
so the commit message we typed there
before okay
now ctrl c ctrl c to commit
now it's commented now let's push it to
the server
capital p p so now it's
on my github xl html
mod good
close above a close-up of uh that's the
code we
done uh before we close it we want to
um close it
uh let's i want to show the source code
describe function jump to the source
code
there it is copy it close it
close this page uh
close that back to the talk show page
where is the talk show page
yeah go to talk show
talk show and at the bottom
uh insert the emac this template
show in browser so at the bottom
here's today's code now let's syntax
color it
color it back to browser
refresh there it is that's today's code
thank you guys for watching
if you like my stuff go to
my emacs tutorial you can learn all
about this
in detail and buy my tutorial okay
thank you guys for watching
bye guys
you