Hello guys, welcome to another episode
of talk show. We are going to code wan
language geometry. Okay, let's begin
quickly. Let's just start. Um, yeah. So,
if you are here, say hi. Love to see
your comments. If you are watching this
offline, uh, play at 1.5 speed and skip
around because I ramble. Hello,
Chokeman. Cher man. Okay. So, woofam
language coding. So, any questions ask
me about wam
language. Um, yeah, if you are watching
offline, skip skip around. Okay. So, uh
video check, audio check. Good to go.
So, let's let's go.
Okay. So, uh let's stop stop
this. Stop. Okay.
So, I have done like hundred videos on
woof language. So just search for it,
you'll find it. So I won't be doing
introduction
today. So last time about two weeks ago
we did this uh wam language graphics for
beginner draw pedo curve. So that
involves learning how to do graphics in
wam language and also mathematics
mathematics of vectors. Okay. So watch
that one. Today we going to clean up the
code here. Uh I'm just going to show you
some wam coding. Okay. So, let's copy
that. Uh, we need to do some cleanup
code here.
Okay. So, let's
um start a code block. So, here uh so
here is wofam language and we need to so
let's go to the previous talk show uh
here and uh I want to copy some links.
Okay. Uh so we got this parabola
uh parabola curve and wam language
tutorial. Copy it. Okay. Close. Okay.
Let's paste it
here and remove the section. Remove
that. Remove to do. Okay. Showing
browser. So that's today. So we got
start to code. Okay. So
um so wam language. Hello guys. Hello
guys. Say hi. and uh ask me questions
about wam language. Okay, we're going to
focus exclusively on wolfam language go
mouse save and dam. Okay, so wam
language. So let me just show you the
code first. What does it do? So kind of
flashy. So a new uh a new notebook. Uh
let's
magnify 125. Paste it and uh magnify.
Okay. So we pasted the code. So we are
defining this function here is the
inline documentation. That's how you do
it. Uh the inline documentation. So
shift enter to evaluate it. Then this
part is the code. Now now this part
shift controln to make it type set so it
looks
better. Okay then. Okay. Then then uh
then split shift control D to split into
two cells. Now shift enter to evaluate
that. So now UFA language knows this
function. Okay. And this is how we
actually use the functions. Use the
function. Shift enter. There it is.
Okay. So we did the animation of moving
the point. Then you see the line change.
very fantastic. Uh my job today is to
update this code. Okay. So uh this code
to kind of modernize it because this
code is like two years uh this code is
like 30 years old. Okay. So let me show
you one by one. So first of all so okay
so you got this code. So you got I want
to modernize the code but also make it
easier to understand because right now
in this code I use a lot of the woofam
syntax shortcuts for example this slash
at most people wouldn't know what it
means or this amperand so remove that
turn them into more normalized standard
um syntax so everyone can understand it
okay so let's just begin okay so this
part you see this part the amperand that
means a function. So that means whatever
before it this is a function. So this
can be written uh like this. Okay. So
um
what yeah so can be written like this.
Let me just let me just show you.
Okay. So remove that amp percent uh and
uh and uh uh then x. Okay. So xx
fxx okay so that is equivalent to that
but this can be further simplified this
add sign is a shortcut shortcut it's a
prefix notation so it is equivalent to x
okay that that okay so same thing let's
do that so these three lines are
completely equivalent okay Because what
wuam language does that whenever you run
a code the first thing it will do is you
it will transform the syntax to to the
full form. So actually this is
equivalent to uh let me do it
again.
Um so the pound sign just stand for the
argument. You see over here this
function is like a lambda. So x is a
local variable the the bound variable
the parameter. So then you apply xf
function to x and yf function to x make
them a list. But here is exactly the
same thing but just shorter syntax. So
all these four lines are
equivalent. Now if you want to know
about details go to wam language
tutorial search on
kasali.info. Okay. and you go to the
functions go down there's a section on
defining a function then then you go
down there is a function syntax shortcut
so that will explain you see examples of
the equivalence between these various
forms so in this form it's a shortest
you know cryptic but nobody understand
but this and then the second crypted is
this because nobody understand what's
the pound sign. So, so then this make it
a bit more simpler. So, you can see x is
a bound bound variable and you know fx
at x and yf at x. This one is more uh
everyone can understand. So, let's use
this one. Okay. So, that's a sample. Um
that's okay. So, let's just use that.
So here
n what n means n at okay so here
n at something uh let's say uh 2 over
three okay that is a shortcut notation
for like we explained
before okay so these two are exactly the
same so what does the n function do is
that it it um changes or symbolic or
exact expressions into numerical code.
Okay. So for example, you can just uh
run it. Let's run it. Uh actually I can
run it here. Okay. So I can run
it. Uh running for the first time takes
a
while. Wait. Okay. So finally you see
0.66 66 and this same thing. Okay, the
same result. Run
it. Same result. Okay, but if you do
this in wam language, it's the same
thing. Shift enter. See. And
here, shift enter. Now, if you just do
2.3, it returns that exact result. For
example, you can say 4 /ed by 10. it
will reduce the fraction but you get a
fraction okay so whenever you want
numerical result just slap a n in front
of it okay that's what this n do okay so
now here I want you know I want to say
numerical but let's remove it I don't
want numerical
um so now another syntax you see this
range let me explain that one okay so
usually uh you know so usually you map a
function to a list. Okay. So, range
range is uh range means uh let me show
you. Okay. 1 to
five. So, that means apply the
function
f to range just generate a list of
numbers 1 2 3 4 5. So, you get that.
Okay.
Um Okay. So, but there's a syntax
shortcut. So, instead of writing that,
you can write
um
f map. Not that uh uh do I have a
shortcut? Maybe not. Okay. So, you
can This is a syntactical shortcut. They
mean exactly the same thing. So wam
language whenever you run it it will
change all these shortcut syntax to the
full form like that then it will
evaluate. So they are 100% syntactic
syntactically equivalent. So in some
language you know in in computer science
sometimes they call it sugar syntax but
the sugar syntax syntax in skim list in
JavaScript they are not exactly the
same. They are not exactly identical.
Okay. So but in the wufam language they
are 100% identical because whenever you
run something in wuam language it will
turn all these syntactical shortcuts to
this full form syntax like this is kind
of like this fully nested then evaluate
so they are like 100% the same. So
that's a critical that's kind of one
important aspect of wufam language
syntax. Okay. Now you can learn about
these what I just talked about at this
article on that um let's see global
variables local variables conditional
loop iteration functions pattern
matching data structure uh and advanced
symbols principles full form. Okay. So
this article warm language full form
syntax will explain the
details about what you know what we
would uh I was just talking
about and uh if you go to the full form
versus uh let's see uh syntax operators
cheat sheet this page will give you a
complete list of all these kind of
syntactical shortcuts uh very
interesting because this this syntax
system allows you to have infix
notation. You know 3 + 4 will actually
become plus 3 4 you know three divided
by four or or list uh you know so it
allows infix notation. So this page
lists all of them like you can learn all
about them. So for example, the add sign
we mentioned before is right here. Add
sign is just a prefix notation for f
bracket x. Okay. So let's go back to
clean up the code. So we are doing here.
So so this this part so this part let's
change it. So let's change it to the
full form uh because that's simpler to
read. and uh map at so this range map at
this range okay so this line is
equivalent to that
okay so let's just remove that so now
okay so next other things I want to
change now
remove let's see other things I can
change so hue now hue hue is a color
function So it you know it re it just
represent red. Okay. So if you look up
the documentation hue is
um hue
uh hue saturation brightness model for
color. Okay. So you can read more about
it. Hue. But this 30 years ago. So today
you have
um today you have um you know if you
want red close that uh let's go back
here if you want red you can say red
just say red okay so this is added I
don't know maybe 10 years ago uh more
than 10 years ago 15 years ago so you
can have blue instead of the hu
something something number so this so in
other words you
named colors. Okay. So, let's change
this
hue just to red. Okay. And the hue.7 is
blue because I memorized it by now you
know because coding wam language h.7 is
blue. Uh so I memorized now this part
this uh numerical result let's remove
it. So in wine language whenever you
have an argument
that's already approximate number then
the full expression will be approximate
approximate approximate number okay so
you don't necessarily need the n if if
your you know a and b or whatever the
argument is numerical so if you start
with a exact expression like fractions
or symbolic expression pi Okay, then the
result will always be symbolic and
exact. But if you begin with a uh CPU
number like you know so-called by the C
guys float or float float then the
result is float. Okay. So you so so why
do I have a N
there? Well because when you are uh
creating graphics you don't need
symbolic result. You don't want the you
know all the computation of the graphics
by using symbolic result because it
doesn't make sense because you just want
to see a graphics. So when you use
approximate approximate machine numbers
they become faster. That's why that's
why I put all these n to force them into
uh you know the machine numbers.
But it's not you know but if you don't
if you don't do it
then it'll still work you know but it
depends on two things depends on when
when you call this function if your
argument for example this mean max if
you are given giving them uh machine
numbers if you do all is good but if you
don't then the computation will be done
in uh exact numbers so it's much slower
you fractions, they will reduce
fractions and so on and but when it
finally finally tries to show the
graphics, it'll still work. It's just
slower. Okay, so the advantage
of of adding, you know, forcing
numerical result is that it's faster.
It's always faster. But the
dis disadvantage is
that is that you know so the advantage
of not having that n to false machine
number is that you can control what kind
of uh result you want because if you
want numerical result you just call it
you just call this function with
numerical inputs like
this. But if you want exact
uh you know fractions symbolic
computation then you just use for
example this 0.25 25 then you just say
uh one over four instead you know then
you compute symbolically but what is the
purpose when you want when you do
graphics symbolically because sometimes
sometimes you don't want just the
graphics sometimes you want you know
this mathematical formula to create
something you actually want the result
to work to continue to work with it so
so that is why sometimes it's useful
just sometimes usually usually not.
Usually when you call a graphics
function, all you want is just a
graphics. So anyway, so that's why I'm
removing the N. Do I make sense? Okay.
Uh do you do job or no? Uh what kind of
question is that? I don't answer that
question. Okay. What? Like you you want
to pay me for
something? Uh so next, let's see. I want
to Yeah, I want to optimize. So this
part. So let's just um again let's let
me do
that. So this one let me rewrite this.
Okay. So rewrite this uh cup
points. Okay. And map this
function. Okay. So
this Okay. So you don't need that. So
that's these two are
equivalent. Um by the way function has
many other representations, many other
syntax.
Um shall shall I go ahead?
Um hold on a
second. So these two are exactly the
same. Let me show you another
representation for a function. So
another representation for a function is
that uh here. Okay. So you just
say
x do that that that okay
x2 x. Okay. So you can see this is also
kind of familiar to a lot of people. So
you got x is a parameter. You this means
a function. it then this means return
that okay
uh you know so x is here so this these
three lines are all equivalent okay now
typically in wolfam language if you or
mathematica if you code a lot
usually a lot of people just use that
because it's
uh easier to type kind
of anyway so so So let's I don't want
that. I want this function fully spelled
out.
Okay. So these two lines are exactly the
Wait, not not the same. Okay. So next
uh next. So next uh Okay. So let's
rewrite this
one. Yeah. Okay. So line. Okay. is a
line is a function
uh
fn. So we just want
that. Yeah. So
uh
map map this function
to
this. Okay. So these two are exactly the
same.
Uh, wait, I forgot the line. Hold on a
second. I forgot the line. You cannot
forgot the
line.
Wait. Yeah. So
that
cut. Now in fact, we can actually just
test it. Okay. Just test it. Did we made
uh some error? Run it. Oh, you need to
clear it first. So clear it
then code. Then try this
again. Fantastic. So far still good.
Still good. Now next one you we're going
to rewrite this this block. Okay. paste.
Um, again it's a map. So you see map is
used used so often. Okay.
So map function to a to
the to the curve points. And what is the
function? The function is going to be
okay this
one. Cut.
Cut. Paste. Okay.
So that okay let's see map a function
this function is a line and this line is
a list of things and the list got two
things one is this uh reverse normalized
uh and we got the n again let's remove
the n for numerical
result fantastic hello I don't know Uh
okay so this okay so this n for
numerical result let's remove it okay
uh okay so we got normal normalize
normalize means turn a vector into a
um unit vector okay then you reverse uh
yeah
Okay. Okay. The Okay. This is uh this is
vector vector geometry. You move you you
know you you you do
um you you basically this part you
rotate the line 90
degrees. Yeah. That's what it does by
this trick. Okay. Then you increase the
length by 100. Okay. So this part. Okay.
So let's just do that. Okay. So
let's make sure it's correct. One one
double check last time.
Okay.
Yeah. You sure? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. Then then the last part, the show
graphics. We don't actually
um now 30 years ago you always need to
call show but but sometimes like in 2005
you don't need to call show anymore or
you can you can just call graphics
whenever you have a graphics it will
automatically show. So you remove the
show and put the options here. Okay.
So, so something like that. Okay. So,
something like
that. Now, copy that. Now, go to the
top. Cut that. And let's let's copy the
documentation. Okay. Let's clean up the
documentation. Let's remove the line
here. Draws the negative pedal lines of
a parametric curve. XF YF at points uh
at points let's clarify this this
uh use English from min to
max with step okay so let's instead of
using code use English to explain okay
so that is that x and y must be pure
functions
Okay. Uh this part is a bit technical
and here's the example again example
using this cryptic notation. So let's
not do that. Let's use
um let's let's convert it to a way most
people would
understand function uh fun uh uh file
name. Okay.
Wait function. Yeah. Okay. So,
w there's a abbreviation issue in my
Emacs, but
anyway. So, let's make it verbose so
that people can understand the most when
you have verbose syntax. Okay. So that
that that that that that
that. Okay. So here's the example. This
pedo plot function takes two arguments.
The f first one is a list of two
functions for x and y. The second one is
a range uh from 0 to 2 pi instead of in
steps of 2 pi divided by 30. Now you see
let's make it numerical. So you when you
put a dot after a number that makes the
computation using machine
numbers which is C
C++ what they call
float. Okay. So here and what is the
last argument? So wait mean max step
mean max step and what is this X0? Oh
that is a pedo point. Okay.
uh so we can we can kind of do that. So
this is one thing. Okay. So instead of
that you know so these two are
equivalent. So but let's use the uh easy
to understand
one. Okay. So let's shorten the usage.
Okay. So now copy that. Go back to our
new code here. So now copy all that.
Copy back to wam language. Let's
paste. Paste. Okay. New
code. Evaluate it. It's done. Now,
now, now let's call
it here.
Uh
fantastic and let's let's try a example
we have here you know negative pillow
plot. So whenever you want to ask the
inline documentation in wan language you
just type the question mark and the
whatever function name. So you see it
returns the documentation we just
defined here. So you see so you you see
now you copy now when you copy paste
this it returns a string which is not
good. Okay now so now control shift
control shift N to make it type set. Oh
beautiful now let's try to run it shift
enter. Fantastic. Okay. So what is this?
This is s and cosine. You want to do the
pedo of s and
cosine. And what is this information
usage text? Okay, that's not
good. Line spacing. Um why do we have
line
spacing? Yeah. Okay. So that's some
artifact from this. But anyway, let's
try this
again. So 0 to 2 pi. Uh yeah, so you
need to
say plot range.
Okay, plot range and
uh plot range.
Um I don't want all. So plot range x x
and y x from let's say 2 to six
27 y from
uh y
from oh we got a style here that's
up. That's why that's why you got
this thing. Hold on a second. Let's try
again.
Yeah. Okay. So, you need the plot range
y from uh y from
negative two to three. Let's just say
that.
Okay.
Copy. Okay. Let's put the plot range
there.
See?
Fantastic. Oh, right. This is s cosine.
So let's say
uh -1 to 1 multiply them by 3. Same
thing here. -1 2 1 ult* by 3 enter.
Beautiful. Ah right. So this negative
pedal the ne negative pedal of a circle
with respect to a point inside the
circle gets you a elisp can you
see so uh if you want you know so let's
say increase the plot points you know
40 fantastic so you see the so this
shows the relationship one of the
relationship between a circle and
elp with respect to the
elp's
focus I believe so okay don't take my
word for it because you need to check
the mathematics but visually it seems
like that's the
case so this is about a property of
negative pedo curve okay so but we need
to update the you see we need to add the
plot range because otherwise it
just you know otherwise wise it shows
the whole thing it's not
good. So we we make the plot rate you
know we update the documentation. So
this uh actually we don't want to use
that. So let's you know it's showing the
back slash
square bracket pi is
because when you copy it shows that
because we are using uh type set pi
there you see. So if you don't want the
type set pi, you just control shift
control shift I to turn it into a you
know normal
um normal input form. Okay. So now
copy now copy paste. You see now you got
the normal I and you got the
multiplication sign which can be a space
but if you want to be verbals you can
have it. Okay. Okay. So that is the
that. Okay. So make it one line and uh
let's delete our uh
that. Okay. So we we got things done one
by one. So let's copy the all and we can
actually select or paste run it. Okay.
And
then then we copy the documentation
here. Let's see. We can copy that.
Paste. Good. Now it's much better. Yeah.
So fantastic.
Beautiful. So are we done yet? Mostly.
Okay. So remember my job what I want to
do is to update modernize this this
function
definition. And uh here you see I don't
have formatting. So right now I'm using
kasaw mod. It's free online.
So here's the source code wa mod. So
about 3,000 lines of code, but most of
it is the woofam language.
Uh 7,000 symbols, you see 7,000 building
functions. So you if you want to code,
you can just grab it on GitHub. It
allows you to um code wam language in
Emacs. Okay. So that's some wam mod. But
yeah, one feature I don't have is that I
don't have formatting code. So I I want
to format this code for example. Then
you need to like uh tap tap tap tap tap,
you know, kind of like that. You see, I
don't want to do it manually and I don't
want my code to do it manually. I want a
function that
automatically grab a fun, you know, a
valid wine language source code such as
a function to then reformat the whole
thing, you know, one button press
reformat like go format like deno
format in go language and javascript. So
I don't have that function. So right now
I can do it in with wufam language. You
see I paste it here. So you got the
code. Then you copy it. You copy it and
paste it back here. Paste it back. You
see Wuam language formatted for you. You
see? So you manually go to a trip to
Wuam language. So I I still need to
figure out how that is done. Um, you
know, so I can incorporate the the pedi
formatting in my wui mod. Okay. So now
this part is we can just delete that.
Okay. So now we did many things. We
cleaned up the code. Is there something
else we want to do?
Um how long have I 40 minutes? So far so
good. Okay. So uh so maybe that's it. Uh
or maybe is there something I need to
do?
Um something else. Okay. So there's
another question. Okay.
So yeah. So another question which is
about the definition of a functions
optional parameter. You see this
part.
Um now to explain
that you see let's go back to
uh wra language operators. Uh let's go
to wam language definition of a
function define function. Let's open it.
New tab. By the way uh Firefox now got
vertical tabs. So guys, you need to uh
upgrade and uh you know it's a great
feature. So wam language define
functions. Now our issue is about
defining optional
parameters. Okay. So let me explain.
That's not um so you know this is a
topic by itself because when you define
a function in different programming
languages there are a lot
issues there is sequential ordered
parameter that's one thing that's the
most typical you know you just list of
things uh each argument has specific
order matters then you got optional
parameters ters. So what happens if some
of them are missing? Then you got
default values. So optional parameters
that's one thing. Default values is
related but not entirely the same thing.
Default value is a separate thing. So
ordered arguments, optional parameters,
default values, that's another thing.
Then you have rest parameters which is
like you might have lots of more
parameters. For example, plus addition,
you know, you could have 10 arguments. 1
+ 3 + 7, you know, or just one argument,
you know, or infinite or lots of. So,
you got so-called rest
parameters. Then you got named
parameters which allows you to give a
name because otherwise you got just got
bunch of values. You you forgot which
one is
which. Um, you know, imagine you're
going to launch your missile. There's a
function launch missile. Then you got 10
buttons, you know, launch it fast,
launch it within 10
seconds. Then the third third argument
is uh launch via via submarine or
something, you know. So you got true
true force force true force, but you
don't know which one, you know, when you
call a function. So that's when you need
named arguments.
Then then you have like launch via
submachine then equals to true or false
then each one is more uh
clear. So anyway so you got rest
parameters then you got
um uh you got others I forgot. So in
each language they have support for for
some of these and they have different
ways to do it. Okay, quite many
varieties. Uh in some languages they
don't even you know have like parameters
in in the in the function declaration
that because they automatically whatever
argument automatically becomes an array.
So then you have a special variable to
access that array. So very different
from different languages.
So you know there's a design issue first
of all you know the the issue about
mathematically about about the
parameters of a function that's one
thing like optional named ordered you
know then there's the programming
language language issue about them okay
anyway so what we want to do yeah so
what we have here is this options
parameters so so you see what that does
is uh you see we use the option you see
plot range you see plot range is an
option in graphics there's tons of other
options for
example op options and uh let's
call I want to see all options in
graphics you see so you you got access
you got color output uh color Output C
output. You got axis style. You got
baseline position. You got grid lines.
Whether you want it to draw the grid,
you
got frames. Frames is is like the border
box around the graphics. You know, you
can have the border box. And then you
have frame tick. You know, whether you
want ticks on the on the frame.
Sometimes that's useful. Uh then you
have axis true or false. whether you
want the XY axis and also you see
there's no numbers there. So you can
also specify axis uh ticks you know
that's this one. So you can you know say
you know at one 0.5 zero 0.5 one one.5
or what other you know so you got these
options so but these options are part of
graphics but not part of the function
I'm defining so these
options I want to pass it you see this
option
um okay this option I want to pass it to
graphics X over here. So that is what
I'm
doing. So
um but so okay. So but but there is
something about that I might want to
change. I don't remember at the moment.
So let's look
up. Uh oh yeah. So yeah. So yeah, the is
the situation is the way I'm doing it.
You see this
style, you see the way I'm doing it is
kind of
old-fashioned. It's like 30 years ago.
There's a better way to do
it.
Um Yeah. So
it it's kind of expand here. Okay. Yeah.
Uh but let's not do it. It's it's
getting, you know, that would gets a bit
technical. So, okay, that's it for
today. Thank you guys for watching.
Yeah, I think that's it for today. Uh 50
minutes. Okay. So, so this thing I need
to think about offline. Okay. So, let's
see today's work. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So,
uh so delete that. Delete that. Delete
that. Delete that. Okay. So, let's see.
Uh, yeah. So, delete that. See? Got
that. Okay. So, delete that. So, this
this is today's uh output. Good. So, we
clear the function. We define the inline
doc string. Then we define the function
here. Uh, then we call it. Okay. So,
good. So now put it
back. Syntax corette showing
browser. Fantastic. Bye guys. If you
like my stuff, pay me. Okay. Go to
cassadi.info my homepage. Then scroll
all the way down to the bottom. Patreon
me, Amazon gift card me, PayPal me.
Okay.
Bye, Cher.
Bye.
Bye. Thank you guys for watching.