Hello guys, good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Exam talk
show. We are going to code wuam language
today. Wuam language geometry.
So we going to spend an hour to create
wam language code like that
to draw this thing. So it will be a
general function.
Anyone can just copy it and paste the
code and it'll run. So the goal, you
know, I already have the code here, but
the goal is to not
not uh use a package like this is my
code, but it requires this package. You
have to download for free. It's on my
website. I talked about many times. Uh
but we're going to rewrite this so that
people don't need to
have this package installed. they can
you can just run the code about six 60
lines of code. Okay, in fact we can
shrink it. We can make it like just a
few lines. So anyway, that's a goal. So
the goal is to create a program that
allows you to draw the uh actually not
not we we already have this code
actually it's allows you to draw any
costics. Okay, so it's more complex.
This is just tangents. I mean this is
just normal lines. Okay. Uh normals
normals are lines that is perpendicular
to the tangent. Okay. So but we are
going to draw a code that does this.
Okay. That does this reflection. So
optical property. So you you you have a
a ray
uh light from a light source light ray
from a source and it bounce off the
curve. It reflection or refraction.
Okay, that is what we're going to code.
Now this one is normal lines we already
coded. I let me show you. Okay, let me
show you. So anyway, if you are watching
this offline, play at 1.5 speed. If you
are here, say hi. If you are offline,
fly.
Uh if you are here, say hi. Okay. So,
we're gonna code this. It's gonna be
like an hour talk. Uh yeah. Okay. So, is
everything good? So, if you don't know,
I've done by now over 100 videos on wam
language. You can
uh download the woofam language. Just
search for uh Kasali Wuam language for
programmers
at kasali.com.
Okay. So let me demonstrate one more
time. Copy that wam language. Wait, what
did what did we copy? Okay, not that. So
we want to copy that
wam language for programmers. Okay, that
is a wam language site. Uh do they show
my website? No.
Okay. So, uh
yeah. So, that's all Wuam language
website. They have very good
documentation, but they literally have
like millions of pages.
So, there you can see uh launch
launching today free wam engine. So,
that so that became free in 2019.
So, wam language for programmers. So
best introduction that's their uh
introduction but they have different
approach
mine well of course I believe mine is
better so there it is wam language
tutorial okay so you can download it and
so on but you know oni.info kxi.info
info. So anyway, so let's let's go back
to what do what we want to do. We we
want to uh
code this. Okay. So so let's do that.
Okay. So so let me show you first of all
the this this uh normal lines. Okay. So
first of all you copy. So let me uh let
me show you. So this code will create
any
um
copy paste shift enter. It lets you draw
the tangent lines and normal lines for
any parametric curve. Okay. So this this
code is good.
Uh
okay. So then then okay. So we we got
that copied. Um, so what are we doing?
So, so here's a code.
Okay, that's uh, so we want to go go to
the Hello. Hello mach
greeting from Germany. Hello Germany.
Um,
oh now, okay, let's go there. So we want
to yeah we want to regenerate this
image. Okay. So let's um
let's go this
we want to open now. So what section is
this
uh evolute? Okay. Search for evolute.
Okay. And uh then there is the language
code that we're going to create another
one and pop it out. And okay, so hold on
a second. Yeah, here.
Paste it. Pop it out. And we need to
know what is the equation the parametric
equation for for this
S shaped curve. Okay. So let's copy
that. Let's
so the parametric equation is just that
okay
that okay so that would be uh cosine sin
sin cosine sin cosine okay so that would
be
yeah so you just copy that and replace
this part so that is the curve function
okay and the other important thing is
the plot range so it's t from 0 to 2 pi
and uh in in steps of 2 pi over 60.
That's a steps. That's also important.
So let's put that somewhere.
Uh plot range. Uh yeah. So plot range
here.
Now you don't
equal to 2 pi. Okay. So but you don't
take a step over there. Uh
cut. Okay. 0 to 2 pi and in steps of
oh god in steps of um 60. Okay.
So what you do here is so that is the
range. So you just say range range is
like this range function is like
python's range. It generates a list of
numbers. So you just say 0 to 2 pi and
in steps of 2 pi over 60.
Am I good? Video check. Audio check.
Hello Germany. So this creates let me
show you. So we can run it. It will
create a bunch of numbers. Okay. Uh
incorrect. Oh you you don't want the uh
brackets. Okay. So do it again.
You see now you see now that's symbolic
you know wufam language returns symbolic
result. So that's interesting for
example you you run this in wam language
is symbolic result. Now if you want
numeric code all you have to do is you
slash slash that's postcript notation n
is the function that means numeric code
or alternatively just any of the number
you give it a machine number like 60
then it returns machine precision okay
so so that is the um range okay so
delete that cut that so the range list
will be that Okay. And uh let's say n
capital n is the numerical code. We want
numerical code result. So it's much
faster. So so what else? So plain curve
plot. So uh so curve color function we
don't care. Plot curve aspect ratio and
plot range is important. So plot range
because it usually it's specific to each
curve. Okay. Plot range that.
Okay. So let's see what else. Uh that
that plot dot plot curve uh that special
uh plot range aspect ratio axis axis
true. Uh yeah usually we want axis. So
we can see you see like when you do
mathematics usually you want to draw
axis so that you can see what things are
where especially when you are coding it.
Now if you want artistic representation
then if at the end you remove the axis
so you you got kind of more of artistic
representation. Okay.
So anyway so so so that you don't need
anymore no no need for that package. So
this is all code. So I think that will
work. Let's try. So select all paste.
Okay, there's a code. Shift CtrlN to
make it type set. Fantastic. And
beautiful. Now we got arrow here. We got
an extra um comma. So it became new. So
we don't want that.
Okay. So huh. So So that means I got
that error in my other code. So let's go
fix it. So um
open
tangent tangent. Okay. So
yeah there you see
you see that you you don't want the
comma. So copy that select or paste
shift control to type set. Okay. There's
nothing special. Okay. Shift enter.
That's tangent lines the red and the
normal lines which is perpendicular to
the tangent.
Okay. So um so so we fix that put it
back syntax color it show in browser so
that it's about tangent page. This is
also on my website by the way. So you
can copy the code but but again I got a
issue with my website. So it hasn't been
I was not able to update it for a month.
So but it should be fixed. So by the
time you watch this video I don't know
in the next week or so it'll be fixed.
Okay. So anyway we fixed that tangent
code. Okay. Now close that tangent. Now
this go back to this uh we need to we
fix that. Okay. Copy that. Now go back
here. Select all. Paste shift enter.
Let's see what we get. Fantastic. But we
don't get the
we don't get the tension and no more
lines.
Okay, we we we plotted the curve and we
also got the dots. The dots should be uh
but where are our lines? So we got some
issues.
What does this language do better than
Python? Oh, it's a magnitude better.
It's like a magnitude like okay let me
let me explain in five minutes well in
let me explain in two minutes because
I've done hours and hours of video about
why wolfen language is a magnitude
better you can just search for my
YouTube you know um well maybe I I
should show you one but um anyway so so
the reason is that
uh basically one line of wolf FM
language is equals to 10 lines of Python
or a thousand or a million depending on
which how you count. Now if you go by
just Python itself without all the you
know the math libraries or numpy and all
that then one line of wound language is
like 10,000 lines of python because you
know you can you well normally if you
just code without mathematics one line
of wound language is like one is like 10
lines of python typically okay but if
you count mathematics like solving
equations doing integrals, derivatives,
matrix, matrix equations, uh
differential equations, then
obviously Python cannot do that. So you
need numpy and all that all together you
got like uh 4 gabyte few gabyte python
libraries you know to all together
including machine learning you can you
know like there's anacondra you can pack
it together
I believe that's what called like python
huge thing download anaconda
distribution so that's like 3 gigabyte
or something that combines everything in
Python, you know, or uh math, math,
sciences, engineering. So, you know,
um
you know, and and also uh uh machine
learning like it basically packs
everything Python together. Okay.
So now if you compare this with wufam
language it's still true one line of wam
language is 10 to 100 lines of python
with the anacondra
that's what I mean that's why it's a
magnitude
beyond um and you don't have to even you
don't have to load any library like by
default you got 7,000 functions built in
like in Python when you want to do
regular expression you need to load
regular expression library. When you
want to go through fi files in a
directory, you need to load, you know,
you know, system.io or or file path
library, traverse library and so on. But
in UF language, it's all building by
default 7,000 functions.
Then of course then you you got
libraries, you got lots of other things
and cloud stuff and you know uh but
anyway, so that's kind of the summary.
Okay. So why you know why this is uh far
better far a magnitude beyond Python?
No. So why why didn't people use that?
Well becau there are several reasons
because first of all it's not open
source. So you have to pay now. You can
download for free versions of course
since like six year six years ago free
um you know for personal use. So it's
fantastic
and and also of of course all these
quality you see these images if you do
this Python it's going to be ugly okay
well a lot ugly ugly and you have to
trick you can't do this or that you know
it's like cumbersome in Wuam language
it's all like
u well documented and uh powerful
because it's commercial product okay so
anyway so it's free and so also So the
other reason is woofam language um is
typically slower okay because there's
lots of symbolic it's it's like a
symbolic um system uh so it's
so you know and but they have you know
they have par parallel computation and
stuff anyway so that's my uh kind of
summary okay about comparing to Python
Python I did a video like before
comparison to um to the uh um
you know what is that uh
package? Um
okay, hold on a second. Let me let me uh
does that make sense?
Dash. Does that make sense?
So if you can look back, let me show
you. So um
so this is uh this is cloud talk show
index page. Uh so what is that? Um
last month or two month ago
because I have done so many videos by
now 700.
So the you know the Python Python is
actually one of the worst language you
you know just search my YouTube I've
done quite a few and why Python sucks.
Python is really the worst language from
design point of view. Um
and uh what is the one I wanted to talk
about the um
what is the package
that opensource mathematic package? Are
you still here? Do I make sense? Dash
dashanu.
Um,
so let's go to my Twitter because there
is this thing I wanted to
mention.
Okay, we are digressing. We need to get
back to code. Okay, so let me just
quickly uh wrap up. We I want but I
wanted to answer that question that
these opensource
people um
so we want to focus on mathematics not
politics. Uh
Donald,
there's a news Donald used AI to solve.
AI solved one of his problems. Claude's
cycl cycles. Claude cycles. Fascinating.
Um
I I just wanted to show
God not other stuff. I wanted to show
that um
yeah this. Okay. So this this you see
these people when I you know these
people you know he's talk sage math okay
god Jesus sage math so that's um episode
731 so when was episode 731 that's 2025
December okay so that uh over there I
talked about wam language versus sage
math sage math sucks very bad.
Okay. So, anyway, so
um anyway, okay.
So, if I answered your question, say,
you know, tell me what do you think.
Okay. Uh dash. Okay. So, let's go back
to code. I want you know, let's go back
to code. Um so, yeah. So, we we were
doing this code copy. So, we got a bug.
Uh yeah. So why is the curve not
showing? So go this this font is really
too large. Um
you know I got some
some uh itch some um
allergy or something on my own here.
Uh
so it should draw normal lines.
Okay. So when why is it not doing that?
Because uh what is this? Okay.
Okay. So that's my Okay. That's
Let's see the code. So why is it nine
drawing lines, tangent lines? So,
um,
Okay, the font is really too large. Uh
can't work with this. So we need to
shrink it
because when you are doing a video, you
know, to me it looks huge but to you it
looks small. If I use a normal sized
font when I work with computers then
it's like gonna be tiny for you guys. So
you know on my screen these fonts are
like humongous.
Um anyway so why do I have this uh
problem? So the curve function okay
let's look at one by one. Okay foc
focus. So, so that's a function for the
curve. And what is this? Uh, this is a
tangent vector function which is a
derivative. Okay. So, actually you
better just name it direct derivative um
curve derivative. Okay. So, and this is
a range list. Okay. So, list of ranges.
That makes sense. Yes. And this is
tangent length. Tangent line length.
Okay. And normal line length. Okay. Then
[cough]
then over here you plot the curve. So
that's how you plot the curve parametric
plot. And then over here this this block
is about creating graphics. So you are
like creating graphics for uh for
tangent lines and normal lines and and
points on a curve. Okay. So [snorts]
then then you got uh then you got
points. Okay. So points equals to um the
curve evaluated at t. So what we got
here is a table. So you can see this
graphics thing
has
the first argument is this table. Okay.
So this this table generates a bunch of
lines and points. Okay. That's what that
does. Now the second argument to the
graphics is just you know axis this
options axis true plot range is that and
aspect ratio automatic. Okay that auto
automatic means make it you know not not
shraxis
and y axis are equal.
Okay, that's what aspect ratio means,
automatic means. Okay,
so so then uh so so okay, so so the the
heart of the code is about this table.
It generates a list of things, list of
basically the lines and points. Okay, so
but then it declares a local variable,
several local variables, points. Okay,
point is that then um unit tangent
vector. Okay, normalize tangent vector
at t. Tangent vector at t, that's a
derivative function applied at t gives
you a point.
The the point uh a list of two numbers
that represents the tangent vector. Then
you normalize it, make it a unit tangent
vector. Okay, so that's what that is.
It's a it's a point. Then uh x tangent
vector equals to unit tangent vector
times tangent line length. So you make
it you make the the vector to have the
length of the tangent line length by the
specification by the user spec. Okay.
And then you make the normal vector to
be um
yeah so so that okay so that that that
that so why is it not working uh I don't
understand so um
so let me just make this TGT and let me
run it and let's see uh what's going on.
Okay. So, but let let's reduce this to
just just uh you know by points. So, it
will return. So, here is where you know
we can see the actual thing what's going
on.
Uh because when you have this graphics
thing
when you say uh you know when you say
graphics there
you know for example that graphics then
it just show the graphics it doesn't
show the actual expression. So when you
replace that graphics by just some some
rand random symbol symbolic then you can
see this is what actually what you get.
So you can see here why is it not um
so this draws a line from two to two. So
uh what's going on? Uh
so you got a line, you got a point, you
got a line. So lines you you see these
are lines beginning and end at the same
point. So that's why it's not showing.
Okay. So why is the lines beginning and
end at the same point? I don't know.
Well, that's well that's because um
h god I don't like it's block is uh
problem.
I think there's a quite a bit of latency
in the stream, so he might take a while
to respond. Okay. Okay. Ashley,
don't spam. Okay.
So, this
an
uh we so we got a problem here. Why is
it not um
what god this this this this
um
it's hard to debug.
So if you define a function like that
and here is the derivative. Okay. So the
derivative is
incorrect.
Okay. So I know why. Oh obviously
because we made a mistake. You see this
expression is is a function right? But
it's a expression involving t.
Now can you guys see you see this this
let me let me uh shift controlN so you
see this expression involves t but we
say it's a function where x is the the
the input so that is wrong that should
be t so obviously we made a idiotic um
error when we when we replace the
expression so this should be t in god So
copy all go back to wam language. So
select all paste shift controln to make
it type set and uh uh shift enter to run
it. Okay we got oh well
t well this tdt let's return tdt2
graphics. Okay
copy all.
Uh yeah. So this looks much better.
Yeah. Select or paste. Shift enter.
Okay. Still no wait. Did we change what?
Uh we got the another problem.
Okay. I don't know what's going on.
So let's
shift enter
could not combine a graphics. Okay. So
again
we got this problem
but the function is
it now it should work right. Well, maybe
because of the
uh yeah cash kind of issue. Is that
right?
Because if you
say such that you see you got that. So
maybe it's
could could the cache problem be. So if
you run that first paste.
Okay. Then uh
shift control D to separate them.
Control shift N.
Shift enter evaluate that. Shift enter
evaluate that. Okay. So this is the
derivative derivative of
that function. Okay. Does that make
sense? Yes. Now let's try to evaluate
this part and
let's see if it works. It does. You see
because of
Okay. Yeah. So what you get is uh kind
of cache problem. Now that's another bug
because when you use block you shouldn't
have a cache problem. So, I got a issue
I need to resolve.
Uh,
very annoying this. Um, anyway, let's
let's change this to 60. Okay. So, and
uh and shift enter. So, now you can see
now you start to see pretty pictures.
Now let's make the normal line length to
be
you know long 50. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Now it doesn't look pretty
when you have both normal lines and
tangent lines. So let's not draw the
tangent lines.
So all you have to do is just remove the
tangent lines. Okay. Remove it.
Shift enter. Fantastic. You see? So this
So now we got a code
which is what we wanted to do. We wanted
to show
this nail void.
By the way, this curve is generated by
rolling a circle
outside of the circle. The rolling
circle is one half the size of the fixed
circle. Okay. So this curve is called
neoid.
Uh and uh and uh we wanted to do
this one. So this is pretty using my
package and without my package. Here's a
code about
10 lines. Okay.
uh you know so now it it's looking
pretty bad so because all the color so
let me fix it put it back okay now
this is the code okay 20 lines of code
okay to draw that now we want to now
this is you know so you know we we need
to make it pretty for example this make
it red. Uh, and well, I mean the the
dots we want it red.
Okay. So, actually the curve
the curve make it black. Okay.
Okay. So, we want it black. And this
red, it doesn't Let's make it blue.
Okay, now it's looking better
now. Okay, this looks better. I like
that better. So, instead of a blue, you
use a hue
hue 075
by experience. That's about Okay, that's
probably purpleish. Um
or 0.7.
Okay. Uh
what color did I use?
Uh okay. I doesn't say what is the
default color anyway. So that's uh
that's one of them. Okay. So we we we
coded that originally. What we wanted to
code was this this uh
reflection. So you got the light source
that shines rays on a curve and reflect
it off the curve. So
but we already spend like 40 minutes. So
I think today let's just be this coding
takes a long time.
Okay. So Okay. So here's a code. Now
let's do some final touchup. Okay.
Also we got a issue because this code is
supposed to be robust. That means
doesn't matter even if you have a local
variable that's named fcurve. It
shouldn't affect the code.
So that user can paste a code any
anywhere it should run. But however, it
turns out we got this local variable bug
because if you change this fcurve to
something let's say ttt okay let's say
uh
let's say even let's just say three
three okay if you run it then okay
delete that
delete this okay so you see you save
that to that then now you run this
it will no longer work. Okay. Now, this
is not expected. So, why does that
happen? Because um
do you guys see what I'm saying?
Okay. So, um,
so why is this? So, let's go back here.
Okay. So this this
contaminated
get um
Okay, I think maybe it's because that
Let's try again. Okay,
let's just try this. Um
T
sign tt. Okay. So
copy all go here
and select all paste shift enter.
Okay. So this is incorrect.
because
yeah so apparently
this definition affected the code
uh so why is that?
Okay. So, you don't even
much
nasty kind of nasty. um
this kind of um scope problem in Wuam
language uh you know the variable scope
issue is
kind of problematic in wuam language I
mean it's it's um
somewhat complicated because it it's a
symbolic language
Um [clears throat]
okay so let me think. So this we are
using block. Okay block is a dynamic
scope. Okay. So block means any variable
in the expression in the block body. it
will replace any
any occurrence of that by uh
by the function by the definition
you gave there and this is dynamic
meaning that not just what you see like
what you see there there there but also
when whenever any expression that runs
that
that comes up with this fcurve
variable name it will become this new
value. Okay.
So why so okay so okay so
I think I know what's going here. This
is annoying.
Okay let's see for example let's try
this again. Okay select all paste shift
enter. This is incorrect. Okay. But now
let's fix it. Now we
copy that. Okay.
Um and we
do it here. Okay. And in this line we
comment it out. Instead we just say
variable. Okay. So instead of declaring
declaring a variable and give it a
value. By the way, this fcurve prime
that's that means the derivative of this
function it generates it creates a
derivative. Okay, so I mean to your
early question can you do derivative in
Python? Well, in wim language this line
does it. Okay. So this is a function.
This is a derivative and this is
derivative does two not just a single
function but it's a parametric equation
like it does derivative to both of these
functions in one shot. Okay that's
illustrates the why wofam language is a
magnitude
higher level. So one line wam language
is like 10 lines of python. Okay that's
like one example. I mean in Python you
can't even do derivatives unless you
load you know the bunch of math
libraries and also I'm not even sure
even with you know this anacondra or all
the you know math libraries Python
actually can Python actually do symbolic
derivatives and integrals I don't think
so
actually that's an interesting question
so I don't think so but let's ask uh can
pi Python with its math libraries
through symbolic
derivatives,
symbolic differentiation.
Let's just say derivatives.
Yes, Python absolutely can do symbolic
derivatives. And the main and by far the
best way to do it is oh si. Okay, simp
is a full feature symbolic. Okay, okay,
it can it can do uh derivatives, but can
it do uh differentiation?
Possibly it can do, you know, I'm sure
it can. There's a package you know since
you know since you got the uh symbolic
derivatives it's likely you also have
symbolic integration in Python you know
in some you know maybe sai probably in
sai okay but I can tell for sure then
it's going to be inferior than wuam
language
because you know because this gets very
complicated. Uh anyway, so let's uh go
back to
this. Okay. So, so we declare so instead
instead of um
declaring the variable and give it a
value, we just simply declare the
variable and we give the value here. So,
copy all. So, select all, paste, shift,
enter. Now, it works. You see? So, the
problem. So, now I discovered the
problem. The problem is that you don't
want when you when you want to use block
it's best not to
um
not to al not also declare the value
there. The reason is because if you do
that, you see if you do it here,
it is going to use the global variables
value there. You see in over there, you
see
wipe.
Yes.
Yes. It it Yeah. So you know it doesn't
like it doesn't in other words it
doesn't do uh chain um
variable chaining
so that that is why so okay
very nasty okay anyway I think we
finished our code we found the problem
and I think that's it
how do you pronounce your name like mech
ze
there they there Several ways to pass
it. Melchi
Zdeck or Melchi's deck.
By the way, have you ever used Maxima?
Okay. How does it compare to language?
There's no comparison. I mean, I got
this kind of questions all the time like
since several years ago. Well, people
ask that because if you search my
YouTube, you probably you might find it.
Okay. like uh
YouTube. Okay, you need to go to
YouTube. Let's go to YouTube. Like
search for Exali Wuam language versus
Maxima or Wuam language with Python. You
you know I talked about this so often.
People wanted to ask that because you
know that you know I like I have like 30
years experience with that. They wanted
ask that because Maxima was you know it
was a commercial product but now it's
open source. So people the open source
people are very excited you know have
have you ever used Mathematica you know
maxima have you know how does it compare
also maxima is written in lisp you know
so you got this opensource fanaticisms
all the time but the the thing is okay
let let me just be brief because I'm
starting to become like one hour rant
the thing is you know have you ever
tried you know just spend 10 like one
hour to be practical not not 10 minutes
because in 10 minutes you can't even
download a thing right so you spend few
hours you know try try it you know spend
uh let's say 5 hours just just five
hours in your life you know run wam
language and five hours in your life you
know you know download Python the the
whole Python uh symbolic library
everything
or or or maxima you know like just just
Try for 10 minutes you you'll know right
away like you know spend one hour you'll
know what right away which one is
better. Okay. And and in fact I can tell
you you know the the the
all the Python or Maxima they they are
going to be 10 times worse if you
actually try it. But but I got you know
this question. I don't mean to blame you
or you know anyone but I I do get this
question like so often like so often you
know people will start ask me have you
tried maxima have you tried uh sage math
have how does it compare have you tried
g octave have you tried g plot you know
be because the open source you know it's
free people wanted to know well you know
yeah you are showing mathematica it
looks great but I know this open source
what What do you think? Have you you
know
there's no comparison like but like once
if I say I tell them there's no
comparison you know one is like toys
like lit literally you know like I would
say today because if if maxima
or this python if they are great you
know wuam language has no business
you know like it's proprietary they sell
like you if you if you are a Google or
the NASA
You know, Google, these corporations,
they use Wuam language. Even Donald Gut,
you know, have you seen my Twitter post?
You know, like go to Donald Gunn's
homepage. He he uses Wuam language. He
also use Emacs. Okay. And Donald Guth
like uh last month
was surprised by AI because AI solved
one of his problem, you know. you know
anyway like so so if all these um people
you know all these package are so well
you know like open source stuff then
nobody is using um going to pay right
hello Hank
[laughter]
ching thank you Hank have you tried
Emacs that's right yeah
anyway so I I think we we solved this we
did this fantastic and That's it for
today. So
uh but you know so yeah so I need to
actually last okay let me complete just
to be totally complete let me make this
code fully robust okay so we don't have
this bug fix this bug for good okay so
the way you solve it just okay just do
this okay so copy copy copy copy copy
copy all that okay and go here paste all
that and replace the comma by semicolon.
Uh, do that. Do that
actually just at the end. Okay, just at
the end. Okay, semicolon. Okay, and over
here
this block of variables, let them just
be names. Okay, so you don't want
anything just names. Okay, you don't
want any value, just names. Okay, names.
Names. Okay. Names.
Okay. So now it's like you know kind of
easier to read even. So so you got this
these are local variables dynamic
scoping. That's what block means in wam
language. Okay. Then you define their
values. Okay. So that that's a function.
That's a uh wait function come first and
here is a derivative. Okay. Then here's
a list of ranges
ranges to the list of points that you
want to evaluate.
Then you want to say tangent length and
normal normal line length let's say also
60. Okay then okay then you show then
you plot the curve too. Okay that should
be robust code and also here so you can
see block is used again but this time I
don't have you know the values there. So
copy all
let's go to language again select all
paste control shift N to type set it.
You see you also don't have this very
nice automatic formatting type set. Look
at that
in in Python or in in you know in Latte
you know you just press a button it does
that and you can have traditional style
control shiftt
so now you are more you know it's
formatted more like traditional
mathematics which is problematic because
the traditional way of type setting
mathematics they are ambiguous
So one example is the absolute value or
the norm of a vector. We are computing
normal uh you know normal vector. So you
got two bars but you don't know which
part is nesting where anyway this
traditional math notation. Okay. So
control shift n to go back to the wofam
language standard notation. Okay. Then
you shift enter. Shift enter to
evaluate. Fantastic and beautiful. Now,
this is like the psychology thing, so we
don't want to plot the tangent. Anyway,
that's it for today. Thank you, Hank and
uh Chuk Ching and uh bye guys.
Okay, we we we we coded exactly one
hour. Okay, so we we actually so we can
improve this. So, let me do more. Okay.
So in this case we have a general code
to plot um that's right. We got a
general code to plot
normals. Okay. So in this case put it
back first syntax color it show it and
go to the normals.
So go down. So we're going to delete
that. We want to make this our code
pretty like that. Okay, that's the job.
So, um,
so what what what is this? Uh, okay. So,
we're going to delete that soon.
Now, this is our new code. Paste it
there and put a line.
Refresh. So, this is today's code. This
is the code from the package from there.
Okay. Now we need to go back to the
tangent
page because we have something to fix.
Okay. So showing browser. So that's
tangent. Now remember we don't want
we don't want values inside the
block local variable. So let's fix that
too. So we actually
uh because
well you you can have them inside but
you don't want them to be chained like
this for example this this you see this
this
the value of this local variable depends
on the previous local variable. You
don't want that to happen. Okay. So
let's because when you have this
situation then you get into the variable
value collision problem it's going to be
a bug when when you have a global
variable named like that was used in the
chain for example here. So when wine
language sees this fcurve it it will
first check the global variable. So
that's a problem. So this is um
it's you know I would say it's a design
issue. Um so anyway so let's the way to
fix that is of again we paste everything
here.
Uh
use okay then here just don't give it
any value. Okay.
Okay. So that that that that. Okay. So
that that that that that that
select or paste shift enter. Fantastic.
Okay. That's tangent. Put it back.
syntax color.
Go to the next one.
This one also need to fix. One, two,
three, four, five. Okay. Back here. Um.
Okay. Then here you just don't want
that. Don't want that.
Okay, that that that that double check
no comma at the end because Wuam
language doesn't like trading commas.
Okay, so you got that uh is everything
good? So block yes and copy that. So
select all paste shift enter. So this is
generic code for drawing any tangent and
normals. Okay, you don't need any
packages. Fantastic. Okay, now put it
back. Sync task color showing browser.
So there's a code. So in the future, by
next week, you can search for my website
special plane curves, a visual
dictionary of special plane curves. Then
you can the code will be updated.
Not now because I got some issues with
my web server. Okay, so this is the
tangent and normals. Okay, draw tangent
arbitrary tangent and normals. Okay, now
that's fixed uh syntax color of the page
we did. Okay, so now there's no leak of
variables, local variables. Wait. Uh,
that's right. Sounds good.
Okay, close. Now this nefroid. Okay. So
now we just want to make it pretty,
right? So select all. Select all. Paste.
Shift enter. Yeah. We want to make it
pretty. So we want to make it like
kind of like this. It's so pretty. Like
this. Okay. So Okay. So the curve is
black. Let's go one by one. The curve is
black. Okay. Last style
black.
Okay. And you want the dots on the curve
to be red, you know, so it looks like
rivets.
So you want the dots to be red. Okay. So
that you want the points to be red. So
there points on the curve red. Okay. So
yeah. So
red and the tangent lines.
Now right now you do tangent lines. You
don't do you want tangent lines? No.
Because it would be confusing. So the
tangent lines you don't want the tangent
lines. This you don't want. Okay. Let's
highlight it. Tangent vector. Okay. So
you you don't want this line. No. Don't
draw attention. So, but we still need
this
uh actually no.
So, since you are not drawing tangent,
you don't need that. Okay.
So, you can like comment it out.
Okay. So, select all.
Okay. Select all.
Go back here. Select or paste. Shift
enter.
Fantastic. And beautiful. Now, do we
want to change the color? You see? Um,
so actually this is pretty good. Now,
select it.
This This is some kind of can color. So,
can we say can sean? Is there a can
defined? I'm pretty sure. Yep. No, I
don't like C. Light blue. So, is there a
light blue?
Light blue. There is. Okay. No, I don't
like light blue. So,
so what is the color I was using for my
um
over there? I don't remember. But um
so let's increase the dot size.
Point size
0.0
uh two. I think that's huge. See? So 0
05.
That's too small. So,
seven.
Okay. So,
one shift enter.
Okay. So, size is two. Shift enter.
Wow. Wait.
Two and one difference so much.
So about5.
Okay. So this kind of looks good. But I
like that color. So what that what that
what is that color now? Is that due to
like um
interesting you see they automatically
have transparency.
You see, so these are kind of features
you you don't get in Python, you know,
you don't get in Python. I mean, you
don't have this interactivity. You don't
have this type setting.
That's what I mean. Okay. So, shift
enter. So, and uh is it so let me copy
this um
do a screenshot. Let's do a screenshot.
Okay.
Just say
Okay, we got a screenshot and let's see.
So, put the code back.
Put the code back and let's do
show browser.
Okay. So, we got that. Uh, that we don't
That's not what we want. That's my
previous screenshot. Open it. Delete it.
Okay. This is what we want. But the
color
now you see. Fantastic. Now,
now let's put them close together and
delete the code here. Okay. So, search
for pre.
Wait. So,
uh wait. So, search for pre again.
So So, this is my code for my package.
You see it's much shorter. But then you
need to download this package on GitHub.
So,
don't want that.
Delete. Okay. Now, this this is the
image. Now,
cut it and move it up here so we can
like compare side by side. Okay.
Showing browser.
So, you can see now side by side they
are huge. Okay. So, um,
so I do like this color better.
So, let's find out what that is that
color. I'm pretty sure it's zero hue
0.5. I'm pretty sure it's
0.75.
>> [clears throat]
>> uh one uh
one
7 something.
Okay. So let's look at my package. So go
to
our git directory. Go to curve.
Search for curve. Search for curve plot.
And this is the file. Search for
costics. Uh, wait. Search for normal.
So, there it is. Hu 0.6.
Oh god, how could I forgot?
So, Hue model 0.6. Let's see.
Oh, I like this better. So, fantastic.
Finally. Okay. So that's let's that's
let's that's so this is our final image.
Copy that. Oh wait shift
enter.
Uh yeah. So
now screenshot.
Okay. And close that. Close that. set.
Fantastic.
And uh do it. Okay. And uh this will you
will name this this will be named Nefoid
normals. Okay. Uh so rename the image
neoid normals.
Okay. And uh
there's one more to rename. That's the
previous uh
Okay. And go back to the curb. Refresh.
So you can see
our original
the current. Fantastic. And the
previous. Okay. Now just delete
original. No wait.
Delete that.
And
this you don't need need to delete it.
Go back. Refresh. Fantastic. So this is
the
evolute. By the way, if you don't know
what is evolute, evolute uh I'm not
going to explain. Okay. So watch my
video two days ago. I think I explained
that Evolute is fascinating. But you can
you can understand it by visually by
watching this movie. Okay? Just look at
this movie.
stare at it for a while. The those red
lines is the evolute of this
ellipse lur. Okay?
And you can read on Wikipedia. Just
search for evolute, you'll find it.
Okay? So anyway, that's today's root. We
generate we drew the normals the normals
of this nephoid curve and the normal
forms a shape that's called the
envelope. So the envelope of the normals
of nephoid
is another nephro. Okay, that is the
conclusion. Bye guys. Thank you for
watching.
Um Bernardo Loops, thank you. Hi. Uh,
hi.
If you like, you know, so general
advertisement, if you guys like my work,
donate, okay? Pay me. Go to
kasali.info.info.
You can, you know, kasali.info. Then go
to the bottom. You you can find my
Patreon, Amazon gift card, PayPal. Uh,
donate, okay? Because that makes things
go
Okay. And uh you know tell friends about
my video. Post it. Um
yeah. Bye bye. Bye. Mi
by
fantastic.
Fantastic and beautiful. Bye.