hello guys good morning beautiful people
today we are going to talk about
keyboards and we are going to code
JavaScript live and today is a special
we are going to do a ASMR Edition I hope
you like it you can watch this video
that put you to
sleep so let us begin if you have a
questions post it and I will answer
thank
you so let us
begin there are some
interesting things I learned about
keyboard and uh let me me tell you
guys so there are
some keyboard Innovation this one apple
maker
seedo is a great keypad
programmable and uh I think it is the
best
one it's about $60 I
think so you might want to check it out
and there are some great tips about why
do you want to buy a programmable
keypad so the advantage is that when you
have a programmable keypad such as this
one ultimate hacking version two
or
uh oh I forgot to show you guys my
screen so okay so let me introduce my
keyboards this is automate hacking
keyboards over here in
here and this is scub 80 keyboard both
of them are great and uh this is SV
board SW board data hand this is also
fantastic I am still learning it and uh
when I'm ready I will show you guys me
typing on this
thing and
uh there are YouTube videos reviews you
guys can
watch okay so let's get back to the
keyboard stuff so this apple maker cedo
is a great one I think it is the best
keypad so check it out it's programmable
and mechanical
switches and uh why do you want to buy a
programmable
keypad as opposed to for example using
Auto hard key or the Microsoft power
toys the advantage of programmable
keypad is
that once you program your keys your key
Markos they
are um more
robust for
example if you use Auto hard key
or Microsoft power
toys
then the keys may not work
when you are
in
uh see shift Windows shift
Windows
Escape shift
control
Escape so when you are in task manager
your keyboard
marker you program in power toys or Auto
hot key may not work but if you have a
programmable keypad they will
work and another example is that on
Windows if you press the Windows key
plus L that will lock your
screen and you cannot overwrite
that but if you have a programmable
keypad or programmable keyboard then you
can so that is some of the advantages of
programmable
keypad and uh on this page you will see
a collection of the best programmable
keypads that I have
found I list them in order from the best
one to
the to the okay
ones and
uh and
uh the there are some tips about how to
shop a programmable keypad so you want
it to have internal memory
you do not want it
to require internet connection for it to
work and you do not want it to require
you to register a account on some
website and you do not want the keypad
to to require a driver software running
when you are using it for
example razor keyboards are usually like
that and you want it to have a easy to
use
software the best the best is uh those
supporting VR or qmk those are the best
open source
software and you want mechanical key
switches so that they feel good to press
it and and another
interesting important thing is that you
want if you have a programmable keypad
that is more than 20 keys for example
let's go over here for example you have
a huge programmable keypad here over 60
Keys you want you do not want them to be
laid out in a grid
fashion because that way it's hard to
find which key is located
well so instead it's
preferable to have
them to have them have different button
sizes and different uh basically shaped
irregularly such as this one so some
buttons are large some buttons are small
and you have gaps between sections of
the buttons so between rows and columns
so that way you can press the right key
by simply feeling it and it will become
muscle memory so you do not have to even
look at the keys to press them that is a
good thing
and uh a knob or a wheel is always good
because a knob is the most efficient way
to control certain functions such as
sound volume up or down or control
brightness of your screen
there are some interesting cables I
discovered is this one
coiled keyboard cable this is a
fantastic
cable you can check it out and there are
some other
devices I bought and I think they are
good after some research so this one is
the best powered USB 3 Hub I have been
using this one for four
years and
uh there is
some the history of keyboard mechanical
switches is very interesting
and uh here is an article that gives a
short account of it from 1990s to
2000s
cheers the mechanical keyboard switches
have a interesting history so in the
1990s you have mostly the Cherry MX
switches they look like that this is the
most
popular and you have the IB and buckling
buckling spring
switches this is also very well
known among keyboard
fence and another another very popular
very famous switch is the topper switch
this is famously used in happy hacking
keyboard many people love this the feel
of this
switch and occasionally you will see
some switch called Alps switch
these are also popular especially used
by Apple computer some keyboard enjoyers
like them very
much that is the most popular keyboard
switches in 1990s and year
2000s beginning about year
2015 the Cherry MX type of switch their
patent
expired so you have a lot Chinese
manufacturers they created Cherry MX
clones such as gateron
switches and kaiwa KY
switch they are Cherry MX
compatible so that means you can any
keyboard you can also
use these switches by these Chinese
companies then beginning around year
2016 they started to have some
variations they are Cherry MX
compatible but with slight
improvements such as the Kyle box switch
and in
2019 oh about 2016 they are begin to
also have several Innovative
switches completely new design that
includes the logitech's Roma G switch
this is a complete new design from the
ground up and one of the Salient point
about
logitech's Roma G switch is that it has
the lead light in the
middle so that it can shine
brighter and there is also the China
spoody El K Optical switch the
Innovation here is that the electric
switch uses a optical
mechanism so
that it will have longer
life and resistant to
dust or
rust that is bloody LK Optical s
Swit and you have other Chinese
companies making Optical switch there is
this guy
quos CYO run chyos run 22 Thomas he is a
expert on keyboard
switches and he has done a lot reviews
on these keyboard switches
so that is
2016 then in
2019 you begin to have low profile
switches these switches became
popular the idea of low profile switch
which I'm using in this glove 8 keyboard
low profile you can see it is very thin
the point about low profile switches is
that you do not have to press the key so
much you simply press it a little and it
will register it is
wonderful then beginning around
2021 you started to have the new
technology of heart swappable keys
switch
sockets that means you can buy such a
keyboard and you can change the switches
to any other switch you like
without having to be a mechanical
engineer all you have to do is to pull
out the switch and swap them the new
ones
in so this hot
swappable key switch
sockets created a market for keyboard
switches so in
2021 it began to have a explosion of
varieties of key switch
types for example you can go to Amazon
and you can search
for key switch testers
and you will see tens of varieties of
key switch types for example there's
raccoon switch kangaroo
switch Tio
switch Phantom
switch Alias switch Luna may switch
limbo
switch CJ switch
btic switch C Keys
switch and such as zebra
switch seedo silent blue switch seedo CA
switch nude Rosa silent
switch
Leo Rock Le
switch and so on
they are wonderful because that means
they give you so much
choices that concludes a short history
of keyboard mechanical
switches from year
1990 to year
2024 and the following is
some Innovative keyboards I have found
in the past two years it is amazing you
have all these Innovations in
keyboard let's look at
them there is this one called Apple
maker a l a F75
this is a classic one it provides you
with a knob so you can control the sound
level
easily
and it is hard
swappable and another Innovation they
started to have in keyboards is what's
called gasket
structure which is
essentially a way to make the keyboard
quieter and this keyboard also supports
Bluetooth to three Oro
devices and it also supports a y
wireless
dongle
USB and it also supports wired in the
case you prefer to not have
wireless because Wireless may have
connectivity
issues another version from Apple maker
is this one called RT
100 and this one has the
Innovation it has two
innovations one is that it has a little
mini screen a mini display so that this
little TV can display things like time
date temperature your game status or
even a q
animation the other animation this
keyboard has is a
knob a multifunctional knob this knob
also functions as a multi as four
multimedia buttons and it has lead
display on
it so this is fantastic
a knob is very good to have because
without a knob for example if you want
to turn the volume up or down you have
to press the key repeatedly four times
also but with the knob you can
instantaneously twist it and get what
you
want so this is the Apple maker model RT
100 and notice the pink decoration very
pretty this keyboard is suitable for
girls the next keyboard Innovation I
like to show you guys is
this
one you see it is beautiful this one is
called Apple maker brick
87 it features this Innovation where you
have a drum sore bar in front of the
space bar in fact you have two of them
one to control the sound volume the
other one by default controls the
brightness of the leads on the
keyboard and they are
programmable so you can reprogram them
to do other things you want such as
scrolling or page up and down things
like
that another very creative and fun
feature of this keyboard
is at the back of the keyboard they
provide this
Lego
block so that you can attach your
favorite Lego toys on
it this keyboard is suitable for gamers
and for those of you Lego lovers
next on our menu is this very fun
keyboard called Apple maker seedo
ABM
066 Alice
keyboard Alice keyboard has this
Wonderland layout
so when you use an ALICE
keyboard imagine yourself in a Alice
Wonderland so you can experience the
Fantastic dreams and creatures in our
world plus you also have a mini display
that can show you what time it is
because time is the most most important
thing in the
universe and plus of course you have the
knob wheel that allows you to
control the universe of things make them
bigger or make them
smaller that should concludes the
variety of fantastic new keyboards we
have in this world
today at this moment we can go on into
the next topic and we can begin to code
the wonderful programming language
called
JavaScript if you have a question for me
feel free to type it in the chat box and
I will be obliged to answer
yesterday I also did a
podcast and the topic for the podcast is
can you learn math via Wikipedia
media versus
textbook the question we want to address
is whether it is
efficient or is it
suitable to learn
mathematics on your own by reading
Wikipedia or whether it is better if you
read math textbooks
so there is this
podcast where you can hear some of the
opinions and
suggestions that is
provided you can find this article if
you just search for
Kar podcast Kar
podcast
podcast and you can see there are
several
topics in the
past one of them I like to mention again
is syntax
design there are about 30 minutes
worth of voice recording on the very
interesting topic of programming
language syntax
design so let us see what are the next
topic another topic that might be of
interest to you
people is
Linux this is a
tutorial of Linux by command
line there are a lot updates in the past
week so you can learn Linux hardcore so
you dive into the most
efficient and the most most apt way to
use Linux the free operating system by
commands in a
terminal
like
this most
efficient and easy to understand
at this point in
time let us do some JavaScript
coding JavaScript is a great language
because JavaScript is the most popular
language in the
world among the top three most power
popular
languages they are JavaScript
Python and uh C++ or
Java so let us begin to code
this the thing we want to do is to write
a function that creat creates a map
object
for for translating keyboard
layouts for example let's go
to let's go to the keyboard layout page
here and let's go to the ergonomic
keyboard
layouts so you can see all the different
keyboard layouts in their heat map we
have quy we have vac we have
comac we have Workman we have asset and
many
others let us look into their source
code this is the page and search for. JS
you can see here is the source
code so one of the most
important code in this
JavaScript script
is key map so given two different
keyboard layout s such as quy and warak
you want to be able to find out given a
letter such as
e what is that letter in
vorak so you can see the quy
E position in vac is a
DOT and the
quy a in
V is also
a the quity X
position in Ro layout is
O so therefore what we need is
a map data
structure so you can see here is the
source code let's copy the source code
create a new buffer paste it here and
let's let's make it easy to understand
by by adding new line characters to
this
code so this way you can see it's much
easier to
understand so our goal is to create a
key map like this for example this key
map this map object is for converting
quy to vorak so you can see if we go to
the character
a the first character in English
alphabet you can see it's not there
because the
qu translates to vak a it does not
change
so let's look at the example of qutis
s if you search for S you can see quy X
translates to vak
O
check search again search for S lower
case
check so this is a map data structure in
JavaScript
the map data structure is new in
JavaScript in the year
2015 the map structure is similar
to to pythons
dictionary or Ruby's hash table or or
pearls hash table or emac lisps hash
table or Java's map data
structure so essentially it is
a collection of pairs each pair is a key
value
pair that is
fantastic so but to create this map is
very tedious
because because as you can see we have
to create this character translation for
every character in the key
map a better way a very convenient way
is that if we can just create a layout
such as a b c
d e
fgh for
example let's suppose this is a new
keyboard
layout and let's suppose we have a
another new keyboard layout let's
say
aoei and
uh let's say
semicolon q j
k so given these two strings you want to
create a map like
that by having a function that just take
these two s
key
art so let us do that
save the file first let's name it
temporarily uh let's name it XX
State let's name it XX date in do
JavaScript okay so now it's JavaScript
so let's write a function
let's use Arrow function so let's name
this
function
create keap
so there's a question
from Michael via hea what do you prefer
wooden Palm rest versus raisin Palm rest
my favorite Palm rest
is Bath Towers
because bath towers are cheap and
fluffy you
can you can fold them so that you can
create a desired
thickness and they are available
anywhere and when it's become dirty you
can throw them in a wash
machine and uh you will get
new as freshh as
new so that is why I
think bath towers are actually the
best pal
rest now if you buy a pal
rest a dedicated Palm rest in the
store maybe it's made by wood or maybe
maybe it's made by raisin or maybe it's
made in
plastic there are
varieties of pal rest for you to choose
from but usually they are much more
expensive than bath Towers each one is
like1 or
$20 and they are not that much
adjustable that is why I think
bath Tower is the best Palm
rest okay let's get back to JavaScript
let's write this function so we want
write a function create a key map it
will take two
arguments uh let's call them layout one
and uh layout
two and uh it should return a m map
object so let's document our
function this function name is f create
key
map and takes two
arguments return a map object
layout
one is a
string such
as like
that and layout
two is also a string SE just like that
return a map such
as so we create a map such as a b
c d and here is a a o e
i if the
string in the argument is not the same
length return return
error with this function once we write
this function it will be much easier to
create or all these different
layouts so you do not have to manually
create each of these pair of letters you
simply draw the asky art like that and
like that and this function will create
a map for
you via says okay I was searching for a
palm rest and I realized that they are
are not compatible with low profile
keyboards because of the
height but probably bath tow is going to
work actually thank you thank
you so we have written a documentation
for our function and uh now let's code
it this should be very easy to
do it want to we need to return a
function that return a map so we need to
declare a
variable let's call it constant X result
okay let's call it result map and uh
initial value for the map will be
empty so to create a empty map we can
simply say new map and give it a empty
array I believe we can do
that but I'm not
sure when you are not sure you can
always try it then you will know if it
works or if it does not
so we have defined our function and
let's try it so we are going to call F
create key map and give it two
arguments so the first argument is this
one let's save it in a variable so
constant
layout one let's name it layout
one and
constant layout
two
fantastic now we can call our function
right here
and in JavaScript of course you need to
print function by calling console
log so this is our code and we are ready
to run it let's do it run the code let's
see what
happens we got an
error okay some syntax error we can fix
that
easily we probably need a return value
here and uh what
else let is let us prettify the code
Cod okay we got some
errors what is the
error so here is our function that
should be
correct and uh here is a variable a
constant that should
[Music]
be that is not correct because in
JavaScript the quote double quote string
cannot contain new lines so if you want
new lines in your string you need to use
template string which is quoted by
by a tick character like that like that
okay let's replace it that's good let's
run
it fantastic it seems the function
worked however right now it is a dummy
function because it doesn't do anything
now
let's make it do what's what it's
supposed to
do let's go back to our JavaScript in
depth and let's go to we need to do a
loop over a
string so let's go to Loop we have four
Loop we have while loop we have two
while loop we have continue and break
that is not what we need what we want
is four of loop Loop because for of loop
allows we to Loop over the
string in such a way that each iteration
is over a character as opposed
to a code
unit this is a little bit tricky because
a code unit
means code code unit unit is a fairly
complicated concept but
essentially the Practical issue is that
if you have a
Emoji such
as
hug then if you
use if you
use for Loop
this emoji character will become will
have two
indexes so that is a problem for
example we can show this easily
by by printing the length of this
character so if we run this
line it says two you
see so that is the complexity you do not
want that you want to go through the
string by actual characters not the
encoded code
unit
therefore therefore we should use four
of loop like
that so for each character K or key in
the eable the eable is going to be
layout one
string so for each one of them we want
to do push to the map X
result
push and let's look up how do you add a
entry in a map
object so we have create map we have
uh so you can see to add entry you use
set map. set key
value
fantastic so the key will be the
original KK and the value will
be the value will
be of the same index from layout two but
we don't have access to the
index how do we solve
that so in that case
let's let's look into the detail of the
four of
loop so for of
loop
it sets the variable to the item of the
array
in our case it's a string so if we use
four of loop we cannot access the
index so let us not use for of loop let
us use
something
else so what we can do is that we turn
the layout one string into
a array we can do that by the dot dot
dot operator that's called spread
operator it will convert a string into a
array of
characters so now if we put this array
here we are looping over an array
instead of string so but once we have a
array we
can we can use four each
yes so let's go over to JavaScript
reference and uh let's go over to
array let's open it go to
array then
prototype so you can use map or for
each let's use for
each so we have array here and Dot for
each
fantastic and for each takes a function
as argument okay let's write a function
and this function is pass three
arguments the current
index I mean the current elements then
the current
index and the array
itself okay so the
first thing is
element
the second thing is
index so let let's delete the for of
loop let's use for
each so for each item
you push to the
map takes two
arguments the first arguments is the
key in this case it is the item the
second
argument should be an item of the same
index in layout
two so we can get that by layout 2
square bracket
index so this is in this way
[Music]
we populate our map let's pedify the
code okay it has some
errow let's check
again oh yes because we we need a
semicolon here I
think predy the code again again an
error what is the error
let's try again
oh it says parenthesized expression
cannot contain spread operator so our
error is over
here because in order to turn a string
into an array you need to put the whole
thing in Array like that okay now let's
predy our code fantastic
it worked and now if we return the X
result map that should
work fantastic can we try it yes let's
do run the
code okay error we got some error let's
find
out line
35 character
16 okay
so let's go to character
16 so it's having a
problem pushing
it oh it's not push it's set
because
remember the map object you need to use
set to add an
entry let's run it again
fantastic it seems to work this is
exactly what we
wanted now when the characters are the
same we do not need to push it because
when they are the same we can assume
they are the same therefore let's do a
if
check
if these two characters are the same
if they are the same do
nothing
else you
push now prettify the
code run
it fantastic now it is much cleaner
success so our function is
successful and that
completes today's
task and we can appreciate the beauty of
JavaScript and the beauty of functional
programming Leon says You seem much more
chilled out tonight because tonight we
are doing a special
episode of
ASMR as you can see in the title
ASMR
Edition
lovely the word is filled with
beauty and uh we have been
successful
fantastic let us copy the
code and uh go to talk
show and
uh post the code here
[Music]
paste it showing
browser scroll down
beautiful now we press a button to make
them syntax
colored and go to the
browser
refresh
beautiful
fantastic we have complet Eed today's
task how are you guys
doing did you guys have a good
time if there is nothing else that shall
be it for today's
session and uh let me get a drink
again let's have some red
[Music]
y oh we
forgot now we have this
code successful we
should add a new layout to this
JavaScript application
for example there is a new layout I
wanted to add that would
be the homac layout
2016 and bco layout I like to add to my
diagram and the Ingram layout so in
order to do that first of all we need to
type
out these layout let's try a easy one so
the easy one would be to try the
homack this homack layout is supposed to
be based on the latest technology of
artificial
intelligence so let us try that
meanwhile let me get my
drink and if you have questions post it
[Music]
now
for for
[Music]
what is your favorite brand of red
wine I do not drink wine
much so I do not know what is my
favorite favorite red WI
let us see if we can quickly add this H
MAAC
layout to
our keyboard layout
application let's go to the
URL and
uh post the URL now here make a link go
to it showing browser search for
homec and let's go to their website to
see if they already have it typed up we
need the ask key art of this layout
let's check
okay they do not have a asky art layout
but however they do have this code in
the form of
Json which is
wonderful but for all
purposes we will not be using it because
our goal is to test our newly created
function so let us go
to another layout let's see if they
contend asky
art let's go to the engram keyboard
layout they do have some sort of ask key
layout here so we can try
this
fantastic this angram layout are very
elaborate because
because they also
changed the shift key and the number
row their
correspondence for example
normally on a quy
layout the
shifted n
is the left
parenthesis but with the angram layout
it is
not so the angram layout is slightly
complex so in order to use the angram
layout to test our code we need also to
have a
qualy s key
art but
including including all the number
digits and
symbols we can do that but
however our graphical application does
not
support the the changes in the letter
row we can still do it but it's
not it won't show so let's see the
angram
layout there is another
version called in grma which is engram
layout
without the changes happening to the
number keys so let's go there and see if
they provide an asky art
version they do
fantastic let let us try this
one so now we go back to our JavaScript
we make a backup and we pop this out the
code and now we can try
the layout so layout two will be
this engram
layout and the layout one will be quy
and here we need a
quy layout s SK
art search
just
q q
w
oh q w e
r t
y let's see what is the most efficient
way to do this
so since the number row does not change
we do not need
it and uh they also use capital letters
in lower case for the shifted
version we also do not need the capital
case so what we can do is to delete all
capital letters in this block
we can do that in emx by
calling query replace
Rejects and we give a capital a
dash capital Z that means replace them
all
enter
by by nothing
now we can say yes yes yes yes yes yes
yes yes yes yes yes yes yes yes yes yes
it yes is it yes yes yes yes yes
fantastic now this shifted version of
symbols we can also remove
safely remove remove remove
remove remove
remove
fantastic now this back space
backspace not backspace this back slash
in
JavaScript is a special character for
escape therefore we need to escape
it so back space
magically becomes double back
space
fantastic okay seems now we have our
layout ready almost not quite because we
have two spaces here we can show you can
see two space so replace two space by
one do it do it do it wa wa wa
fantastic now over here we can just type
the qualy
layout and it will complete our mission
fantastic in order to accelerate this
job we can try to find on the
website if there is any website that
already have
this quy asky
art let's try to search and see what we
find so that we do not have to type them
ourselves if you are watching and if you
feel like feel free to type the quy
layout
so that I can use thank you very
much for your potential
contribution okay it seems actually
faster if I simply just type Cy
myself okay let us do that
[Music]
to the
top and choose quy
fantastic and move this over here so we
can see and let's just type them q w e r
t y correct correct correct correct
correct and
UI
O Okay UI o p
UI o p o we do want we do not want
abbreviation expansion UI o no expansion
so let's try again UI op P
fantastic and square bracket wrong try
again correct
fantastic and there is a backs slash
don't
forget you need double backs slash then
you have
[Music]
asdfg
obliged then you
have HJ
KL semon
apostrophe h j k l
semicolon
apostrophe
fantastic then you need z x c
v z x c b then b n m BN
M
comma full stop and slash
fantastic it appears we have
accomplished the
task before we run the code let's double
check if we got them correct let us now
remove the Redundant
spaces replace query replace Space by
none yes yes yes fantastic
fastic is it
correct we need to be concerned about
correctness one easy way to verify
correctness is first of all count the
number of
characters it has 37
it has
correct now we can run the code
and it should be correct let us run the
code
run
fantastic it give us this map object
which converts the letters in the quy
key map layout to
the whole Mac no not whole Mac the
engram the enrma layout
fantastic so this is the result let us
copy that close this save
this put it back in the
browser color it showing
browser
fantastic and let's and we have the map
here let us go to the
JavaScript go to the JavaScript of
the layout keyboard layout JavaScript
library and we can now insert insert
this let's see if makes sense first of
all make a backup of this
typescript and uh paste it okay and what
you need is
to
say okay this is a new
map okay so in order to
okay we need to do some surgery on these
data structures so let us split the
buffer create a new buffer paste it here
and go
to JavaScript
mod and now we need to make this format
into
this format first of all let's
add a line to every
comma so that it becomes easy to
see f
fantastic the next job is that each of
these needs to
be okay each of these needs to be
a array syntax with square brackets the
reason is because in Java Script there
is no literal expression for a
map so you need to turn this into an
array of pairs of array so first of all
for each of
that change it to
comma
fantastic then for each line you need to
change it
to like
that like that okay and remove the
ending comma so we can do that easily by
first of all remove the
beginning of empty space then we remove
the end of the comma by replace each
comma New line by just new line okay do
it fantastic now you can call
a customized
command that will add square brackets to
each line and uh use a comma at the end
of the line do it
fantastic that function is
called
Sly that function is called
uh that function is not shown in here
but that function is
called quot lines
okay now do we have the correct syntax
yet no because we need the square
brackets at the outset so remove that
copy cut it add the square bracket paste
it and here we have our
desired
form okay now cut it close it now we can
add it
here paste it make it one
line and add a parent to the whole thing
then at the beginning we need to
say new map so we paste it here and the
name of this map is in grandma
did we spell it
correctly let's
check in grandar 2
m m m and it's m m e
r
fantastic it seems we have completed the
task all we have to do now
is this is typescript let us compile the
code first of all let's try to pedify
the code fantastic it worked and
now let's try to compile the JV
script tab control
HED so you can press tab C to compile
the
file tab C compile the file it
is
Success now we have added a
new layout let us go back to the page
and now all we have to do is add a user
interface a radio button for the in
grammar
layout let us do
that
search let us see where is the library
okay the library the actual code is not
in this library because this file is
actually a library
so close it the file we need to addit is
this
one so you need to add a in gramar
layout here but before we do that you
need to Let's paste it here we need to
go back to
HTML and uh and in this user interface
section we need to
add for example let's add it after
workman copy and paste and the value
will be in
[Music]
Gramma let's check did we spell it
correctly okay that's Yes We spelled it
correctly so if we go to the
browser
refresh we can
[Music]
see oh we made a mistake we need to also
change name here in grammar refresh we
can see in
grammar fantastic it
worked let's capitalize is the letter so
it looks more
beautiful
fantastic we have just added in grammar
layout and now we can see the heat
map it is a satisfactory
work let's see quy
vac all the most frequently used letters
are on the home row comac also on the
home row comac DH the idea is you avoid
the middle
columns
fantastic wman is the first one to have
that idea avoid the middle columns now
in
grammar
fantastic so we have completed our task
today thank you guys for watching have a
nice day beautiful people good
night fantastic coding
today we do not even need to modify this
file at
all all we have to do is to add the in
grammar
layout conversion map from quy to in
grammar then what we have to do is to
add
add a radio button for the in gramar
layout and all things work
fantastic good night