Hello guys, good evening. Welcome to
another episode of S talk show. Uh we
are going to talk random. Uh I'm going
to code some Emacs Lisp coding and
basically just chat chat random. Okay,
so relax, have a wine. This is red wine.
Enjoy the good life. And by the way,
happy new year. This is Chinese New
Year.
So my keyboard, this is UHK80,
ultimate hacking keyboard 80. Okay, Nia
trackboard. You can find my reviews on
YouTube. So now let's have a sip and
switch back to But before we do that,
let me show you. So I got red red wine
and I got this white wine for the first
time. I don't think I had white wine for
like over a decade or something. So,
let's see, you know, what it is like.
Okay. So, let's switch to my screen.
Check
6:30. Cheers.
So, what So, let me tell you guys. So, I
found this fantastic song of created by
Zumas. I suppose this song is about Ela
Musk. Okay. So, can I can I play a clip
like um so the song
is posted on Twitter and there is also a
a YouTube version. So, let's go to
YouTube.
>> There it is.
>> Okay. I I find this fantastic song. You
know, this is a music video. It's
basically about Ela Musk and about X
Twitter uh and Elam Musk's endeavors
such as Rocket and his you know the
political involvement
stuff. So I find this fantastic m music
video the the music video is mostly
generated by
uh generated by uh AI you know by these
you know new type of people new type of
creators. I think this guy Sky Brows,
you know, they use AI to create videos
and the song is also fantastic. Now, I'm
not sure who sings the song, but but I
think I but I find the song fantastic.
Okay, so if you are here, comments,
hello non FVN.
Hi. Hi. Okay.
So, you know, the YouTube is nasty. I'm
not sure if you play it, they they're
going to say, "Oh, um, because you you
violate some copyright, you know, it's
very annoying."
But anyway, so fantastic music video,
okay? And also fantastic
uh song. But also the content is
fantastic because you know I have been
personally observing Ela Musk for the
past three years in depth.
You know for the first two years about
2002 to 2004
I read every of his tweet. Okay. So I
know him kind of a bit in in depth than
most people.
By the way, of you people who is about
to tell me, oh, you don't know Yamasi is
evil. Like, you don't know. You guys
don't know [ __ ] Like, not not a [ __ ]
It's incredible. Okay. Like you you guys
you you guys brain about politics, you
know? There's a lot of politics going on
especially uh for you like pochan type
of people the zoomers the goipers the
whatever the pepe pepe the all used to
be the ma you know maga was the thing
uh there's lots of dark things and
complex things going on and uh part of
this crowd is I mean there's quite
diverse crowd okay there's the social
justice warriors crowd
on one hand versus the MAGA people on
the other hand that's a simplified
version like the Democratic party versus
the republic rep Republican party or the
social justice warrior scan versus the
Christian God believers scan you know
idiots
but but then but but then
um in in in 2024
turns out turns out things became
you know lots of things went happened
you know anyway so so let's go back to
the song this is a great song I think
you know so because it describe Ela
Musk's situation okay
great video okay uh okay let's get drunk
you know I'm going to get slightly drunk
okay and we cannot talk too much about
politics because YouTube is just going
to censor
okay so you I'm going to talk random but
um so meanwhile you guys hear a comment.
Okay, so about this song. So check it
out. The title is breathing Ellens Musk.
Okay, breathing Ellens Musk. Okay, so
let's go to
some music blog. And by the way, I told
you yesterday uh I had some issue with
my uh web server. So, I cannot update my
blog. So, my website has not been
updated for the past week. I'm going to
fix it soon. Okay. But meanwhile, I'm
just going to write update my blog
locally. You can see it though if you go
to kasali.info
or kasali.org. You you won't see my
update. But I'm just going to add um do
it for myself. Then after I fix it, you
you know I'm going to sync then it's
going to work. Okay. So anyway, so here
is a a song Ellen Musk's breathing
Ellen's musk. That's the title. Okay. So
what I want to do is, you know, I'm
writing a blog screenshot. I already
did. I want to so you know I want to add
some uh comments. So you you guys don't
know what I'm doing, but let me just do
it. Okay. Uh for those of you Emacs
users, you are watching my workflow.
Hello Bansa.
So we talking random. Okay. So let me
just do it. Press press press press.
Okay. So, um Okay. So, wait. Uh what you
got to undo. So, you have this command
describe key. Press press.
That's a command. The command name is
HTML fix YouTube description. Which
basically means when you see a video on
YouTube, you can copy. Okay. Let's
magnify.
You see, I want to blog this YouTube,
you know, uh, YouTube video, right? So,
you copy the URL, of course, that's the
first obvious thing, but usually you
also want to copy the title like title
of the video and who uploaded it and
typically the date. So, what typically
what you do is you uh YouTube is very
annoying. There's no simple way to copy.
So you have to copy the whole uh with
with bunch of irre irrelevant things.
Okay, copy. So you go here then new new
buffer you paste it. So this is what you
get. You get you know the title that's
what you want. You also get the poster
that's what you want. Subscribers you
don't want. Okay. Then subscribe. You
don't want that. And then that 44K. You
don't want share. You don't want save.
You don't want this. You don't want but
you do want the date you see. So every
time you want to blog about a YouTube
video that's what you have to do if you
are a careful blogger. Now why don't you
just like forget about that just copy
the URL and just type whatever you know
this is uh Elamusk. So that's got a
problem because after two years the
videos going to disappear. So you have
like hundreds blogs or thousands of blog
like me 10,000 pages blogging for the
past 30 years 10,000 pages but when you
look at lots of those pages they have a
link to some website you don't you
forgot what those websites are you don't
know who wrote it and and sometimes you
don't know know the date like you have
you you have lots of links you have no
idea what they are like but you have
some kind of like clue like Oh, this
website sucks. But but what what is what
is a website? You forgot because you
wrote it five years ago or 10 years ago.
The link's gone. So that happens. So you
you you want to know every link to
external website, there's a link link
rot problem. The link is going to die.
Okay? Depending on the website. Okay? So
for example, YouTube, I've been blogging
for over more than uh 20 years. So I you
know I I I continuously update. So in
the past years I have lot know a lot of
YouTube videos that's gone. It's either
deleted or the account got cancelled or
deleted or the video got deleted or the
video got uh censored you know the
YouTube removed it or sometimes the
account you know the video went private
by the creator. Okay for many reasons.
Sometimes the reason like you don't know
what's the reason. YouTube YouTube won't
tell you like you go there it's like the
this video does not exist. You have no
idea why or when did it got removed. So
this is a link rot problem and uh in
part of it is lots of censorship. Okay.
So but in general if you are a blogger
or if you are actually a historian type
of writer you every time you link to
external link you should have author's
name the date you linked it title of
course uh and also screenshot if you
know if you have time screenshot okay
that's what you have to do
now of you zoomers like you guys zoomers
who don't know nothing You might say,
"Oh, but why don't you use why don't you
use, you know, internet archive way back
machine?" Like, you don't you know, you
you guys don't know. Okay. Anyway, so
that's what you have to do. Okay. So, I
want to block this video. So, I copied
the title. So, you got you got this, you
know. So, you got this thing. So, you
don't So, but you want to put them
together in a nice link, uh, nice text
formatted, right? So that's why you need
this command. Okay.
SI HTML fix YouTube description.
Okay. So go to it. This is a command. In
fact, I made a change today. So let me
actually make make some more change. I
need to uh actually make a change. So
this is advanced emac this coding. Okay.
Uh,
actually save.
Yeah, that's what I want.
Okay, so you guys are looking at EMAC
this is advanced programming science
engineering computer engineering
computer and stuff. Okay, Emacis code
involving recursive functions and stuff
like we talked about mathematics. By the
way, we we did a video yesterday about
mathematics. Uh hello bookshot. So that
was fantastic. Okay. Uh yesterday's
episode. So just watch my yesterday's
episode about classic music. fantastic
extreme and uh proof theory, category
theory, homotopy type theory and what's
wrong with uh set theory. Okay, so that
was yesterday. So anyway today, so so I
need to make more changes to this
command. But for now, let's evaluate it.
Go back. Let me just demo this uh what
this command do. Okay, so you see you
see you show this in browser. That's you
see this part that's all munched
together in one line because you don't
have any paragraph or dive or whatever.
So, but now you call a command uh
YouTube discription.
Okay, do it. So, all those lines becomes
these three lines. You see? Beautiful.
Fantastic. And well, you need to do some
manual. You don't want those, you know.
So make a list and combine the previous
list show in browser. So now you got it
nice, you know,
you know the URL, the title of the song,
the uploader and the date it's uploaded.
Okay. And also you need to this uh
screenshot
uh you need to you want to rename it.
So, let's rename it to the guy's uh
let's press press press
sky brow Ellen Musk song. Let's just say
that. Okay, do that. Okay, then open it.
Okay, fantastic. You it it you see that
command will also rename the file on
disk. So I don't have to go to diet, you
know, then turn on file rename mode and
uh type the new name and you know save
it and then update my HTML page to the
new name. I don't have to do that. All I
have to do like I can change this for
example this file go to the add that's a
file name. You can also show it in
Windows Explorer. So by the way all the
commands I call you you can see it in a
pink window. Okay, for example, start
showing desktop. Okay, so this um
cheers. Okay, is it fun? So this all
these videos um no block. So so now I
want to let's say I want to rename this
file again. Okay, so I can do it right
here. So showing browser you see right
in HTML. So press press you see and that
command is called HTML rename source
file path. Okay, press press. Okay, so
just now just let's say I I I just give
a random string there. Enter. So that's
renamed. Okay, [snorts] so now you open
it, you see new name. Okay, so the we
change the random string part which is
um
which is like here. Okay. Okay. So
anyway, so but then you see now you show
in browser you see the title of the
figure image did not change. We want to
change that this screenshot. Okay. So I
can do that by press
okay press press press this this just
command I wrote HTML relink. Okay. Now
you see the it updates the figure
caption. Okay. Showing browser. You see
now it's better name and also it updated
the old tag.
Uh okay. So
okay so okay anyway so that's some so so
great song. Okay enjoy that song. So uh
but this part we don't need delete it
showing browser. Okay, that's one song,
but that's a YouTube version. But I also
want to um you see I made some comment.
Uh so there I posted a Twitter post. Let
me copy that. I want to um annotate
like when you blog like you don't just
put a link to a video or link to
something. You need to say why are you
doing it? That's the point about
blogging.
like the Malay idiots, the Zuma idiots
these days, you know what they do like
often today is like link dump you know
like
you go to Twitter what whatever you know
you see you you know they just dump
video links or whatever links or to
article you know they they just do they
just do link dump they lost the ability
to express to like say what like there
are thousands millions of links every
Hey, new links to articles to videos,
right? They lost the ability to make a
comment like why why are you posting?
What? Like what's interesting about it?
They lost the ability to do that because
their brain since they were born is just
like scroll scroll or doom scroll. You
know, there's like even a jog doom
scroll. You know, they just scroll eyes
glaze. You know, the the the brain is
good. You know, the thinking faculty is
good for the Zuma generation.
began with the late Malaysenian
[ __ ] Okay, the late Malay
Malaysian [ __ ] like the
uh Mark Zuckerberg and Jack
Dorsey of Twitter. Okay. So the the the
Zuma generation their brains got and
they lost the ability to like make
comment when they want to post something
like and all the YouTube comments like
just one single line like there's no
content like all the YouTube comments
and all the Twitter like or Reddit you
know like and they are a none they don't
know how to write you know and also
Twitter for the first like 10 years they
limit your writing to 140 characters.
You know, that's a anious way to train
you to disable your your ability to form
one single thoughtful sentence. Okay,
Twitter did that. Jack Dorsey scum.
Okay, so these are people from deep
state. So they created the system in
society so that they made the Zuma
generation you guys okay most lots of
you you know the younger generation to
not have the ability to think okay so so
you were born in this world where every
you know you you you don't like you
rarely see a full sentence or article
anymore you see just like blur blurp you
know like all the comments you know all
like if you go to other Twitter you know
blur
uh uh uh law or whatever you know um and
and if you try to write more it you know
the system force you to limit to 140
characters originally there's a reason
for that technical limitation because of
the phone SMS
you know message system blah blah blah
but but that that that limitation went
away but they insisted you know they
kept that way then they increased it to
280 characters, you know, for like the
first 10 years of Twitter.
So, this is like So, why are they doing
that? Well, the deep reason you guys
don't know, okay, you guys like W Chang
or whatever or or or the Red Pe
whatever [ __ ] idiots, okay? or this
talking about or MAGA or the Pepe guys
or whatever camp or the Illuminati,
you know, Illuminati or the Joe Rogan
[ __ ] idiots or the Alex Alex Jones
kind of all idiots. Okay.
So, not all, not all, but there are some
really uh give you deep insight, but you
don't see them. Okay? like most of you
talking about like watching me uh like
you don't know the thing so so why are
they doing doing that so it's a way so
that the the the entire Americans new
generation they lost the ability to
really think or even communicate which
with each other properly you see so so
come back to my previous point I was
talking about the link dump phenomenon
so people just like For example, on my
discord, I hate that, you know, link
dump. You know, people just like they
they they saw something interesting and
they just link dump. You know, sometimes
it's video, sometimes it's article, they
just link dump. [laughter]
So, what happens with the link dump is
that it creates a situation like every
day you see thousands like every second
there are thousand links just like
Twitter. Okay. Every second there there
are like a million Let me let me show
you some like like my my for you tab.
Okay, my for you tab is actually very
different from yours, but it's still
like mostly [ __ ] Okay, so every second
you have like 1,000, you know, these
are, you know, like violence. This one
is what whatever you know. Okay, China
girls thoughts, you know, politics.
Okay, you know my for you tab is like
catered to me but I but it's [ __ ] like
most like vast majority of a [ __ ] Okay,
so anyway the po my point is that every
second since like even 20 years ago well
15 years ago every second you have like
1,000 links like like link you most of
them link them. There's no like like
like normally in a normal real human
touch you know humanity when someone
post something you know you know who he
is you know his name you know you know
maybe you met you know like in real life
you know you seen him you know you talk
to him you know the guy the face the sex
what you know what he is about is he
rich or where he came from you know
[snorts] and he you know he's got
opinions he you know why he's posting
that Right. That's a real life normally.
Okay. But starting with the the Zuma
[ __ ] the starting with the late
late Malaysian [ __ ] like around
2010, let's say, you have the situation
where like most of these people posting
these things, they are known, but you
don't know who the [ __ ] they know. [ __ ]
is what the [ __ ] is this this this
creature? Okay, like all of them. All
like almost all of them. Like you don't
know what the [ __ ] is this creature.
Okay, maybe well maybe this guy is real.
Okay, this guy is probably real. Okay,
so so you so every second every second
you got like thousands of these these
things. You see what? So So you see why
does that happen? You know part of it
you know this this clown word is this
this is a major scum. Okay, a major
I I presume white man or Indian pretend
pretending to be white man's scum. Okay,
this guy K what he he's specialized in
posting like pro maga pro Trump stuff.
Okay.
Um and that and this this this type of
guy is a lot of you like or chan readers
see you know like talking about what
whatever you know Christianity or
sometime you know whatever.
So my point is this Zuma's situation,
okay? Like maybe you guys heard me [ __ ]
about Zumas all the time like why am I
crazy? Well, that's true. I'm partially
like very abnormal. Okay, but but let me
tell you the Zuma situation. So that's
what that's you guys. Okay, like every
second in your life, like since you were
born, that's a situation you are in.
You've never seen a like a genuine
contact of humanity of information. You
like you never seen it. Okay. So this
human situation every second you got
this. What the [ __ ] is this [ __ ]
Okay. Like every information is like
dramatic sensational. Like for example
like what's this one? Uh be Peter
Steinburgger. Sell your company for 100
million. Oh Jesus. Very successful.
spend three years in ex existential
crisis, become jacked, come back to
retirement, you know, like [ __ ]
crap, you know, like the these are like
fake news, sensational like crap and
crypto, you know, there there it is.
There it goes. Crypto, [laughter]
you see like every post, every
information and this, you know, this
one, whatever is is [ __ ]
Okay, that's a situation you zoomers are
in.
Uh scums like this. This is what you get
used this is what you
are used to. This is what you see every
day. This is what you you know your
school. I don't know who how old you are
you know in you know in high school or
in university. That's what that's your
life. That's what your life and some of
these are you you know like uh you know.
So [ __ ] this like that. But you know
it's like it's not your fault but you
being
you are kind of like you know you are
the um
you know what the white man would say a
victim. [laughter]
So anyway so let me just go back to what
I was doing. So I wanted to make
comment. Okay speaking uh so I was
commenting about that song and I want to
write a blog about it. You know, for
example, this one, this one is a Indian
[ __ ] There's lots of Indian
scammers, you know. He he says New York
City, you know, he's like pretending
he's in in New York politics, observer,
and analysis, news junkie, you know, oh,
you know, whatever. Uh then, well,
actually he's based in India. So,
this scums, okay. and and what he post
you know scums you know this like
that's you know that's that's like
that's just like all of Twitter and all
of Reddit and uh like almost basically
all of internet like that's every day
what you see fake news
drama [ __ ] you know like like there's no
real information that's a that's a
situation of the zoomers
okay so They so so what I want to say
about the zoomers so so their mentality
even including you know good people like
they don't like some of you guys you
don't mean to be bad but you can't help
it because that's you know that's what
you see that's that's the world you were
in that's the world you know you were
born with you can't help it you can't
help you know like finding you you can't
help yourself having opinions that's
like really idiotic
you can't help it, you know, that's a
lot of the Zuma situation.
Um, so anyway, I want to talk about this
song because, you know, I think it's
great. So, let's uh Yeah. So, I was
saying about the link dump phenomenon.
So, a lot of the Zuma generation, the
young people, they don't know,
you know, they they they just post link
dumps and uh and link dumps is very
harmful. Okay? because you don't want
you don't want to have a situation where
every interaction or every you know
online website or so-called platform you
go there all you get is like link dump
you know like 1,000 links dumped every
second okay by by whoever [ __ ] you
don't know like by by a bad man by a
prince peach or whatever you don't want
that okay that's you know link victim is
very harmful. Okay. But the why did it
happen? Because the the zoomers they
can't help it. They they they've been
trained kind of like they they've been
um forced into that situation without
they even aware of it. Okay. So, so they
just naturally you know they they they
will say like sometimes if I flame then
say what's wrong with you? I just you
know I find this video interesting. I
just post link. Why can't I do that? Why
why why have you to be, you know, why do
you have to be nasty about, you know, I
just want to post the ink? I'm not like
you, you know. I don't, you know, have
to think about what to comment. You
know, that's what they say. They have no
idea what's going on. You know, that's
why, you know, the Zuma situation.
So, anyway, so for me, you know, I want
to make a comment. Why am I posting this
video? Because I find this video
amazing. It describe Ela Musk situation
associate associated with politics
associated with you know the current
phenomenon the you know all the going
ons in the past five years let's say
okay Ela Musk because this is and this
is critical this is kind of a a cultural
um
a a history of culture via art okay
because this this is Elamus is one of
the richest people on earth and he's
deeply involved with Trump you know like
like basically the most powerful
politician on earth. So they are in many
ways they are you know running on the
earth
you know 8 billion people are under
their control and this video describes
some you know many of the things he's
doing and people's reactions kind of the
feelings about the situation and so I I
I I blog about this video I say why am I
blog it great animation and great song
that's what I find it okay and I also um
I need to say great um like great um
kind of character great characterization
of
the the you know the current era. Okay.
So let's add it. Okay.
Catization.
ization. Wait, I don't have a brief for
that.
I don't have a brief. So, this is a long
word. Let's say
caration.
Okay. So,
Am
I spell correct? Let's see.
Am I doing good? So there's a comment.
Um so you guys be making comment and I'm
too busy to see but uh we'll see it now.
So characterization a brief. Okay. Evow
it. Go back. Characterization.
Okay. Okay. Jesus.
Okay. Finally, I probably need to change
the brief. Okay. Great characterization
of the political
um era. Okay. So, that is a good word to
describe it. You know, why is it
important? I mean, what what what's the
deal with the political era? Because
this era in the past 3 years involves
the death of
like about 100,000 people like just kill
just just kill them involving the death
of of 100,000 people at least. Okay. in
the past two years
not counting you know actually this
actually you should start counting about
four years ago but anyway and
deeply tied to Elamus and Trump you know
this this you know very powerful people
okay so this is my you know my
commentary about a song
uh and also involves and also also
important this video heavily
uh deal deal with AI, you know, it
contains in in the lyrics. Oh, by the
way, I need to uh save the lyric lyrics.
So also also also this this video uh
talks about like one of the animus's
obsession about having children about
basically what the white people
academics would say
um the uh population um decline crisis.
Okay, like Adamus think this is a
critical situation. Population decline
meaning the death of humanity. Okay,
save image. Save it.
Okay, so I I made this screenshot and
this this this is from AI. This is Annie
the Gu AI companion. Okay, which is also
very significant because Elamus made
this into
a common tool for every person to be
able to talk to a girl like that in a
sexual way. Okay. So, this is a change
in society in human animal society of
the past let's say millions of years or
or four 4,000 years of recorded history.
Okay, we never have this happen before.
Now any man, any man or women can talk
to a sexual partner in sexual ways in in
all manners of sex sex activities. Okay.
Via this AI a phenomenon that we never
seen before.
Okay. So that's that's my commentary
about this song. Okay.
So wait um now funny. Okay. So, so that
so that line
that line now breed you fools or we all
die is is a from the lyrics of this
song. Okay. So, let's um uh
Okay. So, I wanted to Yeah. So, uh let's
uh save the screenshot we did. So, move
the screenshot here. It's done. Showing
browser. So, you can see I moved the
screenshot here. And uh let's um
uh rename this because we don't want
this rand random name. So um Ellen Musk
son um Annie uh work Annie. Let's say
breed.
Okay, [laughter] let's name it that.
Okay,
so Annie now breed you fools or we all
die. Okay, that's the lyrics of the song
and also let's get the lyrics because I
always uh because you know human animals
our songs when you look at you know the
there they are usually two parts. One
part is the music, you know, the melody,
the song, the instruments. The other
part is the lyrics. Okay? So, you look
at the lyrics of a song, you can see
lots of it, you know, you you can see
what what what are they thinking? Okay.
In what era is, you know, what year is
this song, you know, um what year is
this song? So, you can you can and what
region, what nationality, you can tell
like their mindset, what are they
thinking. Okay. So in this song in this
you know brething Ela Musk you can tell
you know what's going on AI and Annie
the thinking about population decline
um you know kind of thing. Okay so let's
get the lyrics. Okay.
Uh so it's they they posted the lyrics
lyrics here. So let's copy and I think
that's about it for today. Okay. So,
copy.
Uh, so let's post the lyrics here. So,
do I have uh
Okay, so I don't have Wait, I should
have
What? [sighs]
Why don't I have um
Okay. So,
okay. So, that should be that that that
showing browser.
There it is. The lyrics. Okay. Okay. I
rambled quite long. Um but you know,
actually I got lots of other things I
want to say yet. But anyway, so you see
this a population decline.
uh some people consider it a crisis
because for the past 10 or more years
many nations especially Japan, South
Korea they and also happening in China
and lots of European countries we don't
have enough you know not enough people
were born like the birth rate is below
maintaining population so we are
population in decline less and less
people and For some people they they
they think of that you know Ela Musk
especially because he's been talking
about that for the past two years every
month like every two months or so for
some people. So, so some people or some
people regard it as a um crisis you know
um uh but you know so why and so so this
is also academic subject because it's
kind of important
uh very important
um
I think you know I think I think it's
not a big deal because we don't have
population, you know, we don't have lots
of babies due to lots of artificial
reasons. First of all, because birth
control, we got the POS for women, you
know, women can eat pills, then they
don't have babies. They and we also have
condoms, you know, so-called
um
uh you know uh
anyway the cons you know the
anyway what what they call it um
contraceptive you know contraceptive
tools and uh drugs you know silly
basically stop pregnancy. Okay, you know
women got peels and we got condoms and
we got other kind of devices. So you see
and but is it because we don't have sex?
Well actually we do have lots of sex.
Okay, you see, but if you if you want
population decline to stop very easy, in
fact, trivial. Okay, just stop the
peels. Okay, ban the birth pills. Bang
it right away. We're going to have
population explosion, okay? Every every
girl is going to immediately have a
children because we cannot stop having
sex. We are having sex at all the time.
Okay. So this population decline. Well,
oh, it sounds serious because people
don't want babies. Well, that Well,
that's because you give them pills.
Okay, that's that's why while all the
all the girls they go to, you know, they
they they they show their tits on on
social media, on Instagram, on Twitter,
on Tik Tok, you know, they they they
they split legs. They, you know, they do
all kind of I learned woo woo voice
recently,
last week. Woo woo woo woo. [laughter] I
learned about woo woo voice. Yeah, let
me show you that post. Okay, that's what
girls do.
Okay. And what you talking about
population decline? Well, you stop you
stop the birth peels, then you then
you're going to have population
explosion. Okay. So, it's the decline is
is artificial is you man-made,
you know. Then the some people, the
white people, you know, [ __ ] stupid,
you know. I I consider lots of them.
They say, "Oh, oh, but you can't do that
because then you're gonna have rape
problems or or women's right, you know,
you know, you got lots of things." Okay.
Anyway,
uh so anyway, so the about the Yeah. So
I was talking about woo woo voice. Okay.
Woo woo voice.
Uh I discovered that there's this woo
woo voice. Very interesting because of
the
because of the
relationship of psycho acoustics and
sex. Okay,
there there it is. Okay, I learned about
this woowoo voice. Fascinating.
And uh you also learn about the white
people, the white men hypocrisy, you
know, like I learned about the woo
voice. And you know, starting about 20
years ago, you started to see these
selfies by girls, you know, usually over
a mirror and uh showing, you know, half
naked, you know, taking pictures of
themsel. They did it themselves
starting about like 20 years ago. and
and this this this uh uh
a [laughter]
hair go, you know, face.
And I thought those are like from porn
stars. Those are fake. They pretend to
be like being natural, you know, but
actually not. But you know, you started
to see as time goes by, you see like
every [ __ ] girl is doing them naked
photos of themselves. They are doing it
it themselves, not because oh they are
because the mafia forced them or because
you know whatever the feminist [ __ ]
are trying to say, you know, the white
people's problem. These are the kind of
the white people's
problem.
Anyway, that's it. I think that's it for
today. Uh, so sorry I haven't read the
comments, but perhaps
perhaps it's time for for this white
wine drink.
So, how long have I been talking?
Okay, almost an hour. So,
100 ml something.
gun blank something like that branch or
something.
So, let's read the comments and that'll
be it.
I see you are using quoty and not vorac.
Have you given up on vorac? Of course
I'm using vorac. What you talking about?
Why? How did you get that sense? You
asked that yesterday. I'm using vorac.
This is vorac keyboard. Okay. This is
physical vorac layout. Okay.
Uh what you know this this keyboard I'm
using vorac layout.
physical okay so maybe you are looking
at this you know this is this is the
software layout change you know I'm not
the keyboard itself is vorac and you can
see it by let me just show you are you
are you still here uh uh buansai
okay the white wine this wine seems to
be sour kind of sour taste taste taste
test tasting okay so here is my keyboard
keyboard layout for this ultimate
hacking keyboard 80 UHK. Okay, and
that's Vorax keyboard layout. Okay, it's
physical vorac. Okay, so next question.
Uh I'm interested in this but I don't
know if it's practical that I learn it
quite yet because I'm in an electronics
technician program. Should I come back
in five years when I'm doing E
bachelors? Well, you see uh kebab donors
ask that question. Are you still here?
Well, that's
like usually you don't want to delay,
you know. Yeah, you are. You know, so
your question is that you are right now
learning electronics technician. So you
are afraid if you also try to learn
Emacs then you might have less time for
learning electronic. you get, you know,
you get confused or, you know, you get
unfocused.
Well, my experience is that in life, you
don't have a second time. Okay? Just
just learn it more, you know, like you
you you can there's no problem. You you
can learn both Emacs,
which is about using the editor, and
learn electronics, which is what you
need to which is important to you. Okay?
You can do them both.
Of course, you don't want to like became
obsessed with Emacs, you know, you just
like you you want to um
keep control of yourself. But don't
worry about it being a distraction
because usually, you know, if you are
thinking, oh, I'll learn it, you know,
after I finish my electronics, you know,
after I become expert of
electronics.
usually that's you you're never going to
learn it again because when I was
learning calculus
in the early 1990s
you know let's say 1992 to 199 you know7
many problems or many calculus books I
thought this is so interesting I'm going
to you know next year or after a few
years I'm going to come back and look at
it thoroughly again
usually that never happened. Okay? Like
when when so at that time right now if
you're going to do Emacs do it now
because that will never happen again.
You like usually depends on the person
but you know because in life you got
as as you age you know you got new you
got into new uh situations you know uh
maybe your wife or girlfriend or
whatever you know you progress you like
you don't you are not going to have a
master plan. Okay. So don't think about
oh I'm going to come back to that in 5
years or you know usually not it's going
to happen
zana do space no I don't know what's
zana do space
pl in serial experiment lane I think
lane also a least programmer in anime I
got a lot fans into lane but I myself
never actually watch it but I can feel
it because I'm kind of like,
you know, I read kind of the summary of
the what lane is about, so I can feel
I might like it when I was much younger,
but I I'm into similar things, but I
actually never watched Len.
Si, I shared this video in your discord
server and someone immediately
recognized you. Yeah, I'm you know I'm
somewhat a little bit well known in
Emacs community and among others like
lisp community. What the actual [ __ ] is
this? Do you have hallucinations or
something? [laughter]
What is going on? Okay.
So, so uh so we got this guy the last
name. Okay. The last name. You need to
say what
was I talking about? Uh okay, he's
talking about how shallow information
exchange is. I think okay law uh those
are methods of birth control but that
does not address the implications of
population inversion. Okay.
So Lee is saying that method of birth
control like birth peels but those but
that does not address the implications
of population inversion.
Okay. So you are saying you know it's a
complicated topic
implications implica uh does not address
the implications of population inversion
kind of um
too wordy you know so population
inversion you mean population decline
you know just just say population
decline not inversion some [ __ ] okay
just say population decline is that what
you
or population overgrowth you know uh
crowded or decline.
So the implication of population
decline. So
okay. So you mean so what what you mean
implication of population decline is
that what the consequences what happens
with population decline. Okay. Let me
decipher your statement. You know so you
are saying something does not address
the implication of population inversion
which means now it becomes it doesn't
address the the um like the result or
consequences of population decline okay
but what but so method birth control
anyway I don't know what you're
Okay. I don't think I like this.
Uh, okay. I think that's it. Is it good?
Is it good you for you guys? Do you have
kids? Cuz no.
Uh, my wife is too old to have kids.
Okay. And uh maybe I should just [ __ ]
some like young blonde. That's what I
like. [laughter]
I want to have some kids. I do.
Uh but there's a question of money. You
see,
you see
you know you know like like usually kids
happen just just when you [ __ ] you know
like a lot of like throughout human
history
kids did does not happen because of
master plan. Okay, people fact.
That's how we are here. That's why we
are here. Like most of us people just
like you you see her ass. You see an ass
out there like this girl, you just
[ __ ]
She you know well I'm not talking about
rape but you know that's that also
happens. But
for and and also for girls you know when
they are hot they they see a guy they
just you know they just [ __ ] and you
have and then that's why we are here
okay for most of us for for thousands of
millions of years it is not because of
master plan because oh I thought you
know maybe it's the right time to have
kids nobody nobody [ __ ] thought about
that except the current era, the idiot
zoomers and the white people, you know,
they think, you know, the liberals or
whatever, they think, oh, because, you
know,
you know, parenthood planning or
whatever, you know, uh, rights, human
rights or whatever. [ __ ] idiots.
Okay, we are here because, you know, we
we, you know, the guys saw some ass, the
girl showed their ass. We saw it and we
[ __ ] That's why we are here.
Uh and uh [sighs] should I learn Chinese
given my career path and interest? I
understand how I am sometimes. Um so
what is your favorite alcoholic
beverage?
Okay, I think [clears throat] you know
probably I should stop now. How long
have I been talking?
Let's see. Almost an hour. Okay, few
more minutes. Five more minutes. Okay,
so let's see. Uh so let's see method
birth control. It's a choice people are
making to not have kids and instead
focus on their careers. You know see you
see the white man society they got the
concept of careers.
Uh Lee last name says take Tokyo as an
example. People have ridiculous hours
and not enough time to set aside for
raising a family. Their culture has
overvalued company success while
undervaluing the household. Okay. Uh Ka
Donald Dab
says I think it's because adolescence
has effectively been extended into the
20s. That is also true. you know the you
know people became like childish
you know the modern society you know
anyway this is very complicated kind of
fairly complicated topic on society
on perceptions on you know on also on
philosophy on religion like what of
course religion heavily influence the
view about population about sex
Especially for example Christianity and
Islam and
probably Judaism too you know
Christianity obviously you know
Christianity
they are
you know they they cannot touch sex they
got problem with sex okay that's
Christianity especially the American
branch like the like the Protestant the
American branch they got problems with
girls you know you can't talk about that
you can't have sex.
uh then then the the Islam they got they
forbid you know you can't do this you
know girls you can't have this kind of
you can't do this you got to cover
yourself okay otherwise the pun
punishment is death in some
some some part of it okay now that's not
true for Muslims in general it's just
like some some some some of the parts
okay because uh Because the because this
complicated politics you see because
some people
for example the some some the some of
the ruler class in USA want you to
believe that that they they want you to
believe that for the Muslim countries
they they they
uh they don't have they don't allow
freedom for women. Okay. They want you
to believe that. getting very um hot
but but I want to say it's like you
zoomers you know the zoomers you don't
you guys don't know nothing not a thing
functionality closer to the patriarchal
worship As ancient Anglo practiced okay
yet sex is taboo yet that's Yes. Yeah.
That's what I'm saying. The uh clarity
of expression sex, you know, for for
like the American Christians like
Protestants, sex is taboo for them.
That's well put, succinct.
And yet they are the they are also kind
of the most degenerate. Um
yeah. Well, kind of like especially in
the past 20 years, you know, because the
American they started to have this, you
know, this LGBTQ,
you know, uh, gays and trans and but
it's also the it's not like it's also
not authentic, you know, part of it is
pushed by the deep state behind it. You
know the deep state for example they
want you to believe all Muslims you know
they don't allow you know you know they
they think that women should be veiled
at all times right that's one thing they
are pushing they want you to believe
that meanwhile they you know also part
of it they they want you to believe that
you you you you should be gay you should
be trans you have the right you know the
the all sort of things very dark going
on. Okay. You see, so so part of this is
like like what people actually believe
due to regional culture. That's one
thing. But the other part is like what
there's certain force power that they
they they they
basically brainwash you to make you
think that certain things is going on in
certain way. Okay. So this kind of
complicated. Okay.
Okay. Anyway, that's it. I think that's
it, you know. So, I was, you know, so,
so I, you know, by the way, let's go
back to this topic. So, I was looking
at, you know, I was looking observing
the the porn and sex phenomenon
throughout my life. Okay. I'm a porn
watcher. I'm a like I watch porn. Okay.
I document porn. I watch porn. I
document the behavior of girls and men,
their sexual behaviors and activity.
Okay, that's what I that's kind of what
I do. It's kind of part partly what I do
besides coding and and computing. Okay,
mathematics.
And I don't know why am I into you know
I started to study these kind of things
but that's kind of
uh the part of the study I do all my
life okay observing sexual behaviors and
pornography and and you know this kind
of thing. So, so you know in in the past
20 years we started to have this selfie
you know we are told oh you know I
thought you know actually I honest
thought oh they you know they are done
by uh porn actor you know porn actress
porn stars they pretend to be like
average girl but actually they are porn
stars but that's not true it turns out
like every [ __ ] girl every [ __ ]
teen girls today you can see them you go
to chatterbase
A thousands of them every minute, 24
hours a day. You see the the girls they
compete spreading their legs on
Chatterbait or Only Fans and others.
Okay? Like thousands of them, millions
every day, every every minute. Like you
can go to it right now. You can see it.
That's what the that's what these girls
like these normal girls like they are
not special. like they are average
normal girls. They are doing especially
the white girls. Okay. the white
American culture, the western culture,
you know, like like every time I talk
about these kind of things, there are
special they are certain class of white
people. They they get very angry,
offended, sensitive, then they started
to attack me because because I talk
about chatterbait, usually they don't
talk about it. But if I talked about it,
they they're going to start to say, you
know, you you are a pedal, you know,
like pedal pedal like their one one of
their obsession, the white people's
obsession like you are a pedal or you
know like they get very offensed usually
Christians. Okay. Usually Christians,
the white American Christians.
Do I uh
do I have a content for streamer
streamer girls? No, I don't have a
content for them. That's the girl.
That's who they are. Okay. I mean,
that's not that's like part of human
nature. Okay. The girls do these things.
That's normal human animal. Part of
normal human animal behavior. If a girl
do not do these things, they are
inhuman.
Do you understand? That's what I'm
saying. I'm what I'm I'm what I'm saying
is particularly addressing the kind of
uh mainstream white American cultural
people, their thoughts. I'm attacking
them. This white [ __ ]
Okay, that's it. Bye, guys. [laughter]
Uh uh. Okay, so that's, you know, lots
of rant. Okay, bye guys. So, if you like
my stuff, if you find my stuff
interesting, donate to me. Okay.
So, just go to go to kasari.info
kasari.info. So, you can go to go to it.
Go to it kasi webcas.info
and at the bottom you'll see at the
bottom. So, this is kasali.info my
website. At the bottom go to the bottom
you'll see Patreon and my Amazon
gift card or PayPal. So, you can pay me.
Okay. If you have a job, pay me $100.
That would be nice.
Okay, I think that's it. Uh, bye guys.
Uh, so you know, yeah, you know, that's
so you are watching talk show. I'm
technically, you know, statistic
statistically speaking, my I I'm kind of
a weird guy. So I'm like rather so I'm
I'm I'm abnormal. Okay. I am like one in
one in maybe 100,000
or
probably one in a million. Okay. I'm
kind of abnormal. So I'm not a normal
person. Not normal Chinese or not
normal, you know, American for sure. Um
and uh
you know maybe one in a million is is
apt description because you know even
one in a million there's a lot you know
this like if you look at the population
if you actually look at people this
really like diverse you know people like
like you look at anyone and or anyone in
your friends online contact you know you
don't really know them like each person
can be very different. Okay. Anyway,
okay. Bye, guys.
Bye, guys.