good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of XR talk show today is 2020
May 14th first day two o'clock in the
afternoon San Francisco time welcome all
so what are we going to talk about we're
going to talk about several things if
you have a question or comments type it
with my name so I can see it okay so
we're going to talk about we have 11
people watching and we're gonna show you
coding fantastic coding and stuff and
keyboards in Japanese and whatever so
actually let me start by I don't have a
topic today so let's start by by the way
this is a buta and with this fantastic
symbol this symbol the Western the white
people loves okay we talked about it in
one of the saw TV episode okay so that
is the saw arts website now let's close
that and let's talk about today's things
I want to let me begin by I'm going to
do some coding of my website life okay
now I have hand paint you know I have
RSI repetitive strain injury it's right
here it's this is my left hand and you
see the forearm
okay the forearm and it's right here
for some reason I do not know like over
the past 15 years that my first is I is
in 2004 because I was using a laptop
keyboard for all the time
exclusively for two years that is a
Apple MacBook and because of that I got
an ISI so I switched to the Microsoft
natural economic keyboard and before
that I hated
ergonomic keyboards because the be the
key B is on the left hand weird position
and the number six is also on the other
hand I don't like that I don't like I
did not like economic keyboards just
like you just like the most people
unti oh and here you got pain so I got I
switched to Microsoft
natural keyboard and got used to it then
now I cannot know type on normal
keyboard whenever I type on a standard
keyboards it spells pain and right now
I'm hung as you can see I'm on this
fantastic this stupid [ __ ] video is
either too small or you cannot adjust it
okay so anyway I am currently using the
fantastic ultimate hacking keyboard I
did a review of that you can watch it on
my youtube somewhere okay
so we don't have a fixed topic if you
have a question for me just type it and
we'll talk about it I'm going to
periodically check what you guys are
saying and stop this video stop this
idiotic thing wait MA all right
talking on voice yes yes check yes I'm
good so what are you saying so have you
seen Twin Peaks Twin Peaks
yes of course that's a very popular TV
show I've seen a few episodes it's by
this guy weird director David Lynch and
it's got it's got a coat following now
his show
I like his show but but Twin Peaks I
think once you have you watch it after
wire it becomes somewhat boring you know
after all it's just a TV show it's drama
you know it's soap opera that that's
what those are soap opera and by the way
is speaking of that you know we start to
digress let me show you saw favorite
movies okay you go to search for saw
best movies and you'll see this movie
directed by David Lynch and that is a
fantastic movie go to best movies of axr
arts
and this thing you need to buy you need
to buy it because I get money the money
goes to my pocket and for you you become
healthier okay you need to please so
let's go to a society sci-fi hard sci-fi
comedy society psychological
psychological or drama so let's click on
that and click on that this all these
are my favorite movies okay so you can
go and browse it so let me copy the link
okay I have fun look I have a fantastic
shortcut system I press a key now you
see it copied URL and switch me back to
the Emacs the mechanism of that is via
the programmable keyboard ultimate
hacking keyboard okay now I'm in Emacs
you can see I go here taste and magnify
you can see there is a link so we gonna
go to castle talk show today this is
some talk show and put for the link here
make it a list and show in browser you
see that's today's topic buta and the
best movies so you can you can go and
check it out ok so let's go back to the
movies ok I'm gonna have several things
to do so let's talk about this movies so
best movies best psychological thriller
movies now these are the pop these are
popular topics because when I talk about
if I talk about programming or the
esoteric mechanical keyboards very few
are interested you know but these are
the top these are the pub
my friends pop now this movie more
Mulholland Drive is fantastic movies
okay you might like it okay
you see we nerds have a taste that is
slightly different from others anyway
this is a great movie and it comes with
a song and by the way this is American
Beauty look at this so let's look at the
song okay muha moo-ha land drive there's
quite a few songs there that is a normal
people would say it's creepy okay kind
of very very weird
okay there is this song and there is roy
Overson also 1964 and it's in Spanish
and there it is English translation and
there is lesbian sing we all love that
so anyway so this is Mahalo Mahalo and
drive okay it's really fantastic movie
you should go check it out so let's put
a link here okay
and Mahalo and drive by David Lynch
okay so let's go to and there is some
other movies I want to show you okay
some other movies these all these are
fantastic this American hustle American
hustle oh my look at those attires of
women women satires the you know they
have for thousands of years they have
all these fantastic variations with the
same core you know show show the tits
and show the show scheme fascinating and
Belle de Jour this French movie I
haven't seen those are you know what's
called French arthouse movies I like
them you European movies you see you
rope here oh these are European movies
well this one is from Hong Kong it's
also fantastic 2046 to 0:46
and Camille Claudel is a real-life
sculptor it's she a female sculptor you
see RSI back twice I hand paint so I
need to hammer hammer then it's soothing
now let's check what you guys are saying
so you see I have these I have this I
can you see you see I at all and
[Music]
forehand exercise and you can buy them
let me go to em I'm gonna show you the
links and meanwhile this this is met met
marble okay it's a stone well this one
this this one is made of metal and they
chai ok don't buy those light chimes
because I'm you know at first its it's
cute but after why oh it's annoying you
don't want them to chime so you want to
buy metal ones solid ok oh by the strong
ones the problem with the stone lines is
that if you fall down they crack you
know they chip or crack anyway there's a
dual purpose so you take that and you
hammer Hongkong it is so you know over
the past 15 years I have eyes I doubts
every to every three years every time
there is a reason I realized you know
for the when happens you go into a panic
you know you don't know what's going on
because then you're gonna be wasted you
are cut your programming career is over
so there's a panic but then so for me
when it happens I noticed you know
tingling or pain my old you know I never
really actually have pain but right now
it here is like just just my out it's
always there and this is gonna be I
think it's permanent and unfortunately
now it's you know somewhat hurts
somewhat just you know just barely there
but it's been like that for the past
three years
and for this cause this this episode I
can I never found out exactly why what
is causing it
so keep keep the comments you know going
okay type it so over the 15 years every
time every three years or so I have
eyesight but eventually you know what
happens I try to find out what's causing
it and typically I always found I
identified that I traced the source the
cause of the problem and I have articles
on that I have detailed you know written
out every time I find have an episode of
eyesight about of our side I write it
down so you can find you know just such
focus Ollie is I history something like
that you'll find quite a few my
documentation of my eyes i okay I detail
the reasons what's causing it but this
time you know since three years ago
there's you know this I cannot quite
identify it but I think I think I kind
of know why because the reason is
because I'm using my middle finger to
press the number three key you know on
the keyboard number rows number three
key why do i press I so much because on
a go Emacs mod in Emacs ago Emacs mod
and sapphire keys Emacs stuff like is
key binding system the number three key
is used for to a bit of the split pin
let me show you okay you see we have a
split pane and split paint happens often
you know whenever you do a like you know
messages or whatever you have a split
pane you see let me show you again okay
so now you are normally coding and well
and and let's say you want to see the
message buffer
okay now you press a key there it is
your message buffer the you see the
buffer becomes split and you want to get
rid of that split you press number three
now you see I press number three you can
see right there you see you see let me
magnify you see the number three there
it's not working because I removed it
but normally
I press number three by default you
remove the sleep in pain you know so
number three key in Ocoee Mac smart all
three are in Sophocles
you press number three that reads bits
of the splittin so you have to do that
often you know I've been doing that for
that for ten years for 12 years and now
I remapped
to my keys let me show you okay key yeah
so I'd be mapped it so that I no longer
you see you see you see this line number
three Neal so I changed it
why because I think it is because
pressing the number three key with my
middle finger left hand too much you
know this motion that that caused the
pain here I've been doing that for ten
years so so that is a problem but now I
use a different key so you can see when
I spray the window like I press a key
you see I'm using the - key you can see
on this window it's a - key
on the Borak layout okay so on QWERTY
that would be the single quote key so
anyway digression digressions
integration let's go back to what we
were talking about
okay so Mahalo and drive let's show'em
browser so we were talking about best
movies Mahalo and drive and the song
okay so now I'm going to do some coding
of my Emacs website okay so go to sake
board show in browser if you have
questions type it okay I'm gonna go into
it so now I want to modify
you know this tremendous update on my
website so let's go look at this Nachi
tag ago k 860 keyboard this is new just
came out three months ago
in January so this is a fantastic
keyboard so I've been doing research on
it now that one is a video it's not
showing in idiotic Firefox you know this
[ __ ] open-source [ __ ] let me tell you
why okay [ __ ] open-source [ __ ]
open-source [ __ ] if you if you are
open-source phonetic don't be okay after
you know watching TV after you watch
Star TV F after you become addicted to
TV then you should not no longer be a
Linux or open source phonetic [ __ ] this
these people they damage society let me
explain you see if Firefox is known to
be the open source proponent right and
also this let me show you
m'kay
wait not not this fight okay so let me
show you the Logitech okay it's a
Logitech keyboard okay it's here m'kay
you see so you see right here let me
show you see this line that is a video
file
MKV now what is MKV MKV is a video
container okay a format you know
basically for video files for containing
video codecs technically speaking you
know baby stick [ __ ] nerds [ __ ] they
like to say Oh codec you know if you
didn't use that word they think oh you
are wrong this is called cadet this is
not just a video format this is a
container [ __ ] you [ __ ] [ __ ] the Linux
and take kicking [ __ ] heads because why
because they know nothing they don't
understand society so so so what they
get us is this Google Empire you know
Microsoft Empire now Linux is gonna be
part of Microsoft and you know the
that's why these [ __ ] Linux fanatics
are doing that's what they gave us
so anyway the MKV is a video of
container okay and it's open source by
the way it's open source it you know it
this is one of the format actually this
is the video format that the open source
phonetics advocate advocates you know
they love you know they say this is the
best format and open source and all that
but however notice this strange thing
you know this open source video format
does not show in this open source
Firefox [ __ ] fact least open source
phonetics but however if you show this
page in chrome okay let's show it in
Chrome let's call exhaust fantastic
commands opening Chrome browser yes
indeed press Enter
open come browser there it is now slow
down there it is the video fantastic
beautiful video
so you see you see these these you see
the problem you see open-source video
format that's not shown in Firefox why
is that because you know because this
open-source fanatics they don't
understand society anyway so let's go
back to these keyboards so there is
something I want to modify you know I I
did this page quickly when it come out
usually I have to do research like you
have to read all the reviews oh all
reviews that exists on the web so you
watch all the youtubes you know and
watch all the Amazon comments what they
say and then you write your article I
read my article but I you know it takes
tremendous time so sometimes I don't
have time to go through so I just slap
on you know just steal pilfered compile
those photos and put on my website so
this is eggs so for example let's say
you know this picture you know let me
show you this picture it's no good okay
this picture doesn't contain much
information you know it's one of those
marketing pictures you know one two
three means you can okay switch to
different operating systems by a press
of a key and it's a small type device in
multi OS okay yeah and also the picture
is too big
okay too big picture means you know it's
large size you have to download so it's
not good for the website so you see lots
of details you have to go through when
you do a website so I'm going to modify
this picture what I'm going to do is now
so this is Emacs demo for those of you
Emacs users or for those of you writing
blogs comments posted okay with my name
okay so so this I'm going to modify I'm
first of all I'm going to crop this
picture I don't want the multi device in
multi or a spot crop it and then I'm
going to shrink it okay so so how am I
going to do it okay so look at my source
code so first of all show in browser
it's showing Firefox go down go down so
you see this is this picture so there's
a idq Nyepi
so such for kyun IP so you see it's
right here it's right here okay let me
show you the it's right this one so I'm
going to now watch my keystrokes okay on
the right window you can see all my
keystrokes in commands so press ENTER to
open it you can see this is this is an
image file you know you know in Emacs
you can view image files that's what we
are doing but it's kind of stupid it
doesn't it's not very good so I'm going
to press a key and show it in preview
okay press a key opening in the default
image viewer of your operating system
there it is preview now preview allows
you to edit the editor picture so we are
going to do that but before we do that
go back to Emacs wait before we do that
go back to Emacs press a key make a
backup now the backup is done go back to
preview now let's cut it
okay clop clop it
of course you can also do this in [ __ ]
if you want okay now that's my crop now
command K to actually cut it so done
okay and it done close it okay
now go back to Emacs now ot Max has Auto
buffer updates so actually it's already
updated this is the new version so we
can close it copy the file path copy it
and put here put the file path layer and
relink it make a link okay wait oops
okay now make a link now you see these
two are different now this one has with
1466 while the other one has with 1500
you see that because we cropped it now
the second line we don't need anymore
and now we can show in browser you see
that you know it's now it's cropped now
this is a this is too big of photo so
I'm going to shrink it and you can see
all my commands here now let's go a
command to shrink it so
we need to shrink this image now I have
a command I don't need I do not even
need to go to the image I can just call
the command directly so let me correct
press a few keys and that's uh create
thumbnail image okay so now I want to I
want size to be let's say 1000 ok 1000
pixels width so enter it's done so you
see it inserted a new path of the file
ok now make a link showing browser go
down go down you see now we are we have
two versions the first one is actually a
smaller file the second one is the
internal size now you cannot see the
difference we could because because of
the CSS technology it will display with
the maximum width you know just fit the
window so that's why you don't see the
difference but now if we fullscreen the
whole thing you'll see the difference
you see the first version this is you
know default size the second version is
actually larger so we don't need you
know the two larger version so I'm going
to deal TV the second version ok shrink
it again now back to Emacs back to Emacs
open it dido file
okay I look at my commands on the right
okay and now delete this line we don't
need that anymore and this caption we
need to change the caption it says it
should say buttons allow feature buttons
to switch to different operating systems
okay now back to browser reload there it
is you see there it is feature buttons
to switch to different operating systems
so this is some of the Emacs demo
actually I've done this quite a few
times in my talk show and now here is
another photo which is idiotic because
it doesn't contain much information is
those these are kind of the marketing
photos you know they they serve a
purpose because a picture is a is worth
a thousand words so for average people
when they look at this page they see
these oh then they immediately know this
has batteries this use battery batteries
and it's wireless they immediately know
without having to read you know
otherwise you have to read Oh requires
two AAA batteries what the heck is a AAA
batteries so that's why you know so I'm
I'm telling you about the you see we are
looking at we are observing and
deconstruct the photos used in marketing
why are they this way or that way but
for me for my website I don't want these
pictures like that
because you guys are all smart you don't
want to look at idiotic teachers you
want to use emacs
you guys are Emacs users you guys are
the muses Linux users you need things to
be as hard as possible
no pretty pictures okay so open this
press a key can delete this paragraph
show in browser or single key press okay
go down there it is fantastic fantastic
efficiency of this by the way this is a
good keyboard okay one issue I didn't
like is that you see this palm rest it
is not detachable you know it's
connected to the device it's not
detachable I'd rather I don't want the
you know the palm rest I want I want
just I want my own palm rest because you
can see let me show you okay
you see this is my palm rest you see
this is this is Tower this is tower you
know past our paths tower is my palm
rest and that's the best pumice most
comfortable and flexible easy flexible
conform to your hand curves or whatever
conforms and if you get sturdy washable
you know this is washable high
technology washable washable by the
high-tech washing machines okay so
there's one more thing I want to do okay
you see this cute picture of the hand
it's kind of too big you know I can
shrink it now let's forget it let's just
leave it okay so that's about that Emax
demo but there is one more thing okay
let's show my keyboard block again one
more thing now I need to sync to my
server so you when you go to Kasauli dot
info website you'll see or these updates
so in Emacs let's go through ECL and
press a few buttons and it's all done
there it is we have updated quite a few
things you know kewal blog logitech ago
k8 60 keyboard tech Trackman and
magnetic USB connected connected by the
way this is I think this is a good thing
for those of you who have was got money
and who is using Apple keyboards Apple
stuff especially you know magnetic USBC
connector this you know Apple has been
idiotic that they removed their magnetic
power connector since you know since
Steve Jobs been dead when Apple become
idiotic they you know they invented the
kind of invented or popularized the
magnetic power connector but now but in
later MacBook versions they remove that
so you have to plug it in you know Mac
idiocy of the Apple then by anyway this
magnetic USBC connector for your tongue
goes I think that's a good thing
so has has anyone used it is it good now
let's see let's talk about the next
topic okay you know this is the this is
the very old 1989 trackball someone is
using it in all this code is talking
about it so what's the next topic let's
see how long have I been talking that's
close this by the way this movie the ice
stone is also one of the fantastic movie
you know this this movies our drama
movies typically Americans they don't
like drama movies they what American
like is crashing bird you know big big
fire big big giant trucks big explosions
you know those are American type but but
anyway this one the ice storm that's
American American movie directed by a
Chinese guy this featuring Katie Holmes
okay this is fantastic
so there it is Katie Holmes she is now
old of course this is this movies like
20 years old and and here is our
spider-man you know this is a drama
movie it's fantastic
so let's go back to YouTube let's see
what you guys are saying and I have been
talking for I've been talking for 32
minutes okay
what is the next thing Eric Chen says
you keep saying open source is bad but
never explained why do you know what
you're talking about I expand a thousand
times in my past videos variables
understand Society can I type
Erin says can I type Emacs with CSS
what do you mean can can I style
Emacs with CSS of course you cannot we
feel confirmed no pretty pictures bin
you can also use it to wipe up T to wipe
up T huh what are you talking about you
know sometimes the smart comments gets
incomprehensible hey Emacs friends today
i used Emacs but I wrote no e mclees
have you seen Twin Peaks okay yeah
probably from Kibo rather than Mouse
usage Roland Drive yes Freddie good
morning Freddie
perhaps you can make international
Amazon affiliate links yes indeed you
know it's something I need to do I need
to be concerned about money you know so
Amazon you see when you buy my stuff on
my website you know you can click and
buy you American scope buy it but you
know for people in Canada in Europe in
Japan they cannot you know they cannot
use Amazon USA but however Amazon if I
go to my account you can you know you
have to you have to create an account
you know and link your account you have
to create an account for Amazon Europe
for example then you can link to it so
that so that people who came from Europe
visit my website they can go to Amazon
European pirate I need to do that
I've been you know
I need to do that for half a year
already anyway something I need to do
you know for money I rather just sit
here and you guys give him give me money
so what's the next thing so next thing I
think let's do some coding okay Eric
chance or what question you have Eric
Chen okay Eric Chen where you from are
you from China China are you from China
or are you from Hong Kong and by the way
you said you are on discord right do you
what's your name on this cord so I can
get to know you I so I can get to know
where you came from
what's your thinking so I can answer
your questions in in in a way that you
will find persuasive okay so yeah so you
know okay so let's go to next topic no
questions I'm going to talk to random
okay so no questions I'm going to talk
rendom and let's go back to so there's
something I want to do okay so keyboards
let's talk about
whether so I'm thinking of doing a
JavaScript live coding what do you guys
say should we or should we do something
else let's go to let me show you what we
gonna do okay so let's go to so this is
my keyboard block click on keyboard
layout okay then go down click click on
Japanese wait
oh I need to add an item here wait I
need to add an item of Japanese
character frequency it's missing so
anyway let me show you okay
so also click on the character frequency
chart you see so here's a light life
JavaScript this is a this is a
interactive JavaScript app that allows
you to allows you to show the character
frequency of any text you see let me
magnify in real-time for example like I
typed EDT it doesn't let me impress you
you see I type T and your CT comes out
now there is now let's go to a let's say
you want to know JavaScript you let's
say you want to know the punctuation
frequency of a particular programming
language in fact I have that somewhere
here you see when you study keyboard
layouts you want to know about semicolon
frequency for example semicolon verses
apostrophe which one is small you use in
programming languages and here is the
answer and you can go here computer
language computer languages characters
frequency and have prepared for you you
can see so you can see JavaScript I have
three charts of our JavaScript you know
JavaScript language punctuation
frequency then you can read about Java
which the period is the most frequent :
also period in parentheses in C++ is the
underscore you know because C and C++
underscore is the most frequently used
character because every name they they
use underscore separator
low-lying character in unicode those
that character underscore is called low
line that's official name it is also the
better name low line is not under
scholarship you know it says that's a
aspect of linguistics an aspect of
jargons you know that we I have articles
on jargons which you study jargons which
is more intuitive which is more
communicative which which you know
scientific jargons the naming of things
you know jargons is there's it's is
there's a great science in joggins and
naming of things and terminologies most
people you know programmers they don't
understand at all you know in fact you
have standards for jargons like
international standards for Chagas or
terminology you know in fields you have
to you know you have different
terminologies especially in engineering
in sciences math and you need to have
you know there's science about what
terminology is the best terminology you
know communication you know things like
that anyway programmers know nothing
about it they're idiotic programmers
[ __ ] you know these programmers C C++
Java or Haskell they talk about you know
the and then programming programming
jargons like oh patterns patterns object
orientation this [ __ ] idiot
[ __ ] and that Martin guy you know about
injection
crackpots anyway back to this topic
about so we were talking about yeah we
digressed because of this character
underscore you know we should it you
know unicode official name for that
character in unicode is low-lying now
that's a better word okay it's by the
way it's called underscore there are
reasons you know don't confuse reasons
of something with you know the analysis
or or logical analysis of something of
some naming for things in society
there's always reasons you because you
know history that's how things you know
there are reasons for something came to
be so underscore why is it named
underscore well because because you know
I don't know precisely why it's named
underscore you can you can you can you
know to research just start to look up
but I can I can tell you probably why
because typewriters in a beginning
beginning you know typewriters you don't
have you know learn the score is mint to
emulate underlie you know underlined of
some words or blank you know you need to
type that so you have these under score
and by the way why is it named score
because it's a good reason linguistic
reasons you know let's look up
underscore the etymology of in the skull
okay digression so let's go through were
the English you can see this is my were
the English blog and let's go to let's
add a new entry okay and the score and
etymology okay link if I show in browser
etymology of underscore let's see what
it says okay so it says now I want to
magnify the page okay 1771 to draw a
line under okay for that meaning from
the word underscore okay so it says the
figurative sense of to emphasize exactly
is attested from 1891 now meaning a line
drawn below something is recorded from
1901 okay so but so in order to
understand the history of this world
underscore why is it score you have to
understand the etymology of score click
on that
so you see a late old English scholar
ooh 20 ok well the connection notion
probably is the connecting notion
probably is counting large numbers
scores of ships scores of them something
with the notching stick for each 20 so
anyway you can read about it but I think
so score also means to cut with incision
or notches to keep record so to achieve
something so so anyway do you have to do
you know read them in detail
so what so what we are trying to there
okay well what we are trying to find is
the connection between the word score
with underscore what you know why does
it mean underlined so I think here it
touches upon it basically mark okay you
want to make a mark you know you know it
trains you know this when you study
things in a random way like I do right
now
you see you are not just you know you
are learning so you know for example we
are we are looking at keyboard
characters frequency then there's a
digression
about the underscore and the underscore
the linguistic aspect of the jargon
underscore why is it called school then
we go read about etymology of
linguistics you know and etymology then
you see here you see you know it's about
the score it's about a notch a notch in
a stick for each 20 you know the way of
counting you know so so now you are
starting to look at the history of
counting that's how human animals we
count you have a stick you use a knife
or something you know you cut a notch
that you know for counting that's so
from from computer character frequency
to etymology to the history of counting
you are learning things you know in a
non-standard way you know not in the
academic [ __ ] the educational
institutions [ __ ] you know they with the
education you know the educational
institutions in America what they are
teaching today is what you get social
justice warriors
okay back to keeping in touch with you
guys what we what are we where are we
have been talking for 46 minutes
good morning parts there is a really low
noise buzzing the whole time yes indeed
I don't know why because since I was
maybe I should change the maybe I should
change the the plug you know the the
extension the the prevention of the
electricity surge surge suppressor you
know that's another jargon surge
suppressor I think maybe I change I need
to change that you know it's
speaking of Unicode characters you know
ask Alan he's asking what do you call -
- you know - I you know the so I have a
strong interest in Unicode characters as
you know oh you mean you you may not
know so let me show you okay so let's go
- let me actually copy this ok copy
close and go to some talk show so we can
have the topics today listed here ok so
let's wait hold on I also want to copy
this link
in fact wait okay okay copy these stink
and copy copy that link okay and go back
and copy I wanted to show you the
Japanese characters frequency now we
going back to the topics we were talking
about let me show you okay you you
probably got confused let me go page by
page so here is this page is talking
about Japanese Kibo layouts great
science of that is we did a video two
days ago on these so when you study
Japanese layouts what you need to know
is Japanese character frequency so I did
this page with Alan's help you know when
you compute the frequency of characters
what is very important is the source the
source take text you know the data you
are computing from because
for example for English letter
frequencies you can take all
Shakespeare's work and compile a letter
frequency but that's you know that's
typically useless because nobody use you
know type words that Shakespeare uses
it's gonna be useless so the source
takes text is very important or in
academia they call it you know they have
a word for the source text you know
idiotic [ __ ] what is it called in Kadima
what's the word they use for the source
takes anyway I have lots of wait I want
to remember
the body is a source take text the
source text for compiling letter
frequencies used in for example in crypt
analysis the word is just on my turn but
I forgot so somebody did somebody say
Copas Alain is a linguist Allah knows
copper's exactly this academic facts
yeah they use the word corpus okay now
by the way by the way there are
circumstances where it's good to use a
jargon but most people don't understand
that the programmers okay they they are
idiots for example when we are talking
about you know for example when I
criticize okapis idiot idiotic jargon
then some of the programmers you know it
happens all the time they were say oh no
yeah but the chipper dragons are useful
because we need to agreement they the
[ __ ] idiots because they are bred you
know they don't think they don't have
you know they never think about
something they never think about
something or they know is from here say
like hacker news hacker news every day
how can use reddit that's what they know
from the institutionalized you know
educational institution anyway so ok so
that I'm kind of rambling about Copas
and back to the topic so when you study
Japanese keyboard keyboard layouts you
have to know Japanese letter frequency
ok so when you do letter frequency one
of the important thing is that you want
you want to be picky you want to know
the cup you know where yours source data
you know the source text come from so
for our purposes what's our purpose our
purpose is to you know study keyboard
layouts which characters are most used
frequency by people you know by average
people in general
so you want the you want the source text
to be like common speech like you know
something your mom would say or
something your mom would write yo your
dad you know top 2 or in business you
know busy maybe your you maybe you are a
business person oh you are maybe you are
programmer so they are difficult rightly
different but that's a issue you need
you need to know for example you do not
want the source text to be from you know
classic novels you know the greatest
classic novels that's what that you
don't want that because novels you know
the the words using novels are typically
very different from everyday speech in
general ok depend on depending on what
kind of novel anyway so the best source
you know the source so you need you need
to pay attention to that so anyway so I
have you know so I have this JavaScript
apt apt that compiles Japanese letter
frequencies you know so here is example
of output but there's a problem
let me show you what is the problem for
example I go to let's say I go to
Wikipedia ok I go through a Wikipedia a
Japanese version on on the Alice in
Wonderland ok so I copy the entire page
ok copy the entire page go back go back
to my page and I go to character
frequency counter ok and I paste all the
Japanese here
there it is you see then there is the
Japanese character frequency but you see
the you see some Chinese characters
shows up you know Chinese it's actually
part of Japanese characters for this one
it doesn't show a lot of Chinese but for
example if you go to another one you
show a lot of Chinese let me show you
okay I don't have this prepared so you
know you have to just bear with me okay
so let me walk it out yeah so we two we
go to the English what wiki page not
found
oh yeah wiki wiki [ __ ]
yeah okay I mean I mean made a mistake
let's start over
close okay so what we want to do is we
want to go through Wikipedia Japan okay
go to Wikipedia Japan click on that
[Music]
okay here's an article on Japan in
history and all that you know this type
of Arco tends to be scholarly scholarly
so now we click on the Japanese language
to go to the Japanese version of this
article there it is
now I copy the entire thing and go back
to my key keyboard frequency character
counter paste the whole text here now
you can see it started to show a lot of
Chinese you see you know these you know
Chinese characters and quite a few but
they are some of the articles that it
shows actually more Chinese anyway that
the thing that's the thing you see so
when we are doing Japanese characters
frequency we usually do not want the
Chinese characters even though Chinese
characters are part of the Japanese
writing system but we don't want it here
in this case because because for
Japanese keyboards for our purpose the
Japanese input systems you don't type
Chinese directly Chinese came out when
you do a conversion so you typically you
only type the hiragana you know the
phonetic symbols so we want to filter
out Chinese characters but right now my
program does not do that you see my
program you can filter out for example
top 400 top 40 you know there's a future
that shows only the top 40 but if you
you know if you don't have that on Soyuz
you see thousands of character seeds it
becomes unreadable so you want top 40
only then you can click no AZ let's
filter out English alphabets so let's
say no space no digit okay no
punctuation you see so we we want
basically we want an option that filter
out Chinese characters or we want the
option that only shows the Japanese
characters nothing else so that is what
we need to do I am planning to show you
how to modify the JavaScript code to do
that should I am wondering how long have
I been talking 57 minutes we can we can
call it a day actually
no comments okay no comments plain text
okay so is it from body in Latin it is
from party all right
right so copper's means body in Latin we
streamed so Alan says what would be
better is to Auto convert Chinese
characters to Japanese kana yeah that is
that is true yeah that would be actually
more fitting I mean for our purposes but
but that also involves more complexity
you know yeah definitely so what we need
is actually another program to convert
Chinese characters to to kana but you
know that gets more involved because my
my JavaScript app is kind of simple you
just type in you know it just compute
the frequency of characters with the
ability to filter out certain class so
this can be you know used for Russian
text for Indian text for whatever
without getting into the details of
linguistics of a particular language you
know so
so you know even though you know yeah so
we could convert Chinese to conifers
yeah but that's that's what we need but
that's kind of a different task okay so
this is because you have to type Chinese
yeah so anyway maybe that's it for today
or should we continue to code the
JavaScript I have 19 people people type
something common okay come on let's keep
this going or maybe worse that's it for
today
oh yeah so we were talking about Unicode
it's just talking about Unicode okay
maybe you're talking about Unicode so we
were talking about Unicode let me show
you Unicode okay so let's go to my
unicode page okay copy the link
let me wait let me show you why is it
taking so long but the pack
okay coffee unico close it paste it here
showing in browser okay go to Unicode so
I have interesting Unicode I've done a
lot unicode as you know so unicode in
there section - Ian - and all that in
fact today's in today's blog let me show
you okay so quite a lot of things
interesting things punctuation so we go
to punctuation and you can see you know
for example there's a lot variations of
the question mark
some are emoji some are not and there's
inverse question mark using Spanish and
there's double question mark and there's
reverse arrey arrey big question mark
then you have the inter interrobang
which is means to which is meant to be
sarcastic you know it's a combination of
question mark and extreme nation then
you have various exclamation marks quite
a lot quite a lot you have the for
example inverted one double exclamation
then you have full width then you have
Armenian weight Armenian Armenian
extinct lamination then you have Latin
letter retroflex quick now that's deep
into linguistics now this is Latin
letter retroflex quick okay it means
something I don't know so Allen because
that's question for Alan then we have
limbus exclamation mark limber limp limp
ooh exclamation mark
so anyways and then then then we have -
you know - - ma a.m. - yeah and so on so
you we have - man - - now this is a
character on your keyboard you know when
you type - that's that in Unicode is
called - - why I can tell you why
because I've been reading about this
obsessively you see on the ASCII
keyboard we have you know - oh and but
it's also used for the minor side you
see when it comes to the typographical
notes those two symbols are actually
different you know the the - in the -
sign are actually different you know
they have different width they have
different positions slightly different
and they have different thickness kind
of so in typography you know what why
the distinction I mean why the [ __ ]
why don't we just using yeah I mean
after all it's just it's just a little -
why do you distinguish them between this
you know the little length and [ __ ] well
that's because there's a reason for it
you know in a computer age to us you
know we think of them the same but you
have to you know the thing is you have
to consider history so history in
history you know in the past you don't
have computers when you need to type
something it's about printing is you
know giant machines you can you know
that you never see in your life it's you
know printing you know it's you have you
know those metal things printing
and then before printing it's something
else
it's woodcut you know it's something so
easy there's a huge history you know
before we don't even have capital case
you know where does capital case you
know like you ask this [ __ ] program
of [ __ ] idiots
you know these programmers who are
concerned about ligature and fauns know
this idiot
they don't know nothing but pattern in
the way back then back then back that
back before the printing press and and
even back 2000 3000 years ago there's no
capital letters it's just there's just
capital letters there's no lowercase
okay then getting involved you know this
need you then you you know then you
sorry to writing you know writing you
started to have anyways you know it's
the the the the the history of writing
okay that's a giant history your book
you know you you can have several books
about that so then you have lowercase
letters then lowercase becomes gradually
become different from calf case capped
okay it's something like that and we are
talking about English we are talking
about only English you know the Western
phonetics by the way the first one the
first one is this one okay
let me show you the first Phoenician
okay basically this is the grand grand
grand grand grand daddy
the first study of the English Western
alphabet Phoenician this is three
thousand years ago
okay 1200 BC you began with this then
eventually then you got you got the you
know you got photosynthetic then you got
food you know okay then you got
Phoenician then you got Asian Greek then
you got Latin then you got Roman then
you got English okay this is the
granddaddy there's no capital case in
lower case you know so it's a big
history of you know how they evolved so
in the same way with the okay we we
digress and rambled a lot so what I'm
going to say Rambo is my thing okay
grumbling is my expertise I was going to
say the punctuation okay weird why why
do we distinguish these - - and all that
it's all the same okay then the the
because of the printing they you know
they are a profession you know I don't
know the history - that much but anyway
I can guess you know the basic outline
because then it's a printing you know
bring printing then you have to do one
upmanship just like in academia be
concerned about aesthetics because those
metals you know you make them once it's
not like writing you just all changing
like computer fans you know you make
them once they are difficult to make you
make the name wasli they are permanent
and your book you know it takes very
expensive to print a book
so you have to end usually and you know
in this is big history and what are
those books those books are Bible ok
those books are Bibles
those who cannot to not you know not
random books those books are bibles ok
so it's important and the Bible's come
from the you know top down
who rules the country nations you know
this is the book so you get you cannot
get things right I and you know I want
this to be impact particular way things
like that so so you have you know all
this Ian - and e/m - and figure - that's
you know I think that's the general
reason the distinction because of the
typography you know the grand you know
the fancy academic word typography [ __ ]
in reality typography is just the fact
okay typography in human society - you
know as far as the concept not
historically historically it's very
important for great reasons but today
the concept of typography is is a [ __ ]
okay if you think you like you know you
are the glue the nose idiot or the Steve
Jobs idiot
well consumer take typography less
because the reason is because you are a
idiot
that is why
typography I have 1,000 articles on that
and I've talked about before and you can
read where does you go to read that okay
you go to read that by going to my
programming blog and go to web design
and battle by the way let's go back I
want to show you this this thing okay
correct correct and insertion sign and
logical end and you know this but anyway
let's go you know you go to web design
then that you know here we have web
design that's what they are then you
have Donald Knuth Steve Jobs and the
idiocy of typography okay now Donald
Knuth and Steve Jobs they are victims
they are victims of type of typography
they become their brain become idiotic
because of the typography it's a trap
you know you even smart people high IQ
people they fall into traps we have lots
of examples of that in society and okay
so
so back to the - and - okay so so in
Unicode you know you know back to the
topic you know on keyboard we just have
the that - which is used for - or - I
and basically anything you just use that
but in Unicode you have proper symbols
for each one of them you have - - you
have - okay - it's the proper one
now the - - one is the one on your
keyboard why is it called - - because
well sometimes it's used for - and it's
also useful - purposes why because well
because you have typewriters you know
you don't have the luxury to create you
know one symbol for - one symbol for -
and so on you just have one - you know
so so you have this character named - -
which is not a proper concept in
typography okay there's no such [ __ ] as
- - okay there's - there's - there's no
such focus - - but anyway you know again
we have this character because of
history okay anyway then you have -
symbol Papa - then you have the proper
number aching - okay then you have E and
- then you have figure - then you have E
em - then you have horizontal bar okay
so you know so in Unicode you have kind
of quite a lot of these similar symbols
ok I think that's it for today what what
else there's any interesting things to
say or counter arguments let's see maybe
an otherwise that's it for today and see
I've been talking for one hour and 12
minutes and okay and subscribe to my
youtube ok subscribe to my youtube and
by ok you buy stuff on my website you
just go there when you see things you
just buy it
let's help economy and let's help great
person like myself ok you can buy my
emails the greatest Emacs and Emacs
peace tutorial the greatest one on earth
no kidding oh you can buy ok let's copy
this to my website I need to you know go
go buy history ok go buy JavaScript
tutorial now this is the greatest Java
Script in-depth tutorial on earth
including or printed JavaScript
resources or online I would claim this
is sorry okay let me yeah in English
there is no better one actually I would
consider they are possibly too
javascript resource that's possibly
better depending on your preference on
terraria styie okay I coughed blood for
two three years ready in this tutorial
and you should check it out
so there are two possibly two books they
are available in pretty in online and
also printed that is possibly better or
equivalent as great as my tutorial that
covers JavaScript in depth I can talk
about them you know I can talk about
that topic for one hour but I I talked
about that before so you can buy them ok
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching
so Alan says what we what would be
better is to auto convert Chinese yes
count kana if you use kana input not
count Roman G if you use Roman chamber
yeah I hope you have doing well base
hey good morning base haven't seen you
for a while join this code base this
code we have vibrant discord and since
the bat death we have a lot people
talking about all sort of things you
know so you might join including
conspiracy theories and you know we have
great many colorful people with great
varieties variegation of personalities
we have every ran who and and from all
over the world from india every run is
from india he he is our media expert he
is the link tompa he come here in link
dump every every link he think tank dump
links and we have reaper who represents
the establishments the correct view of
things of american the the proper maker
american view
so we have you know a great number of
people and this guy Merc crap McRobert
he is a schizoid I haven't mentioned
before but let me tell you guys he is a
schizoid now in our forum we have so far
at least three ski so it's proper me for
instance and we have a gamma
unfortunately he got pissed off by me
because what's his name the gamma who
got pissed off Alan yeah so he left but
he is a schizoid okay and then we got
this merle mcquoddy
he is a schizoid popper and kind of you
actually a lot of you know Robbie so
join discord
it's a is fun okay I'm tired and have a
nice day
Nabby yes that was Navi I miss Navi I
like Navi okay now he's a great guy but
he's a ski so he just you know he's just
like he just go on and he talked he
basically talked to himself and in
elaborate detail like he's gonna tell
you why he's doing these elaborate
reasons you know talking to himself and
yeah he you know this the there's one
thing very funny about Nabby which is
not a characteristics of schizoid okay
schizoid personality me
for example we usually don't care about
what other people say praises or attack
or criticism like we are we are immune
to it you praise you say great things
about us we appreciate it
you know we schizoid that the thing
about schizoid personality is that we
are kind of like
cold you know it's like mr. data okay
you know since like code and and apathy
you know we are you know today apathy
has a bad connotation by the Malayan Gen
[ __ ] the man engine idiots they
think empathy is a bad word anyway the
skis of personality one characteristics
takes you you know just it's the nature
it's natural for us we don't have like
much emotions so so we don't you know
one of the characteristics is that we
don't care about phrases we don't care
about criticisms it doesn't you know it
doesn't affect us in in a natural way
you know it's like we are immune to it
kind of but met Nabi but you know in a
case of Nabi it's different okay he is
special in that he is very sensitive to
criticisms like you know when you are
chatting if you disagree with him and he
get he gets edge edgy and he starts to
pan you you know whiskey so it never
been nothing because it doesn't affect
us you know you say what you want that's
what you think as I say my things I
think you know that's generally true for
schizoid
but Nabi is different but an a/b as a
schizoid he he come out forth you know
he come out forthwith and he tell us why
right now I know why because he's got
he's got heart problems
you know his personal history you have
problems in you know stuff so he gets he
gets you know he you know he when he
gets into argument his blood pressure
gets high not good for him things like
that okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching hi guys
and stream yes yes let's see let's see
last minute something something in
stream
and I'm hungry I need to go