good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
today is 2021
uh december
9th
and we are going to talk about so here's
today's topic we are going to talk about
the
new line convention and complexities and
tedium of the new line convention
so yesterday i actually you know i was
writing a powershell script to generate
my emacs tutorial so you are looking at
my powershell script that generates a
emacs tutorial so you know one of the
things i want to do is that i want to
replace these multiple lines you know
here is a here doc here string syntax so
anyway i want to replace a string of
multiplied multiple lines
uh of all files in a directory and
it you know it didn't work it you know
so there's this complexity i was puzzled
you know why does it not work and i
spent
then i spent two hours you know reading
about it
eventually i find of course i find out
why it didn't work because of the
complexities of the new line convention
in the coding
industry you know lots of the
complexities so
i'm gonna tell you what all about it
today and there are many interesting uh
issues about this issue
okay so if you have a common questions
post the answer here okay
hello mo
so
yeah so let me let's begin okay so let's
go to talk show today's talk show notes
and open and close that open today's
talk show notes so let me tell you what
what is the problem okay the
okay first of all the new line
convention now you guys may not know now
the new line convention is that let's
let's go here so you can see so i
already have an article this is written
in 2010 about the new line convention so
in windows for example
on linux for example linux unix linux
mac os 10
you
you represent the new line
by
for example let me show you okay so
magnify
and turn on white space you see so those
are new lines so hold on a second let me
turn global highlight mod
so you see those uh paragraph symbol
represent there's a new line that's a
character you know that's just a
character it indicates a new line and in
unix
unix linux micro x 10 convention that
character is called line feed okay line
feed so in e-max so i'm gonna
so in my talk show i'm gonna
talk about several things you know the
technical computational issue
the conventions tips about using emacs
uh about programming language design so
today we will talk about emac beast
powershell bash pearl php
you know so usually i talk about several
things related so it's like
you know multi-discipline you know
what's what's called multi-discipline
which
which is what how things should be you
know you don't just focus on you know
computer science or whatever
multi-discipline so
so in in running into this issue there
are several very interesting things i
discovered so anyway so you see this new
line character that's a character okay
so in unix linux mac os 10 the
convention is used is to use the line
feed character what's called line feed
okay
so that's a
unicode code point
10 in decimal okay so oh ascii code
point 10 by the way ascii
and unicode
they have the same code point for ascii
characters so
it's equivalent to say unicode code
point 10
it's the same thing as ascii code point
10.
so anyway so in unix you know the new
line is represented by this character
one single character line feed however
on the
on windows you you use two characters
one of them is the carriage return
which is ascii 13
um
then
followed by line feed so you have to
have you have to use two characters two
characters to represent a new line
so these characters are so if you don't
know what they are so this is uh this is
before unicode so you have this ascii
table
common in questions okay now ascii table
so ascii table so you know when you have
a character this is a fundamentals of
computing so if you are new uh if you
are a student you need to know this
program if you are new
i mean
so
so you have so any character is
represented you know come on computers
you have to represent them eventually as
a sequence of ones and zeros you know
bits
so
so you need a convention to convert each
character to to say which character is
represented by what number so
ascii table is one of the earliest
convention
so
for example the
the character a
is decimal 65 so let me show you okay so
for example let's let's open a new uh
document okay so let's let's show you a
so i type a so you move there and in
emacs you call describe character
you know so you can see
you can see the command i called uh
describe char okay
so you call describe character and it
will show you information about the
character under the cursor so in this
case you see that's capital a latin
character capital a you can see the code
point is 65 in decimal
and then you have
octo notation and hexadecimal so you see
the character capital a is 65 in ascii
as well as in unicode okay
so that's so you need this you know uh
this this
uh encoding
system you need a standardized way so
that computers don't get confused
so that's a representation of the ac
character a and abcd and all the letters
and punctuations but you also have
what's called control characters for
example what's you know for example uh
let's show some for example tab okay so
i enter a tab something you know so you
can see that's a tab
now let's turn on the show white space
you can see that a triangle and now if i
if i call describe char you can see
it says tab and then
you have the character name character
tabulation that's the old name the new
name is just uh
anyway that's the digression okay so
anyway so this type character
that's one of the
um
so-called um printable characters so you
also have these characters for example
new line you also need to represent it
in some way so that's a print
unprintable character normally you don't
see it you see
so you have new line and you also have a
horizontal top tab new line and for
example space
some
thing here so you have a space space now
called describe char you can see it's
codepoint32
and the name character name is space so
so you need a this is called encoding
okay you need a standard
standardized way to
represent each character and also
invisible characters such as space
represent them by a number
so that's what basically what encoding
is about and one of the earliest
standards is called ascii from american
uh association of
american computing association something
like that from 1960s so ascii okay
and today of course you have unicode
now hello alan
so
encoding
you know you have the encoding standard
standardized encoding to represent um
[Music]
characters okay so let's let's post here
uh
[Music]
okay so we have uh we have a record of
what we talked about so we we just
talked about encoding okay
uh ascii table so
so back to the
new line so it turns out you know
because historical
um
complexities you know the development of
computers from
taylor type so you have you know you
know you have lots of complexities but
anyway so in unix you represent the new
line by this line feed character and in
in
on windows you represent the new line by
a carriage return character then
followed by a
line feed character okay so it's
you know it's shown here so let's look
at so let's look at the control
characters so
you can see line feed is here okay so
ascii number
ten um you know line feed
then so that's line feed
so that's a tab you know the tab you
know uh there's also vertical tab then
there's a foam feed foam feed by the way
it's interesting because in emacs you
have um
okay
so you can see
that is using emacs but anyway that's
digression so you also have carriage
return
cr usually uh you know represented by
the word cr
character number 13 then you also have
you know you also have characters for
delete
for example 127
that's a character for delete
essentially when you press the dd key
the backspace key uh your text editor so
terminal usually sends that
and you also have escape characters so
you have you know so you have one you
know this is uh history so you have kind
of lots of this
uh
to today is kind of confusing so you
have line feed you have foam feed then
you have carriage return
uh so anyway
the bottom line is that on on linux unix
today you use line feed to represent new
line at new line and on windows you use
carriage return plus line feed two
characters to represent new line and on
the mac the the mac os classic that is
before year 2002
you use
just carriage return
you know so one of the interesting thing
i learned yesterday during three hours
you know looking into this issue is that
uh in the unix was it uh plan nine
or was it infernal you know the the
operating system created by uh rob pike
and and and other people you know rob
pack is one of the traditional unix
people unix philosophy and he created
gold land golan i truly love the design
of golem
and rob pike is also known as a inventor
of the utf-8 encoding system which is
compatible with ascii
so anyway so so in the operating system
i learned yesterday was it inferno or
was it plant nine they also used
carriage return
to represent the new line
so
so here is several interesting issues so
from a programming design point of view
or protocol design point of view or if
you are creating your own operating
system which which one is the best you
know so you have the question so that's
an interesting question for those of you
interested in design
and uh
you know in in programming language
design or protocol design you know so
which one of these conventions is the
best now apparently the windows
convention using two characters is kind
of a lame because it's inefficient why
you why do you need use two characters
but there's a
there is actually so there's a
historical reason which i also learned
about uh yesterday actually
so history
historically
this you know you know before you have
computers you have teletype you have the
most code you know
so anyway so
the carriage return followed by line
feed that is that that is the convention
so
back then that is the standard
convention not until the
the operating system called motex
they screwed up with this convention
they just they they they're gonna say oh
we're gonna start new you know we're
gonna screw history
and so they created this line feed
convention for new line then
so that's motix the operating system
mortix okay
uh you
you know actually i learned this
yesterday so you know motex is uh
heavily involved with uh emacs emacs
development you know in fact i i
about 10 years ago i um
i uh exchanged email with one of this
guy who is on maltex you know who
created
a version of emacs or something
yeah i don't yeah one of the least
machine people but anyway mo you you
have more text operating system then
unix
you know it's a pun of motives unix is
created after motifs so mortix uses the
the convention of
lf you know
you know schooling history
then eunuchs followed you know
so that is the history so i mean too
many of the open source and phonetics
linux phonetics idiots you know they to
them
most of you they you will think oh
microsoft's up
you know
not that's not true okay if you want to
say who is a that created a
incompatibility incompatibility that's
motix and unix okay and which linux
followed you know then mac os x followed
because mac os x is uh you know based on
bsd kernel okay it's not exactly a linux
it's not exactly a unix
you know again the issue of what which
operating system is unix that's a very
uh
complex question
so anyway so you have these conventions
then but mac os classic you know the
operating system which is overseen by
steve jobs the great guy for design
he's got the eye for design he
you know he saw you know he saw the unix
convention he saw the microsoft
convention and he
decided
that's bad we got we're just gonna use
carriage return
this is actually the most logical
from a design point of view so if you're
gonna design a operating system from
scratch and if you don't care about
compatibility with convention or
tradition you're gonna start fresh you
want the best design carriage return is
the best
character to use okay so that's smack os
uh classic pretty much you know that
means before year 2002.
so you have these conventions you know
for carriage for new life and and that
creates end endless problems because
you're often uh
endless problems when you send the file
to someone else and if he's using a
different operating system you got
problems uh
like sometimes lines will show you know
you you'll show things like that
let me show you okay so
you'll see things like okay so let's
open a new
buffer you'll see for some thing for
example i have something
you send this file to your to your
friend or something then but they will
see it if they when they open
let me let me show you
uh
when they open their edit editor they
will see something like that or
sometimes like that okay so creates lots
of headache
and many tools for example if ftp and
many unix tools you know sometimes they
provide
or get even get let me show you git okay
uh
git
they create lots of problems so let's
see i have a i
recently this year i wrote a article
about the issue of line ending in git so
git also provide a way to
kind of automatically solve the problem
like some kind of automatic
automatic convention okay so
where is my article
yeah so
over here so get new line config for
microsoft windows so if you are on
windows if you are if you all you do is
on linux you know arc linux or gen2 or
whatever
or tiling window managers if you all you
do is on linux happy go linux you are
fine because you are confined in a hole
but if you
talk among different people then you
have you know you have this issue so
forget you know
which is by the way github owned by
microsoft you know so you you need to
convert the new line issue
for example your your team is using you
some of them is using uh unix
some of them is using windows and some
of them is using uh let's say plan nine
which uses the cr the carriage return
convention so you need to so this is how
you can set up git to uh convert things
automatically
uh
so that's so i'm so i'm talking about so
several of these things let's go to talk
show and write it down so what we talked
about so today so we have that that show
in browser turn off the line uh you know
it's confusing turn off the white space
show browser at the bottom so we added a
uh outside of it so
it needs to be inside the main
so we just talked about git on this
issue so this is you know this is a very
widespread issue and on linux on unix by
the way you have the tool
unix to dos okay
does to unix okay if you search it i
don't have an article on that
so if you search it
on linux you have this tool to convert
these file line ending conventions
okay so
now i'm not on linux so i don't have
those tools so let's see maybe
let's try that
get comment on
help
help gcm get command
so get command is
is analogous to the unix which command
so it will show you if you have the
command or not so gcm unix 2.0 i don't
have it gcm does to unix
so
so that's the tool on unix that allows
you to change the file encoding
and of course i you can you can do that
in emacs too so i have a full article on
that
uh
so anyway so so so so far i have
explained
about
the
ascii
so we have explained the ascii encoding
and unicode utf-8 encoding and what is
uh so we have explained
ut
unicode encoding
and control
characters okay
so we have explained these things so far
and we have explained
lining conventions okay
um
and so so this is quite complex issue
because
because another issue about new line is
that
typically a file you know you have the
question whether the end of a file so
you know end of a file should it
followed by a new line or not
you know
uh if you
view
the new line as a separator between
lines then you don't need a new line at
the end of file but if you regard new
line as a kind of
line termination
symbol then you need a new line
at at the end of each file and in unix
you do re you know it's usually it's
required so this introduces another
complexity because for example if i have
emacs so i i saw some of the you know
line line ending i can just replace them
but when you save the file it
automatically adds a new line of
particular convention to your file so
that creates lots of problem because you
thought you you just removed all uh you
know or
some some new line but when you save it
just silently added to the end of the
file so you have to pay attention to
that
so that's about that so and in this
article i tell you how to you how to
convert okay between the line ending
conventions in emacs
uh then i also show you a
e-max list script
that allows you to convert
all files in your directory from one one
style to another the line-in convention
so let me show you how to do that okay
so we got the new uh so we got a new
file for example let's say okay so let's
remove that
let's just say something so you wanna
know
so first of all let me tell you in emacs
when you see something in a buffer the
line ending is always
line feed okay
doesn't matter whether you are on
windows on linux or mac on any anywhere
in a buffer the line ending is always
line feed
but when you save the file emacs will
automatically automatically convert or
transform whatever and save it to a file
or a sequence of bytes okay that's what
emax does but in the in the buffer you
will always just see
i mean that so in the buffer that
character is always just a
line feed
and uh
okay so the way emacs works is that so
you can see what is the current buffer
encoding so let's let's show okay so
um so you do
so here's what you do
you can see here you see
near the mode line
it says unix
you know so that means this buffer is
currently using the unique slide ending
convention when
when emacs save this to a file okay
that's important because
otherwise emacs always use elf i mean
that
you know this configuration only matters
when you save to the file okay so right
now so so how do you control so this
indicates it shows here so how do you
know which
convention is using by this variable
buffer file encoding system okay
so
so we can now we can do describe
variable
then type
buffer
file
coding system okay enter
so it says it tells you that its value
for this buffer is utf-8 unix that means
encoded using utf-8 and use the unix
line in convention okay
so this variable buffer file encoding
system
is the variable that controls
that tells emacs when you save the file
which lining convention it should use
okay so if you want to convert this
landing um to let's say windows so right
now it's unix you can see in the mode
line so if i want to convert it you
call
you call this command
set buffer file coding system so let's
do it so after we do it you'll see this
unix disappear okay so
set buffer file coding system enter
so i can type you know if you type tab
then you have all these you know
tens of encoding systems typically you
want to you you want to say
utf-8
tab
then utf-8 let's say
dos okay
dos is the
old name for windows
so if i say enter
okay now i need to say save okay uh
actually yeah save the file xx
dos okay
let's let's do it again
and it's not okay anyway i saved it i
saved it but this part is not updated
okay so let's close this file reopen it
and
set buffer coding system
utf-8
dos
okay
uh i think this is a
e-max bug i'm not sure why you have to
do it twice but you can see now that
unix is good so save it again
you see
so that you know i don't think this is
this is a great design but because emacs
when your current encoding system is the
same as your operating systems
convention then it doesn't display
anything you can see there
so anyway that's how you change file
encoding in emacs change new line
conventions okay
and uh
okay i'm
so what uh
questions any questions hello jordan
jonathan
[Music]
hello ryan are those
are here no that's not working
screen that's a
cherry mx red this keyboard you are
looking at
uh
i'm not so mor says much more interest
interested in how people encode big data
what do you mean by that
there's no there's nothing
really there's nothing special about big
data any data you have any data
is saved as binary okay it's it's it's
when you save to file it doesn't matter
what kind of storage system it's saved
you know essentially as a bunch of
numbers binary digits okay
now um
yeah doesn't matter it's big data or
image file or text file whatever when
you store something on computer it's a
sequence of bytes
gonna compile my text files for every
operating system what i don't see what
you mean
so anyway so that's uh emax issue so
okay so let's see
what are we going to talk about next so
i'm talking so let's go to um
so i want to explain i explained we
explained what it is uh we expand ascii
control characters
we explain
sure how to insert line feed and control
characters in emacs okay the way you do
that is
so if you want to insert the line feed
okay
so
if you want to insert the carriage
return you press ctrl q
then ctrl m okay that's the carriage
return
now if you want to insert the line feed
ctrl q
ctrl j
okay
now because like i said before because
ctrl j the line feed is what emacs use
for to represent the new line so you
don't even see it so it's actually same
as when you press return so let's do it
again so let's see
so for example something so i want to
insert a
line feed in between okay
so ctrl
q
ctrl j you see it's simply just
it's like you don't see it
so if you want to so that's how you
insert
control characters in emacs
so let me show you uh let me show you
what it means
so
so if we look at ascii table again
so let's say how do you insert the bell
so there is a bell character
so you can see there's a bell character
so how do you insert that in e-max you
can do the same way so the barrel
character is represent the correct
notation is g so each of these control
characters they have several uh
notations
so you have decimal
uh code point in decimal point in
hexadecimal
and you have
then you have abbreviation for example
the
abbreviation nu for you know the code
point zero then you have the correct
notation okay so
here's the correct notation for these
control characters then you have the
unix c convention of escape mechanism
okay this is actually the
not and you know i don't think it's a
good design so but this is uh what we
are used to you know everyone knows
about
slash n
and slash r and slash t that's the most
common
so you have different notations for
these characters and and one of the
you know and unicode also came up with a
character to represent these control
characters you see those are unicodes so
for example
we can actually copy that let's see so
you see
copy this and
paste it here
let's magnify
magnify
okay so you can see each one of these is
a actually a unix character so if i put
a cursor here i call describe character
you can see emacs tell me it's this
character
point
because this is a unicode character
that represents that's a representation
for
for this new character control character
nu
but this unicode character itself is
2.9216
and you can see the name of this
character is symbol for nu
so
so that's pretty new that's a unicode uh
created a notation a character to
represent these control characters
and the correct notation uh let's see so
the correct notation is one of the
oldest
so the correct notation is
it is simply alphabetical for example
the
you know it's just abc
abcde
so that is why the line feed is j
you know you might be wondering why is
line feed j because you know it's just
alphabetical and the carriage return
happened to be m
and the tab the
vertical tab happen to be i so that's i
so i can insert a tab let's let me show
you i can insert the tab by pressing
ctrl
q
okay i'm using a very keyboard then ctrl
i is key okay so you see that's a tab
now show space you see that's a tab
so that is why that's the explanation of
this
correct notation
okay
that's the explanation of the different
notations for these control characters
and we also have the escape
syntax that's from c
you know when you inside the string you
represent these characters by this
escape mechanism
okay the string syntax is another
interesting question but let's skip it
today
okay so this is a question so vice q
says why do you say it's better to use
just carriage return rather than line
feed
well
you see carriage return
it makes the most logical sense
you know what do you like for example
what do you think if you ask a common
question
if you ask average people
carriage return
like uh carriage return versus form feed
you know carriage return is more
intuitive because that's the came from
the typewriter you return you just you
press the return key you see i mean even
correspond to the keyboard return key
uh return you know you move the cursor
from the right return to the original
position on the left you know that's a
kind of history mechanical typewriters
so you can see history of mechanical
typewriters uh
here so let's see
okay so you know you have here several
of the ancient
mechanical typewriters
and
you know back then even the return key
is not standardized
so on this one
where is the return key
uh this is what this is french or what
they have a mr but i don't see a return
but anyway pretty soon
i think very early on it's it became
standard you know look at this one the
numbers on are on the side you see in
the you know they have two space bars
you know
and this and and well another
interesting thing about this one is that
it's
orthogonal
you know you keep both mechanical
keyboard nuts this is not not staggered
you know typically you have this weird
staggering this is orthogonal okay so
this one is smith premier typewriter
from what year
so anyway let's get back to focus on the
return key so i want to show you and by
the way on this typewriter this is a
spacebar okay the the the two things on
the side that's the space spa
okay
oh yeah carriage return you know why why
why you don't see your carriage return
key because back then
you have this um this thing you like the
thing
the mechanical bar
you hold it and you push it to the left
to move the
to move the head you know the whole
that's why you know the the mechanism to
the left okay that's why you don't see a
return key
uh so you see a picture where i show
yeah here i i guess well the picture is
not too big
you see that bar okay so but but i can
show you wait i can show you one of the
um
you'll see
the carriage return bar
is emulated in this retro keyboard okay
so
here
okay
you see that bar
you see that but it does nothing on this
keyboard you know this is a emulation of
the retro style but it's just uh it's
just a modern keyboard but that bar so
why do they have that but that's a
carriage return you know you you push
that to the other way to the left
so
you know so that's the spot okay so why
is it return well you return the whole
thing the carriage that's the thing you
know the carriage return then it becomes
you know it became computers character
carriage return then it becomes a key
return key you know return to the
original position and and also another
you know let me show you another you
know so this is all
intertwined together that's history
that's how we got what we have you know
that's why
you know many things maybe it doesn't
make sense but there's a
there's a reason for that for that
you know so why is it for example why is
it called carriage return why don't you
just call it return why don't you just
call it enter
and form feed of course line feed you
know you have line feed and foam feed
they also have their own history
so
but if you are asking me which one is
more
logical i would say today you know given
if if we have to use one of these uh sim
you know this
you know ascii table which we are stuck
with because you if you invent view new
then your system is gonna
be not compatible with anything else
you know you can't use anything
so if we
given the you know given these control
characters we have to choose one for for
to represent the new line i would say
today you know this character is the
more the most intuitive carriage return
okay and and why is it called you know
so carriage you know why is it called
carriage well because you know that that
that mechanical thing is called carriage
and also let me show you a return symbol
okay
keyboard for example keyboard
keys
so here we look at keyboard keys and we
have the enter key many different
designs for the enter key many different
shapes and we have the
symbolic representation you know which
symbol to represent the
uh the return character the new line
character for example that's another
interesting question for example as we
have seen
uh
what
okay for example when in emacs i turn on
i turn on
white space mod to show the white space
you can see
i'm using personally i'm using a
paragraph sign
so
but if i want to i can also use um
okay let me show you okay so
okay that's a paragraph sign okay
that's a unicode
code point 182
uh
the name of that character is called p
cosine okay that but i can use also
okay i can also use this symbol to
represent the new line okay
so that this character is unicode
codepoint9166
and the name is
return symbol okay
but i can also use
enter okay this is another interesting
character now this unicode character the
name is called
enter key okay
the old name now they have a new name
the new name is up arrowhead between two
horizontal bars but it was called enter
key
so what is this key about so it's you
know so that's history so you have the
return key but on the numerical keypad
you have also a key called enter so
usually this represents that key
but again
you know if you look at
you know mac keyboard you know some some
of them call this key enter some of them
call it return so you know so you have
lots of these interesting things
and another thing i want to
say is that you can also use this
character for example all these
all these characters
uh
wrappers can can be used to represent
you know the enter key for example on
the mac on the mac if you look at uh max
documentation apple's documentation they
use this
hooked arrow okay so the character
of this character is called
leftwards arrow with hook
so
you see here's a
apple's documentation and you can see
the character there and they they use
this enter
symbol to represent the enter key on the
number pad okay so that's all the
interesting um
things
so
right now we are talking about how does
this relate to the control character
this is a
graphical representation of the concept
of new line so it's kind of confusing so
let me show you okay so
it's really interesting
so you see
let me let me explain so you see this
paragraph sign
so why should you use a paragraph sign
instead of the you know instead of you
know
you know which one is the best so if you
are design for example if you are
designing an editor
and you want to show white space or in a
word processing word processor so you
have the question you know which which
one of these should you use to represent
a new line
for me i actually customized my emacs
you know to show uh to use a pure cosine
but
but but this this
these two will also make sense but this
not so much because it's kind of
outlined
and also it will it also depends on what
which font you use and this one wouldn't
be appropriate because that represents a
enter
so you can see even it's almost exactly
the same thing but there's so many
different aspects you know
so let me let me write it down so let me
explain so what what's the issue here
so let's
shrink to the original font size what is
this keyboard block close
let's um shrink to original font size
showing browser
so we talked about that
we uh
yeah this is a talk show today
delete that
so we we are talking about so what are
we talking about um let me show you okay
different
aspects of
the
unprintable
characters
the unprint the unprintable characters
themselves
encoding of it okay encoding so you have
ascii you have unicode but you have also
uh eptic you know all these issues if
you just look up wikipedia you also find
it
encoding of it um
then
notation for them
okay so you have different notations for
them
as you can see
the you need the different notations for
them then you also have
repetit representation for their
concepts
such as you know this paragraph sign
this
you know return key symbols or
you know
used on keyboard
or used in a text editor
so you have these different aspects of
them so show in browser
so that's what we talked about
okay what else
you know so this
so actually so let's go back let's see
how long i've been talking
we already talked for one hour wait
okay 50 minutes
and we also talked about let's let's uh
for example let's copy that paste it
here
this is a reference representation of
the keys
and we also by the way you know we have
representation
a symbol to represent a key on the
keyboard that's what these are okay
now this is about a symbol to represent
a key label okay key label
uh which is actually pretty similar to
this okay key label issues
so by the way you you can see your helm
there that's actually an iso standard
symbol to represent the control key
that's a
that's actually a iso standard symbol to
represent the control key so you have
many uh different variations
um
then we have let's see what we talked
about then we have the shape of a
different control key okay that's a bit
unrelated uh it's just about different
shapes of the control key this one is
called fat ass enter
europeans usually the europeans like it
likes it
big ass enter key you know so the then
the japanese i think the japanese has
this one the japanese their convention
is like that
now this is the you know the horizontal
shape is american convention
okay so then we talked about uh let's
see what what else um there's actually
quite a few things i want to
say about this oh yeah this keyboard why
is it called carriage return
why is why is there a word carriage
okay then we showed several of the uh
typewriters okay
paste it here
okay
con join the
and make them older properly in the
order we talked about them
showing browser
okay we talked about all that
multimotics
motex is the one who began using line
feed as the new line
character
that's
then unix inherited from it
uh then we talked about ascii table okay
so actually so today
i think that's it actually we
there's some
we haven't started to talk about here
doc so which is the actual complexity
when writing writing a
shelf script
so the problem you know in the beginning
of the video we talked about i'm i'm
writing a powershell script you are
looking at and i want to replace a
string a multi-line string
in a bunch of files
and it turns out didn't work you know
for some it worked you know it's like a
puzzle mystery
but if i change it you know after so
many so much testing i realized if i you
know debugging like i can't figure out
what's going on it should work
everything is you know it should work
but eventually i tried to delete you
know
trial and error i realized if i replace
the multi-line string by just a single
line then it worked
then
then i realized the problem is the
problem is with the new line convention
so what's the problem so if you are
writing powers powershell so let me talk
let me tell you about the here doc
the here doc syntax okay
so what is a here doc so
so in a primary language usually you
want to you know you have a bunch of you
know you have a whole bunch of text
you know you want to represent them as a
string
and the text may contain you know double
quotes you know it may contain a double
quote character or a single chord
character so you can you can you cannot
just like quote them
because then you need to unquote eat
your currencies so that's a pen that's
painful so therefore
they you know there's this syntax called
here doc
it looks like this in php
okay so in powershell this this is a
here doc okay so i want to assign
this stream
to a variable you know this string is
like google
google
analytics you know
you're finding every website
so i want to find it you know basically
i want to remove this you know in my in
my in my files
so it's multiple lines and i so i can
just say
this variable equals to
then using this syntax that's the
powershell's syntax for here doc you
know this kind of syntax is called here
string
meaning it's it's very interesting
jargon okay it means like here it is you
know just a big uh chunk of string
so this way you don't have to put escape
like you don't have to put like
backslash quote like in e-max or in
powershell the
escape is
the tick okay so you don't have to use
this
you can just paste it in
then you can just
find replace you know for you can see
the replace line here
okay but it failed so so why why does it
fail so eventually i realized that's
because so
so it's it's fairly complex okay it if
your current file you know it depends on
what's your current file it's encoding
so if your current files newline
you know this
if this file
is using the unix line convention
and
the file you want to replace also unix
line convention
then it works okay
however
if this file the powershell file is in
let's say windows convention
then but the files you are trying to
find replace are unix convention
then it doesn't work it doesn't work
when you have a hear dark string
that's
you know
why because you know because the current
file the powershell script file
is using using the you know there's a
new line
character at the end so depending on
what
how the current file is saved you know
what line convention is using
you may have problem you know
finding that string
so that so eventually if that's that's
that's the reason
so that's an interesting question then i
started to read a bunch of powershell
you know and so there's a tool like i
said before there's a tool in unix in
in um in unix you know it's this is a
very old problem 30 years problem
there's a lot of tools to do that so in
unix you have
like we talked about in unix you have
this unix 2.3 unix shell you know tools
you can just run it on a whole bunch of
files but i was trying to find a proper
solution on windows you know now windows
powershell is
supreme so there must be a solution
there is indeed but it turns out
this
very simple issue or seeming seemingly
very simple it's actually it's not that
simple because if because as we explain
even emacs there's a lot of complexities
this seemingly simple issue
you know if you look at powershell let's
let's look at
powershell
so there's a lot of articles about it uh
on the web
uh tracing back to you know it's
changing back to 15 15 years ago you
know powershell began around 2003.
so there's a lot articles talking about
that okay
like tons of them and each each person
or each blog
they try to tell you how to do it okay
but it turns out you know because it's
when you actually look deep into the
problem it's not so simple because
there's a lot um
kind of issues you know we talked about
how editors or tools they automatically
add a line at the end of your file when
you save it
so
so that happened that happened in
powershell until a few years later they
added a new option to to prevent that
you know so
you look at all these uh things you know
also you need to pay your attention what
year they are written
because you can see this there's a lot
issues
um so there's a stack overflow
um but there is one
particular article i i want to try to
tell you this one okay so this one
this answer
is written by a powershell developer
this guy okay mk lemon okay
this
this is this article this answer is a
summary
of all previous answers on stack
overflow about
how to replace line endings in
powershell what are the issues involved
so he he tried he you know he looked at
all the solutions and he write a
unified you know state of the union
answer you know to this question
and indeed and in it he mentioned that
you know so this is written in year 2018
okay three years ago he mentioned that
on github on powershell microsoft github
you know they actually tried to have a
tool you know building powershell
script so that you don't worry about
this anymore
so
so imagine
this
issue has been around for 30 years
there's lots of tools that try to
convert it seemingly simple
and but for 15 years powershell still
don't have the solution okay
you know you can you can you can do it
but you know there's so many answers
different each one uses different
different command
you know i haven't got into that yet i'm
i
today is probably too long but i can
explain the different solutions in
powershell for example the best the best
the best explanation is this guy okay
this guy is a classic old hacker
you know you look at you know his
website is called ss64
uh
the writing style and web formatting is
not so great but however he has got the
best technical content so in this page
he provides let's turn on javascript
maybe
make it look better and it doesn't
so in this
in his website he explains the technical
detail the best solution
of using powershell to do this new line
convention so this is the best technical
content
with respect to powershell okay this guy
so he also for example he explained
the different ways of using powershell
to read the file or write to file to
write to a file for example you can see
this line
these two lines
is this is powershell but however he's
using he's calling the dotnet
function to do it
meanwhile he also explains
uh somewhere here you know here
of using the powershell command to do it
so they are both powershell but they are
using different methods so he expand a
little bit not fully about the
differences the pitfalls okay so it's a
very you know fairly complex issue
then
you know there are so many different
people you know trying to say what they
think is right then we run into this uh
powershell developer
so they are talking about so this is
2008 they are 2018
three years ago they are trying to come
up with a solution like one solution for
all in powershell but it seems you know
i haven't completely finished you know i
finished reading the whole thread
but
apparently
to this day there's no
built-in solution it's uh doesn't seems
to me so far i haven't seen it
you know so this 30 years old problem
that seems simple but today you still
don't have a solution in powershell for
after 15 years
okay and and when reading this thread
okay that's that's one topic but now the
next topic when reading this thread
yesterday i spent several hours in
detail i just i actually learned a few
things okay what i learned
that in this operating system this plan
nine or something
they are actually using the um
let's say let's search for plan
okay panda is not here let's search for
inferno
uh not here uh what's it here i'm pretty
sure it's here
but anyway in this thread i learned that
this operating uh
uh way where is it somewhere
was it plan 9 or inferno or what one of
the one of the new operating system
that use carriage return
you know the
same as the classic mac os
9 in 1990s okay
so i that's one thing i learned another
thing i learned is that
um oh the the other critical thing i
learned that solved a problem a question
i had for emacs for years
is that when when emacs for example said
buffer file coding system okay so you
can see here okay so let me show you
so you have all these encoding systems
in emacs now notice okay let's see utf
okay now note it not now look at this
okay
now notice that they combine
the encoding with the new line
convention for example if we look at
utf-8
so you have utf-8 dos that's
a windows line in convention you have
utf-8 unix
that's a unix or linux creation then you
have utf mac so they map convention
using carriage return so they combined
the concept of carriage reta you know
the line ending convention with the
encoding
concept
you know so i for
for 10 years i have the question you
know why do they combine it i think it
should be separate you know encoding
file encoding is one thing okay line
convention is another thing but it turns
out i learned yesterday from reading
this they are connected
you cannot simply have a line convention
without knowing what encoding it is
uh so so so so i read you know from
these you know their design you know
they are powershell
then i realized oh that's why that's why
emacs also combine them okay so because
they
it kind of one one has to do with the
other
so that's what i learned okay so
so i learned from this thread the
powershell team that one one of the unix
platini or something operating system
you is using the cr line commission you
can find that on wikipedia okay by the
way
so wikipedia so you can see wikipedia
has lots of details on that and then you
can look at the operating systems okay
and by the way unicode came up with a
bunch of new
like new line
character
code points that's another topic we
haven't covered
so
so now we are looking at the you know
the conventions of the operating systems
they have at least
somewhere
you know so yes all these are related
kind of issues
so a seemingly simple issue you have all
these complexities that's how up
our codings in you know our programming
industry is
but um
but right now i'm trying to find
the how different operating systems what
they use okay so
uh here's a bunch of encoding systems
here is operating system there it is
okay mo
so you see unix linux motex
amiga bos
b os they all use line feed
now
windows does
and many of the old
operating systems atari
deck
rt cpm you know some of them i don't uh
cp slash m that's very old palm os they
all use the you know what we call we
would call
windows convention carriage return on
feed
oh then here yeah so
classic mac os mago s9
mit list machine there it is mit list
machine
they all use the just carriage return
you know so that's why i think this this
is actually i would say this is the most
logical since 1990 okay
you know from modern point of view if
you want to disregard
you know the legacy
carriage return because that's what
supposed to be carriage return
so tsr-80 so these systems use carriage
return
some other weird ones they use actually
others q and x
use rs now what is is
rs
c0 and control codes okay i'm not sure
what is ix
which
po call point is ix
what
bs we need to look at the shortcut
notations let's see
oh record separator
they use the record separator for for
new line oh that's interesting
so yeah so a lot history is here
and what is this
use okay this operating system zx80 they
use you know this is sinclair you know
this is very popular computer uh in
united kingdom you know i learned about
this system
uses a
non-ascii character set to represent new
line wow that's interesting
what
what is this decimal value one one eight
wow they use an ascii character set to
represent new lines so that's that's
another thing i learned so
yeah very interesting so that's
so different operating systems uses
different um
you know many interesting things
oh this is one of my questions back in
2009 you know yeah so
in 2009 i i tried to learn powershell
okay i tried to learn powershell and one
of the problem is that i want to convert
all my bash scripts to powershell okay
you know like
i that didn't you know i didn't my my
real two power shell didn't win far so i
kind of abandoned until until this year
i learned so much powershell so
if you guys are here uh check out my
powershell tutorials the most succinct
succinct the best tutorial for
powershell okay and uh you know you can
learn the the easiest the
and actual correct
way
the most efficient tutorial
so but back in you know so back in 2009
i tried to learn powershell and one of
the first tasks is to convert all my
bash scripts to powershell and one of
the problem i encountered is the new
line problem because in bash when you
generate when you grab some file
you know it
the return the return text is you know
with the new unix line convention
but not so on windows
but i need the unix you know convention
so how do i you know so that turns out
so then then
then actually one of the unix i mean the
powershell inventor okay who is the guy
so let me show you the powershell
the powershell creator actually
commented on my blog okay so let me show
you where is that
okay so i have this old article
powershell for unix for unix people so
powershell versus smash so on in every
line i have a
bash version to do something and i show
you a powershell to do
a powershell version to do the same
thing okay
so
i had this block in 2009 on on blogger
okay on you know the googles
uh which is not good
so i have this article and the guy
jeffrey snover
who created he you know i he actually
he's a creator of powershell he
he answered like
half you know five or seven of my
questions
but however one of the questions is how
do you get you know the powershell to
behave just like the unix tools to have
the unix line ending
that was not that that question is not
solved okay he didn't answer because it
turns out you know as we can see as i
learned now
that question to this day
is not satisfactory solved in powershell
this you know it's just complexities
okay i think that's it for today and i'm
gonna read the comments and we close in
five minutes i think uh probably
nobody's watching
uh
my show wow night people
and we haven't you know there's more
issues i want to talk about i haven't we
have we haven't got into
the issue of the here dark design the
design
the design of the here dark syntax and
the art of naming
whether should it be called here dark or
not talk or hear string you know i
haven't talked about that yet okay let
me show you what about what that is
okay close that wait
reopen it
copy it close it or actually
copy this back to emacs close it
um go down here
paste it we need to have a record of
what we talked about so many things okay
powershell versus smash yes uh yeah
close that
then
okay so
zx880 okay so then different operating
systems
so one of the new one using
carriage return
is
mit this machine
okay yeah so copy that
so these operating systems
os that uses cr
like mac os
classic
you know
i was thinking you know so anyway so
that's a good to know that's great to
know that so you can see you can observe
different operating systems and their
choice you know this is for those of you
who are interested in programming
language design or protocol design or
youtube user interface design you know
i'm very much into design aspect of
things so
therefore a lot of my followers you guys
so from this you can see kind of the
design issue you know although it's kind
of a trivial issue you know uh
like it doesn't matter you know you just
use whatever the you you know if you are
a practical person just use whichever
that is the what most widely used you
know go with the
crf or go with linux you know unix well
windows is actually far more wide widely
used so go go with the crf
which
historically is came from the teletype
machine so that is actually the most
widely compatible historical one the
choice is character return line feed
okay if you are a practical person but
but if everybody
is a practical person like who should
work you know don't worry about
useless things you know get on with your
life you know follow the you know
get in line follow with the tradition
then
apple will never be invented okay apple
apple computer steve jobs he's got
an eye for design
without apple you will not have cd
player you will not have dvd player you
will not have usb
you will not have
gui
okay graphical user interface where you
can click and select and you will not
have mouse you will not have um
graphical user
interface okay now some of you might say
oh well but
you are wrong but the mouse is invented
by the
you know the mother of all inventions
you know empire am i
by like xerox and so on well that's true
but
the mat the vast majority of inventions
that we use today
that you come to know keyboard or
whatever is not because of the inventor
rather it's because of a entrepreneur
so steve jobs he
actually didn't invent
graphical user interface he didn't
invent the mouse he didn't invent
the usb he didn't invent cd on a
computer he didn't invent dvd on
computer he didn't invent the concept of
online music streaming but he's an
entrepreneur and he didn't he didn't
invent phone cell phone okay but he is
responsible for the fact that we are
using it today so who do you think too
well
the original inventor the engineers
usually are important but
it is the entrepreneur
that made things happen so
of you people you know you know it's you
that's a important thing you need to
realize
okay so don't do oh steve jobs he's just
uh nothing because he didn't invent mars
not he didn't even anything no no you
are idiot
if you think that way
okay i think that's it for today bye
guys yeah
yeah we haven't get into the design of
the here doc
the design the design of the heel dog
let me quickly show you so i'm done okay
i'm done today this is getting too long
this is getting
it's like
[Music]
12 30
it's coding getting 90 90 minutes
the design of here doc okay very
interesting so you have the php has a
syntax
like that then perl has a syntax
so
i got my perl tutorial which i
did not include the here doc
syntax in here
uh bash bash also have here docs
uh and powershell also have here docs so
powershell here docs i can show you
uh in my tutorial you can see it here
the powershell here docs so you go here
string
so this is a powershell here docs
convention
okay so um
that's it for today okay uh bye guys so
let me read the comments answer
some questions quickly
so this keyboard if you are wondering
this is called kinesis advantage too
okay
uh
why bash on windows when you can because
bash is no good on windows
well
bash versus powershell okay let me tell
you guys so powershell from pure
technical point of view you know the
language design the syntax the power the
semantics
from a pure language design
point of view powershell is a magnitude
better than bash
okay in in in terms of the syntax the
readability the speed the command the
ease the ease of use you know powershell
is like
much better than bash
bash and and there's a good reason for
that powershell is you know
bash is designed 30 years ago powershell
was designed 15 years ago
the difference in years make a huge
difference you know in general
the
the later languages you know
are better than older languages in
general generally speaking
if everything else considered equal
because you know you know you if they
differ by you know a year or five it
doesn't matter but if uh two different
languages their birth
their design year differ by more than
ten years
that has some significance okay so
first of all i want to make a point
technically speaking from a pure
technical point of view powershell is
much better than bash
okay this is
purely technical point of view
disregarding
other
factors such as open source or not or
what company or
uh or compatibility or which one is more
widely used and so on okay
now that's all so
so the second thing i want to mention is
that um we
on you know
you you want to use a xiao language that
is native for your operating system so
the best show
if you are linked on linux the best
child is bash okay bash or z z x
something similar bash c z sharp among
them
we can compare but that's a different
issue but my point here is that
when it comes to languages or shell
basically
you want to use the one that's native to
the operating system so on linux it's
bash
okay bash z shell and whatever on
windows
you want to stick with powershell okay
because therefore for many reasons
because one first of all it comes with
os every window is bundled with a
powershell for bash you have to install
it then you have to you know different
uh
versions of different from different
people you know
so anyway my point is that you want to
stick with the native
shell if you can that's the best
native to your operating system okay
now
the third thing i want to say is that
powershell is open source today the
entire.net is
open source okay that's what microsoft
is doing you know they bought you know
they bought github they you know the
entire powershell is open source
um but
so i think powershell is much better and
also it's open source and also it's um
so it's available you know powershell
you can you can install you can run it
on mac or linux in fact i have a
screenshot you can you see this is
this is powershell on mac
and here's the powershell on linux okay
you can just download and install
um
but
you know because of history you know on
linux you have you know a lot of
resistance to powershell
very strong resistance i mean
and probably most of you when you're
laughing powershell
even you you don't know like you know
you don't know nothing about it
like in general you know if you are the
4chan type of people in general when you
have opinion you know you know after if
if you after you studied powershell for
half a year
then you tell me oh i don't think
powershell is better than bash i think
bash is better then i respect your
opinion okay but but
but the opinions i hear you know all the
people
their opinion is like they don't know
nothing they never coded one line of
powershell but they're gonna tell you
look at that idiot
he's doing hard you know that's you you
are you are your idiot
so anyway i think powershell is better
and i think
um
it's also open source but the question
of
you know on linux there's a strong
resistance resistance and i don't see
the day
i don't see the day that
you know it
you'll be a long time if powershell is
ever gonna replace
bash on linux because the linux people
you know they they are not going to um
so anyway but but for personal use i
would recommend powershell
if i'm on linux you know i don't like
windows because you know it's possible
i'll
you know there's there's lots of
problems you know it's possible
by next year
you know i i'm not going to probably be
not going to you know switch to windows
11 so
sometimes in the future i'm
you know uh i'll be back on the mac or
possibly linux
so if i'm on the on mac
if i'm on the mac
i'm probably gonna
stick with either powershell or z shell
because z xiao is the max default now
why because the gnu the free software
richard storman you know they
want to push for gpr3 that's why
on the mac you know they switched away
about three years ago the mac apple the
default xiao is no longer bash it's z
why because
the gpa are three the richard storman
idiot okay
that's why so you know free software
foundation they are dying you know
nobody knows about it anymore so
but if i'm on linux maybe bash anyway
uh so that's it for the any anything
else let's see okay
so i'm just read the comments and that's
it for today okay
uh if you have a question for me i'd put
my name to it okay so
i got a haircut so you won't be seeing
me the tech and
i'm no longer the taken about boss guy
okay bye guys thank you and donate don't
forget the most important part of the
youtube
is that
you pay for the service okay so you
think i
you know you enjoyed the show either you
learned something technical or you
enjoyed us comedy entertainment
buy me a drink
whatever drink cost in your country okay
so you can see my paypal my amazon my
stuff okay
window sliding windows
usually we know diamond windows
[Music]
i use fish on linux okay that's good for
you that's a kind of a gui show oh and
that stream is full of dining window
manager users
you can try sway the exact same config
unless you are stuck with
nvidia so what are we talking sway okay
i don't know
i heard there's a new tech sway i don't
know what that is about
uh sway what so what the is sway
so
suede gpu nvidia on sway tutorial so
what the is sway
minecraft
microsoft wait
what
so anyway i don't know what what is wait
so a media on sway tutorial and
yeah let's see
okay so microsoft sway is a
a presentation program and it's part of
microsoft office
no i don't think that's what you're
talking about right or what what is sway
microsoft sway is a presentation program
and is part of microsoft phone value
okay i don't think that's the one that's
do you prefer tags or workspaces for
your
desktop i don't use text and i don't use
workspaces
like i you know you might have seen my
article i use only one
single
uh one single
desktop
no no others okay
remove them
you know i stick with one single
uh
virtual screen or whatever you call it
bye guys
oh sway the way land windows manager
okay that's that's got a long way to go
because i
i just learned that e-max
is not compatible with wayland yet
the wayland's got ways to go
okay this way is a tidying window oh my
god another tiny windows manager and
wayland compositor composite my ass
you know about 10 years ago when i was
on linux you know i heard oh there's a
fire compositor you know but then then
when you actually use it and dig deep
into it it's the lord just crap the
worst technology possible but but
every day you just hear the linux viewer
wow wow
well you know rotating cubes like like
like you can
switch your uh
you know virtual desktop with a rotating
cube that was fashionable like 15 years
ago
but you don't see it today
when you actually use linux you know
like daily you know then you dig
then i think you know i dig deep into
the technology it's crap what's crap
possible then you got on linux telling
window manager let me tell you guys okay
titling window managers on linux
you have the
how do you call the the windows um
the
you know they they are not they they you
know i have article site so many
articles i forgot where i have to search
for it the the windows uh how they call
tear okay when you drag a window you
have tear on your screen that's linux
that's the average normal typical linux
you have tears on your screen
in in one of these titling window what
manages that poison for example you know
you know let me show you okay
uh let's go to linux okay so the entire
linux tutorial then you go down those
are all about commands useful gui app
names okay not that uh then you go you
want to go to the
uh
x you know this so this is this is what
my screen looks like in 2012 that's the
year i was going to die
2012 on a puny you know
trash walmart
pc okay so i was on linux so you know so
i
dived deep into all these you know
technologies
xfc ev
you know these two are actually the best
okay lxd
and
sxfc these two are the best because
i have a puny machine no memory and so
on and these are the most lean okay and
and they you know
they they are not what's what's what's
the code the technology the buffer okay
they don't use the buffer in your in in
the screen and they what's up you know i
thought
you know then you have to get into the
details of the
uh
of the of the thing what they call but
anyway the screen buffer okay they are
the windowing system they don't use the
screen so anyway the point the the
bottom line is that
often you'll see it every week okay you
have you you'll have tear screen tail
like
oh oh
um
like part of your window that already is
already deleted but you'll see it still
there that that's linux okay the telling
windows and that happens and then
then you might think oh all these linux
cool kids they are talking about rad
poison or i3
and so you you know so i thought okay
i'm going to install you try them they
are all the same problems
the
linux people are dribbling they don't
know nothing what the what you guys are
thinking
they all have the same problem
screen
tear
okay i'm an average person you know i'm
not doing trying to do things fancy when
i did either when i deleted the window
it left a you know
shadow there the
is that that's linux
calm peace yeah confess is one of the
earliest yeah bye guys
you know screen time happens often you
know not you know when you um
when you um you know for example you
know
you know when you actually work with
linux you know
such as you know
you know when you actually do
lots of things you have problems you
then
of course it maybe it doesn't happen to
you
because you have you know what you know
you have a system
lots of memory or something each person
is different but the point the point is
that
you know i'm not trying to do anything
special esoteric and it just happened it
does happen for every day average user
you know sometimes your um
yours um so for example i can actually
tell you uh example when it happens okay
but but it's been a while i have to
think about
you know if i look at my articles
i will know okay so if i look at my
articles let's go to linux
okay so
look at this some of these articles okay
um
so this is about finding the command
name for graphical user app app you know
you need to do that you know if you are
um
very technical like me okay so let me
show so when does it happen
so these are the different image viewers
uh on linux then
you know i tried them or i tried them
all the different image viewers to
assess to judge which one is the best
design many of them are just totally
crap
totally crap
linux
you know the linux idiot they are they
are crap not you know in in in in every
way in every way
worse than windows many of them
in every way the linux
people
um
okay so i have anyway that's it that i'm
not going to um you know that's it i
made my point uh
you can decide whether it's true or not
bye guys