Good morning, guys, or good night, or
whatever. I think I'm late for 5 minutes
because a OBS software update.
Let's see
how many people watching.
Okay, so today I'm going to talk about
Emacs, the most efficient way to open
files.
So, that's the topic I'm going to talk
about. So,
again, um
you know, post your questions so that
can guide me
to
what I'm going to talk about.
Let's see.
YouTube.
Oh, yeah, electronic dance music. That's
my favorite type of music.
Stop.
Master done.
Okay, so I'm going to talk about the
most efficient way to open files. So,
let me start up the
command log.
I should have a um
alpha command log mod.
I should have a quick
key set up to turn this on. Now, this
mod is problematic. I talked about it a
few times.
In order to run this mod, you need to
run this command first, then run this
command first.
Uh then you run this command. It must be
in that order. What this does is that
it just show you all the commands you
call in Emacs. So, I'm going to leave it
there.
And maybe, you know, um
well,
let's see. So, people here yet?
Oh, hi guys. So, I'm going to talk about
most efficient ways to
um
to open files in Emacs.
Now, I'm going to
um
Yeah, most efficient ways to open files
in Emacs.
Uh what I was going to say? I forgot
what I was going to say. So, yeah, so
anyway, so you know
feel free to ask me questions, you know,
just type in the comment box. I'll see
it.
So, I wasn't prepared, you know, I mean,
I'm not this is not scripted. So, I'm
going but I know this stuff. So, I'm
just going going to tell you
what are the most
um efficient ways to open files, you
know, I'm going to give you some tips.
First of all, master Dired.
Master Dired. You know, people think,
"Oh my god, master Dired. That's the
first thing." Then, you know, it's so
boring then they stop watching.
But anyway, master Dired is actually the
the most important thing. Right?
Uh yeah, let me you know, so so all the
commands I call in Emacs is going to
show up on the left panel uh with the
keys. And by the way, I'm using a Vorak
keys, so the letters may be funny.
And also, I'm using soft light keys
mode. Um you probably know already uh
what is that already, but if you don't
know
let me just uh
that there. You can just look it up. So,
uh and okay, so I'm going to show you a
few commands. Uh not that one.
I'm going to show you some of the
commands you you should use. Uh and
actually, I'm preparing here. So, master
diet, uh, I mean this is what I'm going
to cover. Master diet, diet jump, and of
course you can use soft light keys, but
it's not related to opening files
exactly. Um,
Okay, let me
Uh, what's going on? So, uh,
So, close that. Uh,
So, you want to master diet, diet jump,
and I want to also, uh, show Oh, yeah,
bookmarks. So,
there it is. Uh, Oh, yeah, this command.
This is real command. So, I'm just going
to write it down first at top level, you
know, what I'm going to, uh,
sh- uh,
tell you. And, uh, so, I'm going to,
first of all, prepare
all the commands,
um, that I think is appropriate.
So, that
that I'm just going to put here. And,
um,
Yeah, so, basically these I'm going to
Now, this is actually my Emacs block, so
you can show in browser, and you can see
uh, here, and there's a certain order to
it. So, let's
change it to OL, and master diet is the
first thing. Diet jump is important.
Then, you want
open recent.
Uh, that's important. Open bookmark,
that's important. And when you use
bookmark bookmark, uh, you also want
this command.
Now, actually, uh, each of these items I
actually have a tutorial on my page. So,
you know, I I see people on Reddit
asking Emacs questions all the time, and
actually, if you just read my tutorial,
they are all covered.
Hi, Yihong Chen. I'm sorry I if I
pronounced your name incorrectly, but hi
Chen. Hi Mr. Splendid. That's Splendid.
I'm not Emacs user. Basically, I use
fuzzy search in project project files
most of the time. Okay.
Well, uh
that's great. But this this uh talk is
going to be about Emacs.
So, um
you know, for Emacs users. Uh but
of course, you are very welcome. You are
uh love to have you here.
Uh so, anyway, so master Okay, so
yeah, so I'm going to focus on um
the subject of opening the most
efficient ways to open files. Now, in
Emacs, whenever you find yourself like,
you know, typing a path, like what I'm
doing right now. For example, I want to
open uh some package name like dot
Emacs complete. Okay, uh that directory
alpha, that directory uh yes, then that
directory. That's no good. Stop that.
Whenever you find yourself typing the
path,
that's no good. Actually, occasionally
occasionally you still need to. But what
I suggest is that
for every
every few months, whenever you have a
project, you put all your files in
bookmark.
Okay, but let's start from the
beginning. So, first of all, dired.
Uh you know, you probably familiar with
dired. Everyone, you know, if you are a
Emacs user, you should
master dired. Because, you see, when I'm
in in Emacs, you you know, you don't
Like that's what people mean by living
in Emacs. So, once you start Emacs, you
just uh stay here. You don't you ne-
never um
exit Emacs. So, all your opening files
is done in Emacs. You don't like You
don't go to the terminal and, you know,
and maybe open some files and type the
path. No, you don't do that. Okay.
You know, once you start Emacs, you just
leave leave in Emacs.
So, so Dired Dired is, of course, MX
Dired.
You know, then you get to into Dired.
But, actually, I don't I never actually
call MX Dired.
Instead, what you do is you call this
command
it's that this command, Dired Jump. So,
basically,
you want orient oriented your workflow
towards files. So, you always deal with
files. You know, you have files, you
have bunch of files you want to open
frequently. And whenever you are in a
file, you want to go to that file's
directory, then you just um
Dired Jump. You know, like what I'm
doing. So, you see, let me close this.
Okay, let me try that again.
Dired Jump. You see the cursor is on on
this line, and this line is exactly the
file I was on.
For example, now let's go down.
For example, I
Oops.
Let's say I'm on this You know, I put
cursor here. I open that file.
Wait. So, wait.
Now, I close Dired. Okay, so I'm on this
file, and uh you know, I want to go to
Dired, which is where this file is at.
So, I just, you know, Dired Jump. And,
you know, I'm right on here.
Uh
Okay, that's
That's done. Then, let me close that.
So,
so master Dired. Now, Dired has a lot
features, of course. Let's Let's um
Let's go to my Dired tutorial. So, I use
a bookmark. Uh
Emacs Wait.
Emacs site. You know, I have a shortcut.
Well, I I'm going to show you all these.
Not right now Right now, I'm going to
use I'm using a bookmark to open my
Emacs
uh website file. So, show in browser.
That's my Emacs directory. Um
So, um
Dired. Let's go to Dired.
Uh file file topic, file manager, Dired.
You know, Dired is a old word. Uh it's
actually It stands for the Ed. Like
direct directory edit. The Ed. But But,
I just pronounce it Dired. I I'm not
sure how other people pronounce it.
But, you know, it's called the Ed
because you know
because directory in Unix systems or on
Linux is actually a file. So, you know,
it's you know, just a nerd
geek um history of, you know,
computer technology. So, that's you call
directory edit. But, it's kind of silly.
But, anyway, so
of course, on a Mac, you just call it a
folder.
Uh which is actually more intuitive
name. So, you see You see, I just
call this command um and uh
Anyway, so
go to Dired. So, let's let's Let's talk
about what does Dired do.
Uh
Let me see comments.
Five people watching. And remember, you
know, keep the comment going because
there are a lot Emacs users, you know,
some people are like towards the
beginning begin beginners. You know,
they they may not know what's the Dired,
you know, but some other people a lot
other people who are
you know, following me, they are
advanced, you know, they they actually
want you know, some
uh
advanced tips like, you know, some
tricks and stuff. So, I don't know
uh
you know,
which way to go.
So, but but in general, I tends to go
towards, you know, for the beginners.
So, because that's
a majority of people. So, anyway, you
want to master diet. Well, okay, what do
you mean by diet? So, I'm in diet
one second. Yeah, so I'm in diet and you
So, once in diet, you see all the files
listed.
And you can you know, you can you can
page page down or
uh let's see. Okay, you can Well, you
can page down or page up and go to any
file and just press enter to open it.
So, close that.
But it's got a lot of things, you know,
lots of features. For For you know, if
you are new to diet, the the first thing
you can do is once you are in diet, you
will see several
um
Let's turn auto click off. You will see
several several new menus. So, this one
is a menu.
So, it's you can see that you can copy
file, rename file,
delete file,
find file. Find file is actually just
open. It's a old name in Emacs. Like,
this is just open file. Find file, shell
shell commands,
lots of things. So, if you are a
beginner, you never used diet before.
So, when you you can you know, just
systematically
uh go through these these
um
four menus. Operate,
mark,
rejects,
immediate.
Now, you know, if if you are you know,
I've
I've been using Emacs for like 20 years
now, since 1998. So, I
you know, I don't look at the menus. I
don't even remember which one is where,
you know, cuz you are
you know, all just muscle memory. For
example, I want to copy this file to
some other directory. Let's say, okay,
let's say let's go to my
computer programming blog.
Okay.
Now, you can see that's my computing
you know, programming blog and it's
turned auto click on.
So, now I can go to diet of this
directory.
Let's let's show this window. So, I'm
I'm I can
oops.
I just clicked. You see, I have a mouse
auto click on, which is great feature.
Like I just move mouse to where I want
it.
When the mouse stops moving, it'll just
make a click. So, I don't I don't ever
have to click.
Dired plus. Okay, Dired plus is a
extension of Dired and it has more
features. For example, it will actually
color your um
um different type of files. For example,
H you know, HTML files will be in one
color. But anyway, I used Dired Dired
plus for like
um
for for a few years.
You know, a few years ago.
Around 2009 or something. I used it for
like two or three years, but I stopped
because I find myself, you know, I don't
actually need those extra features.
Um but
but hold on a second. Let me let me show
you a copy. So, in this is Dired. You
can see there are two different
directories. So, this is
sardi info, you know, com. This is Emacs
or Emacs. So, suppose I want to copy
um
uh let's say
uh s Emacs. I want to copy this file
over to this directory. Uh actually um
let's copy. Okay, let's copy this this
uh let me do that. This this this this.
Okay, hold on.
Let me show the Yeah, I want to keep the
this panel showing so you can see what
command I'm coding. So, uh let's let's
redo. So, suppose I want to copy these
files over to the other directory below.
So, I just press
capital C.
And uh you know, then if I press enter
now, it'll just all all be copied over.
So, let's do it.
It's done. So, now I move the cursor to
this panel. You can see you can see
those files are here.
You know, now if I refresh uh you
actually sorted. So, uh let's say search
e-list. You see they are here.
Uh 1 2 3 4. You know, so you can cut
copy a bunch of files to another
directory. You can delete them. Right
now, for example, I want to delete them
cuz, you know, I don't actually I don't
want these files here. So, I just select
them.
Uh I mark them as D for delete. Then I
just press X. Now, look on the left.
Now, look look at on the left on this
panel. You can see my operation my
operation. So, I press X.
Then you'll ask me, you know, it's going
it's doing a prompt to
asking me to delete four files. Yes or
no. So, space for yes, and they are
gone.
So, you see once you um
are familiar with Emacs, you know, you
can um then it's all muscle memory. Like
I don't, you know, it's instantaneous.
On the other hand, you know, it it it it
beats, you know, terminal commands by
far. Like, you know, um
um
it's all like visual and interactive.
So, because, you know, I started to use
Emacs in 1998. That was on Unix on
Solaris uh Solaris basically uh the
Solaris operating system from Sun
Microsystems. You know, of course, they
are dead, you know, that was you know,
things move on. Corporations come and
go.
But, anyway, so um um you know, since
since I started to use uh Emacs dired,
you know, you basically you basically
never
like never go back to the terminal to
make the whatever like make the
whatever. For example, um oops.
For example, if I want to make a
directory, this
Okay, let's close that.
Close that. Um
Close my computer programming blog back
to the Emacs blog. So, now I uh let me
show that panel again. So, now I jump to
dired dired dired jump. And uh oh, I I
want to make a directory. So, what I do
is uh to is just press the plus sign.
Now, look on the left panel.
I press plus sign.
And Emacs asked me, you know, what
directory I want to create. So, let's
say TET. You know,
you know, there it is, a new directory.
Then, I press enter.
There it is. Now, I split the pane.
Uh
go to the directory the parent
directory. Now, I can, for example, move
down. Let's say copy these files over.
Let's say I want to move them not copy.
So, I press I just press uh look at
Again, look at the left panel for the
command. So, I press capital R.
It asked me, do I want to move? Yes. So,
I just press enter. Yes, you see the the
files are moved over.
Now, I just move them back. Move them
back. Yes. Okay, it's done, you know, so
it's so great.
And now I don't need, you know, the ttt
directory is just the example, you know.
Now, I want delete it.
Uh then it's gone. So, close that. We we
back to the um
the my Emacs blog. Now, let's view in
browser
and let's go to practical Emacs. Now,
let's see dired. I have I used to have a
um tutorial for dired plus. Let's see if
it's still there. I'm not sure it's
still there.
Uh I might, you know, it's possible that
I deleted because
uh file manager customization
Okay, I I maybe it's not linked. So,
let's try to find it. Uh let's try to
find it. So, dired jump then uh uh
list matching lines. So, show all all
files whose name contain dired.
There it is. You see, dired plus.
You see, it's right here.
So, let's open that.
Open it. Show in browser.
So, that's dired plus. Let's magnify.
So, um you know, I was using it. So,
yeah, it's like 2010 to to 2012.
Um
So, it's got many features, but
eventually I I it's like um I don't
really need it, so I don't use it. Uh
let's let's go back. So,
Yeah, so uh you know, so yeah, so you
want to uh master dired, which is, you
know, really helpful. So, now, okay.
Master diet and diet jump, I already
showed you that command many times, uh
how useful it is. So, basically,
uh basically, never um
never actually
need to do
MX diet.
Just
orient orient your
workflow
by files. Then, on a file, just
use diet
jump to go
to the duh
Okay, that that's the, you know, and
also diet jump has a quick key. For me,
it's just uh uh
space M. It It says delete because I'm
using a fancy keyboard. Why don't I just
show you
here.
You see, I'm using a fancy keyboard and
this is space key.
And and this
uh this is backspace. So, when you see
delete, that at that's actually space. I
mean
Well, it's getting complicated, but
anyway,
the the the point is that my delete key
is just my thumb under my thumb. So,
it's really easy, you know.
Like, press two keys and I'm in diet.
Close it.
Press two keys, I'm in diet. Close it.
Actually, I I also press one single key
to close the file.
It shows uh it shows meta W, but that's
because I'm using a macro. But anyway,
so so, use diet jump. Um
Okay, and okay, I'm going to show you
uh an a
I'm going to show you
um how to use uh open recent
files, recently opened files. So, for
me, look uh
remember look at the left left panel.
So,
I press uh three keys, you know, space c
h, and I have a list of files here.
Uh oops, I just clicked. So, stop that.
Let's try again.
Press the key, and I'm in this panel.
This is recent
uh this is a mod. It's uh in Emacs it's
called uh open you know, uh recent f
that recent f, you know, that's just the
command name. It basically what what it
does is it shows you a list of recently
opened files. And you just then you can
just press a number key, it'll go to the
file. Oops, I just clicked by by
mistake. Uh hold on.
Um personal, let's go back to Emacs
blog.
So, there. Okay, so it's you know,
so there I am. You see the personal
notes I opened by mistake. Now it is on
top because the uh oops, I I clicked it
again. You know, I have a
yeah, I have a mouse auto click, so
that's why. So,
so anyway, so um you can just press a
number now. It just like if I press
number three,
uh look at the left panel. Now I'm going
to press number three.
Three. Uh uh uh wait, what happens?
Oh, yeah, because I'm using soft light
keys, it overrides. But now now look
again. If I'm going to press three,
you see now it opens.
Uh so, recent open files is uh so
extremely useful because um you know,
because almost like what once you have
the files you want open, usually you
just want to switch between them. Of
course, you can always use switch
buffer, you know, um you know, um
I I I switch buffer command.
But anyway, so recent open files is very
useful.
That get rid of,
you know, half of the time where you
need to open a file by typing the path,
you know, never never almost almost
never like you almost never need to
actually type a file path.
So, let's see.
So, again, you know, if you have
questions, you know, just ask.
So, yeah, use
use recent, okay, that's
very helpful.
Let's see if I have So,
on my Emacs tutorial,
I cover
many of these, but not
Yeah, almost Yeah, so, if you actually
read my, you know, my Emacs tutorial,
you will see actually I cover almost all
of them in detail. So,
So, you that's that's
you can do that. Now, bookmark Emacs has
a feature called bookmark. So, what it
does is like a browser's bookmark. For
example, let me open my bookmark.
Okay, you can see my
my key is just the space CC, you know,
it lists all the files I want to use
often. So, you know, for example, I
closed my Emacs blog.
Now, I want to open my Emacs blog. So, I
could just um
open bookmark and search for Emacs blog.
So, actually this is not a good way.
But, anyway,
let me let me tell you So, anyway, so,
first of all, remember use bookmarks,
okay? Now, um
Okay, here is how I actually open my
Emacs blog. I press this key EB
and there it is. Okay, I don't actually,
you know,
look at my list of
you know, bookmarks. But I'm going to
cover that. I'm going to going to show
you how
how that is done. That is actually the
next command.
Okay, but before we go there let me go
back to the tutorial. So, you want to
open recent files. Um
I I show you how to set it up. You know,
you want to um
have this in your init, so it's on.
And remember
you want to give it a fast key, a quick
key, um such as F F7. Oh, you know, it
depends on your keyboard, you know. So,
but anyway, pick a very easy key for
you, so you can, you know
you can list the recent
recently open the files uh very fast.
So, let's go to
uh so, bookmark is covered here. Now
uh for bookmark, uh
you know, how
I got a list, but if you try it, you
know, you are going to have a empty list
because, of course, because you didn't
add any bookmarks. So, you need to add
the bookmarks. So, all these commands
are shown here, bookmark uh set.
That's how you add a bookmark and list
bookmark and and so on. And you can
remove bookmarks, so you know, so
manage, you know, how to manage the
bookmarks.
So, anyway, let's let's go on.
Uh open recent files, open okay, um
open file fast. Okay, so let's cover
that one.
So, what does that mean? Okay, so
remember the bookmarks, so let me show
you.
So, I press the key and I see a bunch of
book bookmarks. You know, I have like
okay, 70 book 100 over 100 bookmarks.
Once you open a bookmark, it's it's
painful to you know, then you have to
search
uh for example, search Emacs which you
know, which file I want. You know, you
you you find the file you want.
Uh for example, this one goes to my
Emacs in it.
I press enter, then this is my Oh,
actually that's my old Emacs in it. You
know, so that's how you open file in
bookmark.
But it's painful, you know, first of
all, you open a bookmark list, then you
have to you know, navigate to the files
you want.
Uh for example, Linux site.
Um you know, then then you are there. So
it's it's painful. It's lots of steps.
So there's a convenient way, you know,
wouldn't be great
you know, if you want to open some file
in your bookmark without you know, first
showing a bookmark list, but instead you
just type some key
you'll actually rejects match the files
you want.
You know, wouldn't that be great? So
that is this command cuz I'll open file
fast. So So now look at the left panel.
I'm going to call that. So
let's say I want to go to my
um
uh my music blog, for example. So I'm
going to call this command by a key, you
see?
Look at the left panel. It says cuz I'll
open file fast. You see it it prompts me
here.
You know,
you know, I can start to type.
So what are these files? All these files
are actually all uh over them are from
my bookmark.
So I now I just type music, you know,
there there it is, music blog.
Enter.
That that is a file I want. Show in
browser.
You know, that's my music blog. I just
blog some, you know, music, dance music,
whatever music.
So So So there is this uh open file
fast. Now that that uh let's go to work
for you.
So yeah, so So this solves the problem
of
uh hold on a second.
This solves the problem of having to
Now
let's say I want to open that. Now look
at the left panel. Look at the command
I'm going to call.
So I do I call the command open file
fast, then just type CSS. You see it it
Look at the bottom prompt. It you know,
it it said that's the file I want. I
just press enter.
Then that's the file I want. Then if I
view in browser, you know, this is the
file.
Uh so close it, go back to Emacs, close
it.
Okay, so that that's that is this
command. Very useful.
Uh just just uh grab the command and put
in your Emacs in it. And also remember
always remember to give it a easy key.
Basically
you want to uh the
the command you use most frequently, you
want to give them the most easy keys.
Exactly which key to give them depends
on your keyboard actually, you know, uh
because different keyboard have
the easy keys are different.
So any any questions?
We are almost done.
Uh I mean, this is going to this is
pretty short today, so
how long have we been going?
Uh
let's see. According 30 minutes. Yeah,
that's not bad.
Okay, so what else?
Um
Okay, I think actually we are done. I
mean, uh
these are the tips I want to um
give.
Um yeah, and basically all of these uh
you do not need external packages. Now,
I know many of you use external package
packages uh such as Helm,
you know, h e l m Helm, and some others,
but
I mean, that's good. I mean, if you like
them,
it works for you, it's great.
Uh but
for me, you know, these these are
sufficient. Uh you can, you know, any on
any project, I mean, if you are using a
Git, uh for example, I'm using Git, you
know, I go to book uh
yeah, hold on a sec. So, I go to the
diet.
Uh you can see I'm using Git.
So, you know, all these files, you know,
they are like a few thousand files. Uh
you know, uh
So, 700 in this directory, uh
and and this direct tree has
1,000 files and another thousand files
here.
Uh
so, you know, there are several thousand
files, and but I can, you know, for any
file I want to open fast, I just put
them in bookmark.
Uh for example, let's go to Emacs menu.
Let's give one more example. Let's go to
Emacs menu, E list menu.
So, let's see uh windows and frames.
Let's open that file.
Showing browser.
So, this is this is a manual uh Emacs
list manual about windows and frames.
And suppose I need to open this file
often. So, what I do, I just uh look
look at the left panel again. So, I
believe my key is this.
There it is. Set bookmark. So, I give it
a name. Let's say Let's just say t d t
t, okay?
Enter. Okay, now it's set
in my bookmark. Now, I close it. Close
it. Close. I don't need that. Close.
Okay, I'm back to my Emacs blog. Now, I
Let's say I want to open that file
again.
All I have to do is
Cuz I open file fast. Oh, it's right
there, t d t t.
I I don't know why it's why it is on
top, but anyway, it's already on top. I
just press enter, then it, you know,
there it is.
So, that's how useful is bookmark
uh bookmark. So, close that. So, let me
show you a example of deleting that file
in bookmark. So, I open the bookmark
again. Search t d t t. I'm there.
Delete it.
Yes. Gone.
Uh
you know, close bookmark there. So,
that's um
So, I think that's it for I guess that's
it for today. Um
Wait, is my Is my screen fuzzy?
Because I, you know, I just upgraded the
uh
OBS. Maybe I have some setup not
correct.
Guys, talk.
So, in Anyway, no, okay, great. Thank
you. Thank you, James Hacking Hasking.
So, any any anything else? I think
that's it for today. I mean, did I miss
anything?
Uh is anything about opening files in
Emacs
that you might have a question?
Just let me know. So,
I mean, if yeah, then you know, so this
is um
questions and
uh answers session.
So, what do you think? Let me know, you
know, what do you think? Do you think
this is a thing Okay, there's one more
thing I want to show you. One more one
last thing.
Um
Now, in browser, for example,
you see, in browser, you have many tabs,
right? Let Let's switch tab. Switch to
another tab.
Now, suppose I close this tab, okay? I
close it.
Oops, I did that I did that by mistake.
You know, you want to reopen it. How do
you do that? In browser, you can do that
by
control shift T.
Oh, on the Mac, it's command shift T.
There it is. So, you see, when you close
the file by mistake, a a tab by mistake,
you can reopen that tab by you know,
usually control shift T or command shift
T on the Mac.
But, in Emacs, if I close this file, now
look.
Look Look at the
the command I call on on the left.
Now, if I close my Emacs blog,
now if I close it, oops,
I made a mistake. I want to reopen it.
And oh my god, I forgot what's the path.
I mean, what what file I I just closed
exactly, I forgot. You know, I don't
remember which I you know, I don't know
if it's a file in my bookmark, or maybe
it's a file a friend just sent it to me,
so it's definitely not in my bookmark.
Uh
but maybe it's in the uh
you know, uh recently opened.
But, suppose I opened that file last
week. You know, then it's not in the
recently opened file, you know.
You know, so So, I closed it by mistake.
How do you get it back? Now, look,
here's the magic. I press one key
and it's back. And so, what is that
command? That is this one. So, open last
closed.
Now, in order to So, you can do that,
too. But,
uh you need to put the function in your
Emacs
uh in it. So, that uh function is it
it's Let's look at the function.
So, this is a function and this is
defined here.
But, I have a web page here uh showing
this command. So, let's open that
and look in browser.
Uh open last closed file.
So,
if you want this feature in Emacs, you
need to put uh you need to put these two
um
Okay, you need to actu- actually put
these three functions
uh you know, three functions in your
Emacs in it.
Uh why? Because
because in order to open
um the files you closed, you need to
record. Every time you close the file,
you need to record it.
So, that is why uh you know, you have
like several of functions I need to
define in order to do that.
So, but it's extremely useful. For
example, let me show you.
So, I'm going to close this file, close
this file, close, close, close, close.
Okay, I closed like a bunch of files. I
don't remember what they are. Now, I can
like revert them, reopen them like
reopen, reopen, reopen, reopen. You see,
this or
you know, it's extremely useful.
Okay, thank you guys for coming by and
if there's no more questions, that's it.
Thank you.
How do you pronounce DeYoung? DeYoung or
Deion?
Richard
DeYoung or Deion? And thank you
informatic. You guys came before and
James asking.
And
thanks Jan for coming by today.
How hard would it be to extend your
function to reopen group files?
Uh
Okay, so you want to reopen a group
file. You can. I mean, you can, but
but I think the question is how do you I
mean
You know, you can you can easily create
a command that reopen the last five, for
example, or last 10. But if you want to
be selective, then it would be
difficult. You know, basically, how this
command work is that um
it keeps a list of files you just closed
and uh set the maximum to 40. You see?
You know, you can set to 50 or 100 if
you want.
So,
um
you know, so I mean, you can you can
modify it and create a command that
takes an argument. You know, you know,
if you say five, you know, then you will
reopen the last five uh closed file. But
it's easier if you just press a key, you
know, five times, you know.
So.
Uh starting files with a certain path,
that certainly that can be be easily
done as well. Uh yeah, that yeah, I
think that's can be easily done because
all you
all you actually are doing is a
here. Look at this. This is a variable.
So recently closed buffer is just a list
of file file paths. So you can have a
command that read reads this list and
filter out, you know, by regular
expression all the files you want. Then
you just, you know, open them, find file
and just open them. So
So thank you guys for watching.
So I mean today is going to this is a
kind of technical and focused
talk. I hope to see you guys again.
Um
Thanks.
Bye.