good morning welcome to another episode
of saw talk show today is June 13th 2019
3 o clock
20 minutes p.m. California time now let
me switch my audio device because it was
not set up correctly so I'll go silent
for a minute I'm back the OBS just
crashed I'm back the OBS just crashed
I'm back no BS just crashed let's see if
that's working ok finally it's working
now the Mac version of OBS crashes often
when you change the settings I'm not
sure why but so we got one person
watching good morning so let me know
type your comments or opinions and let
me know what topics to talk about I just
woke up today I well I woke up this
morning and I just slept for two hours
and as you know I don't have a schedule
my schedule I don't have a regular
schedule my sleeping time is like around
the clock this has been true for 20 plus
years so today's topic is going to be
okay so let's see there are three
possible topics talk about some topic
okay one thing we can do is that we're
gonna talk about some of the topics
listed here I mean this list is getting
long
you know I whenever I thought of
something I paste it here but now this
list is pretty long
maybe we should clear it up and okay and
so that's you know pick a topic here and
we'll do that so the other option is
Emacs mealtime modify command log to
show query to show qualities so let me
show you what that is about
so let me shrink this window so you can
see my window
and let me call a command so this is
Emacs so let's cook saw so actually
let's go through the mod okay no not
that [ __ ] mistake
let's go - let's open the file dot Emacs
ALPA ok let's just go to Don Emacs then
go to ALPA yes that's right
so log there is oh wait I deleted that
yesterday by mistake okay I need to
install command log mod so let's do that
list packages so this is becoming a
Emacs demo these packages so we see all
the packages actually wait command lock
Marty is not here actually it is in
let's see saw start command block that's
right and let's do describe function go
to the definition of the command it's
right over there and lets us show that
in this window so this is the command
I'll call to start the command log mod
why do I write a command to start it
because the mod is the way to start the
mod is complicated and not intuitive let
me show you the source code command log
mod describe function command log mod ok
no mattress its weight let's go to my
Emacs init directory let's search for it
log so I think it is there so why does
it say
let's try it again Amex command log mod
it's not a valid command command name oh
because I haven't loaded it of course
okay let's let's start command log mod
in sauce start command log mod ok now it
started so now every commands I call
every key press I press you will see the
command code on the Left window that is
the purpose of command log mod you know
it shows all the Emacs commands you call
so it's useful when you do a demo so
other people can see the commands and
you know find it find it and use it now
there there is several problems with
this mod so let's look at that that is
why I have a wrapper to you know my own
command rock wrapper to start a mod let
me explain what is the problem so let's
go to the files the source code so this
is the command out mod its 370 lines
about 300 lines so here's the
instruction to begin it actually I wrote
a little instruction here first u MX
command log mod to start a mod then they
are if you want the commands to show up
doesn't matter what buffer you are in
then you want to start global so then
you have to call MX global command log
mod ok you cannot call this command
directly without calling command log mod
first so this is a little bit complexity
you have to Co always you have to always
begin with command log mod then MX
global command
now then now then you need to show the
buffer that shows the commands so you
need to call MX CL m / open command log
buffer then you will show this buffer
the window on the left you see you see
how that is a problem there are several
problems here first of all we mentioned
that you cannot go global command log
mode first without calling command not
mod that's not intuitive because you you
know that by the name definition but by
the name you thought you know global
command much should do it but not really
you get errors you know because if if
this is your first time then you get you
know mysterious errors and then you you
know take an hour or something to find
out what's going on then you have to
code this command to show the command
log mod buffer and notice this command
is got CRM prefix so the full name CRM
slash open command mod log buffer let's
just inconsistent inconsistent and too
complex and you know like what what what
the [ __ ] is CRM okay so so far we have
two problems
calling global command nachtmahr doesn't
work and the show buffer command log mod
the show buffered command is complicated
it's got this CLM cope and command log
mod but you know it's a it's it's bad
because it's a real problem it's not
just a theoretical problem because this
command know people may think this is
this came from another package the
command names are not consistent that's
two problems but that's not not that
that's not all
this buffer this this buffer that shows
the command log is not a normal profit
you cannot switch to it for example I go
to highly stuff not that at least what
hey what yeah at least with her and it
shows all my buffers here and but you do
not see above a named command blog so if
I search command log you know it's not
there so that is another problem it's
not a normal buffer
you cannot just close it and switch to
it so it's some kind of hidden buffer or
something like that so you know not
several problems with this package so
you know five years ago I tried to write
it from scratch but I wasn't successful
after you know I've after 20 minutes
there is some issue but it's not a big
issue I can you know walk through but I
didn't finish since there's already this
one that works kind of me works yeah it
does so you know I want to rewrite this
package I mean but it takes time you
know it would take a few hours three
hours something like that so by the way
this package is written by this guy
photo oak I think I'm thinking if if
that is the photog guy let's check
lambda dot folder that Holger so
apparently this is his home homepage and
this is this guy Michael Weber Silicon
Valley California so for the pursues the
proliferation of functional programming
industry and teaching oh I think that's
the looks like that's the for dog guy
now if you don't know what is a for doc
let me show you
f o our D or C it it is a
something-something dictionary of
computing their computing diction
dictionary now this dictionary is
ancient this dictionary this is a great
resource this one and the jargon file
and before Wikipedia
you know B pedia began in 2003 or
something like that and when Wikipedia
began basically it copied hotel every
everything in for dog and everything in
jargon file you know because these are
open source I I think they are there's a
there's a license somewhere Denise how
we copywriting is how we okay so for dog
is created by Denise how we write yeah
so it's you know open open license new
free documentation license yeah sorry in
the beginning Wikipedia copied
everything of for doc and the jargon
file but so anyway so this is before
Wikipedia and it's very useful this for
doc dictionary covers functional
programming in particular so you know
before this Wikipedia remember this is
before 2003
so before Wikipedia so when you want to
know about
functional programming you know Haskell
was not popular yet you know but you
read here for Doc here it has you know
entry for a scowl for you know lazy pure
functional what does it mean what does
curry mean functional programming
algebraic data types Pat imagine you
know all these functional programming
goodies you learn about from for doc
especially for doc now they are also you
know the jargon file also covers some of
the functional programming stuff but not
much mostly it's for dog so let's see if
it says something about Java let's say
check it does have okay so when you read
for dog you know it's like you are
reading history though you can see when
you read you know just type some
articles let's say if it has entries for
memory
okay memory these days usually used
synonymously with random access memory
or read-only memory but in a general
sense it can be any device that can hold
data in machine readable format yeah
okay so this is last updated 1986 then
you have memoization now if you don't
know what what is memorization that
means when a function when you call a
function given some number you know as
argument it returns a value sometimes
it's expensive to call the function
meaning that the function will take a
long time to compute but once you get
the answer sometimes you need to call
the function again with that particular
argument but every time you do the
function start to compute it again you
know you know make takes a long time so
so memoization is a trick such that
every time a function is called with a
particular argument once it's called
the result is saved so next time you
call the function again with the same
argument the result comes up immediately
so it saves computing time that is what
memoization is for and memoization came
from primarily functional programming
languages background because the in
functional programming because in
functional programming you deal with
functions
you know because otherwise you know if
not functional programming usually you
just saved resulting a global variable
you know in Java and all those languages
anyway so ok so it can also be called
minimal function I didn't know that so
anyway for dogs so I was saying you know
when you read for that you can get a
sense of kind of you can get you know
that you look at the writing style the
attitude that you know things between
the lines you can get things you know of
the 1990s the jargon file by the way the
jargon file which is today also known as
hackers dictionary it is now maintained
by eric raymond you know es are the guy
who wrote cathedral and bazaar not a
very good guy
so the jargon file but jargon file was
began in MIT you know among the hackers
so-called hackers the classic hackers of
richard stallman
generation at MIT and ma a.m. MIT and
stan stanford Lisp communities mostly so
the the jargon file is even before the
UNIX stuff you know before the Unix
operating system so you can see the
Wikipedia entry he says the German fire
is a grocery and usage dictionary of
slang used by computer programmers the
original job on fire was a collection of
terms from technical cultures such as
the MIT AI lab the Stanford AI lab and
others of the ODE
a Pinet AI this PPT the pdp-10
communities including both Beranek and
Newman carnage Marin huge University and
Worchester Polytechnic Institute it was
published in paperback form in 1983 as
the hackers dictionary edited by guy
Steele revised in 1991 as the new
hackers dictionary edited by Eric s
Raymond the third edition published in
1996 so you know back in the 1990s the
jargon file I read basically the
entirety of it the entire thing to be
safe maybe let's say is 70% you know
just to be sure I'm not exaggerating I'm
pretty sure you know I'd read the whole
thing morning
seven seventy percent he's not wrong say
so anyway the jargon file but I did not
realize until later
you know why the time I read it it's
from Eric s Raymond it's online it's you
know it's from his website I didn't know
the history of it and but and but until
later in 2000 I learned you know a lot
that so the jargon file is is among a
beginning Lisp communities you know MIT
and Stanford these communities and it
turns out when Eric Raymond when he took
over
he you know he is a questionable guy
morally questionable he so he edited it
and to his liking you know to it so it
becomes the UNIX the UNIX oriented
jargon file you know if in favor of the
UNIX Fox so I didn't know that and and
and I'd learned later about that so
that's the jargon file and by the way I
you can also you can get the whole thing
you know there's a download you can get
the early version you know you can get
the latest version before the Eric s
Raymond you know took over so actually I
have a copy on my website some computer
blog so you can see this is my
programming blog such for jargon I
recently had added it so it's such for
so there it is jargon so this showing
browser here jargon so Unicode so I have
this entry made in May 22nd you can see
Unicode code bug in the original joggin
file so the Unicode this is interesting
in Unicode so Unicode has this character
it looks like a caterpillar but the
character name is named bug okay so you
can see here here is the character you
know it's named the bug Unicode code
this is a character named bug but uh
however in every browser and Mac OS or
link or Microsoft Windows it shows us a
warm kind of caterpillar or a warm so
that so that is the citizen seems right
you know and but so so so that's one
interesting thing now the other
interesting things is of the word bug as
you know in programming we Berk means a
defect or you know something is wrong
and there is always interesting how the
item about the etymology of that jargon
bug how did the word book became came to
be known as some kind of a defect and in
jargon file is so basically nobody knows
actually but in jargon fathers entry so
this is a jargon file
this is jargon file 1983 edited by guy
Steele good morning FMS so in Japan
Ferrari says spoke now a mistake or
problem possibly simple possibly very
deep and unwanted and unintended
property characteristic or behavior
example there is a bug in the editor it
writes things out backward ok another
example the system crashed because of a
hardware bug ok so that's you know and
there's more to the inner entry but then
but what we are interested is the
history the etymology how did the work
would become you know to mean bug
it says here somewhere ok here it says
son say this term came from telephone
company usage example bugs in a
telephone cable were blamed for noisy
lines however computer scientist Grace
Hopper has repeatedly being heard to
claim that a usage of the term in
computer science comes from a story
concerning actual bugs found wedged in
an earlier in an early manufacture named
in on in an early more functioning
computer in any case in hackers land
what almost never refers to insects
here is a possible conversation that
never actually happened this ant farm
has a bug what do you mean there aren't
even any ants in it that's the bug ok so
they say you know they you know so even
the Geoghan fire back in 1983 do not
know how the book came came to mean
defect
however the Grace Hopper says you know
Grace Hopper turns out she is a you know
one of the early computer programmer
like today the Feynman feminists you
know tries to mention her all the time
so anyway she so she claims appears that
she repeatedly has been claiming that
the the bug it you know came to mean
defect because in a computer actually
they found a bug actual actual insect
that caused the malfunction so yeah that
is the etymology of the bug by the way
so etymology and jargons they are
interesting they are part of you know
does you know properly they are study of
linguistics you know if you dig you if
you are interested in these kind of
things what history and their common use
jargons where they came from the change
the evolution of their meaning so if you
are interested in this kind of thing
studying these kind of things that is
but you know you are studying
linguistics particular field of
linguistics and so here we are talking
about etymology I mean the history of a
word or jargon but now it's also
interesting because now do you remember
Google Google's repository good you know
before github became popular and wipe
out everything else
several other websites you know source
code repositories and one of them is
called Google code
now this is around 2009 so let's go to
Google code now we have been digressing
but since we don't have a topic so let's
just you know have go-with-the-flow
Google code okay
now you might have you might remember
google code which is a repository for
four code but they they shut it down in
2016 you know so it's from 2006 to 2016
you know Google is Google is known for
shutting down their stuff you know
opening and shutting down stuff so here
so Google code now they have archives so
Google code was a code repository for
ten years now in Google code it's you
know it just it works just like a github
okay
except you know back then you also you
know get is not the only thing you also
support CVS mercury SVN you know
different code reversion and code
version in sis systems so I was using
google code for like seven years for the
Ergo Emacs project in fact I think you
can still find it Google code ergo Emacs
ago Emacs was a Emacs distribution just
like today's space Mac's you download a
binary it contains everything you don't
have to worry about so ergo Emacs let's
see if I can find there it is Google
code archive ago Emacs so this is what
my you know my project looks like back
then yeah so ago Emacs eventually we
shut it down well I should it yeah we we
shut it down it's mostly me
and one other guy David Capello okay he
so we you know he was here sometimes
he's a great guy
David Capello he's on Twitter and he so
we shut it down because you know when
you run this project you got questions
every day but you you work on it every
day but no money
you know that's open so saying people
ask you questions bug you all the time
so ergo Emacs but eventually so we
should lay down eventually it you know
the Ergo Emacs contains the main thing
about herbal Emacs is the ago Emacs mod
a package that's the main major package
because that's that is the key binding
system for Emacs it it has very
efficient key binding system so ago
Emacs died but we but the other Emacs
smart lives on you know that mod is
still being maintained but you know the
I passed on that mod to you know Matt is
another guy on github you can you know
you can just go to github ago Emacs so
he has been the leader of ago Emacs mod
for the past seven years also you know
and also he we wrote you know not just a
maintainer he we basically essentially
we wrote the whole thing almost so he's
maintaining that you know then while I
you know I went on to I went on to do
the stuff I keys so that's Ocoee max now
why I mentioned why why are we talking
about Google code because in Google code
you find this interesting because when
you go to issues that you see they don't
call the issues bugs like normally
everywhere you know in every book
database or repository or stuff you know
programmers they just go
books you know bug ID bug bug you know
we are so used to that but in in Google
Code they don't they do not you know
they do not call it bug you know the
proper word is issue
you see issues it's let's look at some
of them let's say 145 logo Emacs issue
number 145 you know so this is
interesting because this is about
linguistics you know it's about word
usage and you can and and also you can
see kind of attitude you know the Google
people for some reason you know you
don't know who decided you know is it
just one guy who design the site and he
says you know she you know says that we
we must take you know we must use the
word issues instead of bugs you know is
it one guy or was it the team or maybe
was it because there's a culture within
Google that they always call bugs issues
he said you know maybe is because of
that we don't know but you know but that
the interesting thing is you see the
Google this group of people they are
using you know they are choosing to use
the word issues since to the instead of
bug for four reasons was for some reason
yeah and you know so that's very
interesting because for a while because
from a logical certain logical point of
view issues is the proper word
what kind of almost it's somewhat a
better not not necessarily but in some
sense it's a better word because when
you say bugs well you know it's a what
you mean bug it was an insect you know
because it was not proper you know it
was like a slang or jargon but we also
must remember that almost like tons of
words half of half of our words all came
from jargons or slurs and borrowed
things you know they if you really want
to be you know tracing you know the
logical ways of the world you cannot
because every word he can has a long
history they change and evolve and most
of them you don't even know like today
you don't even know where they came from
like okay okay this is okay this is not
okay the use of issues for the word bug
is not okay that's a you know the
millennial generation that social
justice types they like to say something
something is this is okay this is not
okay you know as if they lost they don't
have the ability to you know it's like
two things you don't have the ability to
say the right word and they seems like
they are unable to say anything that is
you know slightly negative so they have
to say this is okay and not okay that's
so that's an example of another
interesting thing about you know the
word usage yeah then you know this is
okay this is not okay
so so anyway the issues so so yeah so in
some sense issues is you know maybe a
better word than bug but not really
because there are many reasons again is
using the word issues as well because
issue is issue first of all is a word
that requires a small advanced education
you know bug everyone understand you
it's an insect you know any children
that's it's a primitive word if you know
people 2,000 years ago will understand
what is a bug you know because it's a
primitive it's we thing but issue issue
is getting you know it's getting
abstract you you require elite education
you require this thing you know this
abstract idea of an issue and but also
issue means lots of things you know
issue
issue could mean lots of things you know
it's a it means a problem it means let's
look up issue okay i ssue so let's look
up dictionary
so let's magnify you see so issue means
a point or matter of discussion 0.0
matter of discussion debate or dispute a
matter of public concern a misgiving
objection or complain okay that's one
then to a problem or difficulty a
personal problem okay three
the act of circulating distributing or
publishing by a business government
organization right that's you know like
magazine issue number three an item or
set of items stamps or coins made
available at one time by a business
government organization that's right
stamp you know they have issues like a
collection you know it's like a special
issue yes then okay so and so on in for
the act of an instance of flowing
passing or giving out for example where
the where the lake gives issue to its
waters okay that's that's one of the
rare meaning of the word issue so it
means the act or an instance of flowing
passing or giving out a place of egress
an outlet lake with no issue to the sea
okay that that's a new that's a new
meaning to me so issue so in their small
five and six so you see the the word
issue can mean quite a lot of the things
and it's also advanced abstract word
so yeah so event so eventually I don't
think issue is a better word the word
burg is simple you know and it's short
simple and every children understand
even though burg means something else
Inc in programming it means a you know a
problem a defect you know but people
know you know people can make the
connection when you use a bug you know
even though they do not know you know if
even they do not know bug means defect
in software but any person you know when
if you are programming if you are in
software context when you see the word
bug it's an insect you will quickly pick
up what it means you know you know so
bug is actually more effective and
effective what I think the issue so
that's interesting
by way into linguistics
etymology jargon pragmatics you know but
there's also a branch of linguistics
called pragmatics I believe that's the
name let's search for it
pragmatics what it means is that how
people use language in real world like
in real world when you say something it
does not mean the same thing when it's
written out you know often you know of
it it does not pragmatics so there's a
Wikipedia article let's see if that's
the right article so how many people are
watching now two people ok so what's up
FMS so pragmatics some so wikipedia says
pragmatics is a subfield of linguistics
and semiotics that studies the ways in
which context contribute to meaning yeah
that's what it what it is
pragmatics income
passes speech act theory that's right
conversational implicature talking
interaction and other approaches to
language behavior in philosophy
sociology linguistics and anthropology
okay okay yeah that's basically what
pragmatics is you study you know the
real-world way people use words in
sentences sentences and in fact you know
our discussion about issue and bug is
part of it you know it's kind of misses
part of it by the way there's a new word
here semiotics I don't know what I'm not
familiar with that let's look at a
semiotic s-- it's probably means
semantics or something so semiotic also
called semiotic studies is the study of
sign process it includes the study of
science in sign processes indication
designation likeness analogy allegory
metonymy metaphor symbolism significant
and communication it is not to be
confused with the Sicilian tradition
called semiology which is a subset of
semiotics the semiotic tradition
exploits explores the study of signs and
symbols as a significant part of
communications different from
linguistics semiotics also studies non
linguistic science systems now this
topic I think you know to me I think
it's questionable you know the thing
about there are several things here
first of all we keep hideous not to be
trusted at all times okay you must know
that Wikipedia especially on any
subjects the
that's in the news you know that's
political subject or in the news any
subject in the news in the in the past
one year the corresponding wiki our
Wikipedia article you cannot trust it
okay I'm giving you a guide advice kind
of advice which article you can trust in
Wikipedia so anything mentioned in the
news any person names any anything in
the news that you know you you you
cannot trust the wikipedia okay you can
read it but often it's you know it's
it's heavily biased so that's one thing
now now on very obscure technical
articles academic subjects such as
mathematics linguistics typically you
can trust it you can trust what what
wikipedia says for example linguistics
pragmatics but of course not not okay so
you can trust so so these semiotic s-- I
can you know I can kind of trust it but
but you don't necessarily want to
believe it because you know in academia
you know throughout history thousand you
know hundred years let's say there are
many subjects if even academia subjects
and even email even among Sciences you
know scientific subjects they come and
go you know some some of some of the
ideas are just questionable so what I'm
saying is I this article about semiotic
is kind of it's questionable to me okay
it's like so what I mean by questionable
by that I mean this subject may not
actually have that that much of
practicality okay maybe it's just a
theory by some joke
by someone's by some single guy often it
happens like that some single you know
academic you know invented he just
invented a whole thing that happens
often then once he died the whole
subject went away you know nobody ever
mentions it again that happens often and
we have a lot of examples in history in
philosophy and you know especially in
philosophy so sometimes it's not
practical you know is it's not you know
it's just not something useful or
sometimes it's just studied by a group
of people not you know now it's not
widely accepted so anyway I think I
don't know for sure but I think semiotic
is one of them it's not it's not
significant thing it's not by the way
there are also a lot of examples in
computers really in computing for
example I can give you examples of let's
see cyberspace now I don't remember the
term but from from the cyberspace
article we can we can find the person
into the term so good money is famous so
FMS you are from Midland UK right middle
UK
so what time is UK now so let me see 1 1
1 a.m. is I right so we are reading it
looking at the cyberspace Wikipedia
article and you can see cybernetics
cybernetics article right so UK is
midnight okay so basically 8 hours ahead
from where I live you know California is
like behind it's like behind the times
everyone is advanced California is
behind Hawaii's is further behind
so cybernetics oh my god the internet is
so slow so yeah I'm trying to give you
some examples in related some computer
programming related subjects that I
think are kind of pseudoscience or wacko
you know old in significance so I'm
trying to find the terms but the
Wikipedia is not coming up
anyways the Wikipedia article on
cybernetic is not coming up but anyway
cybernetic is one of the term hose you
know when you read Wikipedia your COC
that oh it's a it's a mixed exit page
reload it's a mixed study you know
multi-discipline study about information
information science mathematics computer
science and linguistics or something
like that like mixed up or of things and
they talk about things and I think
that's all [ __ ] okay that's that's
just something of no significance
okay the Wikipedia article on on this
page is not coming up and in fact the
Google Chrome says page unresponsive why
is that that's interesting okay Google
do not want me to read the cybernetics
page google's AI is very advanced okay
there it is cybernetics so cybernetics
that we wikipedia Arcos a cybernetics is
a transdisciplinary what the [ __ ] is a
transdisciplinary approach for exploring
regular regulatory systems there are
structures constraints and possibilities
and no bird whiner defined cybernetics
in 1948 as a scientific study of control
and communication in the animal and Enda
machine in other words it is a
scientific study of how humans animals
in machines control and communicate with
each other
now this
is a pseudoscience [ __ ] yeah I don't
know who is this no no but wineries guy
is and and not note the word
transdisciplinary you know it's like
trance discipline it's a transcendental
you know it's like you know we are
reaching singularities you know by the
way lots of things you read about
singularity it's all [ __ ] okay it's
like a singularity you know this this
pseudoscience always have lots of
traumatic jargons cybernetics for
example cybernetics singularity you know
these kind of words so apparently there
is something on this page cybernetics
that causes chrome to not loaded anyway
so I think cybernetics and it's [ __ ]
is kind of pseudoscience okay it's kind
of mixed war so that's an example and
also let me show you let me show you a
page okay that keeps crashing it's just
close it let me show you a page sorry
multi okay let's go to saudi page okay
sorry
info Saudi code sorry dot info then we
are going to go to programming then we
are going to go into web spam then we
are going to go into this Arkell word
multi conference on system it it start
over words multi conference on systemics
cybernetics and informatics this this is
a spam email you know there are a lot of
fake conferences we are not really fake
but they make money you know they in
academia you know conference is a big
thing like every year you go to
conferences you know conferences in
different cities you know it's it's one
of the things that academics to you know
it's it's very inefficient and in half
of the time it's a fraud you know it's
it functions like half of the time it
functions like a vacation you know it's
not you know it's like you can travel to
places and of course the money came from
Grants and you know from the University
and or government you know basically the
taxpayers money so as a professor you go
around conferences by the way I'm not
saying this as a I mean it's a it's just
the thing they do okay and it's it's
fairly inefficient and not much of a
need you know not at least not the way
they are doing it you know today anyway
that's that's just that's almost like a
that's just a thing you know going on
you can you cannot stop it you know it's
like when you have a government or
country or
culture there are things you know you
guys do you cannot change it in one day
you know it just you know it's a big
trade it just keeps moving so one of the
things so so there are conferences you
know the academics academicians go to
and then they are also fraud conferences
you know so what they do is so there are
people they generate conferences they
tell you to submit papers they tell you
to pay so you pay them oh and they pay
you know you pay them so if I'm a
professor okay I received this email you
know they send me like every year with
titles such as you know what multi
conferences are systemic cybernetics and
informatics these kind of words happens
often with this fake you know cero
scientic science things and they so you
know if I'm a professor so I got this
email and say oh so suppose they are in
where Orlando Florida this this year
okay so you know I think to myself oh I
haven't been to that city before you it
might be nice for me to visit yeah as I
tell my assistant to send a mail to to
the University and they you know so the
university pays it you know pays pays
whatever this organization requires so I
can visit you know and this organization
what is it it's like this w in SC I it's
a fraud by the way you can check
Wikipedia on the on this oak they have
you know lots of they are so cool I mean
they are not about Sciences or when you
know they ago is just you know spam spam
email or the professor's you know and
get them to pay yeah and and also oh
yeah there are people who wrote fake
articles and submit with payment of
course to these to this organization and
got published like computer generated
fake articles about these cisnet
sistemics cybernetics and informatics so
anyway that that's about spam okay
that's part of the so we were talking
about some some science Sciences that's
kind of studio science now another one
that's let me give you another example a
pseudoscience and a lot programmers are
following to synergetics you know this
pseudoscience always have these fancy
jargons
you know synergetics this synergetics is
started by this this pokeball guy this
which i think is a scammer con con
artist
some kind of okay not foodie but a lot
programmer asaji
you know just following these people
okay wikipedia has got a problems right
it's not coming up let me try a firefox
thing okay firefox no javascript comes
up right away
maybe Wikipedia's got some Java
JavaScript [ __ ] up so anyway you go to
synergetics synergetics is a empirical
study of systems in transformation with
an emphasis on total system behavior
unpredicted by the behavior of any
isolated components including humanity's
role as both participants in observer
that is the problem that is a source of
a problem they start to drag in
humanities so anyway so there is this
synergetics and it's created by this
Buckminster Fuller [ __ ] you know in my
opinion he's a he's a kind of
not a you know these a snake a snake oil
sailor you know not technically a con
artist or a scammer but something like
that you know they like to spread
something questionable that's that's my
opinion okay so he's most well-known for
for being created the Geo geodesic dome
so-called geodesic dome by the way it's
a very bad joggin geodesic idea is
idiots - you're dissing my ass it's not
about geodesic at all geodesic has a
very specific specific meaning in
mathematics in geometry geodesic means
the shortest distance between two points
on in in a particular space you know a
manifold you know which is not usually
straight lines because how do you define
a straight line on a pole you don't have
a straight line if the ball you know
like on the earth so that the you know
the the the shortest path between two
cities is not actually a straight line
you know because we are on earth you
know earth is round so it's actually
curved somewhat if you look at the 3d
space but however on the surface itself
it is a straight line so anyway geodesic
the word geodesic is the technical the
technical meaning is that it means the
shortest distance between two points in
geometry and so the geodesic dome is
basically a polyhedron regular
polyhedron dome okay so anyway I digress
so anyway he so geodesic he the the
Buckminster Fuller guy who made he made
the geodesic dome you know the the bow
dome
popular which is which is great you know
this is a great structure by the way
anyway we are not going to go into
details so I'm just giving you some
examples of something I consider
Crossy science or pseudoscience okay
it's more proper to call them quasi
science again there's another you know
interesting thing about jargons you know
jargons you have pseudoscience you have
quasi science now pseudoscience the
difference is that pseudoscience usually
means it's just fake it's a scam it's a
you know illegal okay not always so but
you know it's just fake that's you call
it pseudo science now quasi science is
is is like this is is something that
it's questionable you know it's you know
some me you know maybe some scientists
believe it some doesn't you know it's
like on the borderline that's what you
call quasi science so in my opinion this
spokeman is this Buckminster Fuller guy
and what you know all his creations you
know these synergetics [ __ ] is quasi
science questionable and same thing
applies to the cybernetics thing the
site cybernetics the semiotic s-- you
know they are kind of like quasi science
to me in my opinion in cybernetics
cybernetics and especially its
associated associated with this guy
suppose i think he won't obey or
something
there's this guy anyway so yeah so
that's interesting digression so let's
get back to so we were talking about
jargons the jargon file the google's use
of the word issue versus bug the
linguistic branch called pragmatics then
there's we go back to ya the jargon file
and the free online dictionary of
computing for talk
then back to the Emacs command mod oh
okay so then back to the Emacs
commandment I think we digressed a lot
and so anyway so okay so I think that's
it for today so what's up FMS any any
questions or anything comments okay then
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching thank you MA FMS and we always
hope to see you next time let's see if
there's anything I want to cover and
okay bye