hey good morning guys welcome to another
episode of San tanco today's is 2020
2020 January 14th Tuesday 3 o clock p.m.
in the afternoon San Francisco time and
today the main topic is going to be
JavaScript and press random so and and
we are going to talk about some
keyboards I think because there are some
interesting discussions about keyboard
and Kathy is Kathy here and see so Kathy
so let's start to talk about key words
and how many people we have here we have
three people four people
okay keyboards let me show you about
keyboards so we go to the talk show
today stop show and okay before we so
let me actually do this okay switch
windows switch close that and make this
into that and let's put a item there and
so number whose so look at the Emax
screen we are going to come on in Kathy
morning p.m. cosa 1:00 a.m. in Vantaa oh
my god we have a person in Iran Rhonda
Rhonda that's that's Africa right that's
kind of Africa that's a place that had
problems Rhonda so that's fantastic
great to see you how it's going
and okay so we're gonna do let's let's
do these okay so I'm going to copy these
into the YouTube description so this is
a list of possible topics about
JavaScript so let me know which topic
you like to see first
okay so description in the in a
description in YouTube description type
a number and we will talk about that
type a number and we'll do that okay but
but but let's let's show some keyboards
first
okay so keyboards let's go to keyboard
so Kathy just bought this key mouse
thing fantastic
so among the Watchers my Watchers here
we have now three person who has these
key Mouse thing now this key mouse is
keyboard and mouse combined into one and
they have two or three versions one is
called let me show you okay one is
called key Mouse alpha which is this one
now this one is shown by hello beautiful
people that's his nickname
so kavod oh so he you know this is one
of the version and this version is
keyboard and mouse in one together so
you you know you type and you move the
whole thing it functions as a mouse you
also have a square square art so this is
key Mouse I think this one is called key
Mouse alpha yes and the other version is
key Mouse track which is you see here
this one is Kathy's so Kathy
got this one I'm amazed this thing costs
$500 u.s. dollars so you see in this one
you have a combination on the left I
think it's key Mouse alpha which is a
mouse on the right you have a trackball
and so Kathy bought it and from Kathy
says it's fantastic
okay good morning
I'll shiny so here are some pictures and
you can go to my website and look at
them and with there are some videos
about that so that's key mouse that's
Nami Safari what what Islam is Safari if
I'm not not mistaken the pen the pen
Chema's what pain see go down go down go
down go down go down go down
oh this okay good morning Nabi so Nabi
once picked a topic of JavaScript watts
so let's talk about that so yeah let's
begin I'm going to begin to talk about
JavaScript because JavaScript Watts
there's a huge number of topics I hope I
can talk about that in a coherent manner
because I'm not prepared you know let's
do this impromptu so anyway there's
there's this key spinner key cap that's
interesting wait so you see it's a
spinner key cap and there is this one
ago - so someone thank thank Matt be
thank thank thanks to Matt B for
donation and he builds this ago -
keyboard with a wheel with a volume with
a knob so I talked about this
with a knob before knobs are very useful
okay especially for controlling any
command that has a forward and backward
pair for example scroll up and down page
up and down or move kusa right and left
move kusa up and down and browser tabs
you know left and right and browser
backward and forward you know they are
like tens over more than ten commands
that comes in pairs up and down or left
and right so for those operations of
wheel is the optimal for example volume
up and volume down
you know usually for example right now
on this keyboard I'm pressing the volume
up in and down
you
thank you sir Vario open up and down is
a pair of commands that it that is most
suitable if you have a wheel now now
this now this now these videos got black
screens anyway let's go on so volume
up/down command is very you know
it's one of those commands that comes in
pairs and when that happens the best
control human-machine control is a wheel
for example on stereo on on stereo you
never see they have two buttons volume
bar and volume but up and down that's
stupid
except on remote control you know
because usually they don't they won't be
the remote control to be light so they
don't they don't have the volume the
wheel so anyway we always the best thing
for that okay and for example Moscow and
Moscow Moscow up wheel master squawk
wheel you never see you know you don't
want a mouse instead of a queer it has
two buttons you know you press to go up
and down so so in many situations the
knob is actually the best thing so
actually this guy build it and let me
actually show you some of the others so
do it yourself for you for example for
example this keyboard we talked about
before it's got one two three four four
wheels of different shape and this would
be fantastic keyboard and we also have
Korea this guy who has been you know one
one of us on this code you know he Bo
this keyboard and he sells it so you can
go and buy it so this volume wheel is a
fantastic thing and that is why today
this guy also be owed the a go - with a
wheel so when you have that you know
then you can you can program it to do
whichever you find you need lots of
commands
so that's about that let's talk about I
guess let's talk about JavaScript okay
and also these smiles I talked about
before this mouse got a joystick on top
it turns out it's not that great because
the joystick is kind of stiff and not a
high quality one not as high-quality as
the one those you find on a on a
controller you know game controller so
not high quality and also you have to
move all the way it's not analog
joystick so it is basically it's just
like four buttons up-down left-right and
also we can push it and it's not high
quality and it's not analog so so
because of that it reduces the the
goodness of this device by a lot also
because the way it's positioned it's you
cannot you know you have to move your
thumb up in order to press that so so if
you press those if you want to use a
joystick you cannot move the mouse so
that's the problem with so I don't think
this is that great okay so that's about
keyboards stuff I wanted to let's talk
about JavaScript in okay so and good
morning Alan
Oh Gordo so ego I so that's Gordo's pain
okay so let's see Kawada spin let's see
let's go down oh that's so that pain is
apparently famous it's a Lamy Safari
okay now we have to look at that Lamy
Safari okay so it's a it's it's those
how do you call those quail pain yeah
how do you call those pain I forgot the
name interesting
no I can hear you now wait you can hear
me
am I correct am I good okay good so
let's talk about there's no audio once
oh when I was
this video thing is always annoying I
know of the oh yeah okay so anyway keep
repeating its to JavaScript
okay let's it's let's go to JavaScript
it's V in JavaScript okay so JavaScript
so what's okay so let's talk about
JavaScript wats so go to my javascript
website and you know I have to put a
concerted effort to do this you know
because now the JavaScript is a big
topic and I'm going to have to I have to
do this extempore impromptu to summarize
all the worlds of JavaScript there are
tons of watts of JavaScript I I need to
okay I need to I need to actually focus
and think about what we want to how are
we gonna do this javascript Watts
fountain pain oh yeah that that that
that's the name of that pain fountain
pain so javascript javascript this is a
big and heavy topic and so let's let me
begin to let me begin by writing out
what comes to mind what what is the
javascript problems what i want to talk
about
okay so magnify magnified browser so
javascript what's the best thing to do
is always to write a topic when you are
unsure what's going on so javascript
what i want to talk about okay
javascript array problem there is no
real array instead array is just a
object that is key value pairs that
pretend to
be a array okay that's one thing
javascript array now let's talk about
JavaScript ah okay
javascript wha problems because it is
its scope problem because it is a
so-called functional scope that's a
problem and JavaScript Wow
another problem is is so called holy
scene problem okay
then I'm going to talk about javascript
function keyword function problem for
example the holy steamed problem and the
holy stream problem and and other
problems argument
let's let's just keep let's dead let
that be that for now holy stream problem
so show in browser so I'm gonna okay so
it's to JavaScript Watts showing browser
so now it's it's clear to see so these
are several of the problems javascript
beret problem okay so now we go to
javascript and let me give you let me
give you more problems and week I'm
going to talk about them one by one
JavaScript so language to Tokyo
JavaScript now the easiest way to look
at to get a list of JavaScript Watts of
JavaScript problems is by by going to
near
where you have where I have the
miscellaneous section let me magnify
this page miscellaneous section you have
style guide in semicolon okay say Mac
semicolon is another problem indeed okay
and strict mod that's also another
problem so when we start to talk about
JavaScript problems they are really
turns up problems javascript is not a
great language it's not a great language
because it's designed back in 2005 to be
a language for non-programmers like for
example website pro website designers
HTML and CSS coders they are not I mean
at that time there is no CSS yet but
javascript is the signed to be those
people who write HTML who are not real
programmers and it is actually so the
reason Java suite let me write it down
okay the reason JavaScript sucks
javascript has tons of Watts
the reason JavaScript sucks is because
it was designed and implemented in ten
days literally okay
javascript is literally designed and
implemented in in ten days and we have
to we have to give credit to the guy who
did it
his name is what's the name of the the
guy who created JavaScript I always
forget the names you can set you know
just such for JavaScript inventor you
know I talked about him several times in
fact we have personal you know we we I
talked to the guy many times he is also
the guy who
created the browser the brave browser
which is the one I'm you are seeing here
so I think he's a great guy okay so so
anyway javascript has lots of problems
because it's designed and implemented in
ten days and it is a language designed
for non-programmers for them to create -
for them to add a little interactivity
in a web page
now remember this is back in 1995 in
1995 so at that time there is no CSS yet
so they are you know Netscape is just
trying to create a language which is
kind by the way at that time it's a
great innovation because at that time at
the time you just have you you you only
have HTML static HTML there is no
dynamic HTML yet so edit you know nobody
foresee you know dynamic HTML there is
no such technology so you have static
websites where basically Nerds you know
right static website just like me I'm
still doing it after 25 years
there's no dynamic dynamic web page and
and so javascript is a big innovation so
that's the reason javascript sucks okay
and now let's get back to the items why
it sucks then we start to talk about it
and JavaScript is invented by Brenton
egg that's right
Brendon pyaari and da and e IC H Brent
da cuenta Ike I think that's his how he
spell his name brand Ike I think he's a
good guy so why JavaScript sucks so
that's the thing that's that's the the
meta preface now
I mean that then we give a list of items
why javascript sucks and there's more
okay so let's go back to actually let's
go back to let me start to get the least
foodist semicolon problem okay
javascript semicolon problem I'm gonna
explain them in detail the semicolon
problem okay and and then I'm going to
here here is a great page where I can
get a list of why it sucks so this page
is is about JavaScript style guide so it
tells you I tell you always declare
variables okay that's another problem of
variables javascript VAR problem
declaring or not declaring BA okay and
actually let me remove all these
JavaScript world
declaration okay vote declaration that's
a problem and no okay so let me talk
about new JavaScript the new problem
because in JavaScript
no is a literal of the type node of the
value type now listen carefully okay
listen carefully of everything I say
because what I say is very precise now I
don't care if you have coded if you are
a professional working for Google write
in JavaScript code let's say for two
years
you you are a big you know hotshot
working at Google on front-end on
JavaScript if you are that I mean I
don't care if you are that or not what I
say you know you might have heard online
or somewhere that people say JavaScript
is this or that that's all wrong
well not all wrong but what I'm saying
is is that what I'm describing carefully
here is very precise and if you hear
contrary opinions those opinions are
wrong I'm taking I'm giving you some
sort of mathematical very accurate
perspective okay so so forth so why am I
started to talk about that because here
I mentioned value type you will almost
never actually you will never hear
people say value type Y you will almost
never hear if you go saying that value
type when they talk about job JavaScript
but actually it is that is the correct
description of the type the types in
Java Script value has types so when you
talk about types it's a type of a value
so anyway so so javascript is a new that
the new problem new is a no-no is a
value of type new
and the only value of that type is the
literal word no itself and that is a
problem because it is a problem because
of okay so type for example let me tell
you type of there's a operator in java
script type of so in JavaScript if you
say type of nor you get a string object
so this is a problem this is the the
reason this happened because there's a
bug in the C implementation of
JavaScript originally so literally it's
a bug so Brendan Eich you know wrote
JavaScript he implemented and he you
know you have to do this in ten days
that's how much pressure you have you
have to invent design the language and
implement it write a compiler for it
within ten days autumn within ten days
then the next day on the 11 states
shipped so so you got lots of bugs not
design problems in bugs - so no today we
if you call type of nor you get the
object which is just incorrect the so
people have trashed trace I've showed
this before traced to the source code
that's why you know it's literally
because the source code is just
incorrect
it's a bug in the source code but we are
stuck with it then there's nothing we
can do you know we can you know we are
just stuck with it so so javascript have
tons of these problems so let me show
you another problem okay
the problem of equality operator so in
JavaScript you have double equal
that's an equality operator and you have
triple equal that's another equality
operator and the difference between them
is the double equal we are automatically
convert to type conversion on the values
on the left and right there
romantic comedy meanwhile the triple
equal they will not do this automatic
conversion you should always use the
triple equal because why because I mean
why isn't the auto conversion great
because why not because since it's
automatic well it's not good because
JavaScript the auto conversion by the
spec is very extremely lousy so it's
extremely confusing so that's why you
guys may have seeing a video about
JavaScript that talks about what you
know you guys familiar with our video by
a very smart guy and he is a great
programmer too he he also does
programming video tutorials so let me
show you you probably you guys probably
have seen JavaScript there's a video
code what or something like that
what what's you know it's like a meme is
the word is not what but it's like so
let me read the comments oh whoa
remember blinking scrolling banners
remember blinking is grown in parallel
panels
yeah that's back in 1990s how did that
happen come up okay i'll shine says why
why is incorrect why wouldn't no be an
object because no is not object because
by the design of javascript by the def
you know by the design of javascript a
object is supposed to be key value pairs
always whenever you know some some
people say wherever you have a value
that's the object it must always have
key value pairs like a hash table in in
python in ruby in perl or in in python
you call dictionaries you know key value
pairs
that's what object is in javascript so
so but the new value it's not a
value pea because you cannot add a key
value pair to it so it's it's really
shouldn't be a object so I'm going to
show you you know I haven't get into the
details yet I'm just right now I'm just
trying to list a list of the problems
the words they I'm going to dig into the
details of each one because I'm going to
show you the actual source code the C
source code you can you know I know
where to look you know I show you the
source code anything else er that's a
that's a book so Navi says you are
talking about the dark ages of
JavaScript reminded me of how bad things
were back then yeah okay right so yeah
we have blink that's a you know that's
another thing to go into that you know
the history of HTML is lots of dramas
lots of dramas lots of deck tech dead
technology lots of you know at one time
it's over the place you know it's like
oh this is a bad thing this is gonna
change the world this is gonna be the
future for the web then after five years
is dead completely dead for example two
of the example is VM VRML okay you know
I'm starting to digress okay so but VI
ma okay
I don't want this to be a history talk
today but anyway VR Mao is one of the
technology that's supposed to be the
future of the web and after five years
is dead and never heard of and XML is
another example is XML for for about ten
years it's supposed to be the future of
XML you know the future of HTML you know
it's it's gonna be truly fix everything
that's bad in HTML you know like the
blink tag or the object tag you know so
we started to every node is like oh you
need to H X you know you need to do XML
and XML I have you done XML yet you need
to switch your website which XML now
after 10 years it's dead it's cured by
another big dramatic history skill by
the html5 working group which is
basically commercial began by by opus
operating officer ousa
you know opera opera browser in the
apple they they want to kill it XML
because they want to do their own things
for money because for example Apple has
started to you know create iPhone and
Apple wants canvas Apple invented canvas
Apple wants canvas Apple don't want you
know each company they just want their
things to drive they don't want the
other so they they created this this
this this rebel standard you know this
rebel group called what the HTML
working group okay so I don't know you
know I can hear the name okay here here
is a group I mean I'm gonna show you
yeah they created this HTML the weight
WG
w
[Music]
anyway I can't remember the names at the
moment because I'm talking so you guys
know you guys know that what so the
group name I have lots of articles about
it then but then we all digress into
finding those articles by anyway let's
close it so anyway they basically there
is this new I can't find it HTML
standard ok HTML spec ok I can show you
right fast there it is what the
working group wh ATW g this is the brief
for this this organization so Apple you
know beginning Apple around 2007 also
2006 Apple and opera you know Opera
browser the the Opera browser is created
by this from he's from Northern
Europe ok
finland don't knowwe or something like
that he's a
he's a Microsoft hater he is also a
creator of CSS so that guy by he's you
know some Swedish some name I don't
remember but anyway he created he
invented he invented CSS and he is also
the tech tech leader of Opera the
browser and he is also a Microsoft hate
hater
you know Opera browser has been hanging
around you know on and off trying to do
things in a beginning it's a very good
browser but today it's like done it's
gone for is it's done for it's dead so
Opera browser the Opera guy the company
and Apple in a beginning
mostly then Google joined in they
created this working group they in the
beginning they are trying to suggest to
the w3c which is a standard for HTML the
organization which is also not so good
anyway they try to talk them to them and
the w3c refused to no they say ok I
don't think your proposal is good we're
gonna stick with our own you know XML
and so so they created this you know
what the working group then then
then this group started to work on html5
that's how html5 arise you know they you
know because Apple once there's own
stuff they don't want you know they want
to they want to push for canvas and a
bunch of other non-standard
things you know for their iPhone mostly
what I understand the for example let me
show you the 2d stay while it's starting
to become this this line for example
meta tag viewport this Apple invented
this one this this viewport meta tag
because so that so that web pages can
will display fine on their iPhone
remember iPhone is created around to us
2006 with a you know tiny screen so you
have to do lots of things to make it
work so anyway Apple invented the
attacks Apple has a lot you know they
want to create their own stuff and this
this tact I'm not sure today it's part
of the standard yet but I know have read
its you know beginning the standard
started to make this tag part of the
standard but even so it's like the
history of HTML is one up or
up you know it's still
so to this day
for example this meta tag even if it is
now part of the html5 standard it
doesn't make sense because it's like
meta something meta you know meta
originally is is the meta tag originally
is designed to be equivalent to the HTTP
protocols headers anyway we beginning we
are digressing into lots of things let's
get back to JavaScript watts
good morning SID to Japan so anyway let
me just say that today we actually have
two standards specification for HTML one
is from this
what the working group you know the
WETA twg working group okay they have
one speck for the html5 standard
meanwhile we have another one from the
w3c let me write down what we talked
about a little bit
VRML what working group w3c history of
html5 okay and canvas and and the
viewport tag okay let me just have a
record of what we talked about today
so anyway so today we have two standard
for html5 you know from different groups
and they the spec differs they literally
differ in some detail so one spec say oh
this should be that way this is a valid
tag the other spec says no that's not
valid it should be this way they
disagree they fight and meanwhile all
the nodes they don't understand they are
so you know anyway that the it's it's
let's get back to JavaScript watts so
okay so let me show you that's a nother
keyboard so JavaScript watts so actually
we I need to get I need to be faster God
we already 40 minutes we haven't
actually begin Chavez squats we only
started to list some of them okay yeah
so this is gonna be a big topic let me
finish the list okay so actually
semicolon rules and style guide okay so
let's follow the style guide yeah with
with statement is another big words with
JavaScript okay I'm going to tell you
why
the with statement that's a problem then
we have yeah the equal double equal and
triple equal and semicolon problem and
the property name constructor oh my god
that's a big giant one huge in
JavaScript the constructor the
constructor in prototype I need to start
to talk about name in detail because
otherwise we never even begin
ok constructor and instant instant of
instance of operator is one one one
incredible up incomprehensible and
most people these people you know most
JavaScript coders they work in companies
they all use it wrong they they oh they
don't know what they are doing
yeah I you know it it's not being
accurate it's it is not inaccurate to
say that majority meaning more than 50%
of Java's professional Java Script
coders their code are filled with
incorrect use of JavaScript meaning that
they introduce actual books not just you
know theoretically incorrect they
actually introduce lots of books because
the way they use javascript and also you
know and well I'm going to start to get
into a rant the head starts to flame I'm
gonna start to flame lots of things so a
way that that's always one big problem
in javascript and yeah then the
constructor the object the constructor
with a literal keyword object that's
also problem avoid for falling in loop
that's another problem okay for
something in that's another problem
because whenever you whenever you do for
X in some object that actually looks up
your parents you know it lives through
all the properties of
of every of your parent your you know
parent chain and a lot of people you
know most programmers use audacity oh
using this wrong constructor named
function e VAR okay so well using a
keyword this this keyword is also a
major problem okay let me start to talk
about them the problem of the keyword
this okay and yeah new is a problem okay
so we're getting more complex I mean let
me start to explain them maybe in in 10
minutes 20 minutes we'll have a good
some useful information you know okay I
I talk for 15 minutes okay let me just
check okay so okay so JavaScript what's
what's a rate problem so what is a
problem of JavaScript array let me show
you okay so array javascript has you
know I need to start to show code okay
because with code you actually see what
I'm talking about so let's let's do a
rate problem it's to a JavaScript let's
start to code JavaScript so JavaScript
constant okay so AR is array now three
four five okay that's a way three four
five you know we got three things and
the console.log array so we can print it
so we got an array three four five now
array JavaScript to do not have true
arrays why because javascript array is
actually a javascript object it doesn't
have true arrays for example this 3 4 5
is actually it is technically a object
with three keys the keys are 0 1 2 you
know the the keys
just indexes of the race so the keys are
0 1 2 and the the values corresponding
to each key 3 4 5 so you don't have a
true array you have you know it's
actually a object that pretends to be
array so what's a big deal I mean why is
it I mean are you
am I making something out of some small
issue no because you have real problems
for example for example let's see you
know for example array so so so let's go
to away ok so javascript let's go to
array let's talk about array and we have
a lot of problems huge or not a huge
amount of a lot problem arrays the
biggest one major problem in JavaScript
let's talk about them ok so create a
response away yeah then you have the
spousal rape problem then you have the
array like object problem you know it's
it's very funny you know you know more
in other languages Python Ruby pearl
array is just a way you know they maybe
they differ a bit you know basically
they are the same away you just have
array you raise an ordered list of items
each item each element is indexed by a
number you know starting with 0 usually
so you know that's that's what a raise
and that's it that's it you understand
whole thing but in JavaScript it's not
that's not a case because javascript is
actually not be arrayed technically it's
an object so you got you start to have
lots of little details problems and
issues for example you have the concept
of sparse array then you have the
concept of array like objects then you
have you have a problem of how do you
determine when is a value that's
actually or ray or ray like object you
know you got this improper problem so
let me show you okay so
so yeah okay so here is one of the
simple the most easy example
so type of type of ARR okay so let's run
that what
oh they changed they changed they change
this thing in in rjs what's going on
there is some change they made but
anyway let's just look at this one this
line okay type of you see I say type of
three four five and you know I say it's
object and it returns true okay so let's
come on out this time so type of you
know that array is equals to object is
returns true so that tells us it's
actually your object and there is no for
example there is there is no value I
mean there is no value type that's named
array so you know in JavaScript you
don't have you don't have a value type
that's just named array for example let
me show you what are the all the
possible value types in JavaScript
bye-bye-bye spec so you go to value
types so these are one two three four
five six seven seven these are the seven
possible types of a value in JavaScript
so you have undefined type you have no
type you have true or false pool in type
you have string type then you have
number type which is any number
including the literal none stand for
naught not a number and the literal
keyword infinity those are all values of
the number type then you have a simple
type then you have object type you see
so these are the these are all the
possible types of a value in JavaScript
now notice among them there is no
function and there is no array so in
technical sense javascript doesn't have
you know when you have a function it's
actually not a function technically it's
just object meaning it is a key value
pairs but with extra okay the extra is I
did actually also is a function it is a
internal body that can you know function
so that's you see that so that's one of
the problem with JavaScript you don't
have actually array you know in other
languages you you say type of something
you know maybe you get array maybe you
get
then maybe you get a object or you know
or a hash-table you know but in
JavaScript you don't have a you know you
a value these are the possible values
you don't have a function type you don't
have a rate type so array and a function
actually technically there are objects
so so what does that mean so that means
I can add a key to array so for example
let's add a key so array xxx key let's
say key 1 okay
key 1 equals to 3 ok let's run that then
then let's let's show all the keys of
the array so let me show you this
actually I cannot finish talking about
JavaScript wats today so because we
don't I don't have time for the whole
thing so I want to show you all the keys
of the this array yeah okay so let's see
where how how do we find object
properties so I'm going to show you a
way to disorder properties or the keys
of a object list properties okay
reflect on keys so let's do that
reflect on keys okay so we added a key
to this array and we're gonna print that
and we're gonna print it okay
granite now you can see here are the
keys so this shows you that this array
is actually an object because it's you
know it's printing a keys so you have
key 0 1 2 then you have a magical key
length actually 0 1 2
they are magical then you have also key
one because key one is what we added you
see so this demonstrate that the array
thing in JavaScript is actually truly a
object in such a way you can actually
use it like at a like an object for
example you can start to add you know
whatever arbitrary keys you want you
know for example three four let's run it
okay so you see key a a and for you see
here key a and a a and B be so so that
means it's city you you can now you know
you can just use this array as a general
purpose hash table if you want and you
can in fact do the same thing with
functions so this is one of the big wads
of JavaScript and also because array is
you know it's actually object but
javascript pretended to be array you
know it it shows you you know like array
but it's actually objects so you have
this link thing this length thing is a
magical key in this array object so
whenever you add a append you know
whenever you add more value to the array
the value of the length changes
automatically so for example let's say
console.log a our length okay so you can
see here it says three and a net
sprinter again is three again so but if
we append console.log
aaarr dot append do we have a paint
method i forgot i haven't been code in
javascript daily yeah
a ray prototype what's the push okay
let's just no not a pen push away push
okay let's let's say 99 okay so so we we
pushed array then we're gonna print our
array then we're gonna print the length
okay let's run it so you see the length
is three and then it becomes four what
are we doing so wait so let's let's
remove that so let's print that okay and
then we push and we print them again so
you see so here is array we don't let's
not have the key okay so let's not add a
key so I run it again so here is a rate
three four five
the length is three then we then we
pushed we pushed 99 into it so so we get
99 and now the length is four and now if
we print all the property keys we print
the keys anyway so do you see what I'm
saying okay um why don't you use object
art keys what's the difference between
reflect an object reflect is a better
version than object art keys okay so let
me show you so you go to JavaScript in
depth go to the properties section
object property and you go to the list
properties so this page shows you all
possible ways to beast properties of a
object so you have one two three four
five six six
one two three six ways now how they
differ why you have so many because
because this gets complex you know
that's one of the problem with
JavaScript so a property has a attribute
of whether it's a number in America or
not okay again let me summarize age' a
object in JavaScript is key value pairs
okay that's a definition of object in
JavaScript now each key value is called
a property okay that's the terminology
each key value is called a property so
object has properties now but for each
property there are about three
attributes for the property that is
whether one of them is whether the
property is in nomura beware I'm saying
so it's a in you know innumerable okay
so that's a one of the upper so object
has properties and for each property
it may be innumerable enumerable or it
may not be innumerable so that's an
attribute of a property so that's one
thing then you have simple key and
string string key okay let me explain
that so a object is a collection of key
value pairs now for each key the key
allows two possible types value type for
the key one is string key and the other
one is symbol key now symbol is another
value we are not going to talk about
that anyway it it allows two possible
values value type for the key so that is
why you have these issues when you use
different ways to get a list of property
of an object you know sometimes you only
want the symbol keys sometimes you want
both string keys and symbol keys
sometimes do you want both and sometimes
you want only the innumerable properties
only sometimes you don't want that
so these are why you have this
complexity because javascript is not a
well-designed language so it's very
complex when you get into detail so you
have so you have now six ways to list
the keys of a object so normally the
most popular one and the earliest one is
the object dot keys so if we our list
we are only these innumerable properties
only so if you have a property attached
to a object but that property is not in
a mobile you can make it so then then
the object keys object keys will not
show it also the object our keys will
not show symbol key we can actually to
that we can actually demonstrate that
and you know so so so let's see where we
want to go next please make a playlist
what free list okay so actually so maybe
I should do that some demonstration but
if we do demonstration we we am not
going anywhere you know so because well
the original goal is to go through all
the JavaScript wats but it turns out we
only covered the array problem and only
partially to and when we talked about
the array problem in JavaScript we also
drag in several of other words so this
is a very big very big topic and you
know if I prepared for it it will be
better I haven't been doing JavaScript
in in in the past week so yeah so we
were talking so so when we start to talk
about JavaScript array we also talked
about several other things such as the
the complexities of properties the
numerable or not and you know the
properties attribute and symbol key and
string key and another let me mention in
other words okay now remember a object
is a list of key value pairs by
definition now the allowed value type
for the key there are two possibilities
one is symbol that symbol type of the
value the other one is string type
anything else is not allowed for example
it is impossible to have a number as a
key of an object okay it's impossible
you cannot have a number so key above
object no can you have a object as a key
of an object in other languages often
you can in Ruby Python Java you can even
email based you can have arbitrary
values as a key of a object anyway in
JavaScript the only one type value type
allowed for the key is string or symbol
but again you look back here you see we
we have added a key here where did we
add a key we deleted it let me see if I
can get it back you see we added the key
here so you see here is the code to add
a key another problem is that when you
add a key there is two alternative
syntax very confusing very bad badly
designed you see these two syntax
they are almost equivalent now
technically the proper syntax the most
versatile syntax is this one because you
are actually you see that a a that a a
is the key you want to add to this
object and remember the possible allowed
value type for the key must be either a
string or symbol anything else is not
allowed so here this syntax
properly shows that you are using a
string you see this a is a string but
however javascript has this also has
this dot syntax okay which is convenient
okay
but it's badly designed okay so so when
you this when you use this start a a
that a a JavaScript will automatically
automatically convert that a a into a
string because why because the key must
be a string or symbol so that a is
converted okay so actually I don't know
what I'm where I'm going it's not so
that so anyway that's about that and
let's see how long have I been talking
one hour in five minutes
so anything else I mean where should we
go like maybe we we shut down in five
minutes or in ten minutes
should we talk about some other things
they should we like any of these which
one of these should we talk about or
should we do some demo like ryuko demo
about some of these innumerable
properties and stuff
I don't know so type let me know okay
type whatever your thoughts and let me
think about what we what I want to where
we go semicolon is another major problem
of JavaScript okay I mean let me say
something about that semicolon problem
in JavaScript so it's JavaScript you
know as you know in in in many languages
C and Java you have you need to put a
semicolon at the end of a usually
statement or statement usually so you
have
my colon but however usually programmers
fine typing the semicolon very annoying
because it's tedious
so JavaScript created a compiler it has
a smart feature that smart feature is if
you do not for example let's run let's
run this code okay
it runs okay it runs no problem
but if you remove the semicolon it will
also walk let's let's remove it okay
so let's remove some semicolon run it it
runs it also works so it seems this is a
great feature
you know the compiler is smart you are
just automatically add the semicolon for
you however that's not the case because
because because there is a major design
flaw with the way the compiler how they
deal with semicolon why because let me
show you example let's put this let's
show that okay actually it's common this
out let's go back here let's say we're
gonna we're gonna add a weight not that
shall we do it yeah okay so I know what
to do so you see now right now this code
runs everything is fine now let's let's
try to remove this semicolon to see if
that works okay run it okay it's also
fine let's do let's do three plus five
let's do three plus five here
actually let's do okay so let's assign X
equals to 7 x equals to 7 okay now first
of all let's put the semicolon okay put
the semicolon
okay let's comment out the rest of it
okay so our entire code is just these
two lines let's run it and let's print a
AR and let's print X okay now it all
works now let's remove the semicolon
okay remove it remove it remove it
remove it it should walk donate it works
indeed I need to find a fire okay let's
just go to my website okay
and let's get an example
let me I mean let's show an example
where it doesn't work you see this is
tricky that's why javascript is that's
why semicolon has these problems so
let's use this example so here we are
okay so here we have a function that's
for the semicolon there okay so so this
is complex to understand a little bit so
we are defining a constant F and we
assign a value of a function this
function takes no arguments and it just
returned three okay that's a function f
then over here we are calling another
function we are defining a function here
a function without no argument with no
argument and it just returned four and
then it just evaluated it right away
okay so if we run this code it does
nothing but let's say three plus four
okay so if we run a it does nothing but
now if we remove the semicolon this I
need to well I wanted to show you an
actual example where in one version you
have semicolon everything works and
you'll print out something then but if
you remove the semicolon it does
something else your code becomes a bug
and sometimes misteriously like you
cannot find out what's a problem but
your answer is wrong I want to show you
that example but I don't have I'm not
prepared here so so I'm not able to get
it show you a good example right now we
have this example but this example is
not so good because right now it just
tells you a compiler error you know if
it's always a compiler error then that's
fine because okay so I've failed I you
know so
the the the semicolon has become a big
issue in JavaScript because then you
have two schools of thought one school
tells you to always use a semicolon the
other school tells you to never use
semicolon but in each school the rules
about when to add a semicolon or when to
omit it is very complex it's very hard
to understand it's not like a simple way
you know where you just add semicolon
everywhere you walk well actually that
works if you add semicolon almost
everywhere that works
it's skinning complex and anyway
anything else maybe that's it for today
we yeah I should close down we see I
have 14 people watching so you know
let's maybe maybe we do next we do
another JavaScript watts you know be
better so that's it for today I guess
Wow problem function problem you know
some of these problems are fixed today
if you some of them are not some of them
are you know forever it's gonna be with
us for example the new problem is with
us the function problem is also with us
although you can try to never use
function and use arrow function instead
instead the instance problem that this
key word problem that's with us the with
problem that's also with us the
semicolon problem is also with us the
double equal sign triple equal sign is
also with us is not going away the the
problem is mostly going away because you
just don't use var you know just don't
use vowel while the others the with
statement problem is also going away
because you just never just don't use
with at all but your the problems they
kind of stays because you could try to
never use them
but in real words many people will keep
using them so it's not avoidable
so since people use them then you have
lots of you know it drags in lots of
technical details when it's good when is
bad when you get lots of bugs things
like that so anyway so that's about it
for today's JavaScript
wats no I have so of course I have
written this javascript in depth you can
read every detail precisely and much
better than my maybe my they my
impromptu talk show good morning but
okay that's it for today and by my by my
JavaScript tutorial okay so you can buy
it just by clicking the link bye guys