episode of s talk show today we are
going to code emac LP continue from
yesterday uh continue from yesterday
hello guys sound talk show uh we are
going to write a emac this command to
validate brackets validate matching
brackets to see if you have a missing
bracket or or misplaced bracket so we
did that yesterday uh so let me begin
let me show you my keyboard and let's
begin so this is kesis foam keyboard
kesis foam keyboard I did a unboxing and
I did a review in the past week so just
check my YouTube tutorial it's a very
elegant
keyboard okay and the new le track Bard
this is my ultimate hacking keyboard and
uh again this is a fantastic fancy
ergonomic keyboard very Advanced this is
called Spar board SV b o a r d you I did
a review kind of unboxing and uh you
search it you'll find it on the web SW
board s v a l b o a r d data hand okay
so I will be using it down the road uh
and let's begin coding okay
sois keyboard newly attractable
fantastic let's begin coding so let's
show uh so we did this yesterday
yesterday and I cleaned up the code so
now the code is much better uh but
there's more to do okay let's begin
coding and let me tell you what to
do uh let's write it out okay I'm just
going to go slowly if you are watching
this offline uh play it at speed 1.5 or
skip around if you are here say hi
okay okay so uh so we have a command
let's go to my init file
validate so this that's old
code validate okay validate bracket so
that's a new code so there it is first
of all we Define so this is what we have
since yesterday so we have a list of
brackets okay watch yesterday's video
this is uh called Association list and
then the main thing is this command
validate bracket file okay so this is
about lines of code and uh what this
will do is will tell you if I have
mismatched bracket for example let's
open a new file uh let's add some
brackets uh parent parent and okay
square bracket square bracket there that
should be good so I press a key I
already have the key set up so that
would
be space
space
TG uh no uh I forgot what's the key so
let's look up so Kar key binding okay so
search for validate there it is TG so uh
yeah that should be space space TG so
close that space space
TG what oh you need to uh yeah you need
to save the file okay okay so actually I
made
the let's save the file this just temp
file okay space space TG so you can say
it says brackets valid you are beautiful
and now if we delete one of the bracket
you see now it's a missing right square
bracket space space
TG then it will say at the bottom Miss
bracket mismatch in file that file
nothing matches this bracket opening
square bracket at position 10 so let's
go here so you can see this is the error
message so this so this is uh this is a
command but we coded yesterday let's go
back um so on a new keyboard I'm not as
fluent so anyway so this is the code you
can get from yesterday's uh talk show
okay it just valid validates check the
current buffer or file okay today what
we're going to do is uh let's write it
out okay
this
validates a file or current buffer okay
if you are calling it interactively
interactively okay like by meta X
now make this uh now I want to make this
to check a directory okay all files to
check all files in a okay we are going
to make write a new command uh yeah so
write a new
command
let's write a new command that command
will be validate brackets
store
okay which check all files in a
directory okay so that's one thing
another thing we want to do
uh let's
see uh you know I was thinking make this
colable in a sh script so if you don't
know what I mean let me show you
control um Windows key one that gives
you my
shell okay control control SC magnify so
this is power sh I'm on Windows on Linux
it be will be bash or on Mac Z sh so you
can call this script emac uh the way you
call it is
emac script then the file name script
name script
name. then a directory the path okay
that will check
all files in the directory and make a
report so that's another thing so let's
if we have time we'll maybe do that but
now we just uh write this command
validate brackets St so you call it meta
X within emac hello guys good morning
good morning good
morning
alaza hi loling hi viix hi you are
beautiful yes you are subit
hi okay let let's write this command uh
fantastic
superb just realized have you change
your keyboard from
glove well I'm doing a new review for
them so check it out in the past weeks
there are two videos about this about
this um Kinesis form keyboard okay check
it
out so okay so now we're going to write
this command so let's let's begin
writing it fantastic so let's put let's
put this here here here here here and
let's copy that name paste it here
actually cut it def for defund fantastic
so we are defining a new command and
this command we'll take a directory
okay
validate uh brackets
in all
files in
okay and recursively yeah recursively
okay meaning all files in subdirectories
as well and also we need to give a
optional argument that is uh file name
extension
okay some okay yeah let's just name it
that uh check only files with file name
extension that created today's date uh
version today's date okay documentation
all important most programmers ignore
that uh which is bad uh okay so now so
the first thing is to get all files in a
directory then it's very simple then all
we have to do is for each file we just
call this function okay so how do you
get all files in your directory e lisp
the power of emac lisp emac lisp Basics
okay that's all about lisp programming
language but you want to go to emac lisp
then there is how do you walk walk walk
walk walk a
directory right here walk a directory
okay directory files so here's a
function now this doesn't recurse it's
not subdirectory so we want uh do we
want all subdirectories yeah we Let's uh
we want all sub subdirectories so
directory files
recursively by the way that recursively
thing popular in Unix you know like when
you do a
LS uh I mean when you do find when you
do copy dasr you know they all say
recursively but that's a idiotic name
because recursively in
first uh
is it kind of in infers the
implementation is recursive but what you
really mean is including all nested subd
subdirectories and their
subdirectories
so but anyway recursive this kind of
gets you the idea but it's
not in some semantic sense is not the
correct word okay because recursively
refers
to uh wait wa okay let me get let me
explain this
well so the word recursively
it it infers nesting it infers nesting
and it it infers an
action okay it it it must be connotes
with the idea of something that is
nested okay something that is nested or
some action that that that is somewhat
nested that's when that's a situation
you say it's recursive mostly the the
word recursively is used in computer
science now I'm not sure if it's that's
an interesting question okay digression
is interesting question I'm not sure
recursively what's the mology but I
believe it's
predominantly today in the past let's
say 50 years used in programming only
computer science or programming or
mathematics okay math first because in
mathematics that's a foundation of
mathematics you have recursive functions
that's original idea the you know when
they are trying to uh Define precisely
what can be computed
okay so that's a subject in
in theoretical computer science
recursively but anyway so I think it is
my guess that the word the term
recursive or recursively is used
predominantly like almost nowhere else
just in math computer science
programming okay now but let's look up
the atmology of
recursive recursive so space space
edge uh atmology e okay that's SAR by
the way the pink window shows all my
commands so that's one of my command
commanda look up atmology and
uh uh and uh space space H so you can
see it's in one of my package s look up
you go there and you go there you can
see you got all these commands look up
Google web Yandex Wikipedia look up
street maps look up what definition what
look up dictionary or or dictionary or
atmology or synonyms or all
dictionaries so that's one of my package
you have to pay to get it okay because
in the past 20 years uh everything is
free and uh people just bug you for Tex
support and all that so anyway so here's
a website so anyway Let's uh let's go
back recursive there it is so I want to
magnify
okay so
control scroll up
okay now recursive adjective okay uh
recursive adjective periodically
recurring okay so it describes something
that recurs that happens again and again
okay so first of all that's an objective
okay now wait okay so I need to get rid
of the control okay
I have sticky keys on by the way so so
then recursive now return backward
movement okay return and backward
movement from
1610 okay the recursive objective
periodically recurring is from
17 90 okay so recursion is from
1610 from Latin recursion um something
something uh running backward return
okay so running backward return
okay so when you
say a function that will list all
subdirectories and their
subdirectories can you say is it
appropriate to say
recursively yeah I guess so okay okay I
was was I would yeah okay I guess
so uh yeah so that's a good definition
in computer science recursive okay so
anyway let's go back to um copy go to S
Talk Show and uh S Talk Show show in
browser uh and go back so now this is a
new keyboard so I don't have all my uh
I don't have all my keys marro keys set
up but anyways
so so there's a link toook web okay we
let's go back to the problem we want to
solve
okay close this next next okay let's go
back to
here uh yeah so recursively okay so so
yeah what you do is you want
to uh yeah directory files recursively
okay directory files recursively there
it is a abbreviation fantastic
template okay so du is going to just be
du uh regular expression is going going
to be the file name extension but uh but
regular ex uh expression okay so the way
you do that is you
conact back slashback slash dot with
file name
extension and then a dollar sign okay
because dollar sign in regular
expression means the end of string okay
so so that part is the regular
expression okay then the rest arguments
are optional so include directory snow
okay include directory snil predicate
predicate is the function that filters I
believe uh include subdirectories true
means in a result include path that are
directories okay no uh the predicate is
a filter on which subd directories to
dive into rejects is applied first
before okay uh we don't okay we don't
care we don't have a you know predicate
NE follow Sim links NE okay ne ne Neil
then we don't need to write it just
NE okay
so so let's give a local variable x file
uh X paths okay
uh so this this keyboard kesis form
keyboard has a low profile key switch
that is 50 g linear
switch uh kind of pretty silent so 50 gs
but that's still too heavy for me so I
have to sometimes I press not hard
enough and I don't
get uh action okay so
anyway so a bunch of file path directory
file recursively okay we got a bunch of
files path and now all we have to do is
we
call
S validate
completion okay we want to call that
function we want to map this function to
this bunch of file path okay so what you
do is you
map C map c means do not return the
result okay so it's like for each uh so
here is one bunch of file path and this
is a function you want to map to okay
the
function
uh uh so actually the function all you
need is just a function name you don't
need the Lambda and you need to code it
you know you need to have a apostrophe
in front
so cling up the code so I think that's
it so map this function to this pun file
paath okay so in fact this is so Supreme
let's make it one single line so I think
that's it anything else okay so when you
are calling so now actually this should
work so the way you call this command is
just that and uh give a directory for
example let's say that then uh file name
extension okay what if what if when the
file name extension is not given
in that
case okay in that case
just all files
okay uh so in that case we can use a
empty string
to get all files let's let's test okay
so for example for
example
uh directory that okay directory that
and and a regular expression empty
string and uh evaluate this it should
return all files in this emac in it
let's do it run it fantastic go to
messages buffer fantastic copy this
line new buffer paste it make each line
a line so basically yeah you see wait
why is sample oh it even went to the git
directory the do git so that you so now
you got thousands of you know pass files
or something interesting so you do want
to ignore git so [ __ ] that gets more
complex yeah you want to ignore get so
close that close this
uh what if you put a dot here dot means
any file I think same same
result yeah same
result so so the question now is if the
user does not give a file extension what
should you do this is kind of a design
issue
okay if the user does not give a file
extension what how you know what should
the program
do so that's one thing the other thing
is that you do want to ignore git
um uh okay so we got you know so kind of
design issues you know you have to think
about so
but can we just shall we just simply
ignore this problem just hack hack you
know like for now just
assume we're going to check HTML files
only or
something anyway let's just do it
properly we have time okay so I mean
long time no see coffee who are you
coffee I don't remember who are you
coffee am I doing good am I alive yes
yes looks like I'm still alive that's
good okay
so two issues what happens when the file
extension is is not given do you want to
make it
optional yeah so when it's optional when
it's not given just use anything okay so
first of all solve one problem at a time
so okay so let's do
that uh let's say x EXT that's file
extension okay now set XEX
t
or now if there's a file
extension then use
that
otherwise uh wait uh I don't like to use
all okay let's let's use if proper
coding you know because
all by the way that's an interesting
question because all operation is
usually used as a as a short circuit for
if statement so for example if you want
to
do if x then one if otherwise two okay
wait if uh okay one is over here because
of the staggered keyboard so I got used
to the grid so that's why I made
got two okay okay so suppose this is
what you want to do if something true
then one otherwise two now usually
people can write it this way okay
or uh wait uh
what so if x you want return X otherwise
something right so people but a shortcut
is just
o
x 2 uh too okay so this is kind of the
same as that similarly in bash typically
you'll see it in bash in
JavaScript in Python okay that's
idiotic okay let me digress let's
digress our talk show is about
digression because there are so many
wonderful and different things on earth
that you can explore not not just the
main mainstream you know mainstream just
you know do professional crap okay so
programming hacker hacker code a
collection of articles about everything
about hacker so you
got on this syntax soup we want to go to
semantic noodles okay why I hate C why I
love goand why I love poell poell
complexity indeed why bash sucks but
today we want to go to all considered
harmful uh yeah I haven't talked about
this online so let's talk about that
search for or uh
uh uh search for logic okay there it is
programming edms and style section logic
operator is control flow one of the
idiocy of the mainstream programmers
including the elite
hackers like the Unix idiots you know
the they they typically are they are
they are Elite they tell you what to do
they you know you see this in style
guide in Python Pro whatever style guide
they say oh oh oh by the way the Ed
idiomatic way is you should do it this
way JavaScript for example here you see
V xal to through
y4 or all this uh wait this so this is
Javascript there here you have python
there you have bash with the m per m per
very common okay by the way there's
another trst with bash because ent ent
is actually end but because the ID
idiocy of the Unix idiots extreme those
you know Unix idiots
they they they they they have they they
return value when something returns
successful they return zero okay it's
kind of reversed from what what's more
sensible when something is successful it
returns zero when something fails it
returns
one why is that you know why do they do
that because when when something fails
it can return a different integers one
or two to indicate what kind of error so
that's why they do that so in bash you
have you know you you use the end end
instead of the of the all okay so anyway
here are some examples JavaScript python
bash and emac this you see you you'll
see this very common in fact you know
people will tell me hey uh you should
use all you know uh because I you know
because that's more ID idiomatic okay no
no no you are a idiot
okay so this is a problem oh so so why
basically or is a logical operator let
let me show you a example why the idiocy
of this this brainless non-thinking
mainstream they think they are Elite
hackers Fox okay let me let me tell you
right away you can clearly see what's
the
problem uh so uh let's
see
or let's
say one okay uh actually let's just say
false so it's easier
well okay well okay in emac is Neil and
true okay so it's Neil Neil NE Neil Neil
and last one is true true let's say now
if you are designing a programming you
know remember there's parallel
computation so when you see a all
mathematically means if any one of these
item is true it should return true okay
so when you have a situation you can
start parallel computation you know
today we have like several Calles CPU
Calles or whatever it eventually it's
going to happen you know we don't have
that like 15 years ago then started you
know multi two call you know dual call
Intel whatever Intel
[ __ ] or threats you know if you are a c
type of programmer C++ or Java idiots or
the rust idiots these people are kind of
idiots because they have no sense of
mathematics they just know bit bit deing
that's they that's what they are good at
okay so if you have in all these
languages when you have all with which
means mathematic mathematic is a logical
operation remember the roots it's logic
any if there's any one item that's true
return true so when you have all you can
start a parallel computation if you have
1,000 CPUs or whatnot you can run you
know you can dispatch and each you know
whenever a a thread or a c get one it
tells it sends back information then you
can stop ignore all the rest okay
but that's not how things are done in
typical programming languages almost all
except a
few when you have all they have to do
sequential evaluation so they check this
one then they check next one check next
one
until until if any one of them is true
then they they stop evaluate okay so for
example when they reach here they stop
and return okay so this this is why but
this is not but but if you have these
semantics then you cannot do parallel
computation you know you cannot your
compiler cannot automatically start a
parallel computation does doesn't matter
if you have 10,000
CPUs so basically the programming
language put a major
restriction on the
semantics this is a good reason for that
too because historically you know we
don't have you know multiple CPUs it's
all sequential so that's why it's
natural things are this way okay but
anyway so so people started to use this
sequential evaluation this is a gist
okay the semantic of all function or
operator in almost all languages
they is sequential evaluation that's
fundamental
so if you have sequential evaluation
then you can start to use all as a
branch control you see or X or2 so if
this x returns true then stop just
return X otherwise um close
that close that otherwise return true
okay I'm kind of going too much so
anyway I think you get the idea so you
know here's a essay and uh eser W disra
agree with me he wrote an article about
it okay he's famous for flaming you know
this programmer idiots you see he says
the conditional
connectives C and and Co for short are
less innocent than they might seem at
first sight for instance C does not
distribute over CN
compared anyway he wrote something
similar um
anyway that's a major digression so so
usually I don't when I use all is only
for logical purposes okay I never use or
or abuse or for branch control I use I
always use if statement okay so okay
that's a digression let's get back to
this problem so if the file name
extension if
uh so if file extension is defined
then uh then just return that okay
otherwise the file name extension will
be
um
uh none okay
so yeah can we do none yeah so let's try
again yep
so if it's not defined and then it's
just empty string okay so that's what we
do here and uh and here we just uh do
there okay so that so if the file name
extension is empty I mean it's Neo then
just I mean if it's
valid then return that otherwise empty
string
okay uh then what happens if you do
oh okay so actually
um back SL back slash
dot empty string I mean can you do that
yeah I think so no actually if you do
that no okay yeah so actually we need to
fix this
so okay then let's just do that
uh so file name extension if file name
extension
then that otherwise empty okay something
like that
so let's change the name file name
extension we uh
got uh GX so I need to type harder so
there file name extension regular
expression okay if there that then that
otherwise empty okay
yeah so now now that that that okay so I
think that's it so um
so what is this validate bracket yeah
you can call it and here test code we
don't care and oh okay so now the next
issue the next issue is about ignore
G and that's that's a problematic
thing uh so now you need to look at the
um the predicate okay is a filter on
which subd directory to dive
into Neil dive into all sub
directories
um function f if F returns true dive
into that uh lse not f is past a sub
directory full path okay you kind of
need a function
so so this will be the Lambda predic cut
X is the full path of a
directory now so if the
directory name is dogit the the just the
name not the full path then
return Neo okay
so so that's kind of we uh yeah that's
one thing we can do there's another
issue about interface design because if
you do this if we write this function
and put it here then basically we are
hardcoding it so it will just all ignore
dogit but what about I mean there's a
bunch of other directories you probably
want to ignore you know for example AG
silver whatever you know the Unix Unix
crab okay this start git and you know
this start is is created by the Unix
[ __ ] let me explain that one
because for example this is a concrete
example why should we care I mean what
you
know so we have a Git You know for
example actually I was working on my I
updated my git
tutorial uh can you see where let's just
go to it
okay practical G in an hour okay how to
add a file how to commit file you know
git is very useful you know so yeah so I
use git but now it created a dotg [ __ ]
am I concerned that's not that's not my
file I'm using a tool and this tool [ __ ]
A bunch of [ __ ] in my in my in in my
toolbox that's what happening with that
okay that's a re that's what actually
happening you know the Unix say they got
brainwashed they they thought this is
natural you know it's natural of course
obviously you have dogit or whatever dot
is you know when you use some of the
because oh yeah because you you know
there something something
no I use the git okay fantastic tool but
the tool should not create random
[ __ ] in my directory you can create a
you can if you need this [ __ ] you should
create it in your uh specific
you know
designated uh directory okay for example
on Mac you have file uh Forks well
that's another thing you know meta
information so you know because this is
not my thing why are you putting [ __ ] in
my in my in my
box that's what the Unix do because the
Unix [ __ ] you know the Unix
philosophy and Linux
idiots they just code whatever is
convenient it's the most easy to code if
I'm implementing git let's let's just oh
direct let's just create a a do git
special this is a special thing in your
directory okay that's what the Unix
people do [ __ ] the Unix
people and it become Norm like people
don't know you know become this is
normal this is normal that's what uni
people do okay so let's go back here for
now let's just hardcode it okay so if uh
so now you need to get the file name the
directory name from a file path
okay uh directory name from a file path
so let's go to uh Eis worker directory
directory name from a file path okay so
file path functions let's look at all
the file path functions file name
directory
okay uh no file name n directory uh yeah
okay maybe that so let's
test file name n directory okay and uh
so this is a directory copy that put it
here okay then evaluate it what do we
get empty okay that's not right so
actually we want um you see this returns
empty because
yeah well so this this n directory is
supposed to return a file name but we
just want the directory
name uh file name base file name split
uh file relative name what so what is
it file name directory okay I think
that's file name
directory file name directory yes so
let's try that
so evaluate
it yeah but it gives the full path um we
don't want the full path we just want
the last path
so is it file name base return the base
name of file name no directory no
extension
okay uh file
name base
okay well file
name file
name okay let's see if that
works empty stram no what the [ __ ]
expand file name true file name
wait uh
absolute Parent Directory this file name
Parent Directory is new in emac
29 I think 29 or
28 okay how long have I been talking 50
minutes
okay tck this channel talk about yeah
different things uh usually emac this
Unix programming programming languages
programming language design wam language
and keyboards lots of keyboard and mouse
and lots of my rent okay so usually if
you just want
pure uh you know tutorial on emac lisp
sometimes I do that sometimes it's just
you know focused like yesterday but
sometimes I go into a rent
uh hi sir what do you think about Terry
Terry A D Davis you know that's another
frequently Asked question
because uh the the the 5c answer is that
yeah he's a relatively great programmer
but he's got a severe mental problem
which is um
um which is called
uh
schizoid schizo
schizophrenic
schizophrenic okay that means you see
Illusions you see things and you hear
things that's not it there so T Terry a
Davis is got that that affected some you
know some great mathematicians also got
that problem you know one of the great
mathematician that's um uh there's a
movie made out of uh that mathematician
what's his name uh
beautiful a beautiful life or something
um anyway I forgot the name at the
moment but anyway schizophrenic okay
it's a
serious that's just an that's not just a
mental problem okay like a lot of us
maybe you have lot stress you have uh
you know you
are kind of a social or you are um
borderline personality or you are
histrionic you you need to make a drama
to be center of attention all the time
you have to talk nonstop some people are
like that or you are skeo like me which
is kind of a loner we don't you know we
don't go out much all these are and then
you have bipolar you have Maniac you
know is personality disorders but then
and
schizophrenic that's not just a
personality disorder that's something
serious seriously wrong in your brain
okay you see you see Illusions so that's
what he's have and he's
got he uh you know he killed himself but
then these Zuma idiots the [ __ ] zumas
today you know online the for Chan you
know channers oh Terry Davis
do you like gay oh yeah you know they
they they don't care about nothing they
they they just like the drama and they
you know that's what happens you know
that's why that's what happens with um
this today's
generation okay so let's get back to
this we can finish this in five minutes
you know okay so uh so right now I just
want the directory name file name um
let's see so given a file full path
that's a directory we just want the
directory
uh wait what why is it uh file name
directory let's see so let's see file
name none directory file name
directory file name extension file name
sense extension wait what is it
I'm pretty sure I've used
this quite a few times but wait but uh
file relative name expand file name file
true name
no uh file name with extensions join
file path file name
concact okay so file name directory name
p file name us directory basically add a
slash yeah I don't think that's
it file name us directory okay so for
example we can check double check run
that yeah it just return itself we just
want for example this the last part so
what what what is
it I don't think it's a Parent Directory
but we can try but I don't want to use
this command because uh
my Marco Keys doesn't work because now
I'm using a a quy layout so control C to
copy so uh for example if we call
that yeah that returns The Parent
Directory that's not what we
want
uh f name
components uh directory
names directory file name wait wa how
come I don't have that directory file
name uh
okay let's try
that it Returns the full path no I don't
want full
path wait I can't believe
yeah we wasted a lot time on this but
okay let's just let's let's
um let's just do a regular expression
okay string string match Okay stram
match the string is the X which is a
full path to a directory and uh the
regular expression is just let's check
git okay let's just check
that slash slash okay okay start we
don't care okay so this is our function
to check if it's a good directory I was
trying to be more proper by you know
actually getting the directory named
itself but this will work
okay uh so yeah so so so we need to put
this in this directory file
recursively a predicate I believe here
uh by the way emac work directory for
facilities sucks okay so there is a
predicate the documentation predicate
can be either Neo which means all Sub
sub are descended into all true which
means all
subies that can be read are ignored okay
or a function okay which is called with
the name of each
subdirectory and should be return true
if the subdirectory is to be descended
into Okay so
so wait where is the position of the
predicate you know emac this doesn't
have named parameters so you have to so
every parameter is ordered so the
regular expression
include directories and predicate okay
so we need a
Neo here okay then this function Lambda
string you know this function just check
if match git if it does
then uh Neil okay so we need
to not reverse it
okay so we got that okay so
now uh what do we do with that cut cut
cut
cut put a new put it there and go back
here okay so we essentially complete
this
I think that's it so validate
directory and check only files with file
name
extension uh let's give a full
documentation if file name extension is
NE
uh do all let's just say sloppy writing
let's just say do all now and uh also
dog the is ignored okay because we
hardcoded it we have to think about
fixing later
okay so one more time last's check uh
regular expression file path regular
expression file name extension this is
all file path and uh then then you just
map that to all file
path
okay okay
now what if what if when this is called
interactively like when you do meta X so
in that case you need to create a value
for the directory and curent and file
extension so let's just put it here
let's add it okay so
interactive uh
interactive okay let so we need to event
create a list okay so current default
okay default directory is whatever the
current buers directory so when you call
this
interactively the directory is going to
be default directory and what about file
name extension uh let's just say HTML uh
actually let's say the current files
extension okay let's get elaborate
so by default it will will use the file
name extension of whatever is the
current buers file name extension if
that exist okay so let's do that here
so uh buffer file name that Returns the
full path of the current buffers file if
it is visiting a file so okay so this
can get
complex if if there's a bu if the
current buffer is actually a file then
then you get then then uh file name
extension
okay buffer file name so buffer file
name then you get the file name
extension if if there is actually your
extension uh but but what what if it
something
something TD what does it return NE Okay
so
when there's no extension re it returns
NE okay what about dot okay okay so when
there is the extension then
you then you just um get the file name
extension otherwise otherwise you need
another if statements otherwise H what
the [ __ ] let's just say
HTML something let's see so if the
current buffer is a file and if the that
file has a file name extension then use
that but if that file does not have file
name extension okay the proper way is to
prompt
it now we got too many nested you know
so the proper way is actually to prompt
you know ask user what what what um but
usually I don't do that because it's a
better user interface design that you
never pumped
okay you don't want when user runs some
command and and sometimes it prompts
sometimes it doesn't either it always
prompt or it never prompt okay that is a
better user interface
design because that way you adapt your
muscle memory when you know when you run
this command you know there's no prompt
you know you just do whatever if there's
issue it'll tell you you know but
doesn't like stop in the middle oh but
by the way I can't find the directory
can you type
something
unexpected because sometimes it does
thattime it doesn't you know then when
you call the command you have to think
about oh uh is my current buffer
associate with the file does it have a
extension you know you don't want that
so usually that's a better uh design
principle emac doesn't you know uh
support that the most prominent example
is when you say file when you kill
buffer for example when you do kill
buffer you know if the buffer is not
saved it will prompt but you know like
you know first of all it idiotically you
know it prompts you you know are you
sure this is a current buffer that's
idiotic then if you say yes then you'll
say you know oh buffer is modified kill
anyway that's very annoying okay but if
the buffer is not modify it doesn't ask
that so whenever you call this command
you have like unexpected you like you
know it's not muscle memory so you don't
you don't want that
so so
anyway so if otherwise prompt okay so
wait if both of file name
then uh
okay if if bu is a file then get that
file name otherwise prompt okay let's
just say prompt for you
know oh wait actually let's just say Neo
okay because down down the road here it
will deal with Neo
here so so here is also NE Okay so you
got the default directory and you got
the file name extension if it cannot
find it then it's Neil So when it's NE
so this part this part will fill out the
value for this two possibly not that one
so that one over here you know it will
check if it's
given yeah
where am I searching okay so right here
if it's given then just do that
otherwise it's just empty
string okay I think that's
it so since we don't have local
variables we can replace that by P R O
GN which is just group okay save it
evaluate the buffer uh error no open
opening bracket what evaluate the buffer
oh God we got syntax Z error no opening
bracket
what wa where is the
error no opening bracket for that okay
so actually oh yeah so I know why
because we are running this delete that
evaluate the
okay so we got this command now let's
try it validate brackets St where do we
try it let's go to talk show directory
okay so talk show directory you have 800
900 files
so uh so let's open this file AI
morality so it's my podcast talking
about AI artificial intelligence and
ethics okay now let's call Meta
X validate brackets
enter so okay it got errors so it says
uh no opening bracket for that at
position
22157 in this
file okay so open that file sh browser
so this file this old file em Emily's
hexad decimal I
mean six based watch she programmed her
I I eyew watch to do
it so but anyway in this file it's
saying I'm missing an opening bracket
let's see where's Arrow
three uh at position this position so
let's go
to go go to
char uh TN okay space TN go to
char
22517 do it oh there because it's a
smiley you
see so that is why you know usually when
I check brackets uh let's okay let's
close that close
that uh close that close that go
uh okay so go back here look up close
that uh go here
here so I don't like to check this you
know this par because the because
these uh
what these are often abused you know to
make smilees and stuff so usually I only
check these others okay let's do it
again so evaluate the
buffer go to S Talk
Show meta
X validate brackets
St brackets valid you are beautiful
597 times
fantastic
now now let's go to one of these file
let's say you know pick a random file
let's say that one and let's
secretly
add a mismatched
bracket
okay there there it is you
know secret mismatch bracket save it
close it close it now meta x s validate
braet do it
aror fantastic you
see it's no secret to the
program in this file at position
386 384 you are missing a opening
bracket for that okay now open that
file expanded let's move the crer
somewhere now let's see let's go to char
384 do it fantastic now deleted
fantastic okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
did you enjoy the
show so how many people have do I have
let's say 10
maybe oh
four
okay John joh John Nash A Beautiful Mind
yes John Nash is one of the greatest
mathematician you know top 100 in the in
the past 100 years uh but he's got a
schizophrenic serious which is a serious
problem because you see Illusions you
know you living your with your friends
with your relative it
doesn't because you think they are doing
something but they are not you know
illusion so that's a serious problem
that's why they found it to be more
prevalent in children born during war
and starvation
okay
uh delusions yes
you know Terry Davis you know I watched
some of his videos like uh I have a
friend which is like forchan type of
people you know young guy 15 years ago
you know he told me first about Davis
about Terry Davis you know the tempo OS
it's interesting too because you know
Terry Davis he's creating a God's
operating system this is you know this
is God told him to do it you know and
it's for God or whatever you know
Christian things okay I'm not
Christian but but but
then and it's quite interesting because
you know I watched a few you know videos
you know it's got It's got a buil In
Like A variation of C programming
language he created and a compiler and
everything and also a three CD modeler
Game you know inside you
know so it's quite interesting and
creative um yeah and then he's like
talking
about you know T Terry Davis got this
problem you know he's he's he's saying
this word why why can't we say it
because the [ __ ] deep State scums
that's a Google
right now it's a Google you know it's
Google Facebook you know all the others
okay I got a phone call I got to pick up
okay
okay I gotta go sorry so um so actually
uh shut down I gotta go so
um okay I'll be
back e