hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today's topic is random
we haven't been doing this for a while
for a month I think uh and I haven't
been doing a lot uh some talk show
uh in the past four months or so
uh you know like the reason is there's
not much of a reason but the reason is
kind of every time in the past year I
have been trying to be more focused so
each video is focused on emac emacs or
emac basis programming or Wolfram
language
so I try to be more focused
so there is less of random chat like I
used to do you know like two years ago I
used to do almost every day
uh whatever for one hour whatever comes
to mind so
so you know but the more I try to be
focused the less the less impetus
impetus you know the less kind of even
because you have to plan you have to
think about a topic it's basically more
work but if I do not have a topic if I
do not have a plan if I just go live and
do talk show you know start talk show
like the title is supposed to be then
typically
I have a lot of topics you know like you
guys ask questions I talk
let's check my video is going my audio
is going good to go okay so today's
topic is mostly random uh well I'm gonna
talk about Wolfram language I'm gonna
show you uh
language and machine learning okay
neural networks so I've been doing a lot
of that okay so that's uh and random
okay so you ask questions I answer okay
pay me okay so go to PayPal you know
where to go on my website
saudi.info there's a lot I mean you go
to my home page you'll find the PayPal
link so pay me and then ask me questions
uh talk about or answer that question
okay or you can use Super Chat Super
Chat YouTube takes like 40 you know they
suck your blood and not just that if
they just do that that's fine but they
you know they
a huge censorship and all that
so anyway today so my keyboard as you
know glove 80 search for Sally grab 80
you'll find it my favorite keyboard now
and this is uh
ultimate hacking keyboard version 2. I
have video reviews for them both okay on
my website now let's go to let's switch
to my screen so you can see so let's
start to do some coding okay
again first questions say hi okay if you
are watching
uh okay so let's see so let's the first
stop let's do a Wolfram language you
know this has been one of the things
I've been telling the industrial
programmers especially the list coders
for for 20 years uh usually they don't
listen so let me demonstrate one of the
supremely powerful
language design okay so one of the
functions so let me let me let me go let
me show you where
uh and you know yesterday so Cassat is
good yeah so before we do that let me
tell you about star Discord star Discord
so I have a disco Channel and the recent
you know the Disco they removed
permanent links so right now we don't
have a permanent permanent links okay
but here is a permanent link
let me copy that
uh and let's see if I can paste it
can you can you guys see the link that's
a permanent link while that links last
for one week okay we are trying to fix
that
scored I write a lot a turn on Discord
and all sorts of things
um
okay so that's the start Discord let me
show you the Wolfram language the so if
you don't know yet
so you just search for Sally wufan
language hello Ben thank you for the
money I'm doing good thank you any
questions post a question and I'll
answer so I've been coding I'm back live
with wufam language you know fantastic
let me show you you know uh well I
showed this many times you know um so
anyway you just go to wolfam Language
tutorial you can download it for free I
highly recommend it
um they sponsor me okay so they they
sponsor me I've been coding Wolfram
language since 1990 to okay so for
uh you know 30 years is kind of 30 years
not you know there's some some 10 years
I haven't for some 15 years I haven't
been coding yet but anyway I'm back on
it now uh version 13 so let me show you
uh complan okay so
this uh so uh Wolfram language actually
let me start it so you can see so this
is wolfam language logo over the years
uh the one you know so 1991 this is the
one I'm familiar with most 1991 I've
been using
so over the years and that this logo is
actually my favorite logo okay so but
today
uh Wolfram language version 13 it looks
like that it came out about two years
ago and that's what I have
so actually so let's start with fam
language
okay this is wolfam this is from
language 12 okay not this one
uh where is my okay so it's actually
here
there it is ah friendship
okay we we didn't see the Beautiful
uh
beautiful logo I want to show the
beautiful logo let's try it again there
it is Wolfram 13.
so let's start a new new notebook
let's say three
plus four
shift enter to evaluate it and let's
magnify
okay so you can see
I'm going to show you so wufan language
you know my favorite language so you can
you know go to my website and uh
Language tutorial if you are a student
if you don't have a job right now I re I
I highly recommend you download the
Wolfram engine that's for free okay so
you can read about it what's the
difference with an engine wolf and
script Mathematica what's the
differences and
so you can download it for free if you
have a job you work at you know Google
Amazon or whatever or even a small
company I recommend you just buy it okay
uh it's because it's hugely powerful
it's good for life
there's no other language comparable
comparable okay so for example if you
want to learn about any any kind of
science engineering chemistry physics
mathematics or cellular automata or
computer science all sort of algorithms
you want to explore or graph Theory uh
discrete mathematics statistics
probability you know they have every you
know and especially also machine
learning and neural neural networks I've
been learning a lot of that I'm gonna
talk about it today so it's like nothing
comes close the the closest you might
have today is you know you
um you might get
or something you get the huge
one gigabyte downloader python and
that's only I would say that's only at
most five percent of wolf and language
Mathematica okay that's only five
percent
uh so
so and so let me show you one of the
functions that's in wufam language that
you will not see anywhere in any
programming language like Java C C plus
plus lisp doesn't matter what list
closure uh scheme emac this uh you will
not see anywhere python JavaScript group
Ruby Golan rust you know
the power okay the the kind of the power
of Wolfram language and usually when I
talk to the you know this is one of of
my pen for the past 20 years when I
talked to the industrial programmers
they don't understand they don't get
what you're saying I talked about this a
lot of times in my live stream like
yesterday uh you know I was talking
there's a you know a friend hot dog you
know in our Forum I explained to him
this function and he kind of get it but
he's like oh nobody need it it's just
niche
incredible
you know this because you know so why is
that because actually let me show you
because then you uh you don't know what
I'm talking about okay
so as you know in most languages you
have you have a map function so let me
show you okay so actually let me start a
uh let's start a Wolfram language let's
go to talk show
and today's talk show and let's start a
wolf and language Okay so
I have written
mod it's on GitHub so right now for
example I can show you
the source code you know here's examp
and you go to the source code so there's
about
2600 lines of code and you can go to
this website just search for it showing
browser you'll see subwoofer mod and
it's on GitHub
so why do you code Wolfram language in
emacs because emacs gives you know
especially with stuff like he's gives me
much more efficient uh keystrokes to
manipulate
so anyway because I will find mod that's
what I'm using Okay so let's see let's
map okay so you map a function so
typically in most other languages let me
show you okay so let's say one two uh
three uh okay so you can run it
okay so here's the result this map
function are familiar to you most of you
they it's available in Python JavaScript
these days it was
you know over the past 30 years
programming language kind of improves a
little bit a little bit functions like
map doesn't exist 20 years ago and
gradually it's in kind of in Pearl in
Python then today in Rust of course
um you know because map is kind of the
functional programming concept okay but
anyway you are familiar with this you
map you up you map means apply the
function to each element in the list so
you get that okay so copy that we can do
this in Wolfram language
so okay so what
um so that is the map function most of
us are familiar with but here is the
power of wolfam language okay so let me
uh let me see let me go to
um
yeah so you can map a function to any
specific
depth of a tree so let's say let's Let
Me Show an example okay
uh
okay that's the output now let's see
what what are the questions hey look so
I'm glad you found your account it just
began began learning lisp and have found
your content incredibly helpful thank
you uh hello George
[Music]
so there's a guy I believe a Chinese guy
who bought my emacs tutorial two days
ago I'm gonna send it out okay so if you
like might like my stuff you can buy my
emacs tutorial you can find it online
just search for
emacs tutorial so anyway so this Mac
from map function returns that but what
if you have a tree like that for a
nested list okay
am I doing well yeah can you see it yeah
so yeah
okay
so what if you have that okay so let me
show you so here is a function
uh wait what happened
paste it
okay so XX is a nested Beast
right so you can also show it in kind of
tree form
so actually let me do this so you are
familiar with the percentage sign means
the last input I mean the last output
okay let's let's say XX okay so tree
form will show
The Nest at least in in kind of the tree
style so you can see
you can see that okay so anyway so you
have a nested Beast now you want to map
okay so
uh let's let's do it so
map
okay normally
uh
when you map you get that okay now let's
map to you see you apply the function f
to each of the elements
right
now let's say I want to map to
all the leaves of the tree so what are
the leaves of the tree that means a b c
d e so you can compare over here
so how do you do this in Python well
it's very cumbersome cumbersome you
cannot okay so in wufam language you can
just like this uh negative one
okay so this argument the third argument
specify the level which level you want
to map to for example a second level
in Unix it's called
depth you know in Unix when you find you
know find some directory you you type
the command find you can specify your
depth
but in Unix that means if you specify
three that means step up to three one
two three one and depth one depth two
step three
but you cannot specify just depth three
not one and two you cannot do that in
Unix but anyway so here is how you map
to a
uh to the leaves so you can see
so let's see uh
tree form okay so let's show it in a
graphical uh kind of way
so you see you see those a b c d e
now they have
an F in front of them because f is
mapped to the leaf okay that's the power
of the wufam language so why is this
useful why is this useful
you know in because I write my HTML so
here you can see kind of you know my my
directory uh not here okay so let's go
to talk show
uh actually so open that put it back
color it showing browser so here is what
we did you know
so but we go through the dial directory
shrink so you can see this is my
directory go up one directory shrink so
you can see this is my Sunny info
directory so for example you can go to
emacs then you can
open emacs subdirectory then
you can open sub subdirectory so that's
a picture
you know lots of pictures of emac stuff
so anyway so you have nested directories
so sometimes I want to do a find and
replace on all the files in your
directory but however I only want to do
them on level 2 for example specifically
or
subdirectories that are at the depth too
not depth one just two
not F3 so sometimes you want to do that
so in Unix you know typically the
command is find Dot
depth you know and you you you pass it
to um
uh what What's the
yeah you xox and the set or grab
whatever
but the depth it will do depth one depth
to depth three you know all of them so
that's no good I just wanted three you
cannot do that so that's one of the
example but why do you need to do that
because because when you have a file
with lots of
um
with lots of relative links like dot dot
slash dot dot
you know you you want to specify the
same level of directories otherwise all
your relative links will be screwed for
example I want to change the name for
example this is a CSS file
uh you know this is a CSS file so so if
I renamed the CSS file and I want to
change all of the links to that file
you have to be sure that you know the
you kind of just oh I mean if you re if
you move to this file to One Directory
up or one direct directory down so in
that case you want to change all the
relative links when you do that you want
to specify just the third level
directory so things like that
okay so anything else so
yeah okay so
okay so that's that's about
these
concept okay so this is this is about so
the map function you can specify
you can specify a level like what you
know or a range of level like from the
first one to the third one and when the
level number is negative that means
count from the last count from the
Leaf of the tree so if you have negative
one that's the leaf of the tree or the
nested list if you have negative two
that's the you know you know that's one
branch above the leaf so this is very
powerful you know I've been programming
pool Farm language since 1992 then I
started to learn lisp because lisp is
very much related and and I don't see
this English so I was wondering because
I I was a fan of Wolfram language and
lisp you know because you know emacs and
AI so I was so how come this doesn't
have this like I was puzzled about this
issue for 20 years 20 years since about
2000 year 2000.
so I talked to the lisbus the master
lisbus the expert the common disperse
you know like they don't
they don't know I mean they don't they
they don't buy my you know they think
who needs to do that you know like like
they don't they don't get it
so 20 years ago I'm not you know I don't
know I'm kind of a beginner programmer
you know I don't know much about things
you know then some you know I try to
tell them language look at this you know
and they don't like they don't oh that's
fun you know that's it you know
so I was puzzled and sometimes I got
into argument he did argument like like
they don't get it so they they say
they'll say nobody does that or they all
say oh it's trivial you just you can
just write it in five minutes which is
false by the way okay I got an argument
with Dia you know
you you know
so
so I was personal for for 20 years but
you know over the 20 years I have
learned so much programming languages
computer science theory you know
algorithms theoretical computer science
I know I kind of now know why
lisp does not have this
the the reason this does not have this
because the conspired [ __ ] it up you
know because in this lists are not
Primitives lists are made of Concepts
anyway do I make sense
um
so if you want to know about that
so you can you know I have written a lot
a lot articles about these cons issues
so you can read about fundamental
problems of lisp uh
uh you know this article just search for
it and read it this is this is written
in 2008
okay
and the cons thing the lispers like they
why don't they like why do they not
agree or understand
this point
and automatically that's because it
became it has become a code
just like emacs or Vim or Unix uni you
know Unix philosophy when you become a
code people don't think anymore
could we Implement custom support inside
of list to support it yes you can so you
know it's a great exercise just to write
this function okay so you if you are
learning lisp you could
try to write a list program
that does this
okay
uh
there there are some libraries that kind
of similar but never like never
comprehensive like what I'm doing let me
show you the documentation for the map
okay so in stuff like his tab F ink
subwoofer mod you can see the
documentation for the map function
JavaScript
and now enlarge it
now you can see
there it is the level spec okay and then
you see the level spec can be a number
or it can be Infinity that means to all
levels whatever whatsoever you know 9000
or a million
uh or you can put inside a curly braces
that means specifically just that level
otherwise it's 1 to n
okay or you can have two numbers
in a list that means from this level to
that level
a range of levels
so you can read this and there's a lot
examples then you can try to implement
that in lisp
okay so the you see the thing about this
wolfam this thing level spec is that in
general when you have an expression
let's say this one nested list you know
nested this is tremendously useful
because nested list is also used to
represent Matrix or nested Matrix of
five dimensional Matrix or three any
three is a nested Beast
Okay so
so when you have a tree or a matrix of
let's say 10 dimensions
the level aspect or the level of the
tree which basically means you can
specify a particular column or
depth of the tree so any function not
just the function map any function that
deal with at least
in Wolfram language has this level spect
ER
so this is just not for this function so
for example you want to delete certain
elements you can specify only at that
level you know when they match your
function or something oh oh when they
match your pattern or when they are zero
or simply delete everything in that
level you know things like that
so for example I can delete all the
leaves of the tree
you know so
Okay so
delete uh
anyway so
that's about that
yeah crochet is a different different
closure doesn't have con sales which is
excellent you know it's like finally
after 30 30 years crochet is excellent
however
closure issue with closure is that it
heavily it is heavily intertwined with
Java so I like this very much I've been
coding closure for about a year uh
and get paid for it thanks for uh thanks
to David [ __ ] one of the big closure
Coda well no okay David [ __ ] so
so he was helping me you know he paid me
to do some closure work uh closer the
language is at least right I like it
very much however
I realized it's deeply deeply
intertwined with Java and of course it
runs on jvm but however the language is
not independent from java like every
notion it refers you to Java objects
Java regular expression Java stream this
function creates a JavaScript string
what does that mean well you look up the
Java string documentation or Java
regular expression documentation so it's
deeply intertwined with Java
and Java is the circus language and
extremely complex because you know if
you don't know it's you know object
oriented you have to call object you
have to you know you have to write
classes then create objects object then
you have methods
you know it's like pure it's pure op
so then then you have you know in Java
then you have abstract class you have
interfaces you know so enclosure if you
really want to understand it in depth
you know you read the documentation for
closure functions you know get the
element of at least then it says oh this
is this is the Java interface something
so you have to look up you have to
understand what Java interface means
exactly so that is the bad part about
closure I don't like
uh okay anything else
so let me show you some articles I have
about what we just talked about
so I have a lot articles so I you know
during the time 2014 I wrote some basic
crochet tutorial uh
okay and then the article I want to show
you is
you know so in closure you can call
every Java methods
uh then you have collections list Vector
set map and sequences so closure doesn't
have the list cons that's excellent
yeah but the problem is that it
intertwines with Java so much so that
you basically have to if you really want
to match the closure you have to kind of
Master Java too because the rich hiki he
came from you know he came from a Java
Enterprise programming
uh so where is it so let me find the
article uh
so there it is
so these two articles I want to show you
one is Croatia's popularity a Tango with
Java okay
so I explain why it's intertwined with
Java so wait is this this one or another
one
trapped in the Java Train Northbound is
closure southbound is Scala okay people
don't like Java that's why they so you
have two choices
uh and so
the one I want to show is okay why
crochet is dense okay
so in this article you can see
how it is you know what I think closure
is very
fairly complex you know it's like
paradoxical because the guy
which hiki
you know his idea is he's he's very much
emphasizing simply Simplicity which I
completely agree
you know programming language becomes so
complex and you have different protocols
you have different languages and many
details and exceptions and
uh and especially in Unix you know lots
of problems and all these problems
essentially stem from complexity
for example in JavaScript huge
Watts number of words and Dome you know
it's like [ __ ] total [ __ ]
so richiki
one of the things he and he he his idea
his philosophy in programming language
is like focusing on two things
one is you know he like pushing it like
the idea of Simplicity he he thinks that
is the most important thing I totally
agree
now the other idea he pushes for is is
uh functional programming and parallel
programming which he created much of
closure is that okay so that's also a
good thing but I don't know much about
that topic parallel concurrent you know
concurrency and parallel programming
these are kind of related but separate
so anyway closure is you know very and
functional programming so no States you
know every you know he has a
philosophy about the whole thing but
anyway the other thing he emphasized is
simplicity
uh he's got a jargon something like
something like
I forgot what's a jargon something like
something is simple to do uh when you do
something that's I forgot what's a
jargon but anyway Simplicity is one of
his emphasis emphasis emphasis okay but
however the closure language is deeply
intertwined with Java
you know so in that sense there's no
Simplicity because when you want to
understand for example for example
here closure collections so you have
these different type of data structure
list Vector set map and sequence okay
so
normally when you want to master
programming language you study the
detail and all these you know these are
the most important uh things in any
language basically this hash table or
dictionary or Turbo or vector you know
because that's that's your data that's
the most important element in just about
every language
so closure has them you know you know
list Vector set map and sequence okay so
you want to understand the detail you
know what's their differences and so on
so you when you so when you study
closure then you'll see
you know let me see if I can show
example let's say closure Vector okay so
uh
you know this is very outdated close
your documentation I have on my site
uh
array map okay so you have this array
map key pair okay so you have different
you have you have
very fancy ones array map so did map
hash map okay let's look at array map
okay so uh I'm trying to find an example
where
uh
they talk about
so basically what I'm saying is that
let's see closure map okay
closure map function Returns the lazy
sequence consisting of the results of
applying F to a set of first items of
each call collection
uh also closed closure prefers to use
all these abbreviations
okay so first item of each collection
followed by applying F to second item in
collection so anyway my point is that
when you look into the detail what are
the collection and differences they
basically just say it's a Java interface
for something okay
so then you have to understand what what
exactly is you know they is a Java
interface
and so on so actually I have an example
somewhere here
okay let me read it then
this stuff Paran Marcus reader okay so
that's all part of closure very complex
these are the reasons why crochet is
hard to understand it's kind of um hard
to learn language so first of all it has
the lisp concept of parent markers and
reader now reader is a thing very few
people really understand okay okay so
crochet has that
then crochet has its own idiosyncratic
concept and technology that does not
exist in any other language okay not in
Haskell not in erlan nodding Wolfram
language
not in common lisp not in emac bisp not
in Java okay it has like its own you you
know for example transducer
metadata that's what not that you know
disclosure metadata that's not what you
think when you think of metadata you
know it's kind of different okay no
other language has it closure has its
own concept of protocol you know when
you hear the protocol you might be
thinking HTTP protocol email protocol
that's not what it is here you know
closure has its own protocol closures
the enclosure has ref and transactions
atoms and agents those are related to uh
concurrent computation or parallel
computation
okay so you know this concept not in
anywhere closure it's closer thing then
closure is has this abuse of syntax and
thirst function function names okay for
example
let me show you okay so these are what's
called seizures in programming Okay so
uh basically weird characters in
function names like that
or slash or you know so here is a page
that explains them all
magic characters or you call them
seizures that's part of the function
name so for example you can you you can
slash slashes for namespace separator
okay then you have the asterisk in
function name or a variable name in any
in identifier name that means when you
see your asterisk
a name starting and ending asterisk
asterisk that means this this name is
building okay it's a building variable
okay then
if it start with asterisks but not
ending with it that means it's um
building variable whose value will
change often okay so then you have
question mark then you have explanation
you have you have
minus sign you have colon you have
double colon so and you have you know
then you have Ampersand you have
percentage you know so this kind of
thing
and you have a DOT one single dot is a
function name okay then you have double
dot then you have dollar sign you know
some name dollar sign something okay
that means access Java inner class okay
then you have
correct correct colon correct
quote and you have ADD sign Cancer you
know
these things they break the convention
of lisp okay
in this programming languages typically
they use full names they don't use this
cryptic shortcuts there's a few in
general but you know in general not you
know closures is like got a ton of them
Plus
you know like then you know you have
back tick you know uh
single quote
grave accent sign
then you have theodosine you know so
closure is filled with this plus their
function names is very short like they
don't use full names often for example
different
I forgot what's the difference Define
enclosure Define function is what
um
for example
function okay
yeah FN you see FN
FN is defining a function so really
cheeky you know he'd be your coaches so
he
it's filled with this you know so you
have death death is one of the function
to define a function FN is I suppose F A
is Lambda okay I haven't used for a long
time so you have def then you have def n
d f n then you have FN you know cryptic
names that's that's all over closure all
over
so
so this is this is a departure from the
tradition the kind of the convention
these family languages they don't have
that so Croatia is kind of unique unique
in that sense
so anyway so we are kind of digressing
into why closure is
um
is
dense is kind of complex okay
so let's see if we can
yeah so you have that then you have
abuse of syntax toast function names
okay then you have intermingle with Java
the language okay so for example sick
okay he's sick you know another very
first name seq okay that's a function
name
so what does it mean usage okay return a
sec sequence it means sequence okay
return a sec on the collection if the
collection is empty return near okay uh
return yeah okay and SEC also works on
strings native Java arrays and any
object that implements iterable there it
is you see so you want to understand SEC
you know one of the important questions
then you read the you know the
documentation then it says okay native
Java arrays what the [ __ ] is native Java
array what is the difference between
let's say Java array and Native Java
array you don't know because it's Java
he's talking about Java then it says any
object that implements iterable what the
[ __ ] is iterable that's not a crucial
thing that's Java thing so you have to
go study Java e-tourable
okay trouble is the interface so what's
the interface well you have to study
Java Java interface Java's concept of
interface okay then blah blah blah no
that's know that s e q s okay now here
is the function s e q s that's different
from seq
so it says I don't know if that's a
function or what so note that seq s
cache values thus seq must not be used
on any e-trollable whose iterator
repeatedly Returns the same multiple
object
[ __ ] incons comprehensible [ __ ]
that is why closure is dense
you know in this document you just in
this piece of documentation by itself
they they mentioned one bunch of java
Concepts that's not part of crochet they
mentioned a bunch of java concept and
the writing the using of the you know
extremely thirst brief you don't know
what he's talking about then you know
like the rich hiki guy when he write
documentation
it's like he assume you being
programming Java for 10 years and you've
been programming this for 10 years
that's that's a situation you know like
a bunch of then
is this sequence should not be used on
any etrobo whose iterator repeatedly
Returns the same mutable object what the
[ __ ] is that
there it is
now this documentation I am quoting is
kind of old from this article 2016 okay
now let's look up what is the current
article for the seq function for closure
closure seq okay let's see we can find
it okay closure sequences okay that's
not a good documentation because this is
one of the essay
which hiki wrote you know you can try to
read this one there are about 10 of them
uh you know
you know you know rich rich cheeky so
this article
is kind of documentation sort of because
it's an essay it's not actually a
documentation you know no more sense
it's like part of the 10 extra essays
where he talks about he kind of
introduced you the ideas of closure
things like data type and whatever so
it's you know so there's an essay about
sequences
crochet defines many algorithms in terms
of sequences seqs seq a sec is a logical
list and unlike most lisps whether this
is represented by a concrete to slot
structure cons he doesn't mention
crochet use the isec interface
what the [ __ ] is Isaac interface that's
part of java again you know so closure
use part use the isec in interface to
allow many data structures to provide
access to other to their elements or
sequences okay so anyway so there is a
link to the sequence function so let's
click on that
okay so here is the documentation for
the current documentation for the seq
function
yeah exactly just like I quoted it it
didn't change you know one bunch of
JavaScript jargons that you don't
understand
tutorials on sitting up on a setting up
emacs for typescript
uh yes
so how long have I been talking close to
an hour so maybe that's it so
I guess today we talked about closure
and we didn't talk about machine
learning much yeah machine learning is
very interesting uh
let me answer that question okay type
script and also let me mention uh some
news about Richard Stoneman this is what
he looks like today apparently it seems
like he got cancer
so it's kind of sad uh you know although
you know it's kind of sad because after
all he has he has been um
you know leader of the emacs well I mean
he made emacs right emacs is my favorite
thing I've been using for 20 years so
and in the past 10 years he has not done
very many great things for emacs but but
still you know he's you know he's one
you know the founder so apparently he
got cancer
you know I I'm not hundred percent sure
yet 90 percent because I just learned
about this today uh you can click to
watch the video you know so
something you know so he he's lost or
his hair so he's you know he looks very
different
um
foreign
crochet
um
yeah so closure you know I wish he is a
my last word about kosher now all the
you know all these issues
there's one thing that is
most problematic to me that is the
intertwining with Java okay so if
closure because Java Java is the worst
language it's a huge humongous
and it's slow okay it's you know some
people say claim Java is actually fast
very fast well the the the the the the
Practical matter is that whenever you
develop in Java you have to run J jvm
including closure and all your fans if
you don't have a fast machine with lots
of memory all your fans start to war
whenever you run a jade application
written in jvm
and you know and Java is the circus the
worst language you know you today is
what it was created by by some
Microsystems one of the most scum
cooperation back you know 20 years ago
the microsystem most most scum
Corporation they try to you know not
support Linux anyway that's history you
guys don't know and Richard Stromae has
written about the Java trap but anyway
it's very complex you go to Oracle site
then they they some Microsystems they
love jargons Java what jvn a Java
Enterprise JV jvjs something something
Java Java beans you know 100 bunch of
incomprehensible jargons Java and when
you go to their website you know then
you have development
jde you know Java development kit kit
then you have the Enterprise kit you
know they have so many versions like you
don't know what the [ __ ] is going on
Java you know like the sun Microsystems
you know they created Java they are the
worst
the marketing scan you know and they
they they they they do bad things okay
JavaScript so Microsystems then it got
bought by Oracle another giant biggest
gun in the Computing industry or World
Cup
so it's then closure is like intertwined
with it yeah
when you start the closure app if you
don't have 1000 gigabyte the memory or
stuff or slow computer all the fans
start to work and then
every time you you try to match the
closure then you you read one bunch of
java stuff like oh this is Java
Ito interface what the [ __ ] is either
what is [ __ ] is either interface you're
gonna go study Java interface you know
so that's the situation
uh
I also coded Java for a year you know
long ago
so you could
um
search for
my Java tutorial my Java tutorial is
very old okay so it's like 15 years old
okay so if you want to know about you
know like various
solid fundamental concepts of java
what's Java interface
you know what's abstract class for
example you have abstract class very
complex the ROP [ __ ] you know then you
need abstract class then you need
interface
um then then you have arrays then you
cannot do you know it's like it's it's
just [ __ ] okay
Java but better than C and C plus plus I
would say
Okay so
so yeah I would the one thing I wish is
that
closure of course you know closure calls
itself a hosted language just like
JavaScript meaning that it's not a
language independent
it's not an independent language like
python python Golan
communist
or Ruby or Pearl you know it is but
instead it's like it needs a host okay
so the current implementation is like
hosted on jvm so it kind of like so
that's what it you know called hosted
language so you have enclosure you can
access all Java things
uh so what I wish is that you know so
it's hosted okay but stop you know at
least in your documentation stop
constantly refer to the Java stuff you
know you know try to be you know
independent then
and uh you know my best wish is that
closure becomes a independent language
so you don't have to run on Java jvm if
that is the case if closure becomes
independent I would love it you know a
modern at least
I don't want Java I don't want anything
to do with Java or jvm
okay the the question about typescript
is that you
well for me
okay so let me start the typescript okay
so right now you are seeing my son talk
show
and uh let's start a typescript I'm
using side HTML mod
and so you can see I start a typescript
block
and showing browser this empty type
script
then I
press the button it pops into its own
window
I mean let's say console log 3 let's say
constant okay in typescript you can
Define types right I haven't been doing
typescript for a long time so
I suppose you know it's actually
redundant because it can infer so here's
a typescript and let's say
console log X okay
print it and let's say so I have my
commands so I'm using
actually what I'm using is Javascript
mod okay so let me show you
actually I can just go here
so I have a command type script compile
file okay
Eva region Eva line complete symbol I
can run this script for example let's
run it okay
oh stream uh what is the is being a wire
I type let's see
let's see my typescript tutorial which
is not very good it's just basics
uh what what is the
oh yeah you forgot the colon
okay so you have to put a colon there
okay so now if you run the script
you can see it's TT okay let's say some
thing okay run it
okay that's the output uh and the
command you run it is Saran couldn't
file okay so you can search it
okay so you have the code in emac this
you can copy it and you'll get it
uh you know so you can do the same thing
I do but if you want to run typescript
you need to install demo I highly
recommend
okay
so let me show you the page then or
intro it's the best okay never use
not JS or npm use Deno okay there's a
current a new one called bun
Ben JS uh
I don't know too much about that one but
I highly recommend Deno because the guy
is a great guy he's one of the most
competent programmer in mathematician
and also most integral Ryan doll okay he
created not JS but not JS got corrupted
with you know that guy what's his name
npm guy a very bad guy
so I recommend Deno so you have to
install Deno then you install
um
what is this
when can fire okay so where is that
oh yeah so you install then you get the
code here
install dinner then you can run it
you know just like what I'm doing you
just print then okay so that's one thing
that will help you run typescript the
other thing is I'm using I'm actually
using my own JavaScript mod so let me
show you
okay so you can see I'm using sar.js mod
okay so open that
is 1600 lines of code uh if you like my
stuff you have to pay me okay pay me and
you get this file so this JavaScript mod
it also
uh
typescript it also handles typescript so
for example you have typescript compile
file for example we go through this line
you have the typescript compiler which
compiler you want to use I'm using
Microsoft's default okay so for example
let's compile this file close close Okay
so let's go to the directory
so here is the directory for that file
let's delete the backup
okay so here is the
file type script
and let's compile it okay so
type c
now it's compile successful okay so you
go to the directory again
refresh
your C
too big
there it is you see
this and this you see so it's it's
you see so you open the so this is a
compiled output
you see it removed that
uh let me show you okay it removed that
stream type specific specification so
that's one way to go you can just use my
uh you know if you want pay me
I think it's thirty dollars okay
it's open source
so
uh otherwise you
otherwise I don't have much
recommendation I mean Microsoft has one
Microsoft has a
let's see let's search Sally
typescript Emax they
okay so the compile type script command
is also here so you can grab the code
just search for it because uh emacs
compile typescript file okay
and then
I'm trying to find
an article where
they
exactly Microsoft
typescript
you know when typescript came out 10
years ago they actually thanks me for my
you know for my emacs tutorial
so yeah here is Microsoft original
typescript
package
you know typescript.el
and uh
and they
they thanks me for it
somewhere uh
let me let me go to my blog and find it
[Music]
so there's a lot articles about
Microsoft because lots of controversies
with Microsoft
yeah one bunch of Microsoft mouse and
keyboard articles okay so let's type
Microsoft end typescript
[Music]
some interesting articles and this is
back then when coffeescript is still
around and Dot which is Google's
trying to replace JavaScript
kind of failed
uh
yeah this one is interesting because
this is a source code of typescript you
you actually find this this in
typescript source code
and that you look at that
Okay so
yeah I I I I cannot find weight
I I want to find that article
so I think the title contains typescript
or it contains Microsoft
Microsoft minus keyboard
minus Mouse
minus hatred
thank you Ben
there it is Microsoft cites ago emacs so
this is 2012 when typescript came out
so I think they
you know mentioned my emacs tutorial
for the Emax package
let's see if they still there
yeah his gun
okay that's it for today I think
catchy search I don't know what is Kaji
such kaji's Kaji used to be
one of the
like payment system like if you are a
independent software developer you can
write your software you can sell it on
catchy
that's what it used to be but so I don't
know what you mean by catchy such
okay I think that's it for today
anything anything else
does do I play any video games yeah I
used to but now I'm getting old
okay thank you guys bye
hello Alan
yeah
you know the funny funny things in our
Discord we
came person posted a video
because I was Hitler oh my God Google is
gonna censor me I mean I'm not going to
show it um
well anyway
bye
okay close shut down in one minute
now I want to gather all the links I've
talked about and put it in the talk show
page okay
so Rankin file close typescript compile
compile confile
okay put there because that
and the Microsoft typescript
miscellaneous notes no that's not it
research typescript ladder flow
interesting
because typescript will kill coffee
script in dot okay that's kind of
back then 2012.
when they are trying to compete
test typescript Miss notes close
Microsoft sites or go emacs thank you I
need to change that name to
Microsoft
well
okay close close
bye