hello good morning hello good morning
welcome to another episode of EX talk
show so today we got we are going to
code emac L uh this is going to be maybe
20 minutes to 30 minutes so short okay
my keyboards glove at ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic check YouTube I have
reviews on it okay let's begin Let's uh
so we're going to do it this quickly if
you are watching offline um you know
Skip around and play at uh speed two or
something and if you are here say hi
okay we just going to code emac this
quickly today so the job is to uh I'm I
need to modify my command so here is uh
the thing okay so something you want to
turn l a line into a HTML list okay so
for example dog cat elephant hello buo
so we got dog cat elephant and press
this key they become a list showing
browser so you can see so back to emac
undo
undo okay do it so that command is HTML
lines to list so uh you know uh describe
key then I press the key so here's the
documentation C HTML lines to list it's
in C HTML mod if you like it pay me kind
of donate and I send it to you it's all
open source okay so you can see Kar HTML
search for Kar HTML mod you'll you'll
find it or UHA packages this is all my
packages they used to be free for like
10 years but nobody cares you know
nobody pays and you become T support so
I stopped doing you know giving up
free so you know the CHL mod is actually
my most um lines of code you know
because I work with HTML so all these
are functions you know you got 94
functions uh insert tag remove tag image
tag ined image in ined YouTube and so on
ined PDF and you know uh you know so
anyway so let's let's focus so we we're
going to modify this command let me tell
you why I need to modify so let's see so
let me show you another command I want
to remove all the list uh yeah so do
this do this you know press three keys
and they they become that they back to
lines so you know sometimes you have
lines but sometimes you have uh
something okay so this is a paragraph So
when you're working with HTML sometimes
you have that okay now you want to make
these lines but you don't want include
you don't want to include this P
paragraph obviously so but if I call the
Le two lines they include that you know
paragraph because this this two lines
HTML HTML lines to this they they
capture the delimiter by empty lines so
you need the need need to have a empty
lines or you have to select it uh
actually um no if you select it it does
something else but if you have like for
example uh this is a
long
paragraph something like that you want
to make this one list item so
that's when you do a selection so you
select them then you call the command
then show in browser you
see so anyway so the problem I have now
is to I want to modify the command so
that so that if a line start with a
um uh you know the markup HTML tag it
should consider that as a delimited
H uh so actually now we have a design
issue
so yeah so first of all you your code
should grab all the empty lines
then uh you see the problem is sometimes
let's let's make it this way so it's
easier to
see you know so sometimes you have
something above it and something below
it so what you're going to do in those
case uh I don't know you know so this is
about designing user interface design so
you think about what exactly you want to
do how you know exactly what you to do
uh the command you should be doing
exactly you have to think about that
then you code so for example in HTML we
have you know like usually you have
blank blank lines you
know so why do I want to do this because
I want to save keystrokes you know it
gets annoying every time you have to go
to the bottom you know because this
situation
happens so anyway let's let's just push
on okay let's just move to wherever
whatever we need to do and go you
know think about it as we go so let's
look at the source code of this okay so
describe key press the key for that
command here is the documentation jump
to the source code look at it so here is
a source
code
now let's let's try the
um let's try the uh senser font not
monospace eight concurrent viewers
fantastic hello guys
Alexandra Alexandra and blue
R so here's a source code and in fact
the source code is on the website so
open it showing browser so you can grab
it you know and it'll
work uh and uh so now we want to modify
this let's think about how we want to do
okay open a new buffer paste it and copy
the function name save it XX today's
date then function
name. okay that's so we got a temp file
to work with just this function
so so the first
thing so let let me go over how this
command works so basically you just
first of all find
out you know find the uh let's let's go
back to find the beginning of the empty
line search you search backward by two
back slash end okay then you search
forward by two back sln then you got
this text block then you just just uh
grab that text block then then you split
that text by a empty line you know End
of Line character so you got a list of
items emac list of items then it's easy
then you
just okay so let's let me show okay so
that that then you just insert UI Ur at
the top and also insert the slash Ur at
the bottom then for each this item you
just insert Li the item then slash Li so
that's how you'll do it so let's try
again do it you see fantastic undo line
to list undo okay so that's a basic how
this command works and you can uh okay
shall we so for example let me show
you so this in so this function takes a
beginning and end
position and and uh okay sorry about
that scratch my
eyes beginning end position and uh takes
uh item
separate regular expression normally
it's just one single BL uh End of Line
character but sometimes you want two you
know or multiple end of BL blank line in
case um so anyway a bit you know tedious
detail so
that's um then you want it ordered so
when you have it ordered through this
optional argument that means uh do a
ordered list instead of an ordered list
you know an ordered list is URL ordered
is
your an order is UL order list is
O Okay so for example I press a
universal command which is control U
then I call the command and now you see
you got a older list O So showing
browser you got older list like that so
that's so so the function first you know
when you are
calling interactively like meta X
something that's when you need this
interactive interactive block this will
basically fill out the parameters to the
function so how do we feel it so we
basically you know if region is active
then just get the region beginning and
region end that's a selection then then
the item separator is going to be two
End of Line
characters so that allows you to if you
have you know one of the least item is
actually a paragraph multiple
lines and then the ordered you know
whether you want order list or an order
list that depends on whether you
called whether you pressed control u in
the beginning so if you do control U
like uh describe key control U that's
actually coding the universal
argument and uh
if if the user code you know press
control U first then this curent prefix
AR which is a building variable that
will be true so that's how you know you
know where whether you want to do all
the list or not so that's the
interactive block which just fills this
uh parameters for you so once you have
the parameters then you do so then then
you you know like just I described okay
so local
variables uh so if begin and end end is
NE and this gets a bit tedious to
explain and also because here I'm
calling my own function but this
function is actually easy to understand
this function just just return the
beginning and end position of empty
lines so this function so you see it
just search backward by one empty line
character then maybe a space or tab
character multiple of them then another
line empty empty line character so
basically just two empty lines so so
that would be the beginning delimiter
for a text block like that okay then you
search forward and do the same thing
search for those regular expression then
you just return the beginning position
you know those two positions and end
position that's what this get command
block so you can also see the source
code you can grab it if you go uh if you
code emac this is right
here so let's close that so you know so
I'm setting up the beginning and end
position here then grab the text you
know beginning end position substring no
properties that Returns the string
between those two positions then you set
up your regular expression for the
separator of each list item so so if the
regular expression is given that's a
beginning that's you know that's a
parameter here so if it's given then
just use that otherwise use a uh End of
Line character so once you got the you
know so so far you got all the
parameters filled you know all the
required parameters to that's Essence
what you need to to to uh
turn lines to a list then you start to
code uh you know actually turning so you
can
see uh
has empty lines if if it does have empty
lines items so you see the split string
we split the text block into a list of
items split
string then
you um then you turn each list item into
a you add Li and slash Li to each item
okay so that's a list then
you then you join
them okay the code is a bit complicated
because I'm
determining has empty line why do I need
to determine has empty
line uh
[Music]
because yeah that's because when you
want
to
turn
some
thing uh wait C something
okay cat something and dog
something then you select all you want
this to be um list item but each list
item is actually multiple lines so
that's when you do this okay so you see
that's one item so showing browser cat
something dog something so that is why
I'm doing this has empty lines okay so
has empty lines
but uh but wouldn't that be has to do
has to do with the regular expression I
forgot you know this this code turn
lines to list is pretty old so you know
here it says 2022 but actually it's like
10 years old more than 10 uh 2020
actually 2013 okay
something created in 20 13 so you know
because over the past decade I've tried
I've you know improved the code in one
way or another change the user interface
I've also uh sometimes change the
function name
so yeah so okay so where are we
going okay so
actually then you just then you just
start to narrow to region
then ah so many code okay so then you
start to insert now if you want if the
user requested all the list you insert u
o and/ o otherwise it's ul and
then okay then it does something else
okay then it goes through each line the
insert line and remove the dash in front
or remove period or remove the unic code
bullet
so what does that do uh that does is
like if you have cat so for example the
in the markdown so when you have a on
the list you use the dash okay
cat space uh Dash space dog okay so when
you call the command it turns to cat and
dog without the dash because you don't
need it now so that is so you have to
remove the dash and in you know one
thing annoying about markdown is that
you can also use the multiplication
character which is also allowed so you
also have to remove the multiplication
character and the other thing is that
for me sometimes I use the Unicode
bullet okay bu becomes a bullet cat Okay
bu dog that's done by a brief so like
everything I talked about it's all in my
emac list tutorial so you should uh you
guys should you know check it out make
use of it emac this this Basics emac
this you know all the all the all this
um you know search forward how do you
get the block of text how do you turn a
text given to beginning and and region
position turn turn them into turn into a
string you can all find it you know
tutorial uh about them so so back to the
code so what we want to do now actually
so we we are like okay let's try this
one okay that's a unical bullet so you
can describe chart so you can
see name bullet okay that's so that
that's a unic code bullet which I
sometimes use I you can turn it into a
list okay so that's why in the code uh
in the
code you
have this block of of code so this is
done when you insert the list then you
want to remove you know beginning you
know those Beginning
characters uh you know there are so many
ways to do it because you can remove
them before you insert so you know so
um do it at the end may not be the most
efficient but but
anyway
so so what we want to do now do we so
now we looked at the code do we want to
still to
prevent uh prevent you know so if you
have like cat
dog then you don't want to include
this as part of the list
so do I want to have that feature yes
because it's useful because if I turn
this into a list that's not what we want
you know this this you know and
sometimes it's worse for example let me
show you sometimes it's worse okay so
sometimes is for example let's change
this paragraph to a
dive so I press a key okay so I press a
key change it to dive do it so you can
see now it's dive now when you have a
dive sometimes usually it's long so this
is long something you know it could be
you know a page pages long it it can be
a you know interactive JavaScript or
whatever so when you have this situ
situation for example now you call turn
into a list you be you get that and that
is invited HTML so showing browser you
know
that that is invalid
HTML so you know so you do want this
feature you want this feature so okay so
we decided we do want this feature of
turning a line in into a list but when
one of the line is starting with a
um opening angle bracket you want to
consider that as the
end or the beginning okay so opening
bracket is the end if you have a opening
bracket then that's the beginning so
let's uh try to do this
again
um so insert the dive some okay let's
see
okay so when you have this
situation then you call the command it
should also it should also do these two
okay so you want to
consider
okay I have to think about so what uh
you
see so we are still in the designing
stage about the user interface exactly
what you want to do because then you
have several
situations what if you have something in
the
middle uh and your Cruiser is here
okay so but what if your Cruiser is here
that's another case Edge case uh I think
we can ignore that case you see to fully
do this is is going to be quite
involved um but we would just consider
the more common situ ation the cruiser
would be here okay so you want to search
for okay there's another issue for
example if you have a URL link for
example you have a UR link then we do
want
to consider this line as a
item so okay so it gets complicated what
if the line is just the URL itself in
that case we also want to consider it as
item yeah okay so
this so there's quite a lot situations
you see so actually so right now I'm
thinking maybe we shouldn't do
it because if you add a feature where
you know where it's going to skip this
dive
tag then but then you do want you know
when you have a link like that you do
want that to be part of the Leist
item
so you become you have the situation
that some of the tag it will skip some
of the tag it will not so to the user is
starting to become
complex and you don't want that I mean
though even though sometimes it's
convenient but you know but then use a
have a hard time to figure out exactly
when is a
tag you know consider the end of the
thing um yeah so that's a
issue so actually now I'm thinking that
um maybe we don't add this feature or if
we add the feature then we're going to
start to check the tag names
because tag a would be allowed okay but
tag
[Music]
dive you see then it gets really complex
because you have something bold okay
let's say
bold the question is do you you know
obvious obviously in this case you do
want that bat to be part of the line you
know line
item but not dive okay so so now the
situation is you have to look at all
HTML tags which tag should you skip
which tag should you keep to be part of
the line okay so this is getting really
complex you know just to think about the
user interface
design uh so
because there are let's see uh HTML tags
you know they are like 30 tags
also uh you know header meta are you
know obviously you want to skip them
because you don't encounter those in the
body often but then you have nav header
footer usually you also skip those main
aside article
section uh what about
H3 H header header heading TXS you also
skip them you consider them as beginning
or end of the list of lines okay then
what about text block
uh here it gets complicated because you
see technically by HTML spec this di P
pre block block quote and erra they are
technically
allowed they are allowed as part of the
LI tag they are allowed to be inside of
it uh but in practice does people do
them yeah sometimes actually people do
sometimes you know like sometimes you do
want to have a dive inside you know like
some you know
something uh wait okay so you need to
select it wrap a dive tag around it okay
so this is you know sometimes you do
want that in some
situations yeah so
yeah and then you have Leist tag it gets
more complex Ned least then then span em
strong B italic obviously you want to
consider consider them as part of the
line
uh yeah so overall the whole thing gets
very complex what about table usually
table is not inside the list
okay uh image yes image is
often inside the list tag okay yeah so I
decided you know now we looked over the
issue I decided I'm not going to add
this convenient
[Laughter]
feature maybe you know so I think this
is interesting because you
see like typically when when we think
about coding we just think about the
problem is how to code you know in
Python JavaScript how to code
it but
actually um you know from my experience
you know been coding in the past 30
years I
think half the problem is actually like
about half of the problem is actually
designing the user
interface function for example if you
are writing a function exactly what kind
of parameters you want and also buling
parameters especially when you have
bullying parameters you know the worst
example in this design scenario is the
Unix command line you you know the
Unix idiot idiots the Unix and Linux
these type of people and
see you know the unix commands for
example typically they have one bunch of
confusing options like AB bcde e FG g
overwrites d but if you include D it it
toggles C you know like incomprehensive
crap that's Unix bash and the shell
tools uh okay let me pedal my Unix
website I think today we are done I
mean uh you know today we decided we're
going to not going to write the command
we went through I hope it's useful to to
learn about this user interface design
issue you know today is a good example
so anyway in Unix you know you got uh
you know the this bunch of crab
commands let's see where where can I see
a bunch of them uh let's see let's check
for
bash bash Keys uh well so yeah so anyway
Unix is just whole bag of baggage 40
Years of
History so you see when you use unix
commands you often see the very
extremely badly designed function
options you know they say according to
the uni Unix philosophy small is
beautiful in fact it's not the
Unix is not beautiful at all because
each command do like they stamp on each
other for example the most po um common
example is the Unix
find and XO you know there's a lot
interplay you are and also if you do LS
uh wait not LS copy for example
sometimes you can include R in many
commands Okay so let's go to Shell you
uh shell mod not eell mod okay so shell
script
mod so copy sh Script Mod doesn't
highlight what the so you have copy
you have move uh you have you know move
serves two purposes one is move a thing
to different directories the other one
is
rename you know that that's another bad
design but why does the Unix people do
that because it so happens you know with
the directory they they they they do the
same thing it just so happens on Unix
side way on the on the other hand
Microsoft they they they did away with
that okay so in the past week I've done
a lot update to my Powershell tutorial
if you are on Windows Powershell is the
thing you want to learn if you are uh
working in Windows as your profession
okay so you don't want bash you don't
want zshell you don't want fish or any
of the zomer shells you want Powers
shell on
Windows that is if you work on Windows
professionally okay you make your your
money by working on Windows whatever
technology on Windows usually usually
C++ for game gaming gaming so if you
work on Windows a lot you want to learn
Powers shell okay so Powershell for
example let's go to my Powershell
tutorial uh show directory is a tree uh
here we want to show the move okay move
the uh
um uh create a directory so copy file
rename file you have the full name of
the command command is rename item Okay
then if you want to move it's move item
MV
shortcut so in Powershell they actually
separated this entirely distinct concept
moving something is not the same as re
renaming something but the Unix
they they they they up
they give us bad Concepts which
brainwashed you know several generations
of programmers like to this day you
you'll hear a lot you know the elite
hacker types they say they every day
they tell you how Unix today Linux you
know Unix is kind of good you know how
Linux is great and the most
incompetent that's a Unix okay now
remember back to the issue we are
talking about the user the the function
interface design or command interface
design so Unix tools and Bash they are
the
worst case example in case okay and one
of the concrete example is the move and
rename and besides that you know each
you know like you know like like some of
the command allows you know dash off for
recursive but then you have find which
is designed to be um you know find an
xar is like like one one bunch of
confusing uh backs so if you really want
to have like small is beautiful each
command does one thing according to the
so-call Unix philosophy then all the
commands you don't want you don't want
the dashr okay when you want to
recursive you just you you should be
using find and pipe and com combine them
so each command truly does one thing
then if you want to Traverse the
directory walk the directory then you
use find or whatever then use you know
use xox to pass the command name you
want to
call and this that is the case that way
of design is is the case in Python in
goland in wolam language in you know in
just about every programming language
you have a work directory function that
get the list of files maybe and
including recursively then you can call
other functions to do on each of the
item file okay but on the Unix you got
the one factor fact some of the command
has are some of them doesn't you know in
some of them for example image magic you
know technically it's not part of Unix
but in practice it is image magic
okay uh you know let me just pedal some
of my website recently I've been working
on image magic too image magic
tutorial uh image magic is one huge back
of crap okay it's pretty old for example
let me show you okay uh image
M this is this from emac this coding
becoming a rent okay so let me show you
uh so I've been looking at Alternatives
you know VIPs lip VIPs that's
alternative on the Mac I discovered the
great thing the Apple people proprietary
they created six
sips that's building in Mac OS so it's
link and fast you know it allows you
convert image is recis rotate you know
and all things like that you know link
and precise meanwhile the image magic
let me show you image magic image magic
becomes a extremely bloated crap okay so
let's see where is my um article I just
wrote so let's go to programming blog so
we can find the link here because I
recently just did it so updates on
python uh FST string that's kind of new
although it's already 10 years old
python FST string
uh how to judge quality of programming
language documentation power shell throw
error this I need to do yet um and W
language transform Graphics you know
like this is mathematics geometric
transformation uh and this is bunch of
Zuma things I was planning to look into
them in
detail FD like people will say you
should use FD FD is mod
find ASA XA is modern LS load of crap
you know this load of crab F fzf and
fish shell and there's a bunch of new
ones other than fish and web rip grab we
we actually looked into a year ago uh
live stream I think I did one or to live
stream on rip grab you know on the
ultimate Judgment of of of about whether
you should use rip grab instead of just
grab grab is bundled in every Unix but
now you have rip grab by by the way
there's a long history of replacing unix
commands you know grab in the beginning
there's grab e grab F grab then they
started to merge together you know so
today we just know
grap so there are different you know
regular Expressions you know so before
you have e grab F grab then they become
grab then then grab have different you
know parameters that you know if you
want to be e grab compatible or if you
want to be F grab compatible you know
it's one confusing ball so we look we we
judged on whether rip grab is speed is
worth it not really okay you know if you
are just doing let's say 20 20,000 files
you know most of the time you spend in
grab is the is the dis loading or even
flash drive that takes the most of the
time so if you are grapping let's say
20,000 files let's say if it it takes 10
minutes it let's say it it takes uh two
seconds okay one and half seconds is
loading the
file into memory okay once you did it
one time then the second time is
instantaneous that's the nature that's
that's that's the that's about the speed
of grab okay I would say more than half
of the time is spending on loading the
file into memory okay
so if you do you know let's say 20,000
files which is not too many you know
today you don't need rib grab so when do
you need rib grab that's like when you
work at Google or something like you
have mega Giga data 1,000 you know 1
thou you know like
uh uh let say 100,000 files 100,000
files in a directory that you need to
grab every hour then that's when you use
rib grab otherwise it doesn't really
matter and another thing extremely
idiotic about this rib grab guy this
Andrew Gallen you know I think he's a
great guy and great coder you know great
work but he
refused to add the replace feature to
the rib grab like like like he's
obsessively refused adamantly refused
despite its frequently requested feature
because because he think you know it
gets very complex to do it right
so you know so he you know I discovered
you know we spend I spent you know
several days to looking to uh rip grab
last year so he's like adamant you know
he doesn't want to add replace
feature in that case then rib grab is
not not not that useful okay so again so
if you are a young if I'm younger like
you guys you know let's say 20 years old
yeah sure I would I would install all
these you know modern tools because they
are better you know usually FD is better
than
fine EZ a or EXA is better than LS you
know fzf is better than grab you know
and so on and fish shell and you know
it's got colors it faster it skips doget
directories you know saves you time so
it's better but in in some little way
okay so if I was younger I'm probably
you know looking to but I'm know I'm not
going to I got enough to do you know I
got I got my grab version in goand in
Python in Pearl I talked about many
times you search it you'll find the code
so for example goand so I go to bookmark
so this is a my Goan for grab okay I
have my own in in Goan in PE in Python
in emac and they all can do replacement
okay so for example this one you go to
this page it's on my website GoLine find
stre
okay so every time I want to find
something I just quickly open the
bookmark and the cruiser will be uh you
know at here so I can find let's say I
want to uh type something uh
wait uh yeah where is a okay so
something let's let's say uh I want to
find uh hascar okay I've been trying to
this you know so I run the code actually
oh yeah so I was trying to find the
misspelling type of reporter r e p o r t
o r before so delete that I don't need
that so let's not search hascar let's
search for punch card because that's
punch card that's uh that's not how you
should say it that I think it's called
um I correct
it but if you search for punch card you
know so right now it's searching over
about 50,000 files among which is 10,000
HTML files so you can see all the result
you press a key to highlight them in emx
to Jump them so you can see all the
occurrence of Punch Cards okay but punch
card is the wrong word okay so let's
just
um it's called punched cards okay let's
just open it okay open one of them
showing browser guys still says don't
eat iterate recurse and get rid of Lis
cons Lis cons is one of the most idiotic
thing and gu steo is a creator of common
lisp and scheme lisp
both okay but lisp common LP people are
obsessed with cons they think it's a
great
thing and when they you know when you
show them this article by gu steal you
know he's giving a talk you know and
also for example you go there he's
giving a talk don't this don't use cons
okay ban cons when you show this to the
common list Fanatics the idiots they
think oh but well he's just saying you
know they just basically dismiss it you
know they they they the common dispers
will say but it's still good you know
the extreme fanatical communist idiots
they become that way because because
fanatism you know because they are they
they want to promote communist so they
when you become fanatic like emac users
okay when you become F Fanatics like so
obsessed in like glorify this tool emac
or this you fail to see certain problems
and
flaws and fail to actually do good work
in the tool because for example this
cons you
know you you but but but you ignore this
you know you you kind of dismiss it oh
yeah that's you know gu still yeah you
know like like you kind of dismiss it so
you when you C this use you you back to
using cons when it is not appropriate
that's a thing you know and this
phonetics they want to they deny this so
they want to keep saying cons is great
so that the one major consequence is
that all the these people when new
Learners you know that when they come to
this community they think oh cons great
they keep using it but actually what
should happen is that we should start to
tell people K is bad K is just history
it's too bad we cannot change it because
there's 30 years of baggage you know the
backward compatibility we cannot remove
cons but we can understand cons is
really just you know old we should avoid
it as much as we can okay we spread that
then possibly eventually you know we
have news system you know in this you
know new library you know things like
that new library or so on so you should
not be um so anyway we digress into this
cons so Punch Cards okay so Punch Cards
uh actually it's not punch card it's
called uh let me show you punched cards
okay so the proper name this thing
punched
cards this thing is called Punch Cards
that's used starting around 1940s even
1940s uh you know so you know what is a
consequence remain to this day among the
hacker idiots that's a line
truncation like have you heard the
coding style the python the Pearl the
the JavaScript people tell you that you
should line should not be more than 80
characters that came from Punch Cards
practice okay it's a extreme idsy
another one I've talked in my live
stream for quite a few times
okay so we digressed a lot I think
that's it for today and and we go back
so I was showing you the you know the I
was showing you this skand script that's
my personal replacement for um for the
rib grab you know I have my own I don't
even need Goan okay for example
sometimes I use Goan because it allows
me to still working emac while it's
running and but usually I just I just
call emac this command so uh find let's
try Punch Cards this is written in pure
emac this okay search in this directory
do it HTML files yes there it is so I
can jump to it I can list all the files
that occur Punch Cards okay including
the GU Ste article close it or I can
jump to any one of them press enter to
open showing browser uh so this one is
uh this article is two programming
language needs the concept of core stack
that's another edsy from the C and C++
okay like the C like C++ they
are talk oh because course cor stack and
including they spread they spread the
bad concept to python to JavaScript to
basically all industrial programmers so
it's very common if you working in you
know as a programmer you'll see oh
that's because call stack even the arrow
sometimes Arrow they will say Co
stack idiot okay to explain that one
take take a while but but that's a the
damage from the
C C+ plus from you know in the beginning
from C people okay and the the the the
gist of this problem this bad concept of
cor stack is that they because of the C
people they don't really think in terms
of mathematics and API they don't think
in terms of what user wants to do they
the C coders and C++ and especially
these two okay they think in the terms
of the what the machine is doing and the
implementation compilers that is why
they got this cor stack even your data
even if your data Ty is not a stack data
type at all but when you call a function
magically you got this Co stack where
does it come from I'm just calling a
function what the is the co stack
it has nothing to do with the function
I'm a mathematician function is not
coack where does it you know well that's
because the C
idiots okay that's it for today I think
uh yeah that's it for today um we talked
15 minutes so we back to punch cards so
I'm Dem so I'm I'm trying to show you so
back to you know I'm showing you why I
you know I have a goand version of grab
we were talking about rib grab I have a
uh you know goand for multiple pairs of
regular expression replacement in all
files in a directory recursively and we
have a python version in regular
expression python version version and we
have a so here's a python version and
here's a per version that's my earliest
in written in 2 uh in 1999 okay this is
per version it does has a lot of
features you know find and replace
multiple pairs of strings in one shot or
including regular
expression in in all directories and sub
directories and you can
specify you know file sizes Beyond some
file size ignore it things like that so
you got PE version of course then you
got emac version so here is a emac
tutorial how to do it without any any uh
user defined you know command this is
how to do it plainly in
emac then of course then you have AAR
emac
version package uh which I demoed I just
Dem a moment agoa find replace find
eel. so you can find replace or you know
strings in a directory recursively by a
by PL text or by regular expression or
by or count count how many currencies or
do replacement or just simply find and
so on so you have to pay me to get
it so we were talking about all these
find replace all these my personal
versions you know that's almost that's
the first thing I do when I learn a
language and because we were talking
about rib grab we were talking about you
know whether you should use rib grab is
it worth it then why are we talking
about rib grab because we were talking
about uh this new you know modern
replacement for Unix tools the zomer
things the Zuma generation things and we
were talking about these things because
we were looking at this page because we
were talking
about how in Linux you got all this
confusing interconnected Fu up design of
command line options in the commands
Okay each one do like miscellaneous they
are not small they are not beautiful you
know and you know each one thing doesn't
each one command doesn't do one thing
well actually do sometimes do other
things you know like confusing up
Unix
philosopy
lie okay so we were talking about that
and that's because we were talking about
the designing of the today's talk
show uh about
how should we modify the function about
turning a list of lines to a HTML list
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching donate to me okay go
toad.
info uh you know buy me some Amazon gift
card so I can you know buy something I
need uh you know you gotta use this link
because otherwise if you're using
Germany Amazon or Japan Amazon I cannot
get the money okay like people paid me
before but that's German Amazon I can't
I can't get so Amazon basically just ate
the money you know I can't take it so
that happens that happened a few times
so uh donate me appreciate kali. for
bottom go to the bottom that's it for
today uh okay hello congratulations you
are on my homepage okay you guys what
arguments
uh yeah Unix yeah Unix is a major
problem can you show the regular
expression how can I read uh what is
this one can you show the regular
expression
I can read it
well uh what howy from Tennessee hello
Tennessee now what is the Tennessee
accent Tennessee is the southern accent
right hi
all okay bye
guys bye bye okay
bye let me do some clean up programing
block close that close that s fine
go uh yeah we will demoing that so Linux
Comm line okay so yeah that's it bye
guys