hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today's topic is unicode
what is Unicode what is ASCII what is
character set what is encoding what is
utf-8 and what is utf-16
and all these topics and what is Emoji I
mean so but this is for programmers so
if you program in Python in C in Java
you know whatever language JavaScript
Golan or Wolfram language you actually
need to know about encoding about
character set about these issues okay
and that's today's topic for programmers
uh so now now if you have comments and
questions post it there okay I'd love to
see it okay let's let's so I'm gonna uh
yeah so I'm gonna tell you and what's
the code Point what is um you know all
these things utf-8 utf-16 and what is a
surrogate surrogate pair
and what is bite odor and what is pom
byte order Mark you know this you know
for the for the first uh 15 years of
programming I started programming in
1992 okay starting with wolfam language
I coded wufam language every day several
hours uh for about eight years you know
1992 to 1998.
that that is every day and then I
started to code Pearl and Unix stuff you
know bash in Unix and Java
and then later on you know the next
decade Python and all other PHP and
other other languages and emac beasts
but you know for the first 15 or 20
years I don't really understand uh
encoding because I'm not a low level
programmer you know of those of you if
you are programming if Pro C language or
Java is your first language you know
those low-level languages or even go
land or C plus plus now if you are those
uh language programmers if if that's
your main thing if that's your first
language then you likely understand
more about encoding
okay uh sorry my alarm clock I need to
shut it off
so if you are a c you know low level
language you likely understand bytes and
encoding issues because especially in C
you deal with bytes but these
programmers especially especially see
programmers they don't know about
Unicode when it comes to Unicode Emoji
you know they they don't understand they
tends to stick with ASCII you know
whenever you have an emoji characters
they uh
they uh reframe from it
you know so encoding so you actually
need to know it's actually uh so us so
if you are a high level programmer you
know like me then uh you need to know it
less but eventually you need to know
because every character even if you
don't program every character every
every file when you open encoding is
involved because other letters ABC you
know the computer cannot store ABC like
characters they actually transform them
into binary numbers you know so you so
this process you know for example the
character a let's say
what is this character so you can in
e-max you can say describe cha and you
get this panel of information about this
character you can see you know a code
0.65 what does that mean and here's the
octal uh uh number for 65 and here's a
hexadecimal
41 for 65. you know what does it mean
what what's the code point you know so
that's encoding because you because you
need it even if you open a file in
browser
if you got the encoding wrong then you
got gibbish you know sometimes you'll
see and even in emacs for example line
ending returns sometimes you'll see
these characters over every line at the
end of every line so all these are
related to encoding so let me show you
some so I'm gonna explain you know I'm
actually starting to explain already in
coding why you need it so but let me
show you some of the
um
you know all the talk I do today is
already written so you just all you have
to do is just you go to uh search for
sari Unicode then near the bottom the
panel you can see Unicode for
programmers and here is a whole lot of
uh articles it's all written so you can
you don't have to take notes you can
just read them
exactly Unicode okay so explain about
encoding and character set and the code
point then you have different languages
how they deal with encoding lots of
issues you know uh
for example this this one is interesting
is a problem of simple congestion in
computer languages
versus Unicode you know
especially so if you are a c Java
programmer this hits you because you
don't you you got you know this is a
problem for you
because for example here is a regular
expression you can let's go there okay
let's magnify well
um open image you see here is the
regular expression in emac this and it's
not emac this is the worst but you have
the toothpick syndrome the backslash
Escape you know so for example if you're
a programmer you know about Escape
characters right backslash but in
Powershell it's a different character in
Powershell the Escape character is the
uh
uh is the uh
it's an accent you know let's magnify
actually that's the
this is uh wait
this so accent character this is escape
so anyway the point is you have to deal
with Escape okay maybe not that I have
it written somewhere so but you see
these um Regular expression so
in Python in Java in any language you
have this kind of thing
hard to understand but it would be much
better if you have if you allow Unicode
characters so I'm kind of digressing but
let me show you
so in coding okay so so let me show you
right now I'm talking about all the
consequences and related you know
consequences and related things to
encoding you know for example Unicode
why is it invented if you don't have if
you don't have Unicode what happens what
what is the effect you know wait you
know why don't we stop you know all this
Emoji then what happens to your
programming language lots of things so
that's what I'm talking about regular
expression is an example because you
only have limited number of characters
so you started to need escape and also
the other things
so uh so so so so you have ASCII jam and
you have like the same symbol used for
so many things especially you know one
of the major problem in many languages
and including
computer languages like not programming
languages like HTML you have the
so-called
um entities
you know very complex this these are
entities in other words it's a Escape
mechanism uh more typically known to
programmers you know this is actually a
Escape mechanism to allows you to enter
some character but without the character
itself so you can you can type and
percent that
then a semicolon then you get this
character so this is you know entity
list
now I would say this is a consequence
when you don't have Unicode you know so
your source code becomes extremely
complex impossible to read suppose you
are speaking French now in French you
need a acute e
so for example you need a q e so let's
see let's search for acute
so you have acute a so let's search for
E acute
uh there it is so in many you know
European languages you need these
characters frequently now imagine you
are writing an essay or whatever you are
writing an article and every occurrence
of this e you have to say Ampersand e
acute semicolon you know that's
up that is the consequence when you
don't do when you don't have Unicode now
most programmers you don't think of it
you know this doesn't occur to you but
it occurs when you have regular
expression you know now most of you know
which regular expression is how to read
and why well part of the reason is that
they ask you jam you know like when you
that that's one of the consequences
ASCII Jam but programmers you know you
don't think usually this doesn't occur
to you because you are so used to you
know the typical stack Overflow The
Hacker News you know typical
they they don't they don't think too
much
and are there languages that fully use
Embraces Unicode yes for example
Fortress okay let me show you an example
uh of Fortress lots of problems and also
this Ampersand encoding in url that is
extremely complex okay ampers Ampersand
in coding you know very confusing even
you know different browsers they don't
agree on on what exactly it should be
you know for example when you have an
ampersand in the URL for example when
you go to Amazon when there's a query
that happens a lot but whether you
should encode that then then you have
the issue of different encoding because
sometimes it's like you see percent 26
that's URL encoding then you have the
Ampersand coding so you have two
different encodings in the URL syntax
extremely
confusing okay
this problem
will not happen when you have the
Unicode in the beginning let's say if
you have if we have Unicode in 1960s all
these have problems don't doesn't occur
and let me let me tell you another
significant the most significant problem
about the ASCII Jam Unicode you know
consequences is that when you have
Escape you know for example in
let's say JavaScript or in C in Java in
Pearl in Python in Ruby all the same
okay so but right now I'm using
JavaScript for example so let's see I
want a constant
okay x equals to sum
sum
backslash n thing you know
so let's cancel log X print X okay
evaluated you can see the output is
something in two lines why because you
have this Escape mechanism slash n
you know you you probably don't think
this is complex but this is actually
very complex in different languages they
have elaborate different Escape
mechanisms so so what's the problem the
problem is that
so in emacs for example I want to call a
shell command so you want to pass some
arguments in but often when you do
let's say you want to pass a regular
expression you want to call grep in
emacs
you want emacs in your application to
call a web command of a different
application so you need to pass the
arguments let's say you need to pass a
regular expression so four of the
backslash ancestors but but then
you have the essentially Escape problem
encoding problem because it's almost
impossible to translate correctly
because you are going through different
layers so anyway that's a very common
problem very very common problem
almost unsolvable and this encoding this
Escape mechanism problem happens more
severely when you have
when you have nested parsing for example
if you are writing a regular expression
you know usually it's used to match some
text right now but suppose you are
writing a regular expression to go to to
try to search through or your python
code that contains regular expression
you want to use a regular expression to
see if a particular regular expression
happens in your code
that is when you have hell and it
basically practically speaking
impossible to do why does that occur
that occur because
because of because of the ASCII Jam
issue okay most programmers don't know
don't know about this so that's a
regular so that's an example of ASCII
gem when you use regular expression
trying to find regular expression when
you have some sort of nested thing going
on
another example of this is when you have
HTML
embedded in HTML for example let me show
you okay so let's go back so let's let's
say I want the HTML so
so you are looking at some talk show
this is a HTML file right and you know
so I want to tell people how do you
you know I want to teach people how do
you have a paragraph So in
for example I can write this is
how you do paragraph
use
use this P tag okay
so that's a paragraph you see but if you
show let's say use uh P tag like these
okay let's see
okay so this is the HTML source code now
let's show in browser let's see what
happens
you see this is this is how you do
paragraph use P tag like this empty
why because the P tag is you know
paragraph tag so what you need to do you
need to encode this these angle brackets
so you know I can do it so this is what
you actually want
uh actually yeah you don't actually need
that so so this is what you want okay so
now go to the browser
now watch watch this part show so you
see so this is an example when you have
again nested encoding that that creates
a lot problem this is a huge problem
just like regular expression
searching for regular expression because
suppose I'm done with this but tomorrow
or next year Next program or whatever do
deal with you need to process you need
to change something this often may
become encoded wrong because it may
become encoded twice so for example I
can encode this Ampersand by
let's see
um
let's see what is the key to encode that
ampersand
yeah okay so you have
uh but but anyway so I forgot what's the
um
oops what did I do
yeah so
let me let me do this okay so hold on a
second cancel that so here is all
commands search for in code there it is
tab one
side HTML encode Ampersand entity okay
so let me show you a different example
let's say
Sun okay paragraph now you want to
encode them so you select them tab one
so you see and if you want to so but
sometimes it happens if you encode it
this twice tab one so it becomes that
and that becomes let's let's show in
browser you can see what happens
you see you get that so this is the
encoding Escape you know encoding
problem uh this is actually not encoding
this is a Escape mechanism problem
okay so these are con this these are
consequences when when you have the
ASCII gem okay
so actually let's talk about let's talk
about
um
the actual today's topic okay let's
begin to talk about so we I already
spent 20 minutes on on introduction so
let's so you so encoding okay let's
begin to talk about encoding now we got
some spammers here
uh
okay let's talk about some encoding
problem okay I mean the actual uh
tutorial about Unicode Okay so
so okay so so you need encoding in code
what so what is encoding encoding is a a
way to transform each character to a
sequence of binary numbers once and zero
okay
so let me show you why do you need to do
it
um
encoding is a way to transform a
sequence of characters or text or
whatever
two
ones and zero why do you need to do that
because computers you know the chips the
electronics they have you know
electricity you know and the way they
work is that you have high voltage or
low voltage high voltage means one low
voltage means zero represented by one
and zero so basically it was at the core
everything is just one and zero so you
so that's binary number okay
so you can see a example of
binary number okay but so how does
binary number work let me explain
so usually when we we write numbers
by what's called
um decimal notation system now the way
this system this is a number notation
system okay there are many ways to write
a number for example you have a Roman
numeral you know v stands for five
I stand for one two I stand for two
that's another numerical you know number
notation system in China in India in
other countries in Maya you know or
Asian civilizations or in Egypt they all
have different ways to write numbers but
today the standard you know almost the
universal yeah the universal is a
Arabic number or system anyways but this
system is a notational system for
writing numbers and the way these
numbers system work this notation works
is that you have
10 distinct symbols one two three four
five six seven eight nine zero okay so
you have ten distinct
symbols now this may be trivial I mean
explaining this
because if you understand it then yours
you are clearly understand binary
numbers octal numbers hexadecimal
numbers and numbers of any base not just
you know typical programmers they just
understand oh yeah binary
hexadecimal if you say 17 based number
they go what what what they don't they
don't understand the mathematical
concept behind it okay
so so a notation decimal notation system
is 10 different symbols each one
represent a number so one two three four
five six seven eight nine then you have
the zero three percent you know nothing
but what if you want to say 10 you know
you don't have enough you you don't have
a symbol for 10. so what you do is that
you
when you reached 8 the next number is 9
When You Reach nine the next number is
ten but you don't have symbols for it
anymore so you put so you put a extra
symbol you
you put your beginning symbol one you
know because there's no
symbol after night so you put one you
start over one you put it down then you
put a zero after that this is how
the
um
the decimal number notation system works
now so remember you begin with 10
distinct symbols
zero to nine
okay and when you are out of the numbers
you just
put two um digits one after another
start over Okay so in the same way this
is how binary number works you have only
two distinct symbols zero and one
so 0 is just zero one is just one now if
you want to say if you want to represent
two what to do you don't have a number
you don't have a symbol for two well you
start over so you start with one again
put on the you know put it down then you
follow it by zero
so the next number you increase again
what comes after zero is one so you just
put eleven you know what one what that
stands for three and next number
well you don't have a you know symbol
after one so you start with zero again
you know so you repeat so you add more
one more digit so this is how binary
number works
okay same thing happens with a
hexadecimal now hexadecimal you have 16
symbols to begin with you know zero to
nine zero to nine then after that you
use a b c d e f okay that's how it works
okay these are important because when
you because when you talk about encoding
you have to deal with you know
it comes down to
that's computer that's what computer
stores binary number why why do you need
hexadecimal once you have you know
because computers are just Banning
numbers why do you have have this
hexadecimal
well the re the reason for that is that
hexadecimal number is a
a very compact way to represent binary
numbers because if you use binary
numbers then even a short number let's
say eight
you have to use three digits you have
three digits but if you have let's say
one thousand you want to represent one
thousand by binary number what do you
get is you know let's say one thousand
so here is a so you have one one one one
one one one zero one zero zero zero you
you know pretty soon you have like a
huge sequence of binary numbers
which is a manageable and hard to
process to the human brain that's why
that is why okay I'm telling you so this
is the reason you have hexadecimal
numbers otherwise you don't need it so
hexadecimal number is a a human notation
it's a way to represent
binary numbers in a compact way
okay so each hexadecimal numbers
represent four binary digits so if you
have a hexadecimal of you know one F you
can fairly easily uh translate to Binary
there is an algorithm but
I don't know it anyway so
that's that's about binary numbers and
that's about hexadecimal numbers okay
you eventually you need to be very
familiar with them
okay so so that's
so so let's go back to
um encoding so encoding is a way to
transform each character to a binary
digits
now let's talk about
how do you do that okay so first of all
you need to know you need to have a kind
of a standard agreed upon way to say
what T becomes
you know what for example you know you
have a list of characters and what is a
what is a what is a binary sequence for
a you have to agree on that because
otherwise my computer says a is 65 your
computer says a64 we we don't agree then
it's gibbish you know so that is why
so you have a you need a standard so it
becomes a standard okay so one of the
standard is called ASCII
okay so one of the standard is called
ASCII so let's see
um ASCII characters you know in the
beginning you know because computers are
mostly created in USA so and the
language is English so we have ASCII
characters ASCII characters are these
sequence of symbols okay there's no
Smiley there's no Emoji there's no Arrow
there's no acute e you know for European
language this is English so Standard
English lowercase uppercase and
punctuations parentheses
um equal sign and numbers and some
punctuations okay that's
that's the ASCII character set you know
remember so this is a standard so you
know this is created by
uh what does uh American Standard code
for information exchange created in
1960s so that that way everyone can
agree what each character is what number
okay so for example then here's a table
okay let me let me show you
um
so for example the a character
in dismal is 65 you know
in hexadecimal is 41 in binary you know
you can convert it to Binary it's you
know zero one something something
basically seven seven digits binary
digits seven bits okay so ASCII standard
is a standard that says each character
is given an character id
okay a decimal then you can convert the
decimal to hexel Binary okay but the
main the essential thing is that you
assign each character an ID basically a
number okay a integer
so you you have all these numbers okay
so let's ask that's the earliest the
1960s just for English
so let me so let me talk about
um so encoding so encoding is a way to
transform characters to sequence a
binary digits in order to do that you
need a standard you need an encoding
standard so ASCII is one of the first
one this is all critical because without
some kind of encoding
you can you can do computation you can
do you know electronic computers so you
need so this is standard okay ASCII this
is a very first encoding standard now
let me talk about character set
okay character set is just a set of
characters for example ABC is a
character set ABCD is a character set
let's say a and zero just two characters
that's also a character set so character
set is just a set of characters now why
is it why is it important because it's
important because when you define a
standard for encoding you
implicitly defined a character set for
example for the ASCII your character
said is these you know you don't have
Emoji you don't have right arrow you
don't have acute e and so on
so character set is just a set of
characters that's a more more the most
basic idea so once you have a capture
set you say you know you say in your
standard this is a cut this is a set of
characters that we try to Define okay so
you start with the character set then
you say what each character should be
what number okay standard everyone
agrees on your on if they are using your
standard okay so that is a character id
this is a this is the essence of
encoding standard this is the most
fundamental essence
give a number numerical ID to each
character for each for every character
in your character set okay that's an
Essence give an at you know integer ID
and this integer ID
today is known as code Point okay we'll
we'll start to talk about code point
code point is just an integer ID for
every character so a special important
in Unicode we'll talk about Unicode in a
bit but basically code point is just a
num a number assigned to every character
in your character set okay for example
in Unicode the lowercase a is 97 okay
then you can
uh translate it to hexadecimal
and others okay so the character Alpha
the Greek Alpha has a number code Point
nice 945 okay that's Alpha and this
Emoji faced with tears of joy is has
this ID one two eight five one four
quote Point Okay so
you know technically it's called code
point but you can just think of it as
character id that's much simpler okay so
remember again every character has a
character id an integer
that stands for the character and this
character to ID is the most important
thing is the essence of encoding
standard okay once you know this then
you can convert a any text to computer
sequencer binary numbers or vice versa
binary numbers two you can start to read
the file you know when you read a file
for example let's show let me show you
this interesting in emacs
pixel mod
uh wait and do discard and do info okay
so you see we are looking at the same
file you know hold on a second let me
show you okay
um
what
uh
okay so what did we okay so you see let
me show you okay save a copy so here is
today's talk show right today's talk
show HTML file so you can see it's a
HTML file here now I open it you know it
looks like this readable you know it's
just
HTML with English now but when when the
this file stored in your computer it's
actually just sequence of zeros and ones
so when you open it you actually need to
decode it you you need to turn the you
know sequence of zero and ones into
readable characters so
but so let me show you one way you can
see that so in emacs you can call
pixel mod okay
so this is that how that file looks like
in hexadecimal
so you you know it begin with um
it begin with
um you know three C two one six four six
F you know that's what the file looks
like in hexatissimo and you can turn
this hex some decimal two binary numbers
Okay so
so that shows okay
so so encoding so we talked about
character set we talked about
character encoding you know that's
that's turning characters to binary
numbers and vice versa then we talked
about character encoding standard okay
we talked about ASCII character encoding
standard one of the earliest for English
characters only then beginning around
year 1991 the Unicode begin why does it
begin because
you know in the early days 1960s there's
no internet you know so computers are
created in America USA so we just
um am I still going
comments okay
comments and I mean let me check uh
check video check yeah
so
so 19 so USA created computers we
created the ASCII encoding uh but we
don't have you know we don't have
Chinese because Chinese you know we
don't have Japanese you know we just you
know for English so but eventually you
know people in Europe French you know
they need acute e and they need a bunch
of other characters Iceland you know
Nordic uh German languages
you need some other characters so you
started to have encoding standard for
European languages like
[Music]
um
IEC a859 so that's another encoding
standard so starting around 1980s or so
1990s but
so around 1991 the Unicode Consortium
begin so because why because
you have ASCII you have ASCII encoding
which is great for USA But Europeans
they have you know each language they
need they created their own encoding you
know for Spanish you know Spanish needs
the end with Tilda you know that's not
in French French needs some of their own
in German you need umelot you know so
each country started to have their own
encoding for their language so it became
confusing
so someone's are thinking why don't have
one why don't we have one universal
encoding system you know we have a we
have uh we we Define a character set we
Define a character set a set of
characters like Encompass Encompass all
languages including Japanese and Chinese
so we have one single Universal encoding
Universal Character
said and we for each character we assign
a number so this is universal so we
don't so when our computer reads a file
you can you can just look up this
Universal encoding you don't have to see
you don't have to check or guess what
what encoding is it used because if you
got the wrong encoding decoding you got
gibberish so that is idea of unicode
begin in 1991.
okay so that's the idea of unicode
okay so now let's see 44 minutes uh so
let's we we uh let's quickly finish
almost then okay
so
Unicode begin okay
so now let me tell you about what's a
Unicode so Unicode is organization
organization unit called Consortium the
idea is that one single encoding for
every language Universal okay
so
the but it has some uh bumps
um some Evolution you know so in the
beginning they think that
they think that for every character
today we're gonna start with 16 bits
okay so
[Music]
um
so let me let me let me think about uh
what I want to talk about in the rest of
the video okay
so we cover cover character set we
covered
um encoding and uh as a consequence
you need an encoding standard and the
essence of encoding standard is to
define a character set and
eat for each character you have a number
corresponding to it character id or
chord code Point okay
and but in night so in but in 1991 the
idea came up that you know white don't
have one single why don't we have one
single Universal encoding just one
encoding for
that includes every character in every
language
okay so that became started to become
popular
and by by year 2000 Unicode started to
replace all the other European
specialized encoding used in Europe and
Japan okay
so UTF you Unicode begin
became popular okay so let me talk about
what what does unicode
uh defines exactly so unicode
so let me explain a little bit about
Unicode and history
um
so we also talked about encoding
standard and what they Define let's
remember it's a character id that's the
most that's the essence
so character set and encoding is
different character set is just a
character set okay encoding is a way to
turn a character into a number okay
and what is Unicode it's a you know its
idea of one single encoding for every
language
and unicode character said it so what is
the character saying in Unicode includes
every every character in every language
you know that's that that's uh that's a
idea okay
so we also explained code point which is
just a number given to assigned to a
character okay
now character name is also simple to
understand you know each character for
example the capital a
there's a name capital A in your or you
call it Latin capital capital A or
English Capital a so usually almost
always each character also has a name
so in Unicode they just standardize the
name so in Unicode every character has
has a name and this name is always
unique for example here's some examples
so capital A the name in unicode
assigned to this character is Latin
capital letter A okay and this is unique
and for the Greek Alpha it's quick small
letter Alpha and also by the way the
Unicode naming for characters they are
always all capitalized and they are
always asking okay so you want to see a
cute e or something
so every character has a name okay but
however because of the
you know this is a huge project you know
Unicode income passes all the all human
languages past and present so in this
process you know in act in order to
decide you know in order to assign your
number to every character you have lots
of problems this is no small task
because you have some you have dead
languages that requires research you
know Egyptian for example
um
some of the Dead languages you know
hero glyph Linear B Phoenician run
and you have also event
constructed languages you know that's
right let me show you some of them you
know kuniform
300 uh wait this is 5 000 years ago
5 000 years ago so if you are a Unicode
you know if you are one of the Unicode
designers first of all how do you know
how do you know what characters are
there you don't know you know this is 5
000 years ago five thousand years ago
cuneiform
so how do you know well you you consult
you know historical linguist
you know it takes year decade hundreds
hundreds of years to come up with what
characters are there and uh then you
might be missing some characters so the
Unicode task is not easy you know it's
still actually it's just a ongoing
process
so we are looking at some of the Dead
languages you know today you also have
Egyptian hieroglyphs you know this is
again
three thousand years ago or four you
know Egyptian Egyptian characters by the
way there's an interesting now here is
the
clickbait
okay you see this these penises
these penises are censored by Microsoft
in Microsoft found they display us
squares okay since it and here is the
artifact a photo
very famous for
it is because of this Stone someone dug
up the you know you can look up
Wikipedia look up someone took up in
uh so this Stone
is around
uh 196 BC so two thousand years ago and
because of this Stone this Stone
contains three languages then people
started to finally for the first time to
decipher the Egyptian you know herograph
to not to to begin to understand what it
mean you know what what all these birds
and and they also have you know
this is Asian this is not like today's
social justice thinking what whatever
you know you have Cox of course you have
penis then you have the birth child
birth
you see you know that's part of humanity
that's Asian
uh then
so you have all these uh you know quite
interesting to look into okay so so
there's a lot
um then there's a linear B uh Microsoft
Windows they don't show because but on
the Mac by default you can see these are
Linear B
um characters this is also
four thousand years ago four thousand
years ago Linear B characters okay
then you have the Phoenician this is the
for the Western for English this is the
granddaddy
of English alphabet you know English
alphabet came from Latin Latin came from
you know came from Roman and and then it
Roman came from Latin alphabet Latin
alphabet came from Greek are derived
from Greek alphabet and Greek alphabet
is derived from Phoenician
okay so these characters you see here in
Unicode those are Phoenicians those are
the granddaddy of the English ABCD
okay so the point here is that the
Unicode is just a tremendous project
encompassing lots of things Okay so
the reason we are talking about this
because
if you want to define a
um a standard encoding standard
if you want to define a encoding
standard first of all you need to have
you you you need to precisely specify a
character set
you know but one of the big problem is
that when it comes to Asian languages
what character said are there you don't
even know you don't know so it takes you
know it's a huge process uh project
that's just one of the problem there's
other problems like when you have
Chinese characters Chinese characters is
also Asian
uh let me let me show you okay so
um
you know Chinese characters okay so here
so you have you know some of these
characters four thousand years ago
um you know this is called Oracle bone
you know these are precursors of of
Chinese characters then you can see this
thing this heavy cauldron
from
782 BC so it's about 3 000 years ago and
you can see huge number of Chinese
characters in it and those are actually
legible you know almost the same to
today's you know so you have these
things Chinese characters okay
uh very close okay actually not the same
as Chinese but by but by the by this
time 2000
well three thousand years ago you have
these characters and these are almost
the same as Chinese characters you use
today so so anyway the so you know
so the issue with Unicode is that how do
you what are the characters said and you
need to give a number for each one of
these characters
then it gets more complex because
Chinese characters is then used in
Japanese you know you know eventually
became part of the Japanese writing
system and used in Korea and also used
in Vietnam
but over the you know over the thousand
years they diverged somewhat so Japanese
has their own way to write the same
character you know slightly different
you know you might think of them as
different font but
cultural differences so do you do you
give you know the same characters the
Japanese version or different do you
consider them as a different characters
or do you consider them as just the same
character but using a different font you
know that's the issue and very
controversial as well so that's another
that's one of the big controversy in
Unicode called han han Universe hand
unification you know lots of issues
so
so back to so
back to so what I'm talking about is the
creation of the Unicode it's no simple
task okay but let's go back to the
to what
um to encoding and stuff okay
so encoding
so character said uh character said
ASCII so so what does Unicode Define
actually
so Unicode what Unicode actually defines
so unicode
you begin with the character said you
know you know code by now every year
there's a new version of Unicode so by
today is Unicode 11 Unicode every year
you have a new version
so they
they
kept uh adding new characters
meanwhile they tried to maintain
Backward Compatible so that you know you
can just change randomly but they each
year they kind of add more characters
but what does Unicode actually Define so
this is becoming complex let me explain
this
so before we talked about encoding right
encoding standard is is a way is a
standard that defines the character set
then for each character you give them a
unique ID for the character okay that's
a encoding standard
now Unicode begin like that so when
Unicode begin in 1990
1.
you know they think that okay the total
number of characters we need is at most
16 bits
uh 16 bits that means 16 binary digits
okay so let me let me show you so
uh let's go to byte order
well let's not go over that let's just
uh let me just talk about
um
well uh so
so I'm telling I'm talking about what
does Unicode actually Define okay
essentially it defines let me tell you
okay it defines
two primary things defined by unicode
one is the character set and the in the
character id for each character in the
character set okay that's the
that's the that's what Unicode defines
so you give a each character you give
them an ID called the code point for
that character that's that's the most
important thing Unicode defines and uh
and uh
so let me show you
um
yeah code Point Okay so
like that we we showed there so you have
a character then you have a code point
and also you know
you have a name to go with it
that's uh that's the most important
thing Unicode Define now the second also
in the uh equip equally important is
actually encodings okay so Unicode
actually defined
several encodings okay let me let me go
uh let me explain so unicode
in the beginning they defined
um
so we have to go to Unicode history so
Unicode defined several encodings by now
okay so you have utf-8
and you have also utf-16 but you know in
the beginning Unicode thought thinks you
know the Unicode people they want to
have a universal encoding system for all
the world's languages so they think they
thought that 16 bits is enough meaning
16 binary numbers okay so here's the
link I want
so let's go to binary numbers so let's
see what 16 binary digits so 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 16. 16 binary
digits
okay so actually I need to type the
binary digit here
so in decimal that's 32
767 you know the Unicode people think
that 32 000 characters is enough for all
the words characters okay it in the
beginning they think this is enough for
all the live languages you know they are
not counting dead languages but
eventually over the years people decided
that actually we need all the Egyptians
you know they we need to we need them to
be part of the unit code
so they So eventually in the 1990s they
realized 32 000 characters is not enough
okay that's a problem
in the beginning they think 32 000
characters is enough therefore
you just need 16 binary digits okay or
at most four hexadecimal characters
to represent any character in any human
language okay but over the years they
changed their mind they begin to think
oh actually that's not enough so they
they started to extend it so
so you started to need more than 16
characters
16 uh bits
so
so in the beginning Unicode is you know
they Define their encoding called UCS
okay 16 characters but eventually they
realized that's not enough so they
created a encoding standard called
utf-16
and uh so in this utf-16 coding it's a
variable with encoding
okay so I need to explain that uh this
you know this video is actually kind of
too long I think I'm
just am I doing good
I'm just starting to get very boring and
too slow
so so let me
yeah so we are talking about
what what are the different encodings of
Unicode okay let's let's talk about that
so you know in the beginning Unicode
thinking things that 32 you know 16 bits
is enough which is 32
000 characters eventually they realize
that's not enough but in the beginning
Unicode defined uh encoding today is
called you you know
today
you call it UCS you know Universal
character Inc system or something like
that UCS encoding so every character
corresponds to a number that is
represented by 16 binary digits okay
that's the original the first Unicode
Universal Universal encoding okay every
character corresponds to a number that's
16 bits okay
but they realize that's not enough so
they started to Define utf-16 coding
now UDS F16 encoding is such that
remember every character has a character
id which is you know is an integer you
can translate the integer represent the
integer in a decimal
in a binary notation
but in utf-16 encoding
you know because some of the number is
bigger than 32
000. therefore it needs more than 16
binary digits so six so UDF 16 coding is
such that for some characters you need
binary digits but for some other
characters you need more than 16 in fact
you need 32.
binary bits you know
binary digits so for some characters
it's
16 by binary digits other characters is
32 binary digits so that is the utf-16
encoding okay so this happened in the
early 1990s you know in yeah so in the
beginning
Unicode is called ucs2 encoding every
character is just 16 bits
but in 1996 they decided that's not
enough so they invented they created the
utf-16 coding so in 16
utf-16 every character maybe 16 bits or
32 depending on the character
so
that's 1996 and it is embraced by
JavaScript okay by JavaScript by by also
the Java language the Java language and
it's also embraced by Microsoft's NTFS
file system that is in your
you know in your files and directory the
character names
you know you have you know name for the
folder or files those are encoded on
Windows
using the NTFS file system and those are
encoded in utf-16 okay and it's also
used by Apple's HFS plus file system
now Apple's file system hdfs plus is
used between 1998 to 2017.
okay
so utf-16 is used by this system so
um fairly popular
okay that's one of the encoding
Unicode defines okay we are remember we
are talking about what what does Unicode
defines Unicode defines a character set
defines the character id or code point
for each character then it defines
by now two encodings one is the
beginning UCS
uh
two so-called today you know that's the
original encoding each character is 16
bits then in 1996 they invented utf-16
because they think that you know 16 bits
32 000 characters is not enough so they
created Created uh utf-16 encoding so
each character is now 16 bits or 32 bits
depends on the character okay
and this utf-16 coding is became fairly
popular in the 1990s used by you know
several programming languages and lots
of
and many other Technologies okay that's
utf-16 coding now how it actually
translates into a character we will talk
about I'm not gonna cover because I
already this video is too slow then I
thought
okay
so that's a history of Unicode you know
begin with
um use and see the original version usc2
then utf-16
now let's talk about about utf-8 now
utf-8 is now today's Universal it's uh
it's actually the most common
utf-8 okay so utf-8 you know utf-16
is a problem it's a problem for the Unix
people and because
utf-16 is not compatible with ASCII
because in utf-16 every character is 16
bits
or 32 bits okay so-called variable width
encoding you know because each character
is either 16 or 32 depends on the
character
but it's not compatible with ASCII
because in ASCII encoding each character
is just 8 Bits in fact seven bits
you know but usually a computer unit the
minimal unit is eight because that's a
power of two you know 2 raised to the
third power
so
8 Bits is a minimum unit minimal unit in
ASCII asking coding every character is 8
Bits but it's not compatible with utf-16
so what does that mean that means every
Unix you know the whole entire operating
system all the tools grab Bash
they need to basically all be Rewritten
from from scratch to deal with
um characters text processing you know
this voice this happens in Python 2 to
python 3. that's why this is a major
region reason python you know the guide
of on Rossum created Python 3 because in
Python 2 you know this is a huge problem
huge headache
because all the software before you
before utf-16 or you before Unicode is
just not compatible you have to rewrite
the whole thing every tool
so the wrap pack the rub Peg you know
there arise the Unicode the Unix
phonetic rub Pike you know let me show
you this interesting
um history
uh okay Rob Pike created invented the
utf-8 encoding on napkin okay and here's
the
he was uh you know his article about the
history of UGA eight uh essentially he
and Thompson
he and the Thompson another Unix guy
uh what's his name
Ken okay Kim Thompson yeah I believe
that's Ken Thompson but anyway that's a
history of utfa creation so
you know you have utf-16 with which is
incompatible with ASCII creates a huge
amount of headache but the Unicode
people they they know the problem so
they created another encoding
um they tried but when they send it to
Robert Pike when Rob Pike and Ken
Thompson see it they
you know that's no good they they they
are very uh bright they you know they
that's they can see that they can tell
right away is you know this new proposal
got several problems but So eventually
they so basically they
created utf-8 they invented utfa on
napkin in a restaurant overnight
and implemented you know right the whole
spec in one week about one week so this
is um this happened in 1992 okay
so so they created
utf-8 which is became today is the most
popular and the best okay you know
because I spent a lot of time studying
utf-8 you know in the past month or so
it is actually the best encoding of them
all
and utf-8
UDF UTF UTF uh 16 is not good okay you
should use make everything utf-a okay so
why why is it so great so first of all
utf-8 is ASCII compatible that means if
you have old file you know before 1990s
before Unicode or ASCII file
you it's totally compatible with utf-8
meaning that if the you the same file
encoded in utf-8 is identical to ASCII
okay so you have you no need to change
all the Unix kernel uh programming
languages Splash grab all the tools no
no need to change okay it works still so
that's that's why that's one of the most
powerful reason UTF is the most popular
today is which is great you know thanks
to Rob Pike and uh Ken Thompson
utf-8 fantastic now utf-8 is a variable
with encoding meaning that each
character
is represented is represented by 1 2 4
bytes okay one byte is eight bits so
it's either eight
each character is either 8 Bits or 16.
or maybe uh 24
or 32 okay one two four bytes so
depending on the character so that's the
nature that's the nature of utf-8
encoding
so you might you might think
um well that's then you know that's not
good because then
then you don't know how you know you
have to look up how many how many bits
is a byte is because the you know
usually variable length encoding is a
problem
yeah that's true but the alternative is
that you encode every character as 32
bits but that that's a huge waste of
space
because if you do that then every file
will become four times larger you know
why makeup by file becomes four megabyte
then you have the but you have the fixed
width encoding meaning that every
character is always 32 bits which makes
programming easy
but however you know it's blowed every
time you know everything is
increased by four times especially when
you have to save you know load the file
in memory so
you know if you have eight gigabyte
memory RAM now it becomes not enough so
lots of problems so UTF is actually the
the best okay it's the best and it's the
most used
um on a web you know by now it's used by
97 of all website utf-8 is you know so
YouTube is great so utf-8 so let me go
back to summarize okay
so by the way you can see here's a utfa
encoding scheme and it's very simple
there's lots of great properties okay if
you get down to
uh how you exactly a character becomes
you know the binary sequence
now let me let me kind of summarize what
we talked about before now remember
encoding so what is encoding encoding is
a way to transform a character into a
sequence of binary numbers okay now what
do you need in order to do that one is
that you need to Define your character
set
now in case in the case of Unicode the
character set is all the words languages
characters okay so you know more than 32
um more than 32 thousands of them so you
have a character set then you need a
character id the code point
meaning that for each character you you
give it a integer ID okay that's the
code point
okay we have that then the next thing
you need to do is the in the the actual
scheme of encoding
so given a character you know the
character id which is a number
now now the problem is that you need to
turn this number into a binary digits
okay
now that's easy right because every
number you have a binary digit notation
representation but that's
but it's not just that because because
computers comes with a unit of bytes you
you by one by these eight bits you
cannot have 10 bits you know you you you
well you can but then you need padding
so so encoding is turning a number into
binary sequences and so far we talked
about four ways to do that one is ASCII
okay every character is just eight bits
ASCII
in fact for the SC character set you
only need seven bits so what you do is
you you just add extra zero in in front
so you have eight bits you know one byte
ASCII every character is eight bits
now you have
or engine or Unicode encoding today we
call you SC2
in that encoding
it's obsolete but in in in in that
encoding each character is 16 bits okay
fixed
now that's obsolete now so now you have
utf-16 encoding
you know you you have utf-16 encoding
where every character is either 16 bits
or 32 bits
then you have the utf-8 encoding
where every character is
8 Bits to uh 32 bits you know one or one
two four bytes okay
and this is compatible with ASCII so
this is the best okay I think that's it
for today uh I kind of
this is uh now close to 90 minutes and
it's
probably boring you know
I was thinking to
to cover them in a condensed way 30
minutes but
okay so but let me go on so just to
finish you know
so we covered Unicode now let me recap
Unicode is encoding you know it's a
Unicode Consortium begin in 1991.
the idea is to have one single Universal
encoding for other words languages
characters
so it begin by thinking that 32 000
characters is enough so they created you
know they defined a character set
they defined a unique ID for each
character then they defined a encoding
today it's called you
uh
CS2 which is obsolete okay uh where
every character is 16 bits but
but then Unicode realized you need more
than 32 000 characters you need more
than 32 bits so they created utf-16
encoding which became very popular but
then the Unix people the Unix phonetics
Rob Pike and Ken Thompson they saw the
problem they think you know you know
utf-8
utf-16 is no good we need a you we need
a ASCII compatible one they created
utf-8
which is variable width and it's
fantastic okay
and now it's Universal it's used by you
know 98 of website including all Chinese
you know we haven't talked about Chinese
encoding here but
um
but there were Chinese encoding you know
because in the 1980s in Taiwan they
started to have computers you know they
need their own encoding so
Chinese encoding an introduction you
have in the beginning 1984 you have G
you have big five encoding for Chinese
characters used in Taiwan in Hong Kong
then China
in 1980s decided you know they they need
one too so they created GB
2312. now this is actually ASCII
compatible
uh I don't know if pick five is ASCII
compatible but anyway the China's GB
something evolved into extended into gbk
encoding you know kind of Backward
Compatible extension then gbk extended
to become gb18030
again Backward Compatible and compatible
with ASCII so it's required by law in
China everything you do is should be
support this encoding and this China
encoding is actually
Unicode they are compatible with Unicode
it's considered
Unicode transformation
um
format okay that's what UTF stands for
you know you have utf-8
utf-16 what does UTF stand for that
stands for Unicode transformation format
and what does Unicode stand for Unicode
stands for Universal characters
um
code
you know so so these Chinese characters
said is also
uh you know uh Universal
transformation
um format okay it's compatible with uh
Unico
so even in China today if you look at
all the Chinese
um
websites for example
you know I did a survey
last month you know a few weeks ago you
know looking at all the most popular
Chinese website what do they date what
do they use utf-8 okay they actually
also use utfe quite interesting
uh okay so that's that's about it for
today now let me talk about surrogate
pair okay surrogate pair
so a good pair is something that came
out of utf-16
which is a Abomination now remember you
know originally Unicode thinks that 16
bits is enough but it turns out not
enough so they created utf-16 where a
character may be 16 bits or 32 depending
on the character so when you have a
character 32 bits what what do you do
basically they
they pick some
number
you know in the 16-bit space
that's unused character okay and you
know unassigned number I'm not a sign
called point so you you know they pick
something in that range then
then two of those units together
you know each unit is 16 bits two of
those in an unused range
if you have two of those they say that
that stands for a character that's more
than 32 bits so that's what surrogate
pair is
surrogate pair
this is nasty Okay so we've got paper
creates lots of problems so that's one
of the problem that's that's why utf-16
is no good utf-16 is no good because
it's not ascially compatible then you
have the surrogate pair kind of a hack
because remember
utf-16 happened because
originally you know they think 16 bits
is enough but then it's not
so they try to extend it but in a
banquet compatible way so that's why you
have C you have utf-16 and you have
surrogate pair
okay so that's some technical Point
um
okay I think that's it for today
in email system everyone uses the same
encoding yeah well today it's all utf-8
you know especially if you use Google
because in email
uh it's today basically you just have a
few handful powerful centralized
corporations that runs email because
they
they try to prevent you know ideally
with the email protocol on internet
everyone can run create an email or
server but not today because all the
giant they prevent you to do so in all
sorts of ways so you and also because
people became lazy so
it's not like the 90s in the 90s
everyone if you don't if you are a nerd
you can you know if you run Unix or
Linux you can start your own email
server and but not today it's very hard
so you just have Microsoft Yahoo mail
Microsoft Mail or Google and in those
handful they control all the email why
why because they can so they can look at
your email content
with the collaboration of USA government
and other big
um governments such as China you know
they prevent you from creating your
email but so yeah so in email mostly
it's a
I don't know the details but you can
look up the you know the email protocols
have changed over the past 20 years
um
but I'm pretty sure if you use Google
mail for example it's all utf-8
okay there's a question about uh the
exposed compared to comparable to
Kinesis I'm not going to explain that I
you know watch my other videos
um
okay that's it
bye guys if you like my stuff donate
okay
PayPal patreon me
uh go to my website saudi.info and all
the way down you can see patreon or buy
me an Amazon gift card or PayPal me or
you can also Bitcoin me
and you can get my entire website
content if you give a big gift of 300
I'll send you this is like one gigabyte
also the content and information okay
you can also buy my emacs tutorial you
know
my you know emacs tutorial my JavaScript
tutorial in the independent you know I
have like 800 pages of JavaScript in
depth
okay
if you like my stuff support me
uh there's a question about
deleting emails to deleted emails
actually leave a server that is the best
way to do this basically there's no way
to delete emails okay that's a New
Concept
the deleting email is a New Concept
maybe from Google Gmail someone you know
they added the feature but
as far as I know the email protocol
there's no way to do it once the email
is sent it's sent you cannot delete it
okay so I don't know I don't actually
know exactly what Google Gmail do when
they offer you a deleted email but
basically that's impossible so don't
think about it and you know Google might
have like
yeah I don't think it's possible once
email is gone it's it's out okay
hi guys