hello hello welcome to another episode
of EXA talk show now I need to make
coffee so I'll be back in 1 minute and
let's begin coding emac this
okay sound talk show am I good audio
check video check video Check Yes I'm
good Le coding beautiful girls generated
by AI be right back in 1
minute
for
e
for for
fantastic are we here yet oh fantastic
so many people check audio
check US Army b o you can be this is a
quality
cup Ral count head count
Rolph hello fantastic crystals hello
fantastic
Pinda
fantastic have you given up using SW
board SW board this is swab board okay
SW board fantastic not well
so much delays I never actually plugged
it in you know because coding is more
important for me um you know the reason
let me talk about this for a few minutes
I was just talking to CLA you know uh
fantastic guy who created this okay so
I'm going to do this I'm going to uh
going to play with it uh in my live
stream uh next week I mean within 10
days okay maybe tomorrow but but anyway
anyway uh you know next week or so so
you see magnetic so you see why the
delay because wellow coding is more
important to me and this because I'm a
ergonomic phonetic okay so so this I
everything checked out the the you know
I checked out the input you know how it
works so I think this is great I will be
using it but it takes you know a total
switch like once I learn this you know I
can see the day once I learn this you
know I will not be using any of these
normal keywords anymore so that's kind
of a major switch so that's why I
haven't really got into and also of
course another thing is the layout you
know because I'm
a philosophy academic kind of guy so I'm
kind of slow but in detail so I you know
so this
you know you can there are L layout
issues and then there's standard there's
abbreviation system so you know I can
see myself I'm going to be very
elaborate like I'm going to
take uh days you know B basically it
take me few years to you know I I mean
not take few years but I will be using
it and develop systems on it you know
for years to come so uh so I haven't
done that yet so but you know next week
you know within a week we will be uh
I'll be uh starting to explore it
okay so um hey hey there hey Dan hey Dan
uh recovered after last live session
yeah this next live session is the wolf
wolam language coding coding a
uh uh Advent of a code and that was 6
hours
uh oh that's interesting I must only use
SW board for today's stream no not today
but yeah that would be interesting that
would be that would actually force
myself to you know get onto
it
but and yeah okay so let's let's go
let's get on to emac this today's topic
okay 11 viewers fantastic Where Do We
Begin did uh you know I talked about
keyboard so many times so let's skip it
today so let's uh
show thank you Ai and thank you Elam
musk for bringing us this fantastic
thing beautiful girls girls the center
of humanity you love it I love it but we
refuse to talk about it you know to be
so explicit you know we like today's
zumas they'll say h this is a TH or
[ __ ] or whatever they I don't care but
actually you care very much that's the
purpose of your life okay and girls you
look at girls they themselves look at
other girls you know you look open the
girl women's magazine it's all beautiful
girls okay enough of that so let's uh
let's let's C today's emac list
okay uh
fison says hi if you call
yourself a JX expert why your
website this is interesting why is your
website so ugly without common font end
features and styles my website is the
most efficient most beautiful most lean
most correct then all the other
JavaScript react angular what whatever a
crap bloated okay that's another topic I
can talk about that you know for for for
days you know because let me let me just
talk about that in for two
minutes I learned HTML in
1996 at wolam research okay HTML Life
begin around 1990s web didn't begin
really until year 2000 I mean year 2000
there's only five websites actually more
than that you know
so I mean so the web didn't become like
mainstream until even even
2005 you know well basically until Apple
Steve Jobs created iPhone that's when
every you know non computer users use
web anyway so I learned HTML
1995 at wolfan
research I learned about web server you
know back then I just know wam language
you know I don't know anything about
what's Unix and I I vaguely have some
idea it's like you know this fancy
esoteric operating system I don't even
know what operating system means okay
technically you know I don't know you
know networking what does that mean
networking I mean then then you hear
some you know news articles about uh the
hackers they they writing web quers how
you can create automatic bot that cor
the web you know spider you know it was
called you know cor the cyber space you
know I didn't know what I don't know all
of that I don't know Pearl I don't know
Unix I even don't know what is a tar you
know gzip tar like you compress the file
you know at that time but I was the I
was already kind of the expert I would
say of wolam language because I've been
cing it for like seven years that's all
I know math and wfam language okay it
was called math
Mathematica and CSS didn't CSS was born
around
1997 or 98 or something it did it wasn't
popularly used until after year 2000 CSS
okay casting style sheet yeah you know I
have tutorials on all these
okay uh you know just you know look look
at my website tutorial okay you got HTML
full introduction link
precise concise example based correct
then all the Zoomers crap out there okay
HTML intro CSS introduction okay
visually you got fancy things like
animation or transition you see June
June or Hoover image Hoover that's old
image Hoover is Asian everywhere in 19
in late 1990s okay so then you got
JavaScript this is JavaScript in
depth more in depth more correct than
any JavaScript you can buy okay let me
show you an example moo he's got he he
he he showed a photo of his fantastic
desktop and books okay let me show you
the his desktop first okay his power
station and by the way we have the hot
dog idiot you know
this you know using this
ah God anyway so this is
Moo he's in Middle East okay Arab guy uh
so he's his this is his power
station you know great picture uh but he
also got a bunch of books here you see
there is there is the learning go Goan
one of the best language okay Goan and
fop industrial coding now if you all and
you need also learn UAM language okay
learning go go land and he's got a bunch
of books here and we have a magnified
version let me show you the book moo
okay hi moo uh hi Mo uh and oh this this
you know this girls are beautiful
animation girls from lunar okay not
going to show that but anyway so here's
Moo's books partially you know he got
other books so he's a he's a machine
learning expert moo that's what he does
professionally using python you know
chat GPT is written in Python the most
edic language but what can you do it's
popular like C and C++ and PHP and
JavaScript anyway so here's Moo's book
you know so one of them one of these
series of books top JavaScript books
okay it's called you don't know
JavaScript you don't know a [ __ ] about
JavaScript that is true you know if
you've been coding at Google for like
one year you don't know you don't know
[ __ ] about JavaScript okay so by this
guy what's his name something something
Simpson okay this is a good book
although I haven't actually read read it
you know I don't have it and uh it began
I'm not sure it's even online free but
it began as just one book then it
expanded you know like you don't know
JavaScript five volumes six volumes
JavaScript is the most complex crap
okay but but you really have to get into
JavaScript to actually know to actually
be able to say it is the most complex
crap possible one of the worst language
even today even with you know anyway I
talk about anyway so anyway this book
Kyle Simpson yeah is one of the best
JavaScript book okay now that book is
inferior to my okay let me tell you
JavaScript in depth this
professional you know sponsored by
Google you know they got donations you
know the these people this
this how shall I say you know this class
of people they got a lot of money you
know they can you know the
this anyway so it's a good book okay you
know Kyle Simpson you don't know
JavaScript now it's a kind of a series
like six or so books that's a good book
but my book is better okay not
necessarily better because when you are
correct uh then you know when you are
both Quality quality has many uh
aspects
but then you have the issue for example
Apple you have bad apple app versus good
apple bad apple is not fresh for example
or got warms or doesn't look beautiful
you know even though it's good apple but
you know you know it looks ugly so you
have bad apple versus good apple right
you have bad oranges rotten versus good
oranges but when you have a great
excellent fresh from the farm big juicy
Sweet Apple versus let's say orange also
fresh good giant juicy Sweet Orange then
it's a matter of style okay that's how
you judge the quality of things for
example is this you know my keyboard
glove 80 is it is it better than the
kesis
360 well both of them are the top notch
quality I would say well including the
uh automag keyboard this one but then it
comes to become a matter of style do you
want it portable do you prefer the looks
is the looks bit more important than
than whatever key switch which one you
prefer so it became a matter of
taste so I would claim let me pedal my
JavaScript okay I don't get paid you
know I don't you know you guys watch me
at you know the few donate um so I would
say claim that my JavaScript in-depth
tutorial online and free too
is is equal quality if if not Superior
than this sponsored by Google Facebook
whatnot you don't know JavaScript book
by Kyle Simpson
okay uh in terms correctness in terms of
uh quality in terms of you know every
aspect
okay anyway that's
pedaling my JavaScript and your comment
you know this your comment first and you
think my website sucks you don't know
[ __ ] you go to the common website you
know they are bloated they their CSS is
10 times the size of of my CSS file okay
like for example go to Wikipedia this is
my CSS 13k okay
13k 13 kilobytes okay go to the button
800 lines go to the top okay 13 kilobyte
you check out Wikipedia check out Google
go check check out Facebook they have
one [ __ ] bloated [ __ ] with their
jargon of atomic CSS or whatever
unreadable and
compressed you know if you want to
criticize my
website there are some parts you can you
uh you some criticism would be correct
quality
criticism but so far your criticism is
like you know the like no content okay
so CSS and also JavaScript you visit
Facebook you visit you know Twitter you
can like right now you can check out the
Twitter's uh shift control I you know
you can
check look at that failed failed this
fail to know that well that's because
blocking I
think uh you know anyway so you can
check out you know they CSS you you
you'll see that they are the CSS
exploded in efficient the JavaScript
exploded in officient and on and on and
the web design is [ __ ] up the visual
quality GUI so-call graphical user
interface or by the CSS Guru idiots they
call it
user experience like UI and ux this
jargon this starting with late meenen
okay uh why is that because you know for
example let me just show you one simple
simple example why this user interface
is [ __ ] up you know you you you like
sometimes you press page down it goes
Loop into a cycle and it's slower okay
why because they use JavaScript they
have like lots of JavaScript to track
you know which page you are on lots of
that turns you know they they need to
track I mean with Ellen Ellen musk's
Twitter since about two or three years
ago now it's much better before it's
with the Jack dorsy deep State corrupt
Twitter is far worse okay and uh and
then lots of things you know I you know
so that will be another day's
topic so am I losing audience are you
guys here to see emac disp okay so I
should get back to
eacp uh
so so you know so what so so I don't
know who you are maybe you are a Zumer
feris
like you know you are young guy so you
don't know you don't know the issues and
and you know
this okay let me show you just one last
page then that that's about it about
this topic then let's go back to emac
this okay so so you just search for in
info actually go toar code okay go down
you know it's link they P the page loads
instantaneously and I've started to
remove any YouTube in beds because every
time you have one YouTube
ined it uh let let me show you one
YouTube ined for
example my old video so let's say this
one you know there's a YouTube ined
every time you have a YouTube Ed it
sucks up one megabyte or was it you know
like uh not one megabyte much more you
know they they suck up your memory you
can see it you know in in a you know
every time your page has one YouTube in
bed your
memory increases significantly okay I
forgot exactly what it is okay you know
we can show it actually right
away uh you just okay so turn that path
into a URL that one then you just open
in Brave okay I can show
you oh then you need on JavaScript of
course okay you see this's one embedded
YouTube video now you go here it'll tell
you memory usage 800 I mean 82 megabytes
okay now if you go to Twitter memory
usage
megabytes
Jesus qu
38 megabytes book bookmark news that's
my website okay but anyway so you see
this website with invented YouTube now
let's remove it open it showing browser
that's one go back and uh remove this
embed uh let's say just comment out okay
showing browser so it's good now go back
to Twitter I mean go back to the break
browser now remember it's 82 megabytes
now refresh okay actually that won't do
because it's in memory so I don't think
it'll work let's
refresh uh well then then I need to
upload to my to my um to my
server yeah okay so wait so let's just
show this opening bra
Brave okay uh yeah so if
you and you have to try Chrome now but
chrome doesn't show the memory like that
anyway
um you can how do I st okay so anyway so
this page
is 52 megabytes of memory
what but anyway it 99 now it's 99
megabytes so anyway every time you have
YouTube in bed a YouTube video it uses
like 30 30 megabytes something like that
okay blo it like full of
blo uh partly they do that they promote
that because then they for example
Microsoft they want you to buy a new
computer so they make money and Google
uh Google is
like I'm 22 years old yeah so do you
understand what I'm saying so for you
know if you want look at pretty website
let's go to some tech website GitHub
github.com
okay oh God okay so I mean right now
it's without JavaScript that's why it's
kind of [ __ ] up you know my website
doesn't [ __ ] up even if you have
JavaScript off you know my website like
if you go to Richard stallman's website
or many of the classic like Paul granham
okay po
grham you know his website is the most
ugly possible
because he's old you know he's before my
gen that you know this is his website
let's turn on
JavaScript you know do nothing and these
are image bit Maps you know do you know
what I'm talking about image Maps that's
how these links work there so in short
what Paul Graham is doing he's you know
his HTML is like
1999 HTML you know
so if you want to criticize like
originally you said oh your website
sucks looks like old or something that's
Paul
grham website okay Paul grham a billion
you know billion a or something probably
or 100 Millions you know you know The
Hacker News founder of Hacker News he he
he's a top expert of common lisp coder
he wrote common lisp he uh created one
of the first
online store sold it to Yahoo and he
found it hack news to promote the
so-called you know Silicon Valley
incubator whatever you know the the the
the invest capital investment angle
angel invest investors whatever [ __ ]
money you know to to to promote uh new
website so anyway Paul grham okay his
website is
1999 1999 crap plain and simple
okay but my website is not 1999 okay my
website it's plain and simple just like
Paul
grham possibly you know not larger size
in anything than than his website but
however let me show you some of my uh
features on my website you got well
first of all you got invaded videos when
it is appropriate for example even I'm
trying to remove it today you know I've
been trying to I've been removing you
know I have I've been blogging for like
30 years almost so I started to remove
all these YouTube embeds because Google
has become so corrupt I don't want any
their code because when you embed the
YouTube video they essentially can do
almost anything you know anyway it's a
huge issue okay um so my website you got
interactivity okay for example
image roll over CSS animation and why
does it stop because after like 30
seconds I made it stop it because used
to when C CSS animation came up about 10
years ago it it uses huge CPU okay when
you have CSS animation on you you know
you can see the CPU went up but today's
I think they fixed
that but okay okay refresh you can see
they work again so you have
interactivity you have you know dynamic
highlight you know that let me just
introduce some of the my website
features okay now let's say you click on
color ingredient oh you have random
generation interactivity or you want a
rainbow rainbow or random what about I
just want four colors I don't want so
many okay and you can change direction d
dynamically as you can you see my screen
or am I just oh you can
okay you see
and okay and and let's say so uh select
a syntax you know you see this highlight
that tells you this is the page you are
on let's say click on CSS length units
oh so you are on this page so you know
let's click on 2D transformation move
the mouse here oh
uh oh yeah this so This are example 2D
transformation they are not Dynamic but
if you want Dynamic you click on you see
it tells you you see that highlight
that's done by
JavaScript
Dynamic and uh this transition CSS
transition Mouse overover over me and
you can see
example over here you can see you see
and uh what about you know these CSS
Guru [ __ ] they are you know I hey
hi I I work at Google I'm the head of
Google uh web design these idiots these
idiots okay they they want to they talk
about
responsive design you know another
jargon responsive design have you heard
of it you must have right because that's
your generation responsive design oh
let's see let's see shrink the window oh
oh the panel is gone you see let's try
again in log oh the panel is back oh the
panel is gone responsive design so if
you have tiny screen my website still
works does Paul Gram's website work no
look look all the text got cut off can
you see
that
magnify now you see all the text shrink
the window all the texts got cut
off oh all the text got cut off what the
[ __ ] is po grham this Rich billion air
and master of common this what the [ __ ]
let's go to ca website let's
see oh still good oh this still works
responsive system can you see
that so it's not plain text like this
program have these hackers you know like
even even the you know let's name a few
hackers you know the of the '90s or 80s
era you know um Paul grham Richard
storman you can go to their website and
check compare compare the guui design
the U uiux user experience you know what
whatever [ __ ] J Jons go there go go to
Richard strowman website homepage go to
Paul grham go to ESR Eric Raymond who
write C cathedral in Bazar you know book
open open source Revolution oh Jesus
open source Revolution go to any of the
them these these masters of Unix or
whatever so they website is like Paul
Graham you know
1999 code my website the most link the
most and and they are valid
HTML okay by the way if you check po
Gram's website it's invalid I can tell
you right away I don't have to you know
let's go uh
HTML validator okay let's see how
standard how correct you are okay check
address P Gram's address
check oh you need to
JavaScript okay turn on JavaScript let
Google know where you
live okay let's check is PA Graham's
website
valid yeah verifying you are
human oh oh warning something something
error this character encoding was not
declared error error this [ __ ] error and
that [ __ ] [ __ ] Paul Gram's website is
incorrect what the incredibility this
this this common this master with his
you know books oh hackers and PS oh he
had wrote three books the god the gospel
of the Le coders his website is
incorrect can you believe my
eyes you see what's the
situation let's see code let's check out
C code okay file path turn it to URL
copy the path path go back here and uh
let's go to uh validate validation okay
where
it okay Paul grham failed hey Paul hey
Paul he by the way he banned me he
he he blocked me on
Twitter
uh a white guy this you know he's a
white guy these white people they make a
lot of money nobody cared about my you
know whatever I do doesn't matter how
much I work you know that's the
situation there is certain
Injustice because I talk I criticize
people freely you know they are like oh
you know better not better not associate
witha uh that's a sad PA sad part of my
story okay now let's check validate
doino
check warning okay warning is just
warning it's not technically incorrect
okay info info info info info info info
uh whatever
info that what it should give me a
badge
uh now why is it no badge it should give
me a badge saying that valid HTML
something uh and uh you see no error
okay it's just info but
but did they remove the badge feature
like they usually they they output a
badge saying you know check
w3c approved you know I don't know if
they removed that feature or not but
anyway you don't see errors okay just
info and what is this info about this
info is about how the W3 standard is
wrong incorrect okay he's saying that
you don't you don't need the backslash
idiotic okay because you know you look
into the standards often times they are
just wrong you know like the you know 30
years of evolution of
Dom if you code website you know you
know like extremely complex and
sometimes you wonder why why is that you
well you just have to do it that way
because 20 years ago it was that way
therefore it's this way you know so this
this info is telling you that you
shouldn't have the backslash at the end
of the you know the so-called self
closing tax okay
idiotic so it's like info is not
technically incorrect anyway I have like
you know full story and history about
that particular thing and you know it's
on my blog just search for anyway that
relates to XML you know what why did
they where where did this
backslash was introduced that's because
Ed uh because XML you guys too young you
know you guys don't know what the [ __ ]
is XML XML was for about 10 years all
the Nerds all the hackers like your
peers are saying You must use XML XML is
is the future everything must be in XML
okay you know that's that was the
situation from year 2000 to uh 2008 you
know until the what the [ __ ] group from
Apple and Google and Opera they started
HTML 5 they killed XML and and the
xhtml
okay okay so we talked for 40 minutes we
have not started to code emac this yet
so but back to I was Dem demonstrating
how my website is
interactive uh but this small haven't
finished yet for example unic code okay
let's say click insect you know you want
to know what is this oh you see the
lower right corner they show the name
and the unic code uh encoding for that
character oh
Dynamic not like Paul Graham's website
static okay so I utilize the technology
all thech technology I use okay Dynamic
what about unical search Let me let me
try this okay let's
see okay you search oh w a t e r
oh they update us you type let's delete
let's say fire let's say water okay w a
t e r that's all unic code con
containing whose name contains the word
water okay as you type now I don't want
to show the names so click on that oh
one thing one shot view
beautiful you
see and uh what what is this does this
like mpm 1,000 libraries like react
Unicode Library no this [ __ ] bloated
idiots
[ __ ] copy the URL back to
emex open that page showing browser
there it is back to emac and see the
source
code there it is let's go to search
search data oh this one search you know
JavaScript open it warning typescript
file exist opening typescript exist
opening it oh typescript type
checking the bleeding edge technology
can you see so here is the JavaScript
code actually typescript
magnify the most
Supreme no mpm [ __ ] no JavaScript no no
mpm [ __ ] no react [ __ ] no whatever
[ __ ] the most link
the most
efficient and the most correct possible
okay that is my code JavaScript my
website uh and no minified unreadable
[ __ ] yet my code is this only
eight kilobytes okay go around look at
other websites you know unical search
compare compare who is more efficient
who is faster who you know can work on
the phone small screen or large screen
compare I get um I get angry
because on these issues because my
failure in life okay for you know for
for 10 years I've been living in extreme
Poverty of course
that's a big part of it is myself to
blame but not completely okay there is
lots of this you know this grifter this
typically you know you know anyway
so that's that's you know that's about
that uh
so so we still going to code emac thisp
okay because today I need I want to do
something and uh I got something I got
more things to demonstrate but
um uh but but that's
enough okay so so let's open a new
window let
me regroup and let's code emac this and
that will be it for today
so let's see let's go to talk show
today's talk show here openend I I want
to um just post all the links we talked
about
today uh here
okay so we have a record of what we
talked about close unic code um okay
next close that next
okay that we showed that page kind of uh
that's a URL I want to turn it to a
local file path uh wrong
key there okay link it clur that CL set
next next okay back
here
uh so we talk about Paul Graham what's
his the you know what is his better
basan filtering that's year 2003 okay
that is also edotic you know this basian
filtering article better basian
filtering article on you know all the
hackers you know these mainstream Elite
hackers are chanting singing you know oh
Paul Graham wrote another article this
is fantastic they are all promoting it
promoting it this but this idiotic why
because you know I can tell you you know
this is long ago 20 years ago but I
still remember what is this article is
about he created a fiing span spam
filter system for email okay back then
email is a thing today the Zuma
Generations you know some of them don't
don't know email anymore anyway so spam
become a major problem like 90% of email
is all Spam so Paul Graham created this
thing this is called Tech geekers
fighting Tech
geekers have you guys seen the Spy
versus spy let me let me digress okay
because today I feel just you know
happens feels like digression have you
guys seen the comics That's a classic
most popular in 80s and 90s Spies versus
spy so let me show you
uh here's a badge okay the badge we were
talking about that w3c
badge the Spy versus spy so where is it
so let me show you so you got to go to
um hacker code
okay uh I have too many articles I don't
even remember where is it so
okay you just have to go to
net
anthropology let me explain my
pain when a person sanity is at balance
when human passion is Raging no eate
must get in a way eate is one of the
most popular term around uh let's say
late 1900 19 95 to 2005
okay the Internet is just starting to
grow so but you know like today you have
you know Wikipedia you know you have
Discord for chatting but back then you
don't have you know this you know you
don't have social networks Twitter and
so on but you have you do have a like
alternative like the same thing but in
that in in the technology at the at the
time so net is one of the popular world
you know like people talk about nqu like
this almost every website you have a
page about net it's kind of like today's
code of conduct
okay uh code of conduct very extremely
corrupted
thing so anyway this
is collection of articles I wrote back
around year 2000 okay so what I want to
show you is that spy a spy
thing
uh okay let's look uh I know where it is
okay so let me show you let's just go
slowly let's just you know random chat
today maybe we call emac this Paul
Graham's infatuation with the concept of
hackers you know that's one of the
streak of prr have he's in fact uated
with the concept of hacker because in
his like the hacker the concept of
hacker is like deep in his in his um
Persona in his soul because for example
one of
the you know he's creating new lisp
programming language okay uh Arc then
there's another one replacing it like
Hacker News is written in Arc okay arc
Arc AR list anyway so he in he so he
says you know the best programming
language
is is the one that's hackable you know
so you know like you know PR Graham's
idea ideal language is a language that's
hackable
okay you know you know so that's his
obsession you know and also he create
you know like the hacking is like his
thing you know like the idea
and he also wrote an article about what
is philosophy okay on his website you
know this is my comment you know my my
commentary death of a troll my memory of
Eric nagam okay another famous lisper
what is a tech geeker what is a hacker
hacker versus Tech geeker
hacker the name of my
pain okay the one true history of meow
is one of the biggest flame war on the
internet in the in 1990s okay 1990s or
1980s the biggest this article is
constantly linked by others because I
documented it all the original is you
know
gun you know the the one true history
history of meale by written by you know
this you know the two battle that's a
big chapter okay so to catch a TR okay
so I want to show you you the Spy versus
spy
um let's see this one there it is Tech
geekers versus spammers you see you see
what this Tech NS like you guys is still
kind of so
today for example constantly you want to
fight fight the spammers fight the
grifters fight whatever Discord this EST
establishment the redit the Twitter so
you how do you you do it because you are
a nerd so you don't know you know real
word you you you you just know with what
you know so the way you fight it is you
for example you become a n you stay a n
like a hot dog idiot you know you you
have a you have a need to I must be a n
because in today world you know you have
a you have that you know that almost IM
most zumas you know you need to be a n
first of all and then when you know
you're going to you know you don't trust
Discord but however you going to you
want to use it so you're going to you
know go to you know gitlab or whatever
open source Discord client alternative
or text version Discord even though
Discord license of agreement says you
know you shouldn't do that but you're
going to do it anyway because you are a
nerd you know you just going to [ __ ]
around open source open source you're
going to [ __ ] around you want everything
free you demand demand
it okay so so the way you fight it you
know oh oh I'm going to use a uh you
know alternative Discord how you should
use it too you know you tell every
everyone and you're going to use Linux
and you're going to use oh this you know
like like the moo moo you know he's
saying we should use the net something
net protocol The Matrix you know like
you know things like that
uh you know so that's the story of
nerd uh most clearly shown by this spy
versus
spy Comics you see you know this spy
versus spy if you guys don't know the
theme is that usually you have two spies
you know black spy versus white spy they
just they um how do you say one up men
each other with their tricks and traps
and you know whatever technology you
know like this one thing you know I'm
going to have this bomb you know he's
going to be dead you know I got this new
technology bomb and and that guy is
gonna I'm gonna have this bom new design
this you know he you know he's the other
is GNA be that spy versus
spy uh what's the
word there's a word
um something escalation okay
technological uh escalation but
something
escalation you know like for example
this meat grinder you know the white
spice is going to grind the black but
the black grind you know they both going
to be
grinded and uh you know so this is a
fantastic comics of the very popular of
19 I I think they even begin in 1960s so
this like before my generation okay
Spies versus spy you
see very
funny
uh
they they Mark and they are you know
they
Mark
the you know the the society and you
know anyway my point here about the
Spies versus spy
is that I'm talking about you guys the
Nerds and the Paul granham the Paul
grham idiot because in order to fight
spam po Graham is nerd he come up with
the nerd system I'm just going to have
this The Cutting Edge filtering system
based on the you know basian filtering
St statistic like you know analogous to
today's AI whatever you know they are
doing you know we I'm going to use AI to
to prevent to do this or
that so he's going to you know create
the Bas and
filtering to fight spam okay so you know
the text is too small so now it's larger
so you can
see you know so what is Paul Graham
doing he's he's doing like what this
this this spy versus spies are doing
okay
very bad okay idiotic brandless like
they because nerds they don't understand
how Society Works how you should how how
do you should fight the spammers or
today's grifter scammers they they are
everywhere you go to YouTube these all
these most popular people are the most
you know scammers you know like the
grifter like they got millions followers
they just post drama and [ __ ] every like
this guy this this
guy this guy is a Brian cren standin
he's a very not just the scammer not not
a typical he's a million million star
scammer okay and and the the elamus is
sometimes like repost constantly often
reposting him his things he's like a
professional scammer for like 20 years
right you
know scams million of dollars by
whatever you know whatever is urrent you
know like five years ago or 10 years ago
people are like fat about something else
he's doing that then something else you
know like a huge scammer you know if you
want to know you can look deeper you
know they they are um ex you know ex
they are they are articles and and uh
you know
exposing him you know that these two uh
Brothers Cent and CR and stain Brothers
okay Brian and Ed huge scammer you know
they got they got they got millions of
followers okay and
uh I'm not I don't want to you know I
don't want to
really uh be too harsh on some of the
people because some of them are you know
because some of them are really bad okay
like the Brian guy okay he's like really
really nasty he should go to jail and in
fact the FBI rided his home I think he
made a pack with the with the Deep state
so deep State okay but you do this this
okay we let you go or something you know
that's just my opinion okay I don't know
if it's true or not I don't want to get
legal into legal
trouble um but so anyway you you I I
think you know what I'm saying you know
if you are on Twitter you know there's
huge amount of them and one of them you
know the crystal is mentioning there
that young miles strong guy
okay and
also
uh but also some of them just you know
they they just you know they were born
and they you know they they were born
into this on social network you know
social media world that you know to them
it's normal so they just make money
whatever you know you have to be
dramatic dramatic you know it takes some
skill to be very popular you be you know
you need to re you know you you there
are several many things to consider time
of your post how shall you post wording
of the post you know you you want to
make it so that each each of your posts
becomes a meme you know that's why
there's a lot memers this this there are
dedicated memers like I mean you know
scums
like you don't know you guys don't know
and and many of you um you know some
people idiots like when I say something
elus they say oh elus is this or that
they don't they don't know they you know
you don't know
things uh okay so lots of Random so Paul
grham so we were talking about Paul
grham uh now okay so now it's 1 hour
maybe not least today I guess
H too bad well because
today today where is it you know today
we got
this this lovely thumbnail it says lips
lisp so we should C some thiss let's
let's C thisis okay let's
stop okay thisp okay so what is it today
I want to
do yeah so let's go
um yeah let's I'm not going to you know
since we got this beautiful lisp
thumbnail we are going to do lisp okay
we are going to code lisp in 20 for 20
minutes and uh I can finish
it uh but what is it we want to do let
me show you okay so iMac this write the
command to rename variable names so in
particular rename the variable names xp1
xp2 to X begin X end okay the command
will work on the current uh function
definition okay let's write
that okay let's begin coding okay uh
this is what we want to
do okay so let's uh
what okay so uh yeah defund D for defund
I'm using are fly Keys search for it
you'll find it it's the most efficient
key binding for emac more efficient than
vim and Neo I'm using sofly keys I'm
using a keyboard and you can see all my
commands and uh and keystrokes on the
Ping window close that ping window here
and uh I'm using SAR emac this mod so
that's why you press D for defund expand
the whole thing or you see just single
key press okay no control no meta and if
you want to delete the whole just put
here one key press delete the whole
syntactical unit okay so anyway let's
write the
command
so change uh rename V okay let's just
say that just simply uh rename okay so
here is the documentation let's put here
rename
variables
uh xp1 xp2 to X beginning X
end in
current def okay defund means like
this you know it's a syntactical unit
unit that defines a function okay so any
comments and questions
okay the point about Paul Graham is that
I mean it's not bad okay he I mean he's
a very capable man and very you know
he's a master of common list one of the
greatest you know in common in history
okay Paul Graham
so he's a master and he's a programmer
programming language designer he's not
he he's very high IQ
okay and uh this article his spum system
you know he actually wrote code so and I
think it's adopted by Google and you
know they started to he made it popular
okay back in 20 years ago
2003 so it's not bad but and and all the
Nerds like like back then like today you
know today everyone is talking about
something like today everyone is talking
about ai ai or something whatever before
that is crypto currency or CH blockchain
you know and then then you have web
three you know like these idiots you
know or chanting about it so back then
everyone is chanting about you know look
at po poam B system you
know which is not bad okay but my point
is
that you want to fight the spammer so
how do you fight the spammers or grifter
or these scammers okay you you know if
they do spam scam grifting or scam
comment they go to jail or punish by I
don't want to say the word starting with
d or but the better name is capital
punishment okay like in in in in Middle
East countries I don't know if it's true
today if you steal you got caught your
hands got cut
off okay so how do you fight spammers
and grifters and
scammers go to
prison okay so open source is not the
answer okay what you do if Google you
discovered Google is actually containing
back doors or cheating you know or this
or Microsoft or Facebook you know you go
to jail that's how you deal with it not
like the hot dog today's generation
idiots oh I'm just gonna be a n and he's
going to re erase his post every week
you
know [ __ ] you know you stand for
Humanity
Justice Law and Order order
at least that's the white man's proper
reaction to these criminals this this
this this this you know scamming and
whatever deep State
okay so again my point is that these
nerds you know this these Elite hackers
these thought
leaders I mean it's not nothing wrong to
create a program to fight the spam but
you should I mean but you we you should
at least know tell people that
alternatively because all these are made
by
human if all you do is just write code
or I'm going to like today many of you I
I know Tech I'm going to create a you
know domain you know my personal domain
redirect whatever you know on Windows on
Linux you know like that's going to
that's you know what what is that that
is
that is this that's what
happens what's the word escalation okay
let's search I want to find the right
word wait did I not use the word
uh you know email spam become worse and
worse you know like 90% of email traffic
is
Spam and today it's even worse because
Google they you know Gmail and this all
these emails they they you know it's not
by spammers anymore now it's by Deep
State
they if they determine this email should
not be send they will make it so so your
email to someone is is never send
okay okay back back to emx okay
so let me just quick code quickly to to
get this work okay so we want to rename
okay
so uh Nar region I'm just going to code
this quickly okay let
um X begin X end okay uh we have two
points uh
actually Nar
to Nar to
defund okay do you uh Nar to
defend so it will automatic
automatically narrow the above to the
function definition okay so we don't
need that I guess
um okay so actually I don't have that
colored so here you narrow to defend
then what you do so you narrow it now
you just go to go to char buffer minimum
go to uh buffer uh Point minimum go to
the beginning of the
buffer narrow to Def just like means
this okay so for example let me do for
example
uh something okay so here's a function
right let's C it up right here's a
function so if your cursor here is here
you call narrow to
defend to defend okay you see it just
pretend it as if the anything outside of
it doesn't exist so you can go to the
beginning go to the end or you can do
find and replace it will just work in
this region okay when you are done you
call the command wi done okay if you
don't you know once you widen you can
see the top or bottom okay let's do it
again okay so C narrow to defend do it
you see you don't you don't see you know
anything beyond them now Co
widen to undo the effect now you can
see okay so that's what this Nar Define
is okay now once we do
that uh we
go to the beginning of the buffer then
we uh go to the beginning of buffer and
uh while search for word for X
begin let's just search for word for xp1
okay so bound not NE we don't no need
the end boundary no error true okay
because some if you cannot find it don't
don't uh signal error okay so while I'll
search for
xp1 replace it by uh
X begin okay so fixed case
uh yeah you want fixed case Okay fixed
case true and literal true
okay so but this search forward we also
find the capital version so we don't
want that so we want to
say uh case for search case for
search equals to NE okay when case for
search is true that means any search
will search will be case
insensitive but we want to be case
sensitive so that's why we
said locally case for search NE okay so
search forward xp1 then replace match
you know repeat okay then let's do the
whole thing
again this time for
xp2 okay and replace it by X
end okay clean the
code I think that's it then when you are
done when you are then that's that's it
okay so actually remove that
um remove that okay I think that's it
that's it let's clean let's
um okay that's a code evaluate the
buffer now let's go to now let's put it
back color it and showing browser you
can see here's a code today now let's go
to soft flag
keys so this is the soft FL Keys 4,000
lines of code let's try to use it search
for xp1 okay so you can see here is a
command with the xp1 variable and xp2
variable okay wait there's one thing I
forgot to do we don't want you know if
we have a long word such as
that we don't want to replace it we only
want xp1 XP to by themselves in other
words we have to check boundary okay so
undo so let's go back to the code let's
modify the code
so so let me show you so this code needs
to be modified instead of search forward
you
say
um you say regular expression search
forward and here you want to add a
boundary so the way you do that is
is back slashback SLB for boundary you
know it's ugly but that's how things are
so uh I believe that's it so if you are
not sure I'm not sure so you go
to uh emag this Basics emac this search
for regular
expression
regular uh
rejects wait practical emac
dis okay it's not here so this basic
yeah
okay okay regular expression in emac you
want to check for the
syntax so regular expression syntax now
you want to check for boundary so scroll
down a bit you'll see what's the syntax
for boundary of the
word uh grouping Alternatives class
character classes and character classes
of emac syntax table boundary anchors
okay
so there it is word boundary marker B uh
actually we want the symbol boundary
marker for beginning of symbol actually
so we want that one so what is the
difference between word and symbol now
this symbol boundary is unique in iMac
disp in other regular Expressions such
as in Python in Pearl in goand in Java
in JavaScript you don't have this symbol
thing okay but in emac so this is unique
to emac because in emac distinguish a
word from a symbol what's the difference
a word is just you know the normal
meaning of word like talk show like you
know alphabet Plus numbers you
know so a sequence of alha numerics
that's a word okay but but in emac you
have a a concept of symbol symbol is is
usually words plus the underscore or
words plus the you know low line or plus
hyphen or both of them so that so
essentially a s symbol means an ident
identifier okay in programming language
Jon identifier okay so this is unique in
emx uh close that so so we want to use
the symbol boundary okay back slash
underscore
um okay so end of symbol then
beginning of symbol okay so it looks
ugly when you have a backslash but when
you a string backslash needs to
be escaped by another backslash that's
why you see two backslashes you know
that's incomprehensible thing so okay so
you replace that by that okay so now we
don't need that okay the same thing here
uh we can
just copy this string move here paste
that string delete that string and
replace this by by two okay pretty the
code evaluate it put it back put it back
cify showing browser there it
is and uh let's go to a example let's do
it okay we want to make sure this first
of all
backup
so color XP and xp1
xp2 okay now let's call the
command rename V
okay fantastic now it didn't change xp2
why is
that okay let's undo let's go back to
drawing board let's see why is it not
changing the
xp2 oh we forgot to use regular
expression okay you need research
forward okay so put it here evaluate the
buffer go back to that here call the
command do
it beautiful
undo do it again beautiful
okay even Lo softly keys so this code
you know so we can actually go go to the
directory and uh compile it compile no
error when you have an error usually
compile we'll find it so but no error
okay open the compile file delete it we
don't need it close it close it okay
that's it for today now this one more
important thing to do because when you
replace a variable by another you want
to make make sure there's no existing
variable by that by whatever you are
replacing because if there is already
exist then you [ __ ] up your code so we
need to do a extra
check you know if there exists already X
begin you need to replace it by
something else okay and actually we can
do
that we can do that by you know by by
first do a like pre-processing you know
anyway that's it for today thank you
guys for
watching your hair is
beautiful that's a atomic song I love
that song I I don't I cannot sing
well um okay that's a code fantastic um
yeah
so so let's write a warning one more
step we need to do okay so let's put it
here if the code already has X begin or
X end we
we need to replace them first by
something
unique something like that okay you can
generate a unique symbol easily for
example for example let's say
x random number okay you know press this
key random number this key or if you
want you know uh more
complex random string you can do that
that so that command you can see C
insert random string or C insert random
number okay
there okay but anyway that's the code
color it showing
browser page
down there it is
fantastic so let me explain why do I
want to rename them
because well my style so this is
regarding
programming style more specifically the
variable naming style okay that's a big
issue uh in fact very important I mean
although it's not critical because the
program doesn't care what variable name
you use you can use you
know girlfriend's names or whatever I
remember a joke or story like some you
know like someone says that one time
he's reading source code of a guy or a
friend and all the variable names or or
function names are his ex-girlfriend's
names so anyway the code doesn't care
how you name your variable but to
humans in real life coding the variable
name is extremely important function
name because they serve as a
documentation what this thing do because
imagine
uh imagine let's say let's let's list
all function names in emex okay you see
all these functional command names now
imagine all of them is just random
string then basically emac became
impossible to use but it still works
100% right so this is how important the
naming of things are
when you read the source code you know
let's say un you
know when you when you read the source
code uh let's go to the Unicode search
okay we will we will you know reading
this so here's a source code uh you know
if all the function names let's
say let's list all function okay so kind
of like that so if all the function
names is now a random
string then it will be impossible to
understand the code essentially or you
make it 10 times more difficult so this
function name becomes extremely
important
okay and uh so how so how should you
name functional variables that's kind of
an a top IC by
itself
um but we basically intuitive know you
know you just name it like what it does
but I mean but the the the the science
of this is not settled because for
example if you go to Powershell or bash
or Unix Unix has their own kind of
naming like two characters LS cryptic
[ __ ] cat LS C I think I got a important
um
message okay I got to go uh I gotta
go I gotta go so so that's it okay um
that's it thank you you
know uh no image saw what
image so what um so anyway so you want
to you know pay me okay if you like my
stuff if if you you know enjoy my emx
tutorial or JavaScript or my talk show
uh donate to me okay patreon Amazon gift
card PayPal okay I got to go thank you
guys for watching bye
guys uh if you you know also if you can
comment uh put time stamps comment on my
YouTube comments that would be
appreciated bye guys