hello guys
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2021
and june
25th 2021 june 25th
now it's two o'clock in the afternoon
san francisco time
welcome to another episode of talk show
and today i don't have a topic i was
going to do some
wufang language from language
mathematical coding but
i was debating with dion about
about about economics
economics crypto uh currency and stuff
and i got distracted and now i don't
know what
am i going to talk about i didn't
prepare so
if you have questions comments just post
it okay i'd
love to see your comments your comments
direct
what we're gonna uh talk okay
so otherwise you know the when there is
no topic
the easiest thing is to start to work on
emacs because for emacs
i'm ready to code i have lots of things
to say
after turns like no you know without
preparation i don't need to prepare so
for example let's go to casa fly keys
now the it's 4 600
lines of code stuff like he's fantastic
okay uh okay so if there's no topic i'm
just gonna
work on stuff like keys so what what i
need to do is to add
delete selection mod okay so you can see
here dd selection mod and let's
let's let's show some let's do some
microsoft browser the browser you love
okay let's magnify to 110
magnitude of font and back to emacs
fantastic key binding and set up the
most efficient system possible now go to
the bottom
paste that here so the thing we need is
this one
you are looking at the source code of
stuff like keys and i want to add
this directive into it
so what i do is these matching lines
let's see if there is um if it's already
there no it's not so i'm just going to
add this here so
add this here so where do i want to add
it
okay comment okay comment okay let's see
i want to add winks off fly keys is
on uh yes add to this section
somewhere
okay define minor mod stuff like keys
yes yes yes
ad hook and so on and then blah blah
blah
blah blah okay coding
fantastic uh where do i want to add it
define minor mod okay so that is
that um
let's just add it here okay paste that
delete selection mod okay now this is
if you don't know when this is on in
emacs
that means when you have a selection
then you start to type it will
override it okay however if it's
off that doesn't happen okay this is
other t of e max
for example selected we just you know we
evaluate this code select whatever
selected
then start to type it does not overwrite
you just add you know
wherever the cursor is at so that's not
what what we want
we want we this is a tv selection mod is
a
ah i want to add it so it's going to be
part of stuff like he's screwed
emacs convention let me tell you about
emacs convention emacs
convention is that major mod you are not
supposed to
activate other minor mods
this is uh you know so called the minor
mod it's just a preference okay
you are not supposed to do it but in
general
but for star flight keys i think it's um
you know it's it's uh it's actually
suitable
yeah to turn it on okay let's just turn
it on okay now go to the top
go to the top and you see the version
let's
update the version name okay uh at
today's date
you know including the second i use that
as part of the version
uh format okay so
version 13.12 okay fantastic
now i'm gonna save it call
match it status
okay so let's see it's gonna commit
let's see okay that's the changed part
that's good
okay stage it you know we are using
git which is the last
screw up of the unix philosophy
tradition
okay now turn
on okay turn on dd select tv selection
mod okay
commit
push it uh what what
push it
okay comments hello btx so btx
do you have a question do you uh how did
you
found me uh because of emacs or is it
because keyboard or because of
the uh some other things my website or
something
unicode and stuff so it's committed
so stuff like keys okay so it's
committed we did that
so we takes say something
uh okay no topic you know it's still
it's too random then so we
did that okay so now go to talk show go
to this page
topic notes delete selection mod
cut it go to talk show today's talk show
and paste it okay we added the selection
mode to soft light keys
and maybe create a page of init
tutorials for it
okay so that's a thing we need to do
okay so so that means go to emacs blog
you know so i need to update you know
because i write a bunch of tutorials
so on this section emacs init is all
about
emacs you need files
okay btx says i found you because of
your website it was fun to read okay
which part like you know because i have
a few
i have 6000 articles part of it is on
mathematics part of it is on programming
and programming language design
part of it is programming language
tutorials including
linux you know and and otherwise lots of
uh programming rants and part of it is
english literature for example
wordy english okay let's let me let me
show you some random i guess random talk
let's
you know we haven't talked about
non-technical topic for a long time so
let's talk about that second life okay
second life so i'm gonna show you some
of my
other websites which i'm going to merge
i'm going to merge
all these two um to
to the solid.info domain you know it's a
it's a long story why why i split them
like about 10 years ago
so you found me so via my programming
stuff
website or other parts so second life
so this is second lap anyway so let's uh
where are we
so we were doing let's see
okay so yeah emacs let's go back to
emacs because unless you you know
you you post whatever you guys post and
i'll talk about that okay
so now i'm just gonna work my daily work
uh so my emacs initial tutorial
i need to add a section
or a page about the delete selection
possibly maybe
because
so this section all these tutorials
are about how how do you config emacs
you know emacs you have literally
thousands of configurations
uh
oh you are trying to learn emacs it's a
difficult journey
uh yes indeed uh
and you know you might just as well use
vs code
which which i think is pretty good
but if you choose emacs of course the
reason will be
the advantage you know that you know if
you choose emacs
the you have to spend a lot of time like
let's say an on our day
for let's say half a year or a year to
really master emacs because otherwise
you don't know what to do it's hard to
use
but once you know it uh especially if
you know some emac this
is uh very powerful but however you know
i think actually
like i talked about this before um
okay let me show you okay
uh so you know
this is emacs so you can see on this
page
where you have visual studio code
which is using 350 megabytes of memory
and emax which is only using 22
megabytes of memory and i only i you
know
let me let me do a live demo you know so
so okay so you let's go to the
processes okay so you can see here is
emacs
uh can you magnify this yeah
network disk memory okay let's let's
click on that so e-max is using 59
megabytes of memory and let's start vs
code okay
uh let's show in this in vs code
open vs code we're just gonna launch it
so you are seeing this emacs blog file
let me let me go to the top so you can
see you see
you are seeing the exact same file in
emacs and in vs code and in vs code you
see this very long
on the right panel vs code has this uh
tree thing
by the way that's also available on
emacs but it's not
so good i have article of that but
um vs code for okay so let me talk about
vs code versus emacs
i talked about before so yeah
i you know i've been using emacs for 20
years now uh leaving it
on on the other hand vs code i haven't
used it
much i you know total the total time i
spend in vs code maybe it's
just one hour so i haven't used it much
i barely know what to
you know you know what what keys is the
directory but it's easy to use okay
basically if i start to use it on our
day
within a month i'll be pretty good you
know i know all the features
that's the difference between emacs and
vs code in e-max if you just
begin to use it you cannot be it's uh
it's a pain in the ass
you have to start to read lots of
tutorials
so that's the thing beginning uh vs you
know
vs core is super easy emacs is super
difficult
but what about if you study emacs for
one hour a day for a year
we are your um you know the ability to
use emacs we
we or emacs become better than bs code
that's a question
and even and my opinion of that is
not necessarily okay actually so this is
a
this is opinion contrary to many emacs
fans so emacs expert will tell you they
will tell you
typically okay once you spend certain
time amount of time to master emacs
you will become incredibly productive
and you will be
able to customize emacs far beyond vs
code
that's what emacs phonetics say okay
i don't i i actually i don't i don't
think that's true
uh because in vs code you know vs code
is new it's a new technology you know
javascript is a few magnitude
the power of javascript like the
language it's written in
javascript the power of javascript
language is a fuel magnitude
beyond emac list okay and it's improving
every day every year this new version of
javascript
and for each emacs user
there are ten thousand more than ten
thousand there are hundred thousand
users of vs code or
or or some javascript okay for each emac
list
coder there are 10 000 javascript coders
so in terms of knowledge and expertise
it's beyond
emacs and users okay so
emac so so the vs code and also vs code
uh you know or atom editor you know
these are new
well emacs you have 30 years baggage 30
uh
from 90 starting from 1985 also
so you have 30 30 some 40 30
years of baggage truly baggage because
all the terminology is like
30 years ago and the algorithms the
knowledge about computing algorithms
implementation
cpu and so on you know in 30 years
there's tremendous
improvement so vs code is designed from
the ground up
you know written from the ground up
about about eight years ago it's
beginning with an atom
editor okay atom editor
so if you can look up uh i atom dot
io okay you know i remember the day they
announced
from github you know this is before
github
was bought by microsoft you know github
mentioned they announced that oh we
think there's still room to create a new
editor
and you know so they did atom based on
javascript
they in fact in their original
announcement so when was that
2014 okay six seven years ago
when they announced that atom they say
we believe
something like that they said that we
believe there's still room to create a
editor you know there's already emacs
but we think we can do
actually better today that's what they
said so they created atom
with javascript as the foundational
scripting language to build the editor
and also
also the scripting language you know for
modifying the editor
so adam then you know and
of course it's open source you know it's
uh open source uh
code then after a few you know
after a few years they created
the electron framework you know so guys
if you don't know the electron
framework it came from atom it's a split
of
of the atom text editor okay let me let
me talk about this
so uh and uh okay
okay so i want to talk about this uh
yeah emacs versus
uh vs code okay but first of all let me
read
the comments sorry not quite fair
because vs code looks
gorgeous while emacs looks like gnu done
by default uh
okay that's true i find beauty in
simplicity also you can customize
through your liking okay
uh okay you guys go on argue about it
but but let me tell you uh
i mean okay let me talk about atom
versus
i mean the e-max versus uh vs code
fully you know let me tell you let me
give you my full view of the
thing and including some history so atom
begin
seven years ago and in the process they
created electron
uh which is the uh the framework
of javascript this uh okay there are
a lot of things i'm gonna say i'm gonna
tell you okay so
atom editor so how how does it work atom
editor is basically a
google chrome browser chromium you know
google chrome browser
using the google chrome browser why is
that because browser and javascript
technology they has they have become so
advanced
that browsers essentially can do
anything
you know like you can view pictures you
can watch movies
youtube you know youtube uh any pictures
or any text you can you know there are
text editors written
in in in in uh as a website for example
uh what what is it called lighting table
you know uh back in 10 years ago it was
over all over the place you know nerds
are talking about it
light table right uh
was it that or something i don't
remember
uh who remembers that editor's lighted
table
what not what is this
no it's not that okay so
anyway there's a editor you know there's
quite a lot
actually tens i think tens of editors
returning a browser
that means you go to a website then you
can start editing you know
actually this is needed it's used on
reddit it's used
used on stack overflow it's used on you
know lots of website it's a need
so anyway so javascript and the browser
technology has become so advanced
that they can do almost basically
anything
so they that's that's the idea where i
at
atom it's base it's just it's just a
browser google chrome browser
you know they you know browser with
javascript and they hide
you know for example uh they hide the
url bar they hide you know the bookmark
all those all these things you know it
so it looks like an editor
uh i don't have item installed but
anyway so atom
seven years ago from github they created
that
then in the process they created
electron
the framework electron is basically the
framework and electron
got a life of its own because it becomes
so powerful and so useful that electron
becomes the framework
for anyone to write to use javascript to
write applications for any
operating system or phone so you can use
electron
to write you know application for
windows
for mac for uh linux for
anything for and for iphone ios
or android phone you know and in fact
you see you look
at the discord you know this code is you
know
very very useful very powerful
application it's written in atom
i mean it's returning electron okay and
lots of others
so in fact electron has not just become
you know a framework for javascript it
electron
is today the most
powerful the most easy to use and the
most
you know the the basically the best
crossed
platform uh framework okay so if you
want to
write some application you want it to be
compatible and looks
exactly the same in mac or windows or
linux or on the phone
what do you do use atom okay not g
not not the gnome g uh gtk not the qt
even
okay all these cross platform you can
you know you can search for cross
platform
okay you go to wikipedia then there's a
bunch of
course platform what are these uh
cross platform uh for mobile apps okay i
don't i'm not talking about mobile apps
okay but anyway you go to gtk okay gtk
wikipedia
then you'll find the link to all the
other cross-platform
uh toolkits okay widget toolkits
okay uh usually there's at least okay
gtk is the worst crap that
nobody uses only actually only the gnome
people that you know
they supposedly they are the you know
they are cross platform and all that
actually no uh in open source there's
lots of lies until you actually
dig into you know when until if you you
know try to do it yourself you know
try to write a application cross
platform
you know uh application for windows mac
and uh
and linux and also for the phone try to
do it
and try to use ggk you know that like
get the information yourself try to use
gtk
try to learn it or use qt okay or use
uh several others or electronic using
javascript
okay here's uh so where's uh
you know i i'm kind of uh unfocused now
so anyway on wikipedia you'll find the
link
where they list all the cross-platform
um uh
you know uh toolkits you know and also
you can use
java with their java whatever you know
so all these you know because there's
someone who wrote article
in fact the it turns out today that
electron happened to happens to be the
best
you know how do you judge well judge by
many things
you know how how much effort you have to
spend on it
how much you know how how will they
actually
cross-platform or would they be you know
will the speed be the same
you know for example if you use gtk for
example maybe it works great on linux
but
it doesn't work well on windows things
like that
so it turns out you know the electron
is the actually the best cross-platform
um framework now so that's a story of
electron it
split from the atom uh effort then
because
it's open source the microsoft uh
they microsoft vs code
let's search for microsoft vs code okay
um and search for he said
their visual studio code now i don't
know what's the history of visual studio
code
i don't know i mean i don't know the
history so why did they
why did they create it i don't i don't
know i haven't been um
but anyway visual studio code is today
basically the uh basically now
i guess the most popular um
editor now so anyway i so that's the
background i gave you some background
and history of visual studio code okay
so so let me
repeat so emacs versus vs code which one
is better you know
according to emacs fanatics they will
say emacs
once you learn it once you spend you
know 100 hours to
really master it it will be much faster
than vs code and much more powerful
and much more customizable i
don't agree okay like i mentioned before
i don't
you know i i'm not 100
sure but i'm 90 sure i do not think
emacs is would be that much better than
vs code even if you have
you know spent like full year full time
to study emacs
like me for example i i i'm uh i'm
you can call me an emac list master you
know
but i be okay i believe there's a
there's a high possibility that
if starting from today i spend let's say
two hours to work on to use
vs code and spend two hours you know
every day to
study how to use javascript to extend it
i already know javascript very well i'm
a
javascript expert but you know if i
spend two hours a day to learn how the
vs vs uh code the
structure you know the the architecture
how it how to
extend it if i do that after a few
months
i believe i might say
vs code is just as extensible i mean
just as extensible and powerful and even
possibly even much
more better than emacs okay that's my
claim
now this claim is contrary to most emacs
phonetics believe
now let me just fight that a bit again i
i haven't you know i haven't done a work
on vs code so i don't actually know for
a certain you know
but um but okay so how many people are
watching
light table okay oh dion hey
so light table let's search for that you
know a few years ago
there is the you know all the nerds are
talking about it
light table oh this is the best this is
going to be the best editor and before
that is take
text mate you know they come and go
come and go like every five years so you
know
so light table i i do remember like five
years ago oh
how they look now you know like all the
nerds are talking about oh this is the
future or something like that i never
even looked into um but okay let me get
back to the vs code versus emax
so i you know like i said i don't i
haven't
spent time on vs code but i but i highly
believe that if i do
actually spend time to study vehicle yes
code i may find it actually to be more
much more powerful better than emacs
period not just ease of co
use but power and efficiency and all
that okay
that is my um that is how i regard vs
code
now the reason i haven't spent time to
study that because i don't
you know i don't have time i need to
study math and all that and i'm too old
i'm getting old
so i don't have many years left
so if i get on 3bsco that
basically means throw away my 20 years
experience with emacs and
stuff okay so that is my
overview of how i i think of emacs
versus vs
code but however however this is
important okay let me actually let me
switch my camera to my
face because i'm not coding much
anyway
okay so
so
that this is why the screen i don't want
i don't you know
people you know when people buy camera
they want white screen but for me
i don't want white white screen so
so anyway however
there is a major problem with vs code
uh let me tell you what that is okay
because
you know emacs is created by nuts
therefore everything is extremely tight
okay
so that is why you see you see you know
emacs uses memory what
what percentage you know 58 megabytes
while if i you know when i i just
started
vs code it only has one file and it's
already 370 megabytes of memory
you know so you might be wondering so
why is that
that is because well you might say
because
vs code is based on a browser but
but this is not gonna go away okay so
so let me summarize so so first of all i
think vs code
is not necessarily um it may actually be
more powerful and
uh more customizable than emacs that's
one thing if you spend enough time to
study it on the other hand vs code is a
product of a
giant corporation team at microsoft and
the source code
for vs code
and and and because you know because
it's a
product of giant corporation you
are going to be stuck with a problem
like this
inefficient use of memory and lots of
crap lots of bloat
that's that's that's going to be part of
vs code for certain so even though you
if you master it the javascript the
language the embedded language may
may be your magnitude more powerful and
faster than emac base
which is true but you are stuck with a
situation
where it's gonna be bloated
you know that thing you probably cannot
avoid
you know not just because
you know the electron you know the
browser is using so much memory but it's
going to have bloats everywhere
um because it's a part of
a corporation you know team you know a
programmers in a team they don't they
don't care
they know they care just like you you go
to work
you do whatever you around like
watching
kazaats video while doing work
then you go home you get money you know
you get paid
the next year if maybe the the company
don't like you anymore
or you don't you you quit you find you
you know you find uh you go work for
facebook
you open source fanatic
when it comes to money yeah you're gonna
run for it
or maybe you worked on something you you
uh microsoft says oh your product is
fantastic
we pay you 10 million dollars you're
going to sell right away
and forget about your open source
furniture some
open source anyway so vs code
uh so because it's a product of a
cooperation
you're gonna have that problem blowed
everywhere and it's not going to
it can end it can only gets get
worse and worse and worse okay that's a
problem with vs code
not because the technology okay the
technology of vs code
is a magnitude superior than e-max
because e-max is 30 years old of
baggage
you know you look at the source code see
you know
and they are experts of emac these
source code you know they talk about it
crap 30 years of baggage still works
though still works that's the key
like you dropped your sausage on the
ground but you
you are hung you are poor and you don't
have money it's still good
you take it you can still eat it
it's e-max 30 years old the baggage
crap while the vs code is new
you know new is in general when it comes
to technology
new is always almost always better new
languages
if there's a 10 years difference new is
always better
because compute you know because when
technology changes very fast you have
new
assumptions new cpu new architecture new
hardware
so vs code the the magnitude better
than e-max however
vs code is a corporate thing so you're
gonna have bloat and it's gonna get
worse and worse
well emacs will not you know emacs has
its own problems you know the gnu people
that you know they have like
corporate they they have you know their
community uh they have lots of
organization problems and
problems but um but one thing you it
will it
is not going to have is bloat like the
corporate software because
blood happens in corporation software
because
the programmers come and go you know
nobody really cares
you know well emacs
typically you have one or a few who are
you know who are very concerned about it
yeah oversee the whole thing
okay that's uh i don't know i'm rambling
all over it so
okay let me remember another thing okay
you know if you ask
emacs user so so there so i give you my
opinion about
emacs versus vs code let me repeat again
vs code
technology the technology of escort you
know
chrome browser in javascript is a
magnitude superior than emacs because
emacs is very old lots of baggage and
also javascript you
for each emacs users or emac these
coders there are 10 000 javascript
experts
okay all over the world so and they are
you know and emacs who what's the
financial support for emacs
you know maybe a few thousand dollars a
month or something
donation but what about the financial
where does the financial support for
javascript
in chrome 100 billion dollars every
month
something like that okay you get idea
you get the idea because that's a
you know that's that's that's that's
that's uh
you know google is the the biggest
uh organization the in entire human
history you know they send you know they
they have people on
in space they control everything and
they
what what is the technology google rely
on
google chrome and javascript there's
money talking
so so if you want to compare you know i
know a lot of
nerds you know you want to compare emac
this emac this is quest you know
there's not no no comparison to talk
about javascript
and chrome technologies a few magnitude
beyond emacs can ever will be
uh so technology wise vs code is much
better i
you know um but uh
and and uh however it's it's got a
problem
because it's uh from a corporation
now the one more thing i want to mention
we
when a lot of emacs other emacs nerds
you know
i'm one there are a lot of others right
you see their blogs they you see their
youtube
they are much more popular than me you
know you see them so
they will say you know they will also
have opinions about yes code and
versus emacs and typically they'll say
now vs code is crap
for multiple reasons first you know
first first of all they don't like
microsoft so whatever mic
is oh it's from microsoft they don't
like it they're gonna bad mouth about it
that's that's it that's
it it's for microsoft they don't like it
doesn't matter even
even though it's 100 open source they
still gonna
bad mouth it to death but it is because
these nerds
the open source they are dying and
microsoft and google they are become
more and more and more powerful because
these open source
because they don't know what they're
talking about they just think you know
they just think if they say this they
keep saying it
it'll become better emacs will become
more popular or something no
on the contrary because when you say
something
you don't know what you're talking about
bad things will happen
like the like javascript and php
language
you know the hackers despise javascript
and php
and javascript and php became the most
uh used language on earth javascript and
php
and these two languages are exactly the
hacker
types hate the you know eunuch's
philosophy you know
they hate because they talk they don't
know what they're talking about they
they think as long as they just chant
open source
you know ideology chant oh great emacs
is the greatest editor
how look how you know you can do so
everything in max
you keep saying that and when it's not
true it doesn't fit reality
you're gonna get worse and e-max is
happening
you know that's my opinion so
so taken so but anyway when you when you
ask you know when you look at the other
this is what i'm interested you know
other emacs notes
many of them i respect i i'd very much
respect their
uh you know their know how of how you
know emac this
you know they are a lot emac these
coders who knows emac is better than me
and also a lot
people emacs hackers they know the emacs
c code you know they called c i don't
call c so
i respect their opinion but so i want to
know
what do other emacs nerds uh think
about about emacs versus vs code you
know
so i've looked but you know the problem
is you know first of all
because vs code is for microsoft and
just because that
usually they are just start to bad mouth
vs code
so that's not the information i want i
want the
real you know the good information you
know that info
you know that that kind of attitude is
wrong it's bad
i want solid comparison of technology
let's forget about politics okay
i want solid comparison of someone for
example someone
who started emacs for 10 years ela
images
and who also contributed
for 10 years for example on vs code
javascript or atom you know atom editor
if there exists such a person i want to
know their opinion very much
and i will i will pay attention to what
they say
but however the sad thing is you know
when i look at the other emacs nodes
uh their opinion about vs code and if
you look there at
you know or ask them have you ever coded
javascript or
or have you looked into vs code you know
the
architecture and so on typically no
this this e-max the ux phonetics
no they they don't know nothing
so that's uh so if you know if you
actually know
someone i have a friend david capello
okay
he's a c he's a c he loves c
programming a c plus c and c plus first
you know he worked with
uh me on ergo emacs david cavello
um
uh you know he he he's the uh
creator of the ask a sprite you know
he's the
author of spike so i know him for by now
12 13 years he you know we worked on
urban emacs before
so he's a big c and c plus plus fan he's
a sea prosperous
fan and he knows windows programming
very well you know the
sprite is entirely written by him okay
so
and so what was i going to say so he
he has used vs code somewhat okay he's
not a open source phonetic he's more
like practical um and
and uh uh what
was i going to say so but
uh anyway i i
yeah so i i wanted to know if someone
who have contributed
you know in both emac lists then and
also vs code
then if you know that guy tell me okay i
want to know his opinion
i would pay attention to it to him
but i haven't you know i don't know any
such person except
david capello told me a little bit about
he tried ebs code he told me a little
bit
but not much about vs code
so i'm very much looking for someone who
really
you know have looked into also uh both
emacs and vs code
i would pay attention i would you know
respect their opinion but
unfortunately like all my life
my argue my argument with the tech
geekers
when you actually ask them you know
sometimes it happens
ask them did you actually do do that x
or y you hate their answer is no what
the
you know very frustrating um
okay i think i'm like i don't i'm
rambling over
and i maybe i should shut down so what
what are you guys saying
uh like table you should use uh
beatrix says you should try to change to
uh vs code exclusively for a week
and no and not if you uh notice any laws
in your yeah
i mean that of course that's the thing
if i try to use vs code
exclusively not not not even exclusively
if i just try to use it on our day
that's one day good
you know it like i said i don't have
much time
you know i rather spend the time on math
or mathematica or
language i you know i don't i don't know
when
when i'm going to get on vs code
uh dion says if you like emacs you get
you
eat 30 years of old sausage
i used to work as a solo dev it's
amazing how much bloat just one extra
developer
injects into a project that's that's
true
the only way to avoid it is to spend
more time debating the design of your
software than you don't call it
okay uh what are we talking about
god i think like
this is a bad video i kind of lost
some sense of what the things i want to
say about
whatever different different things
oh so i like to you know
uh kapustin says
alexander says i would like to try some
interesting programming language do you
think common lisp
is a good choice no
i talked about that many many times in
my youtube video
you know many many times about which
programming language to learn
so if you have not watched it you
probably should because
too many of my videos the whole hour
is about which language to choose
and i can show you a few
uh and you know i by now i have few
hundred videos
uh it's even confusing so you might want
to watch this one okay
this is about characteristics of haskell
okay the characteristics of haskar
python this mathematica and
stephenwolfen
okay and there's another one about which
language to
choose
okay so the best thing is actually just
go to xa
talk show because
on my website star talk show videos of
star talk show casa tv there it is casa
tv so here is a list of
all my talk shows with their date so
let's search for programming
basics okay 2021 april 1st
basics of wolfram language richard
stowman functional programming java
pearl
python okay so that one is also good
2020 september 10th programming
philosophy of too many libraries
algorithmic
mathematical art okay this one is also
pretty good
especially the algorithmic algorithmic
mathematical art
part
okay this one 2020
may 23rd which programming language is
worth learning
and the the future of lisp okay let's
see what this one is about
okay yeah i think this one you might
watch this one let's
let's go to youtube let's see how many
people
uh watched it
okay stop look at that on the left
on the upper left corner did you see
that
the google propaganda
okay so let's see saw tv
okay which programming language is worth
learning now how many
how many views
stop what's going on
okay 2000 no no no this is one of my
popular video 2200 views so watch this
one yeah
which programming language is worth
learning i remember i i kind of
put this one on my
on my home page something like that so
common lisp no comment is the last
language you want to try
but you are asking for commonly is
probably
you know you like companies you probably
want you know
i'd rather okay if you want to go with
lisp i'd rather
recommend racket okay learn learn some
skim this
racket or skim this not commonly
commonly is has new no future
absolutely zero future it's it's
you know and the fact you're asking
about it you know not many people know
about communist even like nobody knows
and the only people who know commonly
is a very very very niche emacs among
emacs
and among these you know programmers
you know and to them they still think oh
maybe commonly specific
nobody is already it's dead for it's
already dead
yeah there are still applications
running communists but it's
dead and it's not there's no possible
reason for it to
like revive okay so if you want to use
if if you want to learn this
get on with closure okay
uh okay why closure is dance is one of
my
essay about hacking okay okay you go to
this page
complain perving i recommend all these
videos
there it is you know this is a video i
mentioned uh these two i mentioned
before these are
uh better ones among my talk show videos
okay
so you go to uh so you want to watch
this
uh two okay four languages especially
this one okay
companies with uh is no no future and
dead and also it's a crap it's garbage
purely from even just technical
considerations commonly
the worst crap possible the worst crap
possible you know again
the topic on the topic of lisp
programming language
i've done like 10 over 10 videos about
it each one is one hour about
some aspect of the technical detail of
this language
because that's a you know that's the
least language is one of my thing
you know that's my the half you know in
the past 20 years
i was i i dig into this language
all sort of details and i have tons of
articles about it
so anyways yeah if you want to learn you
know watch my videos okay
i you know like instead of me you know
i'm just going to tell you comment
comments
instead what's use of that you know
but you watch my video instead you know
because i talked about that for one hour
why and the reasons and so on so anyway
if you want to learn this closure okay
you might get a job with that
and it's okay it's it's pretty good
except it runs on java jvm java java
java crap closure and racket okay i
don't have a
tutorial for racket but closure and
racket okay now if you want to learn
about
some language design issues watch you
know these
comp lamp perming okay lots of you know
i have a few hundred articles on
and on this now again you know like i
said i have hunt
i've done tens of videos on this
language so
watch this too for example
you know the the the the better videos i
put on my website
but you know it's it's hard to maintain
because i i kind of stopped doing that
uh because i do too many videos anyway
so you so on this section sound this
you'll find a bunch of
articles written in the past 20 years on
this
and two videos i talk about that so
then then you have syntax soup issues
and you know this section collection of
articles
which focus on the syntax syntactical
aspect of programming languages
and there are two videos on that uh then
the scene semantic noodle again another
article on programming languages and
their
culture pearl python ruby
okay these are language programming
language
issues related to semantics okay uh
then you have a a section dedicated to
the jargons of software industry
orb jargons list comprehension lambda
ripple closure querying tail recursion
asynchronous asynchronous javascript
instance instance instance of object
instance my ass
these programmers they have no idea what
they're talking about
including including the list coders the
lisp coders jargon
what are they uh
[Music]
current tell recursion
recursively uh you know and
you know anyway
uh okay i'm rambling over so is it good
is it bad i think i feel like this video
is uh no good
so there's uh then documentation okay
documentation is my obsession
in my life because i i'm obsessed
reading documentations i read
too many okay and i collect
documentations i read word for what so
these
all all articles uh
kind of i put i collected together on
documentation 20 articles also
over the past 20 years documentations
and and in this you can see
you know i can talk about this for a few
hours just documentation issues
let me maybe i start to talk about this
a little bit okay so you
so what do you get from this kind of
what so what kind of thing do you talk
about documentation why are you
i mean how what kind of things are there
to talk about
doc is just the documentation i mean
what do you
okay i well i can explain you know that
and then i
you know i can talk about this for 10
hours documentation first of all you
know there's a
this writing skill technical writing so
that by itself
is a 10 hours topic technical writing
you know writing is a 10 hours what
writing is a lifelong topic you know you
go to university
there's a literature major in literature
then
almost students you have to take writing
one-on-one
then it involves literature then there's
poetry there's different type of writing
there's constrained writing
then there's there's languages which are
writing systems this takes
takes a few lifetimes of study and you
can see
unless you are an empire you live for a
thousand years then you can master
something about writing systems and
writing and unicode
anyway so technical writing is you know
one kind of study then there's
organization
and there's also computer documentation
the format
you know for example function okay
function when you write a function when
you try to document
document a function you know you've seen
you probably
seen in php documentation in python
documentation
in in lisp documentation for example a
function usually you have several
parameters some are optional some has
default values
some are positional arguments some are
you know keyword arguments you know so
there's a question
how do you you know how do you um
let me show you examples okay here okay
so here is the example from python
documentation so you can see
you know they use those brackets as you
know kind of to indicate optional
arguments
so that's one way but if you look around
you know
like consider this is a task look around
how
you know first of all think about how
functions what are possible function you
know how data
okay this is a this so this is about
kind of a syntax and formatting issue
uh how do you document functions
when a function have you know so python
is one way and this way is very typical
so
then you have example from php they also
use these
square brackets to indicate optional
arguments
then you have a example from javascript
what is this yeah javascript mozilla
then you have example from the wufang
language
stefan wufam the certified genius
so you can see there are issues about
documentation about
the formatting of documentation
functions formatting so that's one issue
formatting itself is another
entire issue because over the past 10 20
years
you know each programming language they
they pick a specific
technology to write their documentation
some of them pick
tech la tech in the beginning but that
kind of died out
nobody nobody is using tech or la tech
to document
a programming language now then python
switch to
you know whatever you know i have
articles about that but i remember i
don't remember now
python used uh what what is the
documentation system used by python
you know then ruby has one ruby user
what what is the codes uh some i don't
remember i have to look up
so ruby is a technology for
documentation emacs
of of course use the granddaddy the tech
info tech info system uh
you know so the the so why why
why are they why are there so many
software to
for documentation to to write
documentation that's a
because it's a very complex issue it
involves organization it
mostly involves formatting the output
format
the you know the input format formatting
so what what so why are there so many
different formatting
you know what's good and bad why that's
another question you know you can spend
a year just to study the formatting of
text
you know text or that gets us into
html versus xml versus html5 versus
html where are they you know what
what why what's the difference
why do you need all that you know who
invented them and so on
so formatting that's another issue the
documentation okay anyway
so the but there's a lot a huge amount
of issue the style okay
so we talked about technical writing
then there is
also the writing style now in in
in terms of content okay we talked about
formatting
of a function so that's part of
we also talked about formatting of the
entire documentation and formatting
systems and software
so that's another entire different issue
now
about the content those are kind of
formatting now the about the content is
the technical writing right
so what what constitute good technical
writing okay
there there's a little bit debate
sometimes okay
so technical writing and how to be good
at technical writing that's another
chapter okay how
how to do how to be a good technical
writer
okay that's another thing okay
by the way many of these these issues
there's no
like one answer depending on like just
like writing depending on who do you ask
some expert writers they have their
opinion you know they think this way is
the best writing some
some have a different opinion but in
general they
you know they they might converge a bit
okay
but on some details they may disagree
but anyway so formatting then the
content so technical writing how to
write a good one besides that there's
also a matter of style
because two different authors they can
write a
very different entirely different
writing style you can feel it when you
read it
but both of them are good okay then it
also depends on what kind of person you
are what
kind of approach you you like you prefer
you know
especially on programming languages
because they are very diverse so
so maybe for certain language uh certain
style is preferred anyway so this also
relates to the organization
for example in php it's kind of
organized on function
it's just like you you can find the
function you want
organization organize around function
essentially
and javascript is organized i mean java
java the language is organized you know
i can show you i can show you the java
java documentation but if i do
then you'll take more time to
search for it you know java
documentation
now that they have a did they have a new
face wait
uh technical documentation what the
java documentation is
have always been very complex
java components i want to get to the api
where is it licensing information
oracle
industries what yeah let's just
search for java api they call it
the sun micro system scum
they started to call their documentation
they call their java as api but java is
not
it's not really api they some micro
system scum abused it
okay here it is here is the conventional
you know the
official java java documentation
they are organized around classes
because java
java is a you know class based language
so you can see
this is how you navigate you know then
you have a class you have you know
parents and
children and you have methods field
field summary
constructor summary the jargons
method summary
method your ass then field detail you
know
remember remember i mentioned uh i
talked about
the uh you know i have a section on
jargons
jargons jargons jargons
of tech info industry you know all
things you want to know about jargons
okay jargons of software industry oop
jargons so you have class
methods objects then you have
then you have let me let me tell you
okay then you have the
the rise of static versus instance
variables
then the rise of constructors and
accessors
them the op
constructors and accessors
then you have access specifiers
okay which is actually just the scoping
complexity
of op unnecessarily so
you have you know private
you have private private class or
whatever java success
access specified private protected
public
there as extreme idiocy the
then you have the rise of inheritance
you know the complexity of oop
then you have the rise of the the rise
of the class hierarchy
complex complexer and complexer
than then the rise and mutation of
interface
yeah abuse of the word interface then
the rise of
abstract class and abstract methods
then the rise of iterators and
enumerators
embraced by python and other op idiots
you have iterators and in enumerators
then
then then later on then then you have
the generators
in java in javascript now you know
iterators
iterators iterators in numerators and
generators
and uh okay i need to get my new glasses
i need to get glasses
then jargon polymorphism you know oop
and java jargons okay
so you can see what okay i'm rambling
non-stop
by now i hope you like it
so do you like it
so okay java okay so uh where are we
where were we
so we were talking about documentation
what i mean what's
so we were talking about what's there to
talk about documentation
and by the way even though you know java
java documentation okay you are looking
at java documentation is one of the best
okay even i despise i despise the java
language
the java documentation is one of the
most
professional well-written documentation
in the entire human animal computing
history
okay java documentation even though i
i don't like the language i disagree
with the many of the language you know
the
i despise the oop and java
but that but we are judging
you know think that you know we are if
we are judging documentation
java documentation you are looking at is
one of the best
in the uh you know in entire
industry you know different very
different style you know
like i can start you know i can talk
non-stop um you know and
then you know but anyway java java
javadoc okay it's one of the best
uh and what are the other best for
example phpdoc
is also one of the best php okay let me
let me tell you
in my 30 in my in my in my by now 30
years of reading documentation
obsessed about reading documentation i
have to read i have to read every detail
of the words you know unique spam page
pearl documentation i have read entirety
of the pearl documentation and more than
one time
word by word and also i've read five
also books
of pearl documentation back in the 1990s
anyway that's digression okay i read too
many
more than all of you have combined i i
would dare to say
more than all of you in my casa discord
the documentation you read
combined altogether is less than all of
you people is less than
the documentation i have read computer
technology documentations including
programming languages
or unix linux mac you know operating
system documentations
okay so let me just tell you now what
are the best documentations
okay i know of i've read wufang language
mathematica okay
let me show you each one okay wufang
language documentation
perfect the impeccable okay
that's one thing uh javascript
documentation i mean java java like i
said java the most
professional doesn't matter you know i'm
not saying
because i study like certain style
therefore
if it's written in this style i like
then it's good
if it's written in another style i don't
like means no good no it's not like that
at
all i'm trying to emphasize this java
documentation although i hate the
language
and mathematica wufang language let me
show you a page okay
let me show you uh let me enter on
javascript
java documentation and the wolfram
language documentation okay
let's let's see language overview let me
show you uh
and the wolfram language documentation
is both
both the best documentation ever in
human animal history documentation of
technical documentation
okay they have entirely very different
entirely different styles okay because
well part
for for one thing java the language is a
oop class-based
object-oriented language while wufang
language is a
symbolic functional programming language
like this it's a
kind of like a family of lisps language
so the two languages are entirely
different
and possibly and partly partly because
that their documentation
style their organization their
organization
and style is very different okay but
okay but but both of them are the best
documentation ever
very different style okay you can you
can try to look at them okay
so these two are good great
documentation
now let's uh php documentation
okay php documentation is also one of
the
best okay i will tell you because i've
read
entirety of it around 2005
you know every word one thousand
yeah you know you know uh how many pages
one thousand pages or something
in fact for for several years i have the
entire
manual mirrored on my website sadly.info
php and also python and also the entire
java documentation
that's the entire java documentation is
500 megabytes
you know it's close to one gigabyte i
think
anyway you you can you can go to
xrd.info
archive you know the the wayback machine
you can
find it you know for a period of time i
have the entire
python php and also java
documentation mirrored on my site
because i link to it because anyway
because i'm writing tutorials
anyway so another great documentation is
php
okay now php writing is pretty lousy
okay
in terms of the technical writing it's
not that
great in terms of organization it's not
that great
okay because well php is kind of a
sloppy
you know it's a very practical language
it has no pretensions to be
you know some computer science like the
python
you know they pretend they are the
computer science or the scheme this
minimal they are the best design you
know
php has nothing like that it's just for
average coders well but
you don't know what you are doing but
you need to create a website
you use php that's why it's extremely
popular practical
so whenever you have a php question you
look at their documentation you search
it the web you'll find it right away and
with tons of examples okay it's let's go
let's show you an example let's say
array okay
can we find uh so the writing
and the org you know so
in terms of writing or organization or
you know technical
perfectionism you know the writing style
is it's not that great but it's the most
practical in the sense that if you are
programming in you know
i don't know um
you know in a language php you can
find what you need you you can find the
answer you need to
know when you code php because there are
documentation okay
and lots of examples now uh let's see
uh control structure okay namespace
class in objects
functions expressions constant variable
okay operators
uh where's data structure i want to go
to the array
uh section i haven't read it for a long
time so i don't
remember generators okay the
uh language reference types expressions
operators control structures
class and object now where's the data
structure though
you know so anyway so let's the easiest
way is just search for php array okay
and also they have a systematic url you
can directly jump to it
i know because i wrote the emacs
function to do that
there it is okay okay we don't want w3
schools the
up you ww face schools uh
there okay php all right you see you
find it right away the first item
okay so here for example so here is a
you know down to a practical example i'm
demonstrating to you right now
we're talking about documentation right
away you find when you want to code php
array oh
uh how does it how does it work you know
you find it right away
and here is an actual example of php
documentation you can
you can read and you can see their
writing style you can look into detail
their writing style and we talked about
how do they
how do they format uh their um
you know the options you know the syntax
how do they
how do they you know for example for
example you can see this one is
this part is white you know how do they
highlight or part of or call the example
things like that okay lots of things to
dig
into you know if you are in you know
if you are you know if this is a subject
you want to get into okay
documentation okay so array so you can
see syntax then note
okay so some sometimes you have notes
then example one
okay there it is okay so i would claim
in my opinion php documentation is one
of the best
from a practicality point of view okay
of course that doesn't mean you know
like i mentioned before mathematica
that doesn't mean mathematica uh doc is
not the practical or java
they are also both very good but
but what i'm saying is that php in
particular
outstanding what stands out for php
documentation
all things considered is that they are
the most practical you know that you you
just find
doesn't matter what you you know what's
your question you'll find the answer
php okay great documentation
so so java
wufam language php these are the
greatest documentation there are more
okay polish powershell okay let me show
you
powershot
powershot is a new thing i started to
read their documentation about
um
powershell where's their documentation
so powershell um
overview or whatever so i need to turn
javascript so let's do
so refresh okay so you are looking at
powershell documentation so here
is um basically the left panel learning
powershell those
are tutorials powershot tutorials is not
so good okay let me also mention in a
documentation
of a programming language often there
are two parts
uh often separate okay one part is the
tutorial
then another part is the documentation
okay now depends on the language
sometimes they
you know some language only have the
official documentation for example java
okay java for example we showed
javas so you are looking at the official
documentation
there is also a tutorial of java
official tutorial but however the
official
tutorial is separate it's entirely
separate
has nothing to do with the documentation
so
that's what i'm saying typically a
programming language they have a
tutorial part and uh the documentation
part
or reference they are usually separate
but depending on the language sometimes
they are like
in one place sometimes they are not okay
so
in in the case of java the java tutorial
is
entirely separate from the java language
you know the api documentation
and also the java documentation is
superb okay
but the java tutorial for micro
symmetrical system it's the worst
possible the java java tutorial
okay
the job the official java tutorial by
systems beginning around 1997
because i read it okay in fact i have uh
in fact i have articles about it it's
somewhere here okay i have quite a you
know java's
java interface in energy you see i'm
citing some of the
um some of the here you are looking at
the java
wait uh no not here okay so
here you are looking at the java
official java tutorial what is the
interface
this is funny okay let me read it okay
so this is a java official
java tutorial from some micro systems
and this one is
a screenshot from 2005. okay let me read
it's trying to explain what's the
interface okay in
english an interface is a device or a
system
that unrelated entities used to
interact in english okay
not in germany not in chinese but in
english
an interface is a device it's a device
or a system okay a interface is a device
or a system
that unrelated entities
unrelated entities use to interact
so there are certain unrelated there
you know in the universe they are
entities and they are unrelated entities
and these entities they they want to
interact
and so they use a thing called interface
that is a device or a system
this is the you know this is this is the
this is the technical writing at its
worst the
i don't know whoever wrote this
what is the interface
incomprehensible it it not not just
incomprehensible it's also
incompletely wrong the interface
is a device or a system
it's a device or system what system
operating system
or car engine system what device do you
mean you mean a pen
you mean like a pen or a hammer what the
is this idiot
yeah but it's a official from some
microsystems
official tutorial of the java tutorial
trademark you see that tm trademarked
of course by now they don't have that
passing i don't think they have that
passage anymore
yeah but back then this is all popular
you know all the notes the heads
the unix philosophy the c
coder i disagree with you know they are
saying oh java yeah
you know look at the java you know go
read java tutorial
idiots
so anyway so that's so so back to
previous topics so i was saying
typically uh programming language
documentation
they have the tutorial section they have
the language reference or
or you know the documentation for the
language section they are
typically separate in a java case they
are entirely separate
and the java documentation is superb
while the java tutorial is the worst
possible
in the python for you know in the
wolfram language case
the tutorial and you know of course they
also have the tutorial in the reference
section separate so
so you can see let me show you okay so
for example language overview
then you let's see you click on table
which is a
function okay then you go down you can
see
related uh guides so you have you know
so
there you see the tutorials so
again you know like i said it's a
separate so
so here's a tutorial on how do you do
repetitive
operations so they they not talk about
table they also talk
talk about do or um other constructs
and you know they have several tutorials
so this is their style they
kind of separate into several things so
they have a tutorial for
whenever you need to do vectors and
matrices
and whenever you need to making tables
of values
or evaluation in iterative functions you
know
or tensors tensors is basically nested
uh matrices
linear algebra so so all why are they
here i mean where are they in this
tutorial section
of the table of function reference well
because table is actually generating
vectors or matrices or tensors depending
on trees depending
your point of view depending on what you
use it for so
so anyway so i'm showing demonstrating
one of the
approach the the you know wufang
language
you know and you know you can see
tutorials here then
then they have guides you know woofam
language is
huge so
php now now the tutorial section of the
php
language is part of the part of the
part of the visual documentation i
believe i'm pretty sure
yeah there you see getting started an
introduction
and simple tutorial i remember i read
this back in 2005 okay
you know a simple tutorial to get you
started
now of course it's been 10 years there's
change there are changes of php you know
documentation they all improve for
example the wolfram language
documentation i read mostly in 1990s
three times 1000 pages
i talked about printed books okay so let
me
okay i kind of rambled rambo in this
talk show and
this is like almost like non-stop let me
show you the
mathematica book okay
so this is the book you know i read you
know back in mostly 1990s i read it
three times in different years cover to
cover every word
every word of it and and now today
i'm making you know 2031 june 14th
i'm making a collection because it's no
longer printed
since 2004 so i i you know i'm
obsessive you know i read documentation
so i make i made a collection of the
online
of the chapters online there's no
coherent index anymore
you know because the evolution of
wolfram language
but for at least nostalgia i still make
a
you know i i try to make a collection of
the indexes
that corresponds to the book i read uh
you know almost 20 years ago so anyway
so we'll find language so that that's
the best documentation okay so
let's so let's go back to uh
to i so another so java wufam language
mathematica and php these are the
greatest documentations on earth
and powershell today there's more okay
because
now there's more you know technology
uh progresses you know now i'm doing
videos you know let's
take progress and phones you know we owe
her phones so also the documentation
people have been programmers have been
getting better at documentation so today
there's more and more
uh good documentation as opposed to
in the 1990s or early 2000s the unix
the unix man page but it's not
they had no idea what they're talking
about
they just grab grip and you know
the unix no idea but
they don't know what is technical
writing they they dribble about it but
they have no idea
okay so powershell is another great
documentation
so so first of all you have the you know
powershell you know
you have a tutorial section part of
their official documentation
but those are not good okay they are
written by different people
i know because i looked in the past one
two months i've been
reading a lot of powershell uh
documentation so
so you have you know installed then you
have uh learning powershell so this is a
tutorial kind of a mess
okay and i don't like the writing you
know i don't think it's good
the powershell tutorial i by the way i
have my own
so if you want to learn powershell you
might try to
uh give my tutorial a you know a try
you know basics you know introduction to
powershell
then you can you know start to use the
powershell reference okay
so i've been writing my powershell
tutorial the best part is the
common examples so if you came from unix
bash you know
you know you feel like how do you do
things on windows but you don't want to
install bash which is a good idea
you do you know on windows just use
powershell okay
so let me show you the common example so
so you came from
unix you know you know bash grip find
you know
those kind of crap cat
uh ls you know then then you can jump to
this page and to start to
you know how to uh create a new file you
know touch
uh you know open file by uh default app
new directory you know uh make the
you know and so on copy and copy and so
on so you might
uh check out this my tutorial okay
now back to powershell okay i'm talking
i was talking about documentation okay
so back to powershot documentation so
you have a tutorial section
not so good but but then the
window the the but then the
the the real reference part okay
installing powershell no
no where is it what's new powershell
gallery reference okay reference
you know powershell is essentially a
bunch of commands collection of commands
okay so powershell core
for example let me show you uh duh your
or
unix ios let me show you one example
okay uh
let's get children so typically you
don't use this you just search the web
you just type powershell powershell
get child item you'll find it okay so
you but anyway
i have you know looked through these so
i know their structure now
powershell call it's divided into
several um
what they call uh modules or package
so you have pajarco and the get children
is the powershell management okay
so get child item there it is
so here is a powershell documentation
which is at
an analogous analogous to the unix man
page
okay so what is get children get
children is basically ls
okay or in the dos the dir okay
so so you have you know like the unix
tradition you have the
synapses the unix idiots they call it
synapses like what the
in powershell you just you just start
with you know they don't even say
what you know they don't even say it's a
synopsis or what
so let me let me show okay so so we you
are looking at powershell
uh and and uh and let me magnify the
font okay
and let's see the okay so so let's
cd okay cd to the
sub directory okay cd to web
okay cd to ergo emacs for example
cd to emax so you type the
let's magnify okay you type the
that's a list of directory just just
like unix ls okay you can also type
ls you see that's a edius
uh by building alias by default so you
get
so you can type help da okay that will
get you the full name help child item
okay that's the full name
so oh so you begin okay it also says
synapses okay
then you have the syntax okay then you
have description
and you have parameters in so it's
superb
guys okay let me tell you it's superb
okay let's shrink let's get get out um
okay so powershell documentation is
superb they have
they have an online version as well
sub-hub because
anyway i'm not gonna get into detail i
think i ramble too long so
am i actually still alive
let's see how many people are watching
night people
so um
so i'm still streaming okay so i've been
talking for
90 minutes already
oh we have 14 people now i'm talking for
19 minutes any comments questions okay
so
i think that's it so java
uh language php powershell these are the
best documentations there's one more let
me tell you one more
go land okay
go land documentation it's one of the
superb one of the best documentation
okay let me show you uh you go to
document documents then you go to this
you know you you basically you want to
go to the um
the reference section okay
installing go now we don't care about
that documents okay
packages okay yeah here they you know
again we yes we are begin we are seeing
certain
uh different little cultural or style
you know you know in gold land they
don't call you know they are
basically you are looking at their
official documentation or the reference
section okay
the reference the manual for the go
language
but they don't call it you know they
don't call it
they don't call it documentation but you
know in a gold line case they call it
um packages okay but this is actually
their
official reference for their
documentation okay
um
because this is this is the part you
actually use
if you code golan every day okay anyway
anyway the the structure of gold line
okay go line first of all go line also
have a tutorial section okay
not here you have for example you go
back here computer you're getting
started
this is a crap okay the goal line
tutorial is not so good
okay it's it's against it's all
also you know they have this this is
their official golan
official golan tutorial but
i of course i read it it's not so good
but however their documentation the real
documentation
which is the which they call packages
okay you click on that
this is superb this is your your uh
bread and butter which
if you go cold go line every day that's
what you need to read about
and so they have a tutorial they have a
official you know
the reference section the kind of the
manual of the language
they also have a another one the
language specification okay
um now is it somewhere here
now i don't remember whether it's linked
here i mean uh
of course it it is link here somewhere
the reference
the the language specification now this
part i haven't mentioned before
so for for example for
for for uh for java for example for java
you also have a language spec again this
happens to be entirely different thing
wufang language you don't have a spec
because it's not open source
you well you you kind of expect anyway
um
you you kind of have a spec but not much
because
it's because it's not a open source uh
programming language
so you don't have the full spec for you
to implement it
but java java does okay java has a
language
spec and also has a virtual machine spec
then php doesn't have a spec because
who needs a spec you just you know it's
a practical
kind of language you don't you don't
you know there's no i don't believe
uh i don't think i'm wrong but i don't i
don't so as far as i know there's no
spec for php language
uh uh maybe hack landers hackling is a
facebook's version of a
typed php language he made it about 10
years ago
anyway php then then then you have
uh powershell powershell i don't think
you have a spec
but it's it's very well anyway anyway
that's a another side point i'm trying
to mention gold line has a spec
okay also it's superb so golan
the reference the documentation and the
gold lands
language specification is superb
however there their golan tutorial the
official one is not so good
okay so go land okay
too many okay i can go on for another
three hours at least about documentation
and
or giving you a different example of
different language for example python
okay this this one is
a lot of people probably want to hear my
opinion
pythons pythons okay let me okay let me
finish let me talk about python stock
and that's
that's it for today
and by the way
you know if you want so i also have a um
tutorial on golan of course so you
should
try try my tutorial okay uh this is
fairly you know this is beyond a simple
intro okay because i
i love golan uh i think it's fantastic
uh i highly recommend it much better
than comedies
okay sturdy golem it has a future
not just that it has it's a simple
language
it's super fast much faster than
communist
it's very simple you can master the
whole thing in one week
master the entire goal and go
language in one week if you really try
on the other hand
commonly maybe maybe three years full
time three years
i doubt even if you can master it and
it's not you know it's not a
goal line okay forget about communist
uh you can master simple fast and it's
in
industry one of the most popular
language okay
used in by industries heavy industries
not not oh some joe like saudis writing
or emac this package
for you to play with not like that this
is million billion dollars industry
billion dollars applications use like
you know you write some go
you know nuclear facility or whatever
usually not that you know that like you
know
whatever google whatever google does
okay go land okay
billions dollar industry like javascript
so you learn gold land you also find a
job if you need it
you know you can you can learn it for
hobby or whatever um
go land okay go live so the language is
fantastic
the the the manual the reference is
superb
you know to the point precise no
babbling
no no no random uh
propaganda or open source propaganda
okay go live so yeah so i also have a
tutorial i wrote you know you might try
so i'm gonna shut down okay i'm gonna
talk about python i'm gonna shut down
uh blm
banner okay go land yeah they yeah
nothing much you can do these days
because um let me go to python okay let
me show you the python where i'm going
to talk about the python idiocy
the extreme idiocy but the python
both the language and documentation but
the python people don't know they they
you know usc i'm sure or some of you are
python phonetics
you don't know what you're talking about
so
go land do they have like um
yeah you know where is the way is the uh
yeah actually i don't want to go over
there because then google is gonna ban
me
google is gonna censor my youtube okay
let's forget about that
i i i didn't see the i missed it
okay python doc python doc is the worst
in more in in every way in every aspect
of the documentation i i i talked about
today
the organization the writing style the
content quality
the precision you know accuracy and
precision of what you
your documentation the organization you
know and the function format
we i talked about every aspect python
documentation is the worst
possible and also examples
no examples python you know they are
they are the
computer science are us we don't we
don't
you know we don't write examples the
python
and the guido idiots the guido vons or
some idiots
they think he he you know in his mind he
created the
the best language for people to learn
programming
it's the extreme opposite so python doc
okay so there you go
there you go the familiar python
documentation
so so you have these um you know you
have
these headers you know this one tutorial
okay
start here okay like i mentioned you
know languages they have a section on
tutorial
the python tutorial is not so good okay
the python taki is one of the worst okay
but anyway the tutorial is not so good
it's okay
but it's not so good then the library
reference you know
first of all the organization let me
talk about
why the python documentation sucks sucks
donkey
ass sucks to the extreme okay first
first of all
what you see is about organization
organization of the documentation so
okay
what's new okay that's what's new okay
tutorial okay
then library reference oh okay keep this
under your pillow you see
now they they add a little you know like
uh this is
how do you classify this this epigraph
you know kind of like a nerds thing you
know it's so it
here this part shows their culture
they're telling you they are the
pythoners they are pythonic
so you know instead of just saying
library reference they have to say
keep this under your pedo go
yourself
then you have language reference you
know describe syntax and language
elements okay
okay so so let's so so i can tell you
what so let me tell you what they are so
the
library reference is kind of like you
know analogous to the gold lines
you know packages this is the bread and
butter
this this is the part you have to go to
the most when you actually code in this
language
so in the same way python you know
they call it library reference okay
similar to golan's you know package
you know packages okay
so okay so that's what that is okay then
you have a language reference so so this
part
is uh like i talked about before this is
the language specification
kind of okay basically it's kind of a
formal approach to the python language
syntax
okay so if you are going to implement
implement python language this is this
part is the most helpful to you
but however if you are a python
programmer for example you forgot what's
the syntax for
python in python lambda or for loop
that's also the part you go
equal to so they serve kind of it's kind
of fussy you know this
is part of the reason why the python
language really sucks so many in so many
ways
on one hand if you are really trying to
implement python
you know you want a very specific
technical detailed specification
this this python language reference will
not do
okay on the other hand if you are just
if you are a python coder
you are not trying to implement python
but you just want to
you forgot what's the syntax for lambda
you also go here
so it's very pretty bad because you go
through then
then the then there's the
idiotic writing you know they don't know
what they
talking about this then there's
also pretension
the python which is came from
inherited from kaido guido guido von
rosa
you know tends to they they they want to
pretend
something bigger than they are like they
like python coders i like to call them
they are
they are the computer science are us you
know they like
they think themselves like that so they
have pretension you know they try to
jargon a choke up their you know use use
fancy jargons that doesn't make sense
you know the standard type hierarchy
hierarchy your ass
you know they don't know what they're
talking about you try as a sp
especially this page data model okay
they don't know what they're talking
about
dribbles yeah and
okay okay so back here so reference okay
so you have section on reference library
reference okay
then you have a section on language
reference now let me
make extra comments okay interesting you
see
on library reference they added this you
know
a little jolly epitaph you know keep
this under your pillow
but then you also have a subtitle for
the language reference section which
says
describe syntax and language elements
so these two you know the subtitle
for these two sections uh in sharp
contrast
so one is kind of like a joke you know
kind of like a joke you know that kind
of
like you know what's a proper term to
describe this
uh i i
i don't know i i have to think but
anyways you know it's unnecessary you
know you just
add on a graph
on the other hand here the subtitle for
this section is actually very
very functional they you know they they
want to make sure you understand okay
this section is actually for
describes the syntax and language
element well that the other section is
keep this under your pillow
i don't like it okay the idiots
uh anyway so then then there's python
how to
uh god in-depth document on
documentation on a specific topic then
very confusing okay let me tell you
python documentation then
installing python modules then
distributing python modules what the
publishing modules for installer
installation by others
then extending and embedding tutorials
for c
and c plus so this is a lot
huge amount of inconsistency okay
extending and
embedding and python c api okay
reference for c
plus plus program okay let me comment
okay so before
i may i commented about the style
of the subtitle in relation to their
section
you know so here it's kind of a joke
keep this under your pedo
and here is very functional describe
syntax and language elements
a lot inconsistency going on here okay
so
here you see here is a tutorial for
c and c plus plus programmers what
what uh what the are you talking
about
so you are telling me you have a section
for c and c
plus programmers you mean if i want to
learn c
i go to your page right because it's a
tutorial for
c and c plus first programmers right if
i'm a c
and c plus programmers you know i write
compilers in some company
and then you have a section reference
for c and c
first plus programmers so you mean i
need to go to your
python documentation this section to
to to to have a reference about c
no of course not what they mean is that
what they mean is that
so this section extending and embedding
is about you know extending and
embedding python
but the main audience will be c
and c plus plus programmers right
because
basically they imply that to extend
python or embed python
you need to write in c and c plus first
so that's what and and also you know
and also they are trying also to say by
implication
and also they try to and by explicit
mention this is a tutorial
so this part this part is kind of like a
tutorial for
for for those who want to in extend
and embed python also they
imply you have to know the c c plus
first language
so they you know they don't know what
they are writing they don't know what
they are thinking they
they pack these tribals together into
together in one place that's what they
are doing you know
this this is how we dive into technical
details
of of technical writing you know right
now i'm taking apart the large
logic the logical analysis what that
what
what do they mean what they mean very
confusing okay
you might think okay oh but you read it
you understand it
not really okay i can go on talk another
hour about that
why why is that so anyway so then
then here then you have a reference for
c plus plus programmers you see
now you compare these two subtitles so
one is a tutorial for c
plus plus programmers the other one is a
reference for c
plus plus programmers so you might think
okay there are two these two sections
are two different
aspects of the
of the second kind of thing one is more
tutorial like one it's more reference
like but not actually
not not so because these two are
actually different topics
one is pad this one is pythons and
c api
which is a little bit dif you know
similar to extending and embedding
python but it's actually different topic
so i'm telling so that this
this is my dissection dissecting
the python idiocy of the python
documentation
and look and look here is the propaganda
you know the the
kind of the propaganda comes in faq okay
faq is a frequently asked questions okay
great
you know usually people have a lot of
questions and here's a collection of the
common questions
and answers of course by you know by by
writing by english itself
frequently asked me ask questions faq
implies
answers okay no idiot don't know that
okay so but they have to say these
python idiots
they have to add with an answers
as as if you don't know and as if you
know they try to
tell they try to say look we are
documentation is so great
we have faq not just that but with
answers
they have to say that the idiocy of the
python documentation
okay that's it for today thank you guys
um
a uh okay i don't know nothing about
orbit you know a bit is from this very
interesting guy
uh uh you know uh the the mode bug
you know a bit
uh it's beyond me actually so i i tried
to spend
some time to underst i tried you know
only actually 10 minutes it's something
beyond me i have to
you know because i have so many things i
need to study first but this seems to be
like you know new tech
based on the blockchain or something
related you know i so i do want to know
this technology but first of all i need
to
really understand blockchain well you
know blockchain the concept i know you
know i i
i did uh you know study it so i know the
blockchain but i i need to go get
uh deeper you know i need to actually
code blockchain so to
then to understand bitcoin and so and so
on
so i don't know uh i find i think it's
interesting but i don't know nothing
about it
uh one of the interesting things the guy
you know who created
you know the guy who created this
thing
you so biased thoughts about python why
am i of course i am i can see you know i
i i uh
admit and accept i'm biased towards
python but however if you ask me
where am i biased python you know i
don't at least
i wouldn't think so i think i might my
opinion by
on python is actually fair
so that's that's why everyone is biased
but you
you you know so so there are two aspects
of being biased
one is that you fully are aware you are
intentional
you know you know you kind of you know
you know there's something to you don't
like and you know the reason you don't
like it not because
all things considered it's really bad or
something it's only because it doesn't
fit your style
okay so you know that so that in that
sense you are biased but you know it
but to me my opinion about python is
that
i don't think i'm biased you know i
don't think you know it's
what i'm trying to say is that i don't
think you know i'm not saying something
you know for example when i talk about
documentation
you know even java you know i i talk
about
java the language i despise some of the
language i
hate the java virtual machine but their
documentation i would say it's one of
the best
so in that sense you know this so on the
other hand i love
mathematica so it's also got great
documentation so is there something i
truly love
whose documentation is bad some language
or something um
anyway i can't think of now but anyway
so
so what i'm trying to say is that
to me i don't think my opinion about
python the language or the documentation
is biased you know and you know
like if you ask me i can't i cannot tell
you where
i think i was biased i think my opinion
is pretty fair
because you know i don't like you know
okay so i like functional programming
okay python for a fact is not you know
it's
because guido van rossum he doesn't like
functional programming
okay so i can accept
for example java okay java is op java is
not functional
but but okay java is you know so java
is a very well designed and not
it's op okay so but i don't attack java
because
it's not functional okay but meanwhile
python you know python they they are not
functional but they pretend they are
that's the thing
you know you can see in their
documentation you know they pretend
anyway i don't like python okay
blockchain uh yeah i don't have any
article on blockchain i don't know much
about it so that's that's it for today
thank you that's a
co it's a two hours oh today's a long
one two hours
this is the longest one i have i think
okay thank you guys for watching that's
it for today bye
if you like my stuff put money in my
pocket okay
donate in my you know go to my website
check out my tutorials comment on my
youtube you know comment and
and you know spread it post to other
people to
to other you know to your blog or
whatever
and check out my tutorials that's it for
today
thank you guys bye
so two hours yeah i'm gonna get the i'm
gonna
i'm gonna get i have still some coffee
i'm gonna get the drink so i'm shutting
down in one minute
then i have to gather all the links
all the link we talked about today and
put them together in my
you know in my talk show page
what the is this clive matrix you
know
java is java is also very huge
complicated language
so basically you want to go to java land
okay
so then then you get into the familiar
things like booleans
uh you know bullying by class character
class
okay so i need to collect all these
links and put into my excel talk show