hello welcome to another episode ofar
talk show today we are going to code
wolam
language geometry mathematics and uh and
wolam language coding okay and I'm also
going to talk something about keyboards
and JavaScript in the first 10 minutes
let's have a drink oh today is Happy
Chinese year in America you call it Luna
year happy Luna Year have a drink so
this is uh red wine and uh uh
juice yeah Happy Chinese New Year lunar
year you know in America uh well anyway
so let's let's let's start so let me
talk about let's talk about keyboard so
this is Ultimate hacking keyboard now
you see the light are different
differently
colored what is the significance of the
different colors that the colors are
functional coloring meaning that
depending on what's the purpose of the
key they have different color for
example Alpha numerics modifier keys
some of them green I have here and
special fun function keys and key Mar
Keys uh I think I I made I made it white
key Mar or key map so anyway functional
coloring which is advancement of
technology in the past few years
ultimate hacking keyboard this one okay
fantastic and this one is kesis 360
wired USB wired
okay it's also
fantastic and you see the background
that's red light red light is soothing
you know I recommend you get red light
red bulbs so red light is just fantastic
red light for some reason human eyes
have Affinity with red lights okay like
you you you you can you can see there's
all kind of kind of questionable theory
about red red light how they
cure your eyes when you get old your
eyes get bad and red light helps like
reverse the process something or the red
light can you know they cure your body
your skin something something but anyway
so that's a bit questionable but in any
case what we know for sure is that red
light is indeed soothing and at night if
your wife is sleeping or your family but
you need to have life to work on things
red light okay because at night the the
red light is very soothing it doesn't
disturb you for uh like when you wake up
in the middle of the night you turn on
the light all of a sudden it's too
bright you know but that doesn't happen
with red light okay so red light bulb is
I recommend so anyway so ultimate
hacking keyboard kesis
360 wired version okay that's my
keyboard in my mouse Logitech something
so let's go to my desktop and show you
okay we're going to talk about
mathematics okay so can you see my
desktop yes this is
Tiding mathematics geometry the most
beautiful thing Tiding okay I'm you know
if you are watching this offline you can
you know play it at 1.5 speed because
usually I talk randomly and slowly and
long usually usually my videos are one
hour so just skip around so anyway this
this topic is my last video I did 1 hour
kind of give you a introduction like to
so you can see all sort of Tidings what
they are but today we're going to focus
on this wolam language package okay so
this is what this package do symmetry
Tidings wallpaper
groups so the purpose of the package is
to generate any
possible wallpaper patterns okay any
possible ones uh and is a deep topic it
you know it's fairly deep topic it's
part of
mathematics uh uh and uh you know so
there are many ways to do it so I'm
going to talk about it so you can see
this is wam language
code lots of mathematics this this is
scientific programming very different
and unusual from industrial programming
for example JavaScript
python
PHP Java C
C++ you know you code every
day but you never see your your code is
never in this way is never like this
this is mathematical programming so but
scientific programming or mathematical
programming except in the past 10 years
because the machine learning and big
data and uh artificial intelligence you
know the and uh since last year the
large language
mods L large language models AI
chatbots so you started to have a lot a
lot of code doing mathematics for
example the chat GPT those chat Bots the
code is all mathematics linear algebra
okay so anyway so here you see so what's
the example of mathematical programming
languages you can see that in Julia in
wolam language and uh math lab and uh R
statistics there's a language called R
for example you'll see a lot of uh
scientific programming entirely
different nature than the industrial
programming web coding web monke
okay and if you are here say hi okay so
this is today we're going to talk about
Tidings and patterns and specifically
what does this package
do uh quite dep quite in depth you know
so and and wolam language generated this
this PDF you know this this is a package
I wrote 30 years ago yeah exactly uh
1998 okay so rof Lang language generate
a PDF let me just go through let me show
you so this is my documentation from
about 30 about 20 26 years ago 1998 okay
in PDF so you can see it documents what
this package plan Tiding
do uh and it's quite elaborate quite
details you know the wpaper
groups okay so anyway let me just go
through this and and I'm going to talk
about keyboard for a bit and some other
things then we come back to this okay so
this image is a illustration of a
symmetry of a wallpaper pattern so
double lines means there's a mirror
image triangle means there's a
three-fold rotation at that Center at
that
point a hex gone means there's a sixfold
rotation at that
point uh Diamond means there is a
two-fold rotation symmetry at that point
and the dashed lines means there is a
Glide
reflection at that line so what does
Glide reflection mean for example
Footprints you know if you walk on a
beach you leave Footprints you know they
are symmetric why are they symmetric
because there's a middle line you
reflect it and you shift it it becomes
itself you know footprint patterns so
that's called in mathematics that's
called Glide reflection symmetry so
that's represented in this diagram by uh
the dashed line so double line is mirror
symmetry dash line is Glide reflection
and uh and all the others rotation
symmetry different um
degrees and there is also a
translational symmetry
which but I I'll show you okay so anyway
so here's the different wallpaper
patterns you can see uh and uh let's see
NE so you can see in this example the
Air Lines is a pattern you know but but
this this diamond this triangle this hex
hexagon shapes they indicate where are
the symmetries for example whenever you
see a hexagon here that means at that
point there is a sixfold rotation
meaning that if you rotate the whole
thing one six of a circle it becomes
itself the wallpap the pattern the
wallpaper pattern it may be a wallpaper
it may be a carpet it may be a
decoration on Islamic mosques you know
usually Islamic MOS has lots of patterns
so anyways here's a sixfold rotation and
this diamond so you see this diamond
that means at that point there's a
twofold rotational symmetry meaning that
if you rotate the whole thing around
that point in 180 degrees half of a
circle it become itself okay and the
triangle whenever you see a triangle on
this on this pattern that means there's
a threefold rotation same thing you
rotate it by one third of a circle so
this this
diagram you know is a indicator of the
symmetry of the warp paper pattern and
they are all together the possible
symmetries combination is 17 of them
only 17 mathematically so so anyway
that's the purpose of this package to
allow you to generate all possible
symmetry symmetric wallpaper patterns
okay so anyway that's a diagram and uh
but that's not the only way to do it
okay so here's a code lots of code okay
so here is a diagram for the 17 possible
wallpaper symmetries so this this one
the first one it means this Arrow we
haven't talked about before this arrow
means there's a translational symmetry
that means if you move the whole thing
by by that Arrow length then it be
becomes
itself you move it again it becomes
itself you know so for example if you
have a square grid then you have this
translational
Symmetry and also you have another arrow
there you know meaning that you can move
up and this
one so you have two arrows but you also
have a reflection of symmetry you see
the double line in the middle so that
means you reflect the whole thing it
become itself mirror okay and the Gray
Line the I mean the gray area is called
the fundamental region meaning that
whatever Graphics in that
region once you have that you can
recreate the entire pattern okay so for
example this one you have the gray you
know area so whatever you draw there you
can repeat and recreate the entire
pattern
okay so there are more this okay so you
know there are
17 wallpaper patterns
symmetry uh ways of symmetry I talked
about this in my last video about four
days ago so you can watch that okay so
there are several okay so let's go on go
on and okay anyway this is a PDF
documentation and you can download it
you can download it let me post the link
if you are here say hi okay hello SOS
hello Chris hello jman
Molina okay let me post my page so you
can kind of uh marketing
okay cut it and paste the link and and
you can get you can get the PDF you know
the PDF file it's actually very good you
know the wolam language created this PDF
okay let's scroll down so let me just
finish showing you some of
it so here's a grid of color different
color
patterns this one this pattern of dots I
call it a star pattern okay a star
pattern and here is another you know
wallpaper pattern very interesting
interesting so you can started to see
knots and weaves you know this pattern
is very common you know in fact it's in
your
textile if you magnify it in some some
textile your clothing uh and you can
also see some chairs made made out of
bamboo weaved in that fashion in ch
China Hat China China man hats for
example the Triangular hats working in
the rice field
uh you know so some of the interesting
patterns and Mathematics mathematically
it's very interesting because you have
to know you have to analyze what what
are the possible we weing patterns you
know but anyway for our P purpose for
our purpose our package is designed just
to generate these
images you know so this is a example how
you can create this uh image
uh okay so some more some more okay uh
snowflake patterns some kind of
snowflake and honey comp patterns okay
and uh this is the aror network very
interesting okay and uh okay this this
quite a few so here's a star Motif so
you this for example this function
polygon Motif generates this pattern
then you can map this pattern
to to for example
um to to each one of these points on the
grid then you get a beautiful symmetric
pattern okay that's that's some of the
ways to generate decorative patterns
okay okay so this is long I want to talk
about keyboard a little bit first as I
promised
uh so you can see some Islamic star
patterns and then we come back to this
and going to show you some code real
time uh running them wolfan Mathematica
okay wolfan Mathematica is amazing it's
truly amazing you know I was just
reading the Stephen wol fam's
um Mathematica Ste uh Stephan Wolf's
wolam language version
14 he has blog just search for it
version 14 what's new so it's tremendous
it it anyway that's another topic so let
me let's go back
to let's let's tell you am I going good
am I doing good am I talking is it
interesting so let's go go back to
keyboard a little bit so there's some
keyboard
news so we talked about uh let's see can
you see it yeah so keyboard so happy
hacking keyboard here's a beautiful
photo so you can see functional coloring
great photo okay you know check out my
website uh check out my website Kar
keyboard blog so you can read about all
the details now here's another
interesting thing this s sve board which
I'm going to get one and I'll do a
review for you guys thanks to this guy
very nice uh you know
so you know he created this this data
hands data hands swab keyboard uh let me
show you what that is I talked about
that before so anyway it's a funky kind
of funky keyboard device so supposedly
this device allows you to
type in a different way and pretty
efficient um and uh and more efficient
than a normal keyboard that's the pr
that's that's why there's this search
keyboard data hand an alternative input
system uh you can buy it and now there's
a discount
okay there's a discount so you go to
their website you know go to their
website there's a
discount okay
I I haven't used it so I don't know how
it's I never used the data hand before
but it's would would be interesting and
I'm not review it for you but if you you
might already know about it so you know
there's a discount if you want it you
can get
it and uh data hand okay so S B stations
so I have a I took a few new photo
again this uh kesis 360 is still my
favorite okay uh I don't use it because
I have so many so I use that on my bed
for you know know my bedside and uh then
kesis 360 glove this is this is glove 80
kesis
360 okay and uh then you have the happy
hacking version two and version one
fantastic okay now all these three I
highly recommend you should when you buy
them get the linear light switch like 35
G of Force now they have they have so
many names for this switch today some
call it pink some call it you know Pro
red some you know different names but
anyway make sure you want linear switch
and you want it light like 35 G
activation Force okay that's what I
recommend and that's what I have on the
ultimate hacking keyboard on kesis 360
and on my glove 80 linear light switches
35 grams AC activation Force okay make
sure you get that if you have your own
opinion then go with your own opinion
but if you don't know about anything I
recommend the light ones okay es
especially if you type a lot get used to
the light ones you you may not like it
in the beginning but just get used to it
okay so and here's my other uh keyboards
I have
and uh kesis this is kesis 2 okay anyway
these are old so I'm just going to uh
and let me show you the old old one this
is this is 2015 my battle station in
2015 okay that's about that's about that
and uh let me show you this one this new
discovery I think this is a great
keyboard okay this is Apple maker from
China so they make made a new Alice
layout keyboard now this kind of layout
you can see is kind of funky it's not
conventional you know conventional is
like a laptop you know flat rectangular
so this is not conventional nor is it
like two sections of a linear grid so
it's it's a bit funky so that's why they
call it Alice
keyboard in reference to Alice in
Wonderland you know at so but anyway I
think this is a good one okay I I don't
have it so I can't say for
sure that's about keyboard news and here
is my best ergonomic keyboard pick so
this is my opinion which one is the best
uh and another one I haven't mention
mentioned is this expose I really like
it uh actually okay not this one you
want you you want to get the new one
uh yeah you want to get this one the
late the newer version expose sight
keyboard I highly recommend this one too
in fact this one is cheapest among them
all so if you don't have much money you
know you want your first ergonomic
keyboard get this one
okay okay so I need to update the link
here so and yeah okay there automate
hacking keyboard okay so that's s
best ergonomic keyboards pick my pick
okay that's about
keyboards uh okay that's about keyboard
okay uh let's go back to if you are here
say hi okay uh hello six now let's show
you a JavaScript now I just did it today
someone is asking
about uh dark background so this page
shows you how do you make a JavaScript
button that changes to changes to Doc
theme and change to light light theme
see so this is all you need you just
need you just need this code in the HTML
and you just need this code in the in
the JavaScript okay that's all you need
so this is part of my JavaScript
tutorial JavaScript in depth the best
the best in depth on technicality of
JavaScript in English language on Earth
there's no other in English that's
better okay including all printed books
I talked about this in one of my videos
like uh two months ago or
so uh about the
detail okay uh part of Ja jaas script in
depth now let's get back to the tidings
okay yeah so let's let's see did we talk
about all the things I want to talk
about yeah so I showed you my uh tiing
page okay let's start to talk about
Tidings
hello Lan are you oh yeah
good so okay uh Happy New Year
uh
so so let's talk about so yeah let's
talk start to talk about
mathematics so okay am I ready yeah
let's
see concur viewers
what
good okay so yeah let's uh talk about
plan tiing plan tiing so my
packages here is a
code actually so here is a code you can
see
uh uh let me show you okay
so lest test we want to open that and
uh PL tying documentation let's open
that I'm working on to publish this so I
wrote this in the beginning of
1996 uh very technical very very
technical and very powerful package that
allows you to draw any possible that
mean that's the purpose of this package
to
draw creatively any possible uh
wallpaper patterns
okay so you can magnify so in wam
language you can magnify these Graphics
to to any
size and it's very sharp and you can
export it you can converted you can save
Graphics save Graphics is supports like
PDF HTML EPS that's a postcript give
jpeg PNG pxr I don't know what that
format is SVG and Tiff in fact you can
export it to almost to to BAS basically
any possible image format that exist or
even CAD formats like 3D 3D formats any
possible wam language that's one of the
good great things about wam language
it's just amazing any possible you know
Graphics format codec graphic Graphics
format video format
or CAD threedimensional format for
animation for for for computer
engineering for car manufacturer or you
know whatever for space shuttle or
whatever you know the Auto Cad and
whatever anyway so here is the package
for example let's delete that Graphics
let's let's let let me show you I can
run it okay so click on that run it okay
it's loaded now let's say this page
okay shift enter to run it so it
generates the graph okay so for examp
example this one run it okay can delete
that and run it again okay so you can
see all of these are generated so let
let me show you run this okay let's
change this make let's make it a
colorful
okay so uh instead of that let's say
let's change so this so what's going on
with this one is that you you map a
bunch of pentagram Stars into a I
believe triangular
points okay so you map this star
Motif uh let me show you okay so you
know star motive uh not
here don't so let me show you some of
the things copy this paste it run it
okay so it actually shows shows this
star Graphics uh you can type question
mark
star
Motif and it will show you the
documentation start Motif n R1 R2
returns a polygon that represents a star
shaped polygon of n Fold Symmetry and
radi R1 R2 okay so let's try
that okay so
so star motive what are the other things
let
uh star
Motif oh a bunch of
uh oh then then you can say start motive
R1 Theta R2 Theta uses polar coordinates
as
vertex okay then you have some
variations you can also scale it rotate
it and translate it okay but let's not
let's not do that let's just say 53
let's see what we
get so n then what does that work
no so let's just say
in
oh okay so you need two
arguments uh let's say two and three
let's see what we get oh okay so we got
a that so this is fivefold symmetry
let's say two and
four okay and we can if you want to show
a large Graphics you can do
Show graphics okay and uh there it is so
now let's say let's change it to
six so you got six pointed star so let's
make one of them uh let's say 242 let's
see what
happens you see I wrote this 25 years
ago very general
okay uh you see this has to do with the
the design of the function so when you
write this function oh God no you now
you got ninja
dots so when you design this function
for example star Motif the goal is that
you want this function to be able to
create all possible star
patterns now what does that mean well
you just you know you just have to think
about it is it you know how do you
define all possible stock can it be
convex can it be convex I don't think my
code can actually generate comx but
anyway you know it give you a lot of
variation let's say let's name oh very
interesting so you see then you map the
a star into a uh a wallpaper plot oh
let's do that okay
so let's do that and instead of this
star Motif let's use
let's use this thing okay and uh let's
just show it tall okay it's it's like
this is too big because they are all
jumbled congested together so let's
shrink the whole thing by
times uh
0.2 let's see what happens okay still
too big so let's shrink the whole thing
by
0 05 see what
happens oh okay now that's not too good
looking so let's increase it a little
bit now it's starting to get interesting
so now let's say six on each side on
each Vector basis so you started to have
these interesting Graphics
okay now looks like you know I don't
like the look of this let's say
three okay so you can see interesting
patterns and can
you uh rotate it yeah scale scale and
rotate let's rotate
by 30° okay by 60° Pi /
2 okay did that work uh pi over three I
type it wrong
uh okay that seems no effect let's see
so now let's look at the documentation
again star motive now let me show you
the code okay so here is the
code here is a code shown in emx you
know so it's PL
text uh let's search for Star
Motif there it is so here is the
beginning of the
package I mean the here's the inline
documentation that's what you see
here and uh here is the various
definitions of the function star Motif
you know you want so this is defining
one function the function name is star
Motif so you might be wondering how come
you have so many definitions for it you
see this is how you do you know in the
op Jon it's called
polymorphism okay so what does that
means is that if the function is given
two arguments the first one is a integer
the second one is a vector then you you
do this okay now if it's given three
argument the first one is integer the
second one is a vector the third one is
a number scale then you do this you see
so this is how you can create
what soall polymorphism in
programming so far so good any
questions jman Molina says have you
considered posting on the wolam
community uh yes yeah um the thing is I
just haven't you know I bu I'm busy with
my own stuff so I haven't really joined
the wolam community for discussion let
me let me tell you about that a little
bit are you a wolan programmer maybe I I
asked you
before are you a wolam
programmer so I've been with wolam uh
okay so wolam community so let me tell
you about that so wolam Community is a
forum okay hold on a second let me let
me talk about that and this one so wam
Community is a forum created by wolam
research the company that makes you know
Mathematica uh so they created their own
Forum so you can ask questions you can
you know talk to other people who
program in wolam language and uh we have
you know several mathematicians here you
know typically these are you know these
people look each one these are not the
Zuma Fox they are not the Mangan Fox
okay these are serious people scientist
Engineers computer scientists computer
program you know they are not the online
you know chat random and Gamers you know
that kind of you can see each one
of them has a photo of their face and
and usually they are you know not young
people you know they are
professionals so
uh okay yeah so so so this is wolam
community that's basically a forum
online Forum that lets you talk
about wam language code and whatever uh
related stuff okay aftermath of the
solar eclipse solar eclipse on other
planets uh how do you how do you display
bar
chart chart labels below x axis you know
all sort of questions and stuff and I
know some mathematicians are here you
know there so so there's a
physic uh from University there's a
physics geometry that's my interest
numerical
computation there is created data that's
my least interesting things created data
that's kind of like the online database
uh for example get all the information
about DNA get all the cities in the
world the names of all the cities and
their population of the world you know
get all the you know that's that's this
curated data is about so you can do that
in Wolf language you can get you know
all the countries in the world things
like that you you return anyway I that's
not my thing I'm mostly interested in
mathematics geometry and computation and
the basic mostly pure stuff anyway wolam
Community is a online Forum created by
wolam
now before that I mean there's also
stack overflow stack exchange on
Mathematica and wolam language
so so there's that also I believe this
was earlier then wam created W
community so anyway I haven't used
them well because I I was just busy you
know I got enough things to do and I
know I do have some questions but rarely
usually when I have a question I know
the I mean
the usually I know the answer because
I've been coding wam language for 30
years yes so anyway so and before that
you know before these internet things
then you have the math groups okay math
group is a maing list which I was so
it's another wolam Forum online Forum
but that's before the web browsers
before internet so you it's a new
scoup um so it's
called it's called math group anyway
it's a Newsnet okay it's usern net back
in the 1990s I me so I so over about
seven years I've been on that Forum you
know in the
1990s uh anyway so so that's about
that oh you use wolam language okay okay
welcome welcome to the team so yeah so
one thing one thing about wolam language
is that it's not
it's not purely for professional
programmers you know in most other
languages especially C
C++ Java it's only for professional
programmers it's not for hobbies
programmers it's not for you know
amateur programmers even if you are a
greatest mathematician you know you have
the biggest brand but if you are not a
professional you can't use their
language because they they talk about
you know little things
of no interest to you most most
programming languages are like that and
python is a little a bit
better um but anyway so wolam language
is kind of special in the sense that
it's easy you know it's very it's very
technical detailed covering the most
esoteric mathematics however it's open
to it's very easy to understand even if
you don't know the math they don't talk
about you know things you don't need
need to know you just need to know how
do I draw this right this you draw that
okay you don't not need to know memory
memory whatever Jon computer programming
Jons you know you don't need to know
that's one thing great about wam
language it allows any technical person
you know as long as you know what's a
computer you know you can you know if
you know if you work with computer you
know you can use it easily for anyone to
do and to do a lot of very extremely
complicated
programming okay I digressed a lot so
let's
um yeah so wolam Community are you in
wolam community jman Molina so I haven't
I I was planning to do so because um
sometimes I do have questions oh so okay
great so this are oh
uh Michael Trot you know some of the
people I would I recognize Michael trout
is a one of the greatest expert at wolam
research you know he's a Michael TR his
background is physics he's a physicist
and he's a he's a is's a I would say top
10 the words top 10 wam language
programmer M Michael chart
okay uh he work at wolam of course now
uh some of the others uh do I know them
Brian
Beckman I guess I can you know I'll see
some of the people I
realize uh especially the older
ones
because anyway so yeah wolf yeah so I
want to I'm going to
join
uh but I haven't I haven't so far found
uh yeah I need to join though I need I'm
going to join it
soon because I do have some questions
okay so let's go back to
um where are we so PL tying curves
okay okay next so yeah so we are showing
uh what are we showing uh we are showing
the star Motif so
let's let's get back to the star Motif
and let's see exactly what
other okay so you can you can the first
argument is the Symmetry how many fold
symmetry the second argument is a list
of radius
okay so a least of radius let's say 24
then you got sharp star if you it's 240
then you got very sharp style let's see
let's see what happens to that if
you try that
wow
interesting let's add a colors okay so I
want the color somewhere yeah so let's
uh okay you want color let's just do it
uh
uh what are these arguments I think I
got it
wrong one pi3 wait I got it
wrong yeah so no wonder 1 pi over 3 it's
rotated t oh okay let's say 1 pi over 4
let's
rotate um rotate each of these
Star by pi over 4 which is
90° uh which is 45° let's see oh okay so
wait that's scale that is let's let's go
back to see the
documentation so scale
Alpha so scale so after the list of
radius then you can say a scale then
Alpha is angle for rotation then a
vector for translation
okay
so so you got a let's
say so rotational symmetry of three then
two radius let's say 2 and six 2 and
seven uh okay then scale let's leave it
one then
rotation let's say zero okay let's see
what happens
okay so let's change this to 17
okay
uh scale 0.5 okay let's shrink
it okay so so let's
say
0.1 and
0.7 then scale
one okay now that's
better now let's rotate it I want it to
do rotate by let's say pi over
3 that's six okay let's say pi over 4
let's I want to see some effect oh
that's
interesting
H but why does that do do that that
seems kind of odd so anyway that's some
of the interesting you know that's this
is one of the way to generate a wpaper
pattern is by mapping a motif let's see
let's go okay you you okay so wa so
anyway you you map a motif to each one
of these points okay now there are other
ways for example the other way is for
example this way so let me show you so
we can run this delete okay delete that
delete that run
it each each time it runs it'll generate
a new graphics you see run it this takes
some time generate a random different
different graphics
so you can see how is this one generated
you see this this is a random wallpaper
plot okay so this is generated
by uh where did the
other oh here so this is generated by
you create an image in this little
triangle this is a this is called
fundamental region okay so once you have
this image is called Motif then you just
use the Symmetry to repeat it all over
so you know so for example you have this
mirror line so you can flip it over then
that'll cover this area then you have
this triangle means threefold rotation
so you can rotate this
thing you know oneir of a circle then
you basically feel the whole thing so
each one of these you can is a symmetry
so then you get the
whole
parallelogram then you can just
translate you know then repeat the whole
uh field of the plane and uh and the
result looks like
that okay let's let's
magnify
okay so that's the result this
is you know this is the what you see in
collidal
scope good morning
Yan the KN hi do you read comments yes
of course what are you talking
about okay
uh we talked about that uh let's see so
what else I want to show you some
interesting things
about uh I wanted to
code so one way to draw a wallpaper is
based on symmetry wallpaper groups okay
that's what that's this one is about
this is one of the way to
generate you see you can also use this
way to generate this Graphics we just
showed but you see the interesting
interesting thing is that it's a
different way it's entirely different in
this way we simply map a you know star
like Graphics to all the points on the
grid but in this way you start with the
you know the fundamental region of the
Symmetry then you then you create
this of course we can use this way to to
create that or we can use this way to
create that you know they are
interchangeable but however the method
to draw them is very different so it's
very hard to do to go from one to the
other for example if you want to draw
this Graphics by the way of
symmetry then you have to find out the
coordinate you know you know you you you
know you you have to find out the little
coent of of this little
region you know it's not so
easy so anyway that's uh that's some of
the methods to
draw uh symmetric patterns okay and here
is a rectangular you know uh here's a
example of a different
symmetry can you make the colors small
complex oh Raper hi
reer uh Denise says did you use 3j as
your Unity 3D for this jobs like
geometry no I use wam language
Mathematica okay the 3js is
crap 3js is tremendous
crap um I have article on that okay 3js
is a
incomprehensible
thing let's see if I have
a a documentation of it I I have a Blog
about it it's called 3D JS right what
what's it
called 3D
JS
uh oh D3 JS that's right d3js I have
arle on that in fact I talked about it a
little bit there it
is
d3js visualization a Quassy science okay
I think the this guy the guy who created
d3js you know he he he's one of the
top visualization expert I would say
okay he's one of the top visualization
expert uh in particular using JavaScript
to do
it but however you know so he wrote
d3.js however his
creation uh is kind of crack parage to
me okay uh you know you can see you can
go to his you know he this year is this
guy Mike B okay you can go to his
website in fact he a a very beautiful
book uh website
tremendously and the the images you
create with
d3js is very complex okay uh let me show
you
[Music]
where wait is this the
article okay let's let's go let's go to
it so here's his website you know but
but but he's got a to me he's kind of a
questionable crackpot kind of thing his
creation okay d3js is very difficult to
use is very difficult to
use however he his you know his code his
stuff is very good uh let me turn on
JavaScript for example I'm very
impressed by you know for example this
his website um so in this article he's
talking about algorithms visualizing
algorithms a very good article okay but
his d3js is got problems
okay anyway so you can see this is d3js
okay and what's this one
click click this is uh random okay what
does this one oh okay so it allows you
some kind
of rasterize or what about this one
okay uh click let's see click you know
some of some of them are Great Click so
you can redraw it from any point you
click PA on this sampling so he's
talking about and what is this one so
this
is uh you know
something but anyway there there's a
graph so here is a visualization of
sorting okay you can go to his
website a visualization of of uh of what
buo sort or
something shuffling okay so then so you
can you know re
reshuffle
um okay so and here is let me let me
show you there's one interesting okay I
want to I want to show you beautiful and
also this is a beautiful Graphics okay
beautiful graphics and it's amazingly
it's done in JavaScript not easy to do
very very difficult to do okay and he
did it with
d3js uh you know very beautiful and then
let's see so here's another some kind of
sorting visualization of uh merge salt
okay another one okay here is
interesting oh yeah I was amazed by this
one beautiful this is like creating a
maze okay there's more and watch this
one this is a a different visualization
of the same
maze
okay you can you know very good very
beautiful and very difficult to do and
you know you you got and that's not all
okay so another
one yeah okay so another one this one
this one is kind of doing
um H how do you call it
uh
the the uh backtrack algorithm something
like
that what is this one doing trying to
solve it
something so anyway and I'm most
spectacularly
spectacularly impressed by one of them
not this one
okay I'll show
you not this one not
interesting
okay not this one not
interesting by this one I'm most
impressed by this one
look so you start with a kind of Maze
and this maze is actually made out of
one line one single line and you redraw
it in kind of threedimensional way into
a tree you see this one is I'm I'm very
impressed by this
one
okay this is D3 uh Jazz who wrote
this I think he did
right I think he did yeah so anyway d3js
is his creation okay but but but but
d3js I think think I find it I find it
problematic I find it kind of like a
crackpot okay he's trying to like he's
trying to create a new kind of
framework for creating visualizations
that's what he's trying to do you know
so here's my
article the title is D d3.js
visualization a Quassy science that is
my criticism of his of of the of his
article um and his article you know he
you know for example introducing D3
scale so what what does that mean
introducing D3 scale now when we create
Graphics we have uh often constantly we
have scaling issues like you know the
label you need to scale in a certain way
or if you have a bar chart you know you
have to scale the bars sometimes they
are too wide sometimes they are too
narrow or the height you know sometimes
you you want to rescale all the height
to logarithmic logarithmic scale or
something other
okay so you have the scaling issue you
know you know so he's talking
about scaling issue how do you do it in
d3js but but now look introducing
D3 scale so he's he's creating a new New
Vision new way so in his you know I so I
read it it's it's like usually it's
incomprehensible you have to spend a lot
of time so he's creating a new way so
you don't just view it as a scale you
view it in some other way this way
therefore the whole thing becomes
easier uh I find it problematic okay and
I criticize in each you know detail so
anyway that's
that's that that's my that's that's what
I have to say about that so so it's been
an hour already okay so I think I talked
for an
hour uh we let's let's go back to my
talk show page let's see if there's
something I want to really
say map OT to a grid or triangular Grid
or Star grid okay we already did that
yeah we we mapped a motif to a GD but
let's try another thing okay let's just
try some random okay let's say instead
of you know wallpaper 15 here we have a
particular symmetry
id5 now let's try id14 with the same
Motif you get that let's let's try ID uh
13 okay now let's try ID
12 another different symmetry okay so
now you get re uh rectangular symmetry
now let's try
ID uh 11 let's see what we got
no so anyway that's so that's why in
it's interesting it allows you to create
any possible
wallpaper uh patterns decorative
patterns so what is why is it useful uh
there are many purposes for example if
you are a mathematician you are studying
symmetry you write papers you know
there's a lot there quite a lot unsolved
issues especially on Tidings you know
you just you can go to Wikipedia Tidings
then you you'll see a lot unsolved it's
very deep mathematical problems so if
you are Professor you know you are a
researcher you need to when you you know
research the mathematics you also need
to show illustration so this package is
very useful to show the illustration
What kind of theory you want to say okay
that's one application of this package
another thing is for let's say you are a
interior designer or you are a wallpaper
literal wallpaper designer you know you
you create these kind of patterns people
want to buy you know to decorate their
house or if you are building a church or
a mosque or U you know or your garden
your backyard
garden and you know you need schematics
you need you know so you can use this
package to help you draw it uh you know
so so that's interesting about these
things uh and there other things for
example this one is interesting because
this
one you know before we showed two
methods different methods to generate a
tile one is by using the Symmetry
information you know for example you
know this is a symmetric fundamental
region we just use symmetry to generate
the whole plan or another way which is
the most typical simple way is you
simply map a motif to each grid points
okay so then we have this these various
examples right then another way another
way to generate a pattern is by this let
me show you this way so you begin with
you begin with a triangular grid okay
then consider you know so you begin with
lots of triangles on a grid then
consider the each edge of a triangle you
transform that edge into into kind of a
kink then you get this you see so this
is a transformation of lines so you
see you begin with this line 0 0 1 0 1
negative 1 that's three
coordinate then you transform that line
into this so basically you introduce a
kink
so then you apply that to all line
segments that's what you get very
interesting so this is another different
uh way to generate a regular symmetric
pattern
okay okay that's and and here is a
similar this is the example of that by
by
transforming uh yeah trans line line
transformation you can see we are we
have nested line transformation you know
this this is a famous curve called K
snowflake okay
um if you don't know that already so let
me show you Wikipedia this is one of the
classic uh fror okay this this curve is
called Kos snowflake
so you begin with the line segment then
you break it then you break it
into um you know before you have a line
then you break you break it into
that then you do it again for each line
segment so this is how you get that and
we can do that on a tiing so it so for
example let's get one more recursion out
of this so right now it's two let's say
three okay so you can see they become
more
factored you see
amazing that's very interesting so it's
a new way to generate you know it's a
different way to generate uh
Tiding and others okay there's any many
other interesting things but that I
think that's it for today and here is is
a example you just map a polygon uh a
huge circular thing to the grid then you
get that okay I think and then here's a
beautiful one okay I think that's it for
today uh thanks for explanation and I'm
sorry for Interruption I was wondering
your
opinion can you make colors more complex
uh rers question yeah of course you can
but what do you mean color more
complex
uh now Unity 3D I haven't tried but but
I think that would be fun to to do
it okay that's it for today thank you
guys
DFS now value says DFS now I believe
that DF DFS is a
three-dimensional uh format right let's
say
Mathematica
DFS what is DFS depth first
scan okay I don't know what um okay
that's it for it that's it for today
thank you guys for
watching bye
guys
we talked for one hour did we cover
everything I wanted to say more or less
yes transform lines yes transform lines
or pattern recursively Yes Show an
example mapping Circle to rectangular
Grid or to triangular Grid or to Star
grid now today we mostly you know we
have done mapping it to a triangular
grid
uh and and the rectangular
grid okay that's it thank you guys now
so if you enjoy my stuff so I have a few
things to
sell uh which is a way for you to thank
me to donate to give me money so one of
them is so you go to SAR
doino SAR web so one of the way is you
go to um
s. info then you go to
emac so I have a lot tutorials on
technical information on programming on
mathematics so you can go to emac so
here is my tutorial for emac and emac
lisp and I also did a video you know I
did I did over 100 videos
on for example this video video is very
good S Talk Show 2 September 7th emac
list for beginner one of my most popular
video 10,000 views 20,000 views
something like
that
um you know so you pay me to get my emac
Lis
tutorial so you can use it on your local
machine without in Internet con
connection okay that's one way you can
donate to me just go do
it uh or you can just Amazon me money
Amazon gift card or PayPal so go to k.in
info let's go
back Kar
code and all the way down you can
patreon me you can Amazon gift card me
or you can PayPal me okay that would be
nice or you can also buy my JavaScript
tutorial JavaScript in
depth uh the tutorial link is here
JavaScript in depth and go down topics
and uh bya JavaScript in depth there it
is okay thank you guys
bye
for