Good evening. Good evening everyone.
Welcome to another episode of talk show.
We are going to code F
exploration write a find and replace
script part two.
Two days ago we did part one. So two
days ago, episode 735,
we explored F. We learned F by asking
guac AI. It was smooth and fantastic. So
we learned about how to read file into a
string, how to write string to a file,
how to print, how to replace string, how
to list directory content or walk a
directory and uh we learned how to list
all sub subdirectories and uh so we
learned that from asking guac very
helpful and we're going to do that again
today but today we are going to actually
create a script of F
uh doing find replace. So as I talked
about the other day I have find replace
scripts in several programming
languages.
You can find them in Golan in Python in
Pearl my earliest one in year 2000 in
Emacs Lisp uh and in Wuam language. So,
we're going to write one for F.
Okay. Watch this video at 1.5 speed or
two times as fast. If you are here, say
hi. Okay. Love to see your comments.
Keep the comments coming. Okay. Nobody
is here. So, I'm just going to uh going
to work on my stuff.
Okay. F. So, are you ready? Yes. So,
first of all, we need a directory. Uh
let's go to we need a directory of files
that to do uh find replace. So typically
I go to Emacs manual. Emac list manual.
So open that show in browser. You can
see this is emac list manual. You can
download on web. Search for it. You'll
find it. Let's see. Go to go up.
Go up table of contents. Emac this
manual from GNU Emacs you can find it.
So this is useful. I usually use this
because they are there are over a
thousand files. So it's very uh similar
to what I have to do for my website
because my website has about 12,000
files. So anyway, there's 1,000 files.
So go up uh make a backup copy. Okay. So
copy the file name. Make a backup emac
this. Let's say back up.
Okay. Recursively copy. Yes. So, we are
using Emacs, the most powerful text
editor. So, you see there's a space.
Now, press press. Now, we rename the
space with a lowline character. So, open
the directory. So, we made a copy of the
directory. I'm using Emacs. And on the
ping window, you can see all my command
calls and keystrokes on the left.
>> [clears throat]
>> as I type. So for example, move cursor
forward, forward, backward, backward. So
you can see the command names there.
Okay. And I'm using So let let's so hold
on a second. Let me copy the file path.
So you can see the command course there.
Emacs, the most powerful text editor.
Now close close. Uh close close.
Showing browser. Emacs block. Close,
close, close. Switch back. Close back.
Showing browser. Today's talk show. Back
to Emacs. And uh so I have just
demonstrated
my efficiency setup. You know, one
single key press. I haven't introduced
my keyboard yet. So anyway, so here is
the file path we will need to use. So
hold on a second. Copy and create a new
F
uh text block preop
it up. So this is going to be uh X path.
Let's say X input path that will be F.
So that will be let variable. Okay. So
in F you need.
So that is actually the program and you
can print. We learned yesterday how to
print. So run it.
F print the file path. Fantastic. And
this is FSX. That's the file name
extension for F#. Now put it back.
Syntax color the whole page showing
browser. So we already began. Okay. So
I'm using Sunfly keys in Emacs. That's
this one. Search for it. You will find
it on.info
my website.
Okay, kxali.info http nos. Okay, let me
show you. x ah lee.info.
If your browser says security error, the
website certificate does not have one.
Uh you are risking danger middleain
attack. You know that's My
website does not ask you for credit
card. Therefore, it does not need
you know the HTTPS because HTTPS is like
actually you have to it became
centralized control. Okay. So anyway my
website kasadi code so you can find my
blogs several of them kasan talk show
today's talk show and uh you know
there are 700 uh videos uh keyboard blog
emac blog so on okay so code and search
bind replace you will find 32 articles
this implemented in different
programming languages and several So
algorithm issues on this uh find replace
because when you find replace multiple
pairs you run into a feedback problem.
Okay. So there's some articles uh about
them replace. Okay. So that's how that's
uh introduction to my website and go
back here. Go page down and let's uh
paste the link here.
Find replace. Okay. So actually uh okay.
So and I have not introduced my
keyboard. The keyboard I'm using is
ultimate hacking keyboard UHK80.
Go to my keyboard blog blog blog blog.
Okay, that is ultimate hacking keyboard.
I have a video unboxing and uh review.
Each one is 1 hour. Fantastic. I
recommend it. Okay. And I also have
Smartboard. I haven't been using it, but
I I I will be. Okay. It's been delayed
for over a year thanks to the uh cross
and um what's the guy's name? Anyway,
smartboard. Fantastic. Okay. And uh then
re uh then in the past several years,
I've been using glove glove 80 also the
best keyboard. Okay. So, that's the
introduction of my my keyboard. And you
if you are wondering about my mouse. Oh,
you cannot see it there. Let's see.
There it is. Newly on track ball.
Fantastic.
Uh 512 I think. So you go down track
ball. You can see the all the best track
balls. Okay. So the one I have is this
one. Nuria
M505.
It's one of the China cheapo wonder
because they are cheap. They are they
are like half the price from the you
know western brand names like Logitech
or whatever or the Kensington you know
half the price but they they are good
quality excellent. So I love this track.
Okay. Oh yeah I forgot to go back to uh
and this one is of course Logitech 502.
>> [clears throat]
>> So that's an intro in introduction to my
keyboards. So uh here is the all the
track ball reviews. Okay. So go back. So
so that's about my keyboard and
trackable. So let's uh shall we begin to
code? Copy that.
Close. Close. Close and paste that link.
Show in browser. Fantastic. So let's
begin to write this. Okay. So F. So
let's Yeah. So search tree uh so we uh
back up. Okay, let's start to write it.
Uh find and replace of
of all files in uh the
okay and also we need to make a backup
of each file we change. Okay, but let's
worry about that later. So the first
thing you need to do is you need to get
the list of directories. So we learned
that two days ago. Uh let's go to F
learning notes because I put them here.
So read file, write file, uh replace
string, list the content. So this is um
so you need to uh list the content and
all subdirectories. So that's what I
want. Okay, let's try that. Let's just
try that and wait.
copy is this key I programmed to this
little module
thumb key cluster module this one. Okay.
So go back you can see. Yeah. So
comments. Okay. Comments. Okay. So open
system typically you put the library at
the top and uh then file path. So this
is the file path. So change that to x
input file path. Change. Okay. So remove
that. So we got that file path open. Uh
that file path open it. Fantastic. Okay.
File path and print. We don't care.
Remove. So this is recursively. So let's
see. Um
so uh input file path we need a file
name extension. So let's add that
file name
extension. Now what what is the uh F
naming convention? Can you is it like
underscore snake case or camel case?
So let's ask guac guac what is the
variable naming convention in F? Okay,
answer me please.
Now let's magnify because
uh so control plus
control plus control + control plus
glorious
text.
Okay. What is the variable naming
convention in F? F variable naming
convention differ from those in many
imperative.net
Net languages like C reflecting the
languages functional programming roots
while aligning with net interpility.
Okay. Local variables and parameters
camel case. Okay. Camel case. Okay. No
problemmo. Fantastic.
So this will be file name extension. Um,
so that will be HTML because I only want
HTML files. So because typically that's
what I work with sometimes JavaScript.js
or TypeScript. So let's create a new
file
and let's name this. So what is this
file? Okay, so let's rename it uh
txt. Save. So we can see if that file is
changed. It should not because you know
but let's create one. So we'll um let's
rename. Okay. Hold on a second. Let's
just xx
random char and uh oh okay and uh and
make it underscope.
Anyway, so there. Okay. So now let's
see. I want it low. I want at the
bottom. Okay. So there.
So input path check file name extension
check. And here uh here you just say
file name extension and uh uh you should
say glob
because that is a pattern and this kind
of style of pattern is known as glob
from Unix. Okay. So file name extension
glob fantastic. This by the way these
variables are supposed to be your input.
So what when you eventually if you want
to write this in shell
you know powershell or bash or you know
in terminal you call the program. So you
give uh you know you give options so
called a parameter that says you know
what is the input directory what is the
extension filter blah so you can you
know you can change them you know so
that these are input okay
close that powershell fantastic so
what's next so file name extension glob
so this directory enumerate files input
path file name extension glob and the
separation uh and search option all
directories and type operator send it to
sequence name space eater
method something like that so let's run
it
so okay so let's yeah so can we run it
yes
fantastic it output all these
file path now notice some Some of them
are slash, some of them are backslash.
Backslash is the traditional Windows
convention. Slash is the Unix
convention. But starting about 10 years
ago, power p PowerShell they accept
Windows accept both. So it would be best
best to stick with just slash is better
because the backslash is very annoying
because in many programming languages
they are used for in in let's say in
Unix oriented programming languages or
in open source programming languages
such as ash, c, c++, python and t you
know the zshell uh t kong shell you know
bunch of shells and They use backslash
using the Unix convention but and
meanwhile the so slash is the Unix
convention for file name separators but
the backslash is used for escape
sequence okay in a string. So that's a
Unix convention. But in Windows world,
the backslash is the separator for file
names.
And while their escape character is this
back tick, okay, typically this this
back tick character this is called
technically in Unicode this is called
grave accent. That's a proper name. But
usually you know programmer just call
this character tick they close that
close that grave accent. So anyway so
this you know this this very annoying
but um let's ignore it for now but you
know let's just use um the slash okay
slash is better because because
of the HTML and all the all the other
conventions they they follow the Unix
way. So, so you know, so you you using
slash is more universal.
Okay, that's a lot digression. So you
got so you got a file list of files. Now
you want to open each file. Okay, so how
do you open uh ses me open? How to show
me uh read file?
Okay, here is how you read a file. Now
what is this part? Uh let's see.
This is get directory info. We don't
need. Okay. So I don't think we need
that's you know that's the like file
name access date file name modification
date. Uh you know they get those fi file
name permission system file name owner.
I don't think we need it. Okay. Not not
now. Okay. So now you want to um read a
file. So
okay so you so you know so this is this
is a file path and here is how you get
the content. Okay. But now the question
is how do you so you need some kind of
loop. You need to write a function
that
go through this iterator you know go
through this list. I suppose that's a
list data data type. So you want a
function. You want to map a function to
a list that's returned by this. Okay.
And then you want to um
so this is a list actually. Interesting.
Okay. Something like that. Okay.
Uh so you want a function you want to
map this function to a list of this
file path. For each one the function
will need to open it. Okay. So how do
you write a function? Oh I forgot. I
don't know. So how so let's ask guac
okay
camel case fantastic new question guac
please new question
uh the question is
let's let's type in emac um in f
how to write a function
that goes through a list
of file path and print the path. Okay,
let's try uh some brainless question.
Why not? Because it's free.
If you are watching, say hi. Okay, so in
F there's a simple way to write a
function that takes a list of files. So
I'm starting to learn um F. That's
fantastic. You want to copy? Copy it.
Okay, let's see.
So you start to um
so okay so before we do anything okay so
hold on a second
before any we do anything let's make
sure we got this correct now right now
that prints a bunch of file path okay
now but can we um
so
file list can you say file list
something like that Okay, let
file list equals to that and then
then you do something like that. Is that
valid? Is that legal or is it illegal?
Let's do it.
Fantastic. Same thing. Okay, I'm
familiar with functional programming.
Okay, file list. So let's name it uh X
file list because I like my variable
name convention to start with X. So I I
know at a glance they are variables.
Uh but except well
except here. Okay. Let's add X.
Uh well it's not necessary but let's
just do it. Okay. Right. Right.
Fantastic. Right. Right. Yeah. Good.
Okay. So that so file list is a
constant. You see this functional
programming
languages their data structure are
immutable. Okay. So I always wondered
you know what if you want to change an
element to another value that's like one
of the things I want to learn about F or
Haskell
because
changing elements is you know of a list
is you is often done you need to do that
often so but if you cannot do that how
is it how do you um write a program so I
don't know but anyway right now but for
for our job we don't need to modify this
ele element we we will learn it later
okay so we got to fire fire list then uh
fire list right yeah
okay let's just be uh more conventional
let's okay capital camel case okay list
then what what then what okay so then uh
now let's so then this is a function
Print file path.
Let's name it process file. Okay. Wait.
Uh what?
Uh okay. We jumped.
Okay. Let's name it F process file.
Okay. That's a function process file
path.
Oh.
Oh. Okay. So,
this take a list. That's not what we
want. Um,
wait.
Okay. So, this take a list. We want it
to
What?
for path in path do. Okay, that's that
seems simple. That's like a map. Can you
use map? Do you have a function map?
Because map is more common in functional
programming paradigm.
Alternative version list. Eater more
idiomatic. Yes.
For side effects like printing. Okay.
Uh
okay we are getting into the details of
F
so
so wait so this function takes a list
then it does an iteration of
then here fun path that's a lambda
that's a
pure function also known as lambda also
known was anonymous function. So firm
path
goes to that means the body. Okay, it's
getting complicated.
So we are learning several things. Um
file path operator list eater print.
Okay, even shorter.
Okay, so what is it we need to do? So we
got a list of files and uh sequence
eater or you can do list ether. What's
the difference? I do not know.
So basically you got a list of files.
Now you need to apply a function
to this list of files.
So does it like does does F has a um map
that because that's what I'm familiar
with. You map a function to a list of
items
or the side effect.
Okay. So I don't know. So
so let's copy that first, you know.
Let's let's let's let's
um
okay let's get the guac answer here so
we can we saved it for later
reading pleasure.
Okay. But here not we need to think so
all [sighs]
all files recursively,
right?
So uh so yeah so you don't you don't
need this part, right?
And uh then you do that then.
Okay, we got a typo.
Print. Okay, delete that.
So we got a list of files
and uh you don't need that
delete. Okay, we got a list of files.
Then we
you can do that and over here you simply
call a function on it. Wait, no. But um
well
looks like you know here you can just
put a function name
and um
so the function this function is
actually taking a list of files and this
EDM is for iteration.
So there are many ways but this is not
functional way so we don't want that. Um
and here is read the file. Okay. So
delete that
delete that.
So process file let's modify it. Let's
just say path a string. Okay.
Path is a string type.
Hello. Why there is no one? Hello from
Arabia something.
Uh so process file
file path variable is a string type.
Then what do you want to do with it?
Well, well, so this annoying uh
indentation
very bad syntax borrowed from Python.
Anyway, so
okay, let's ask. Okay. So something
about how to
in f
how to write a function that
takes
a file path
and
and what you want to do with it.
Okay. So,
let's comment that out.
It's so simple. Okay.
Process file
path string. You can like you can just
print it then over here. So, let's run
this. Let's see what happens. Run it.
Process finished. Okay. Now let's uh
print
that.
Okay. Now this just signify tells us
that the script ran successfully. Okay.
When it reaches this part
now so now we want to
so this all valid so far. So what if we
just uh change that instead of print you
say
process file. Can can you do that? Can
you actually do that then you should
train the old file path should does it
my guess is correct.
Fantastic. So you can do that
you simply you know sequence iteration
and process file. So let's ask a
question quickly.
Um so new gu
so hold on a sec. So yeah god. So new
new new okay notifications
uh new G in F
what's the div
sequent eater
versus list eater
beginner's Question
help me
applies a given function
to each element of a collection. Oh, so
actually the sequence eater or lister
they function as a map
like map in typical other program
functional programming languages. Okay.
uh like printing or mutating state
typically typically for side effect that
is why okay so maps is got map but these
are not equivalent to map they are
usually for side effect only okay yeah
it returns a unit
so key difference so let's see uh so
where sequence uh so this is their
signature so let's study this
List eater sequence eater. List is um
type [snorts] uh uh list eater takes a
function
and returns a unit. Unit means nothing
like unit. Unit means like neo or no
something.
And so
okay so you see they they you know it's
this is uh currying
of basically function of two arguments
but
expressed as
sequence of two functions applied one
after another something like that. Okay.
So, don't fully understand it yet, but
it's
expressing
the
input
type to the list. Eater and the output
type
like that. Okay. And so what's the
difference? List works specifically on F
lists. Okay. Type list which are
immutable. immutable sing see singly the
linked list okay eagerly evaluated all
elements stored in memory up front
that's what I like now sequence eater
works on sequences so what is f
sequences what does it mean which is
which are lazy oh
so sequence is a lazy evaluation okay I
don't like that
uh
You can use sequence on list okay but
not vice versa okay performance list is
generally faster yes of course I don't
like the lazy eval okay and when you
have lazy eval you have this complicated
like move next current you know
iterator and stuff
okay
so the difference is one is lazy. Okay,
I got it. Now that one question solved.
Now next
uh so but is this what does the enumer
enumerate file return?
It seems like it returns a sequence.
Okay, so you cannot use list eater.
Now back to our question. So so right
now our code runs. Okay, it prints you
know at least the file path. Uh but
but now you need to read it.
Okay, so let's
so this this is the code where you read
the file. Okay, so let's say X content
string file read all uh
okay cut it. Let's put it there. Let's
see what it does. Can you have two lines
like that?
Uh, so let's
now we need to make sure the name are
correct. Okay.
So you got a function like that. Does
that work? You know this I don't know
how to write a function. Does it work
please? Oh yes.
Okay.
So now each time you got a path you are
open it and read the file path.
Fantastic. Can you also print it? Yes,
of course.
I'm going to read the comment in a bit.
Okay. So,
uh,
so you can write file and you can print
it, of course. Copy. So,
so, so this is going to print a whole
lot of things. Okay. So you see this is
the previous output which is 1,00 file
path. Okay. Close it. Now we are
printing the actual content.
Run it.
Fantastic. Is it working? Yes. So go
here. Expand the window. It's busy
printing. Busy beaver algorithm.
some red wine and apple juice.
It's very busy. It's gonna be uh what 50
megabytes or something. Keep printing
the buffer. Emacs lisp buffer
buffer and scratch and meta and binding.
Okay, done. Fantastic and beautiful.
Done. So you can see those are file
contents. So we made progress
into the realm of F functional
programming fantastic
science and art fantastic mathematics
lambda.
So you know the the code to the F coder
is probably very lousy but we are
learning. Okay. [snorts]
So so far so good. So let's see the
comments.
Nice to meet you, brother. Are you from
Arabia? Your your Arabic uh name?
Uh my name is Mah Mak. Yes, Arabic.
Uh which continent like which country
can you say? So let's see. Okay, let let
me magnify this.
We must start together. He's not here.
Hi
Mark.
F in ML style. Well, I don't know ML.
Well, okay. So, you are saying F can be
written in ML style? Yes, I'm aware.
So I I would like to write that. I mean
I you know I think in the future I I I
my my F code is going to be MI style ML
style not the Python indentation
because what I like to do often is to
like compress all my code into one
single line. So that can only be done if
you don't have this hardcoded physical
indentation
you know because when I code wufam
language Mathematica I've been coding it
for 30 years I always do this so any
function you can immediately
compact it you know into one line so you
can
so it's it's like those outline uh
outline editor so it's like very good
it's uh bulletproof to any hardcoded end
of line you know that kind of crap
But not when you have indentation. When
you have the Python idiot
did this damage. So, so then you got to,
you know, each line is like indent. How
many indent? Oh, that you know the
indent versus tab that
Anyway, that that's digression. Okay,
let's go back. Uh,
said is also Arabic. Oh, hello Arabic
friends.
Oh, Syria. Really? That's interesting.
Uh, Morocco originally. Oh, interesting.
Why do I get upset about lazy? Well,
I just have I don't know it too well, so
I can't say for sure, but I just felt
that it is not a good feature. Okay,
that's so don't take me too seriously.
Uh optimization. Uh well, I'm not sure
about that, but anyway.
Han here. I don't know what he's doing.
Okay. He does wuam language. Yes,
correct. He's a great patience. Okay. Uh
throwing back some beers to cheers. I
love watching Kasa. He's sharp and deep
guy. Yes. Thank you guys. Thank you. So,
do you guys know F#? Okay. You you know.
So uh said tag
said said tagi
you know said so you know F so you can
help me.
So anyway uh how long have we been 40 40
minutes I you know so anyway so we we we
got the file content and next let's do
find replace. Okay let's get to the
heart of our problem. Let's start it to
do find replace. Okay, that's what I
want to do. Write a find replace script.
Let's see, you know, let's just struggle
and see if that uh
f mode. Okay, so well, let's just copy
the whole thing and uh start to do find
replace here. Okay,
so paste the code here. Okay, it's going
to get confusing. Okay,
so now we need to say
you need to say find string. Okay,
uh
find
string. So this is something user
modify. So okay, so let's say
okay, find string. Then you need another
variable that's replace string.
Let's say x glue. Okay. Then uh so let's
add x per our convention. Okay. Find
string replace string. Okay. Then what
is uh then this is how you do find.
Okay. So okay very easy. Okay. So let's
delete that. So we don't need delete
that. Okay. So just this line. So let's
see
new content
equals to
x content dotreplace
and uh then here is the x find string.
Yes. And this is x replace string.
Fantastic.
Okay. And we just now print
content. Can we can we do that? Like can
can go this
can this work?
Let's try it. Okay. Let's run it and run
it and let's search for X glue. Run it.
Fantastic. Okay. So, go to the top.
Search for X and U.
Uh, no. It seems like you didn't find
it. Search for X and uh XG and U. Hey,
search for XG and U. No.
Uh, well, search for XG and U. Okay.
Close that.
So, there are too many files. So, now
let's change the pattern. So only for
files starting with A. Okay. So let's
change the pattern
A.
So now
search it.
So lots and files done. Now list
XG and U. None. That means we failed.
Why does we found X new? Oh, we need to
print X new content. X new content.
That's right. Run it.
BZ Beaver. Go here. Go to the top.
Search XGNU.
Fantastic. And beautiful. There they
are. Now,
next step.
Easy. Save the file.
So, how do you save the file? There it
is. Write file. So copy it. We learned
it from AI. AI told me
yesterday. Okay. So delete, delete,
delete, delete, delete. And uh delete
that. And we just write file here. So
what you want to write? You want to
write
this is the file path.
So X file path.
That's right. And the content is X new
content. Will that work?
And now you don't need to print content.
You just print uh a file path.
Then on file path
uh let's see let's say finish.
Okay. Now run it. Error.
Debugger list error. Void variable.
What?
Oh, you need you need indent. Is that
right? stupid. Um,
print length neo. So, you need indent, I
think.
Okay. So let
X content and new content
X content highlighted new content. Okay.
Am I doing good?
So what is my problem?
File dot write all text
X file path.
That's right. X new content. That should
work. I just I think I just missing
indent. So
now let's try again.
Do it.
Okay.
Unexpected
identifier in binding.
What? Wait.
Okay. So, let's go back to the code.
Uh, go to char. So, can we go to it?
Yes, we can. Uh you well you but you
want the ah where's the uh error back
trace
uh not [clears throat] there so
not there so you actually uh messages
uh no
uh run output there okay
line 20 that's this line error FS 0010
unexpected identifier.
Oh, so you need I think you need another
indent.
Yeah.
Oh, stupid.
I really don't like the indent. Okay,
but for now I have no choice because I
don't because I'm not familiar with the
other syntax.
Okay. So, close that now. Run it. Now,
do do you need um actually this need um
like
god how does this indent work? And
by the way, I haven't implemented
indentation because I'm using
describe function saw F mode. I'm using
my own F mode. If you are using a
complete F mode, then in EMAC, you
probably just press tab. It'll indent,
you know, just like Python. But I
haven't. But I'm writing my own. So, but
anyway, this should work.
Okay, so run it.
Unexpected keyword let or use in binding
line 19.
Okay, no comments.
So, what is my problem?
Uh let's see. Uh do I have notes about
this
indentation? I read about it but I
forgot.
Ringo Tingo. What a great name.
Thank you. Juicy Dollars. Now I get
$9.99.
That's a big hamburger. Thank you very
much. Can I have fries with it? Yes. In
and out burger with rice. Fantastic.
Do you have a question?
Uh, ring ring tingo. Okay. So, anyway,
we we got into a syntax issue here. It's
all clear. We are all done. But there
there is seems to be syntax issue. So,
let's ask GU
now. Let's test the capabilities of AI.
Okay, go go go here. New notification
gu
fix [snorts]
this code.
Okay, I'm not going to worry about
format. I'm just paste this. Let's see.
Usually we it will fix it because the AI
is so smart,
you know. I don't even put it in a new
line.
So here is a fixed and improved version
of your F code. The main issues were a
typo in the variable name X replace
string should be
what? X replace string. Did I have a
spelling error? X replace Oh, I did.
What the cow? I got it wrong in
both places. So let's fix that.
XV pl A C E string. Okay. Okay. That
shouldn't matter, but that that's fixed.
Okay, then.
Okay. Then undefined variable X find
string and X replace string. Okay.
Missing open directive for system.io.
Okay. Well, because it didn't see my
other parts of code, so I have it there.
Then the function didn't take the search
replace string as parameters, making it
less usable. Okay.
Oh, okay. But but okay, let's put the
whole code. Okay. Because the it's not
seeing my code. So
copy the whole code and
modify this,
select all
fix this code. Shift enter and paste it
and send.
executing code one result.
Ringo Tingo appreciate you saw always.
Thank you very much.
So now
Guac tells me you your provided F code
has a few issues that prevent it from
compiling and running correctly.
Indentation is inconsistent. That's
right. And incorrect.
Okay. So uh usually with four spaces the
fp process file function has misaligned
lines. That's right.
Okay. The replace call uses the instance
method string.replace but f is more
idiomatic
and type consistent here to use the
static
system.string.replace
replace or X content replace. Oh. Oh.
Uh what
type consistent here to use the statics
system.replace
or Xcontent.replace. Repairs with proper
spacing. Miner added some spacing for
readability and ensured the print have
done is outside of the loop. It is
okay. So you need some you know so
there's a indentation issue.
Oh okay. So see the way they do it.
Okay, let's see.
Good. Okay.
God, I need to do the indentation. So,
let's just try see if it works.
Oh, god. [laughter]
Fantastic. Finish. Let's open the file.
Let's see. Search for XGNU. Fantastic.
Find and replace. Can you see that?
So, this is a file. Let's expand the
window so you can see the whole. So,
this is a file. Open it. It did the find
replace. We requested
and uh showing HTML doesn't matter. So,
you know, so it did did it. So now let's
find something else to change. Let's say
description. Okay, let's close close.
And now we want to find all the word
description by
X description. Run it.
Fantastic and beautiful. Finished. Open
that. Open uh Okay. Okay. Open a random
one. Sesame open. Search for X dis.
Wait, not here. Search for X
description. Okay, it's not in this
file.
Search for X description, not in this
file. So, let's um open it and use my
own package to search for X description
in all files in this directory. It's my
code.
Oh. Um, what not found? Wait, is it
because case sensitivity?
Wait, search for description.
Uh, search for again. Uh,
wait, why is it not found? Let's see.
Yes.
What are we changing? Close. Close.
Close.
So why is it not found? So open it
again.
Now open that. Now do find find that
find that find that
it does not in you know it nowhere to be
found. So why is that? Is it because
there's no occurrence of that word?
Copy.
Uh, let's see. Open that.
Open that. Search all in all these
directories. Search for description.
Search. Oh, there's no search word.
Why is it? We We did find a word, right?
Now, let's try a different uh word.
Let's see. Uh let's see this file. So
saving saving is a word right there.
Okay. So this is a file a brief files.
Okay. Remember that. Now let's
[clears throat]
try
savings. Okay. X savings. Run it.
Okay. So
um expand. Let's open one of them. Open.
Search for saving. Not there. Close.
Close.
Copy that. Open this file. Open that.
And there it is. Now, let's find all
words x savings.
Oh, I know why. Because my command, the
command I'm calling, which is uh this
one. Let me show you. Okay. Um press
press. So I was calling
safy text to go through this directory
but however
there is ignore directory directives. So
you can open that. So you see it will
ignore files in this directories. So
that is why when why search for x
describe or or x save it's not found
because those files are in this
directory. So it skipped it. Okay. So
let's fix it. So
okay. So let's go back. Let's go. Us
nets next
do do okay go to talk show uh go to talk
show that's today's talk show now go to
directory
now move this entire directory to the
talk show okay so now refresh refresh
there it is it's in talk show directory
so Now copy the file path. Close it.
And uh go back to our code. Close it.
Close it. Close it. Go back to our code.
Close it.
Where's our Where's our code? There.
Okay. Now,
paste. Copy. Paste.
Copy. Select or paste. You see
this is old. This is new. Now remove the
old. Now we run it. Actually we don't
have to run it. Now we just open this
file. Open the directory you see in talk
show. Open any of the file. Then call
find. Okay.
Find x saving search. search.
Cheers.
Mhm.
Mhm. So, you can see all occurrences.
Fantastic.
Now, let's try again.
Repeat last command. Now this time
instead of savings let's search for um
xdec.
Okay you see that do it. You see now you
found them. So successful successful and
beautiful. Fantastic. And the close
cross close we like we we are done. We
are done. Fantastic. Let's just um we
don't need this anymore. Let's make some
comment
process each
each file and here is this here is kind
of walk the list. Okay,
simple, fantastic, beautiful. Find
replace files of all files in a
directory and recursively
and new feature to add you know uh x to
do wait
to do
features to add
option to back up file. Okay, typically
that's what I do. For example, you can
go to my Goland script.
This is my Goland script. I use it every
day. Um, find replace. You see, I do
find replace all the time working on my
website, which is static website of
about 12,000 HTML files written in the
past 30 years. Static. So I do find
replace all the time and you can find
this
homepage for this script golan and then
you got python you got pearl you got
emac this. So, by the way, the Kasa find
command I was using is this emac this
package. You have to pay to get get it.
Okay? Cuz it was free for like 10 five
years. Nobody give a Um so anyway,
so we are successful. So we need to you
know add some new features. backup is
necessary
than uh whether to do backup and also
uh quite a few you know because I use
this every day. So, so now instead of
going to Goland find replace or for
example you can you can see here is my
Goland here's the Python version I use
it for a few years
then then then there's a pearl version
this is from year 2000
you know so then and now there is
uh F version oh Actually, I tried to
write it before. You see, April 2025.
I forgot. Is it working? I don't know. I
not sure it is working, but I forgot.
So, I did try to write it before. So,
anyway, so now I'm just This is a new uh
this is new king in town. So, delete
that. Put it back. Syntax color the
whole page show in browser. So this is
today's fruit and that's the end of it.
Thank you guys very much.
Now
EU says, "Is there a reason you prefix
variables with X?" Yes,
because I don't want variables to have
to collide with common English words.
for example
uh so make a backup pop it out again so
let's say input path so if I just name
it uh path
you know I can just name it path
but what happens is that you know so you
have documentation you know you have lot
this is
uh the full path for something right
when you want to uh find place like
systematically refactor your source
code. So you change
uh so let's say uh you change path let's
say you want it to become
full path okay so you do that okay then
you do that do that then then this part
got so this is not full full path
okay so undo undo okay but now if you
have undo undo undo undo undo undo undo
undo undo uh and do and do undo and do
back my way. Okay. Yeah. Okay. So, but
if you have unique
variable names that's not likely to
happen in common English literature or
elsewhere then this collision won't
happen. Okay. Now the best of all if you
actually for each and every variable
name you
make it uh uh random string.
So when each and every your function
names or variable names or identifiers
is a random string then that's the best
and this is essential. This is actually
not just a
uh
why not just use RSP for refacting
that's a different story okay but let me
tell you about this you want your
function names or variable names to be
unique that is the best property
but usually it's not done why because
then then your name becomes too long and
random random string you know people
don't usually don't like that but but
However, it is the best thing and you
can see it is needed often because I can
you know you can see it everywhere
because for example in Windows you got
this end user that and you got this
random string there that is the
universal ID so-called okay
so you know so for file name function
name you usually you wanted an ID to
make it unique so when you have
variables or any identifier they when
they are unique that allows that gives
you tremendous flexibility. Okay.
Now let me talk about that for few
minutes. Okay. Because this is uh
actually very interesting.
I have an article that in fact I have
like five articles on that
variable naming. Okay. Uh okay. So I
have several articles. You have to like
bear with me. So, Emac search variable
by name. No. So, the so you got
parameter names start with fee. Greek
fee. Variable name start with
she Greek she. Okay. Then dollar sign as
a variable name and add sign in variable
name. That's called sigil used in Ruby,
Pearl, PHP at least. Okay. Why do they
have to do that? You know, I'll explain
because they they they actually so it's
not just a naming issue. It's also
related to um kind of a syntactical type
system. Okay. And there's more. Okay.
There's a lot more. Okay. Uh but let me
tell you about it. So uh what uh sour
war so search for um now select all
sidual war okay sual war the syntactical
indicator for types of function and
variable okay
and let's open another article for
English
variable naming English words considered
harmful
open it. Okay, that's that is most close
to the question you ask. Okay, why do I
do that? So, let's go through them. Uh,
so paraphernal name parameter name start
with a fee and variable name start with
she. That was my convention for like
five or so years. I experiment all the
time. Okay. Why do you want to do this?
because
uh because English words considered uh
harmful because I want unique names.
Okay. Then there's also dollar sign and
uh add sign common in PHP in PHP in
Pearl in Ruby. Okay. They adopted that
convention which is a great advantage
because
they it so it serves as a type system
by syntax. Okay. You don't even need to
run compiler. It's a type system by
syntax. So the idea is that eventually
you got syntax algebra.
So your your code you don't have to run
it. It's became it became mathematics.
Okay.
Uh then the sidual war this is more
detailed but let let me just get to the
point. Okay. English word considered
harmful. Why? For example, why
why do you uh what is the advantage of
unique names? Because
you have several uh you have several
issues referential transparency
combinatoric
logic
that's basically want to remove
variables from lambda. Okay. uh point
free programming is also removing
variables from function. Okay. Hygienic
macro is scheme lists method to fix the
variable name collision problem in
common list.
So all these issues you know referential
transparency combinatory logic point
free programming
hygienic macro and windows
um this uyu ID universal ID you know
this this uh this string
if every of your variable names or
function names are unique then you don't
need any any of these because all of
them all all of these issues. They at
heart they they want basically what they
are trying to do is to uh avoid variable
collision.
Okay. So that is kind of
tied to this issue. And also let's talk
about another issue of variable naming.
For example in mathematics you know you
you open uh any mathematical paper.
Okay, let's say the par
and uh pi. Okay, journal. Okay, so let's
some random name uh
international journal of topology open
access. Okay, whatever journal of
topology can can we just like open
>> [groaning]
>> uh I shouldn't I should open one
specific article because
revisiting probabilistic metric space.
Okay, let's see if we can open this
download version notes. Okay, so um well
there you go. So you can see you can
start to see this math papers formulas.
You see, you see their function names is
never English words. It's popular in
programming. But when when you do
mathematics, their function name is G,
alpha, gamma, beta, you know, whatever.
Okay. So why in programming do we have
to name functions names like that? You
know, like full name like do this uh
process a file, find, replace string,
replace string, you know, why do we why
can't we just do it like mathematics?
Especially in functional programming,
right? We we love functional programming
lambda and all that based on lambda
calculus which is pure mathematics. So
why can't we name our function just like
mathematics? I tried actually
and you can see my report of the result.
Uh so the article is kind of long so
there's a lot issues. So basically when
you um name so I have an article on that
what is the result what happened there
what happens when you name your function
variables as math symbols you start to
realize right away it doesn't work
because it became your code became
unreadable you know imagine all these
variables like a b cde e fg and this
find file you know is just file r file
S you know like basically became
incomprehensible
and
so then you realized
the reason you know you realized this
these file names and variable names they
serve a very critical function that we
don't usually realize they these file
names and variable name they actually
serve as a documentation okay because
you can start to rename random you
every function name or variable name by
a random string then you then you
realize you can't read the code like
impossible h for human but the machine
still understand it perfectly but not
for human so this function name and
variable name they serve as a critical
part of documentation okay not just
random so
so anyway back to your question so I you
know it's just something so I named I
start with
which helps
them from being a common English word or
help them from so so another advantage
is that every time I see X for example
in my in my F mode uh typically
every sequence of letters if it start
with X it will highlight in a different
color so I know right away those are
variables and you know things like that
especially when I did you know fun you
know I start with my function name by
you know parameter names by the seals
you know fe and she so they highlight in
a different color that that is my reason
okay that is my experimentation and
reason
um as far as you know for me it can work
but it is not a universal solution
because you And it's hard to push this
to the masses, the public programmers,
because
well, you kind of can't. The the best
way is you have to in enforce it in a
programming language.
For example, uh let me show you some
silos because this is very interesting.
I haven't talked for a while because for
example um Pearl, Ruby,
PHP they all use it as a syntactical uh
form of type. Okay. And also in Ruby
also in Ruby. So let's open another uh
predicate. Okay. So predicate in
programming languages in Ruby they have
a convention also in scheme disp
any function. So here is Ruby any
function if it ends with a question mark
that means the function always return
either true or false. Okay. Similarly
for closure and if a function
ends up and the function name ends by a
ban exclamation
that means the function will always
mutate the variable.
Okay. So this this function name part of
the function name they are kind of type
indicators and they um and it's
systematic.
So you don't have to like it's not you
know uh depending on the which case so
any function if it ends in a question
mark then it absolutely must return true
or false that is enforced by the
compiler
by the way I I'm not sure that's the
case for Ruby but you can do that okay
so this is kind of like a a form of uh
type via syntax
and in uh so in wuam language they end
with a Q. So if a function ends with a
capital Q that always return true or
false. Okay.
So that's these are called predicates.
Okay. Uh they came from uh they came
from logic. Okay. Predicate linguistics
logic.
So you got you so so all these are
related to function naming. Okay. Then
then in this it ends in P but it's not
enforced and it's like arbitrary.
Sometimes a function name ends in P but
it's not really a predicate. So you got
this like problem that this is no good.
So in EMAC this it's no good.
Okay. So you got these issues then then
you got um uh so let me see if I want to
um
uh so PowerShell by the way also use it.
If if a if a variable name begin with a
dollar sign they are called automatic
variables. In other words, building
variables global. Okay, so global
variables all start with a dollar sign
and Ruby too. So Ruby has a, you know,
systematic convention. Question mark
exclamation at the end or dollar sign or
s sign or double s sign. Double s sign
that's class variable. Okay. Then you
got uh so you got pearl of course the
kind of the language that began at all
and they also got percentage sign that
means hash table. Okay then you got
syntactic meaning a variable. So let's
see what is that one.
Okay that's a that's a that's kind of
different issue. Okay so let's see um
so anyway that is my answer to the
question. And I hope that's I hope you
see what I mean.
Okay. So I agree with So I think that's
it for today. I've been talking for like
90 minutes. Okay. So that's it for
today. Thank you. Ringo tingo.
Why not just use LSP? So LSP that's the
you know that's the I have article on
that. [laughter]
So by the way I also oh I also want to
mention closure because closure is a
very uh functional programming language.
So closure is full of sigils filled with
you know any variable name start with a
star
or multiplication sign it means
something okay ends with a question mark
same as ruby okay it means it's a uh
ends with a question mark it's return
true or false just like ruby and skim
this end with a ban it means it modifies
the variable okay if it ends with the
hyphen And it means uh it creates a
private function. Okay. So closure is is
lots of these lots of and you know
starting with double colon that's um
closure data type closure l keyword.
Okay that's a okay that's language
keyword symbol similar in emacisp. If a
symbol began with a colon it means it's
a keyword symbol which means the symbol
cannot have a value. It's just a symbol.
Okay. Then if it enclosure if it start
with double colon then it means um
keyword data type but with the name x
expanded to include name space. Okay.
Okay. So also can start with backslash
or you know so you know there's lots of
it.
Okay. Lots of it. Closure. So then you
also got these funky function names.
They also uh
have special meaning. Okay. like
function name starting with a dot that's
for calling u that's for calling Java
Java methods okay so anyway and and then
you got more complicated like starting
with the correct that means uh that's a
shortcut for this with meta okay meta
data and so on and also you got uh add
sign you got pound sign it means mar
dispatch also that happens in lisp
common lisp and eac lisp
So al so so all these
again I want to emphasize they are
related to naming naming of functions or
variables. So they are not just like a
user convention. You can just name
whatever but we prefer this way. They
are not like that. They has a they have
a a computational function
either indicating type or uh something.
Okay. So that is why I started to name
my variable start with X. It's not, you
know, I used to name I used to use
dollar sign because in eagles you can
use dollar sign that because that's
allowed character and then I find that
eventually I
I stopped doing that. I replace the
dollar sign with the X because it's
easier to type. So anyway, you got this
kind of reasons. That's why I'm doing
it.
Uh yeah, so no name space for Emac this.
That's another issue. Yeah.
Uh what's my opinion on Hyper 7
keyboard? My opinion on that keyboard is
it's [laughter]
Okay. Contra contrary to what most
people would say. So let's just talk
about that for a minute. Now let's put
this back. Can this run second? Okay, it
runs. Put it back. Okay. Syntax showing
browser. So that's today's talk show and
let's go to keyboard blog and search for
hyper7. So hyper 7 is this kind of
remake or emulation of a well not
emulation they they are like they are
trying to
make a copy of this classic space cadet
keyboard. very interesting fancy
keyboard from 19 um 80 okay 1978
space cadet keyboard
it's very dramatic you know a lot of
people especially today they you know
they site this oh look at all this weird
symbol what a weird keyboard and
including the thumb up and thumb down
you know so that's the
and here's another version this photo is
more popular space cadet keyboard board.
Okay.
So then
then people started to they created this
um hyper 7. Okay. Open.
But if you ask my my opinion is that
it's no good. Okay. Because these are
not ergonomic. this this space cadet
it's the worst keyboard I would say
because everything is like all together
you know there's no thumb keys and what
what what what do you have to do with
this huge humongous space bar you don't
need it you got two thumbs like look at
my keyboard you know you just need two
little space you you want them separate
so you can do meta you know or control
on the other hand and and you got also
other thumb keys right But on this
keyboard, space cadet, you move all the
way to the left to like go there, press
meta super hyper, you know,
that's no good. Why you why you do that?
And also the function keys on top, they
are all in a row. So you cannot touch
type. You cannot feel it. On normal
keyboard that's group of four. So you
can you don't have to look. You can just
feel where F7 are, you know, like F1 2 3
4. Five, six, seven, eight. So eight,
you know, they are on the corner and and
9, 10, 11, 12. So you can feel it, press
it, but not with this one single row
without gaps, these kind of function
keys. So that's no good. But people
don't realize, you know, people don't
know this uh late Malay genian zoomers,
they think it's cool, so they're going
to try to reproduce it. And they think
better, more keys are better. Then they
created this [laughter]
Hyper 7. Okay. So I I don't think it's
good. Well, it's it's you know it's good
effort. It's novelty but I don't think
it's good.
Okay. Bye guys. Bye for real. Shut down.
Bye.
Let me just copy. So we shut down in in
30 seconds. Let me just copy the links
we of things we talked about uh here.
Okay.
Uh
uh uh what?
So a bunch of links. Hyper 7 keyboard.
Uh close that. Hyper 7 keyboard and
space cadet keyboard.
the most dramatic keyboard. Okay. And uh
go back and
base that keyboard hyper7 keyboard. Go
back keyboard search. Close it. And uh
reopen. Did I close something wrong? No.
And there here is a mathematical article
about something
um
topology something. Okay. Uh do we want
it? No.
Okay. So then then bye guys. Bye. So
this we want to copy variable naming uh
variable naming English words considered
harmful
powershell automatic variables. Okay.