hello guys welcome to another episode of
star talk show today i'm going to
talk about pain computing
tablets
stylus inactive stylus active stylus
what's the differences what's pros and
cons how do you tell the differences
uh you know in the past month i've done
a lot work on um
on my keyboard blog so let me quickly
show you okay you just go to kassadi
keyboard
and you can arrive at my keyboard guide
and over here
there are about
about 900 articles
uh all about keyboard so let me turn on
the javascript so you can see the videos
so i did you know in my talk show i did
a lot of talks about keyboards these are
two of the past
uh videos better better ones
so you go to my keyboard blog as i
worked in the past few weeks a lot on
keyboard stuff and one of the things i'm
going to tell you today is about
stylus active stylus inactive stylus
what's the difference and so on
you know you know this one for example i
bought at dollar tree store one dollar
from china cheapo and this is not good
okay so i've been using stylus for um so
let's let's go here uh my local version
so i've been using stylus for uh
i'm late actually starting four years
ago
starting with the microsoft surface
tablet you know i have you know
so okay i'm gonna give you an
introduction introduction about stylus
okay
and uh so if you have questions about
keyboards this is a good time to ask me
okay hello uh christian
and nuen
and hello the rest of you
okay so stylus okay so i'm gonna so here
are the things i want to talk about
introduction to pain computing what's
active and inactive stylus okay let's
let me tell you so active style so let
me first of all show you my stylus okay
so i have uh let's see
you know i don't have a good camera so
i'm going to buy
expensive camera but for now let me let
me show you
is awkward this is awkward way to show
let me name it
um
so you can see so i put the paper so
that it will focus okay
yeah this is bad this is pretty bad so
so so this is cheap china style stylus
okay robot tip one dollar
one dollar for two no good
and this one is active stylus now active
stylus usually means it uh
always require a battery and there's a
light on it usually always
so this is active stylus okay i'm
gonna uh tell you uh in depth the
differences and this is another example
of inactive stylus now this got two
two tips okay let me turn
so one is the disk tip i don't know if
you can see it clearly it's a disk
shaped tip
and the other side is a
wire mesh tip
okay
you know i need to get a better camera
so this is inactive stylus
and lastly this is a drawing tablet
you know drawing tablet drawing tablet
it's got two buttons here usually so
join tablet but you know you would say
it's part of the active
active stylus but it's um
let me go back here
so so the drawing tablet okay so you can
see
oh you cannot see it
so you can see here is a drawing tablet
so let me put a piece of paper here
cover and cover the
cover these so you can actually see so
you can see
okay so let me let me go over the
differences okay
so
so first of all you have active versus
inactive so so active means um let's see
so what's active in active okay active
usually means it requires a battery so i
have an article here so this is inactive
stylus okay robot tips and this is also
inactive stylus in active stylus they
have different styles so usually it's
rubber tip the cheapest is a rubber tip
then you also have you know a disc
shaped
uh tip or you have the wire mesh tip
okay
that's all inactive
and
and active stylus typically they have a
light on it they require battery
and uh you know and usually it's a
device specific for example this this
one okay this one is by the way go to my
website and buy it this is the best
active stylus for
microsoft surface tablets okay if you
own a microsoft surface tablet you want
you want to buy this one okay then
renames
the
nice stylus okay that's the best one
for microsoft surface
okay so active and inactive so what's
the
advantage of inactive usually they are
cheap you know
one dollar or five dollars uh you know
and they are universal they are kind of
universal like you can use this
wherever on any surface that a finger
works for example ipad microsoft
you know tablet surface tablet with the
finger or even uh apple touch pad
by the way this usually doesn't work
well with apple touchpad but anyway
any
surface that
or a phone on a phone iphone or uh
android phone any surface that requires
uh that can use fingertips
uh active inactive sliders usually also
always works okay that's the advantage
sometimes uh it's called universal
stylus okay inactive no battery required
and cheap you know one dollar to five
dollars
so that's inactive stylus okay and let
me also mention finger always works
better than than than any of these uh
inactive stylus okay let me let me get
into details okay let me tell you so
what's active and inactive so i talked
about that
uh and
how to tell the difference between
active versus inactive okay usually
because active ones usually have a light
and requires battery and usually they
also have buttons on it and usually uh
so active so let's show you active
status so they have a button on it
usually so you can see
uh where's the button uh they don't they
don't have a button on this one
so anyway active stylus require battery
have a light and usually
they
they are pressure sensitive that means
uh it makes a difference how you how
hard you press okay so actually i can
show you
let's show you um
let's do a screenshot of this page and
uh
go to pictures
let me show you okay and the best
the best um
[Music]
the best application let me tell you the
best drawing application is krita it's
much better than okay don't use
game you know i i start you know i found
that krita is open source it's fantastic
okay
fantastic twitter okay this is twitter
and
and right now i'm using a drawing tablet
can you see let's see
uh yeah you can kind of see it i draw
here so back to krita who is with krita
oh yeah so you can press the button yeah
then you can switch
pen style for example what is this okay
this
is a
simple
pen you know anyway krita i recommend
krita okay so
i want to show you a page about krita
krita has got this beautiful
uh mascot you know this
there's a name uh her name is uh
wait what what's um what's the name of
the mascot
i think it's just called krita but
anyway so these are some of the
collections of drawing software okay oh
by the way christian christian is expert
here christian is a artist you know he
you know one of the thing uh christian
introduced me is autodesk
sketchbook okay i don't know nothing
about it but
but he recommends that you know he he
draws
so anyway
i want to tell you because of of my
audience you guys are all usually uh
yeah so here's autodesk sketchbook i
haven't tried it uh you know so usually
we think is the most famous it
sucks
game sucks so bad gameplay is 20 years
old
so anyway so let's go back to my talk
show so we covered what's active what's
inactive um
and let's go back here
uh let's see am i am i doing good
and not this window
oh i just screwed up my
okay so
uh
what am i doing what's my point uh let's
go back to yeah it's yeah active versus
inactive types types of inactive so you
you have robot tip you have this tip you
have mesh wire tip now in terms of
functionality they are actually
different different okay so
let me let me tell you about the
different tips
so for example you can i got
i i need to uh i need to i need to buy
a camera so i can like focus you know
you guys donate it's good time to donate
me so i can get like like like any
youtuber so i can show you quality stuff
so anyway
so the
tips okay so usually so you have three
types of tips uh where is it
uh the tips
the disc tip is usually the best okay
the most the more accurate and and uh
is the best usually the best okay
then after that the wire
the wire um mesh
wire mesh tip is the second best the
rubber tip is the worst okay the rubber
tip
so
you know the robot tip is the worst uh
this one
and by the way there are different
qualities of robotic
stylus okay like like this one is one
dollar for two very cheap and it's it
sucks like you have to press hard
sometimes it doesn't register and so on
but i do have other rubber tips
uh oh i don't i don't have it here but i
i do have what other robot tips that
that works better okay
now wire tips wire tape always works and
it's better you know one one of the
thing one of the flaw about the robotic
sliders in active stylus is that
some of them have very hard resistance
you know so when you rub this on a glass
you know iphone or whatever phone
or tablet they have strong resistance so
that's not good okay you want to find
one yeah there's a different you know
there's a difference some of them
have
less resistance so that's better for
note taking
some of them have strong strong uh
resistance so that's one of the
difference then the other difference is
that for example this one really sucks
so that's some of the difference is
robot tip and the mesh tip
is better because it has least
resistance but however there's a flaw
with the mesh tip you have to press
harder
and that's annoying because when you are
you know working on a computer tablet
you know you have to like click no no if
you use your fingers you just tab it it
works
but with the if you use the mesh tip you
have to like
really press it uh and that slows you
down and so it's not good
and the best is actually the disc
tip okay but however this you know
there's a strange problem you know so i
got this i enjoyed it you know i use on
my surface tablet
let me show you
so this is my you know microsoft surface
tablet you know i've been using it for
several years it's five years old
um
so i want to
so what i want to say yeah but
you know for some strange reason i
cannot i don't i cannot possibly imagine
it's possible this doesn't work anymore
this disk tip my favorite tip doesn't
work anymore like
right now it's like it doesn't work
inactive so for no reason for reasons i
cannot imagine because
because this inactive
stylus
they they simply emulate the fingers
like
capacit capacitance some electric
properties so i cannot possibly imagine
how is it possible this work you know
they come with several tips you can
replace
but all the other ones doesn't work so
for some reason so i don't understand
you know
so so far i had i asked people
nobody can tell you and i searched the
web you know nobody can tell you
why uh it may possibly not work anymore
even though physically it's you know
intact it's all good
so that's some some of the issues about
the different tips of inactive stylus
okay
now inactive now active ones such as
this one the best one the best one for
microsoft surface tablet they they
let me turn it on
so there's a
so there's a button there i got my
camera so you i click on that and you
can see the light is on
now active stylus they always work much
much better than inactive ones they are
much sensitive and if you
hoover it on the tablet you'll see your
cursor you know it's almost like a mouse
so active stylus
is much more
better than inactive ones but of course
the flow is that it's it's um you have
to replace battery every month or charge
it for example this is rechargeable you
have to charge it and so on
you know you that so
but it's always better and the other
significant advantage is that with
active stylus you can have right click
okay now i cannot do it here because my
computer here is not touch screen so i
cannot use it i cannot demo it here
but
but for example when you want to make a
selection okay or when you want to right
click okay
that is when
active stylus is much more superior than
inactive ones because inactive ones they
are just like finger you have to hold it
you know it basically depends on the
software you have to hold it for a
second then it becomes right click or if
you want to to make a selection it's
worse you have to
you know hold it then
then they give you two handle bars then
you know it's problem it's a problem
so sometimes for example if you want to
make for example i want to make a
selection stylus and i want to right
click
to search you know for the word stylus
okay this is suppose you want to do this
now on a tablet if you are using a
inactive stylus
that that's that's painful
some
half of the time impossible because once
you made the selection you know you hold
it then you drag the the handlebars to
make selection then you want to do a
right click so how do you do a right
click well you hold it okay
you hold it for a second then the you
know the the context menu pops up
but if you are using active stylus once
you hold it sometimes your selection
disappears so it's impossible you know
it's impossible to do this so that is a
problem of inactive stylus
now active stylus so it's much better
because it has usually have a button
that allows you to right click
and you know so in summary
between
inactive stylus
okay
active
is much
better than inactive okay
so the order is this active is the best
then your finger is the best
then those inactive pens but however
with finger then it's hard to write you
know it's hard to write notes it's
actually better with a pen phone
so active is the best however
however active
active stylus is worse than uh
is was the mouse or trackball okay
because there are situations you know so
so here's the mouse and let me show you
my trackball
yeah god i need a new camera donate guys
buy me a camera
you know this sucks so
so amounts of trackball
you know before before these years i
thought
i thought you know the active stylus
they just simulate mouse so anything the
mouse can do
the active pen can do not true not true
at all because the software actually
they have entirely separate
functionalities it's not
the software is done such that it's not
the active stylus they do not just
emulate mouse it's actually they have
entirely separate interface so it almost
have nothing to do with mouse or
trackball so mouse trackball or touchpad
they functionally speaking they are act
you know in terms of
um
functionality they are
they are actually better than even
active stylus except of course with the
mouse or mouse or trackball you can it's
hard to draw
but otherwise because in some
applications
you cannot
if you are using active stylus on
microsoft
windows surface tablet
some applications
if you use a mouse you can right click
or
a trackball you can right click but with
active stylus even active ones you
cannot do that for example google
google's um you know youtube sometimes
like when i want to right click here or
something it doesn't work
that's when you actually you that's when
you know so
here's intricacies that's when you want
to turn on the virtual uh touch
touch bar okay where is it
it's somewhere here virtual
uh virtual um
let me show you okay so
okay i i need to move on i'm starting to
ramble and uh
i need i i want to try to be conf
condensed okay i don't have it on here
but i need to turn it on so anyway there
is a virtual
um
touchpad okay
devices virtual touchpad somewhere you
can turn it on it's not here i have it
on my tablet
so anyway virtual tab virtual uh touch
um
touch pad yeah
so quality of rubber tip style differ in
quality okay qualities of rubber tip
differ okay
resistance different differ a lot some
doesn't work on apple touch pad okay so
let me let me let me cover this point
okay so this inactive stylus
they don't you know they actually
if you try them on iphone
or apple imax touchpad
they they they don't work actually for
some you know for a reason strange
because you thought you know if you
don't have money
but you have a macbook or
you know suppose you have a macbook you
know they have a giant
trackpad you know
you thought okay you you'll just get a
cheap inactive stylus then you can you
know it's supreme because apple's got
great
touchpad but actually it doesn't work
for some strange reason i i don't
understand you know the technology i
don't quite understand
and you search the web
you'll not find the answer because i
tried so inactive stylus they actually
don't work well on on apple track
trackpad
as opposed to you know i would imagine
it's fantastic because you know
so anyway so uh flaws of rubber tip
stylus we covered that you know there's
a lot of flaws of mesh style stylus we
covered that
uh this tip is the best okay so let's go
back here so let's
uh okay so
so what's the next thing uh any comments
and questions so inactive style is
always inferior to finger okay that's
right
and active stylus are almost always
better than inactive that's right
and the wilderness type of active stylus
okay so one of the issue with active
stylus is that they
they are device dependent for example
this one is designed to be used on
microsoft surface tablets
it doesn't work on ipad
you know or and it doesn't work on
on any other device usually so
active sliders are very device dependent
so that's a issue
okay so
so i think that okay so that's about it
about stylus did that mean anything okay
so one last thing join tablet okay join
tablet let me show you so you know on
this page i have a collection of also
the pen computing devices so you can buy
you can also buy let me get focused okay
so for example here is a apple's track
trackpad old one
but i want to um
i want to focus on drawing tablet okay
so
so drawing tablet okay drawing tablet
for example here you know
wacom is the most famous one but today
you have a thousand chinese uh
made ones they are great in quality okay
cheap but also great in quality
and this you know they support on linux
so you can buy it for because people had
you know you guys have told me have
showed me
so anyway i got this one
i got this one i got my camera
so join tablet so
let me show you okay so it's so it's
pretty lousy you know drawing drawing
tablet
um so what i want to say about it
yeah so join tablet you know
this is an entirely different category
because drawing tablet it comes with a
tablet it requires this pad to work on
and
drawing tablet
is better than
active stylus that works on touch
surface okay so that's my
tip
you know that's my four years experience
having you know i haven't tried this let
me tell you so drawing tablet is the
best it's better than active stylus and
of course it's better than active stylus
okay and uh
and it's fantastic okay
so
you know go go to my website and buy it
of course the flow is that you always
need uh you know these to go with it
okay so that's about that any anything
else uh
and you can join tablet you can use it
as a mouse very convenient
on windows but on the mac
it's
more problematic okay on the mac because
apple don't really want to support it
apple wants you to buy
their ipad with eye pencil you know i
just i discovered you know sometimes you
wonder why what you know why are all
those where can we have one universal
active stylus for every device yeah
that's ideal but you know
for reasons corporations you know anyway
so joint drawing
drawing tablet is the best okay best of
them all
and uh what else i want to say um
so let's see what else yeah join drawing
tablet okay go back here so
this is the cheapest model i got for
forty dollars i think
uh
doesn't work you know on the mac os
doesn't work so well because
not because the tablet is bad because
mac the apple apple really don't want
you to
use them they want you to buy
their
their trackpad you know or they want you
to buy an ipad with eye pencil
it's blood looking expensive
so anyway so
yeah sensitivity pressure sensitive and
so on and uh
and i have another one i want to show
you did i have it here
uh anyway
uh anyway yeah
okay that's about that so let me let me
talk about some other things okay so
that's basically about
the tablet the stylus the ping computing
okay oh yeah there's some something else
i want to say okay keyboard you go to
keyboard and then you go down you go to
pen input so there are other devices for
example this display inc tablet you know
so they use the technology of display
ink
so they
and you then some of them come with a
pen so that's another you know
uh different
pain put in device so this is from a guy
my friend
who showed a great a lot reviews and
writing notes on it fantastic okay this
is in chinese writing chinese
uh i have written chinese before but let
me show you so
where is krita
okay so
right
chai
knees okay
me
love
love okay uh
i haven't written chinese for a long
time
computers
i got i forgot how to write the word for
brain okay
so anyway
yeah so you can see the pressure
sensitivity anyway so this is a
different category of device and this
one is highly recommended to me the
onyx books
and there's another one that's highly
recommended so we can
so let me show you in full screen so you
can write a lot math
so trigonometry
take notes you know i take a lot a lot
of notes when i walk around uh as you
know every two hours i get up walk
around to prevent
ass rot
you know otherwise you are not you're
gonna
you're gonna have back pain spinal
problems and repetitive strangers so
every two hours i get up and walk around
and with my surface tablet and i write
notes read
so math computer you know algorithms
electronics design
uh resistors and transistors and and
and and and and end okay so here's
another one
uh
okay that's also
books uh those are main channels okay so
here is another one that's highly
recommended to me by you guys by lunaris
and by
um
another guy what's his name so highly
recommend kobo okay kobo
so this model doesn't have a pen but
more expensive models come with a pen
and you know there are a few
so
and another another friend who
recommended this one sony digital paper
this is more expensive this is also a
digital ink but
it
costs like
what 800
or something
fantastic okay he's a mathematician a
invitation to arithmetic geometry that's
that's graduate level mathematics okay
arithmetic geometry
introduction you know it's just the
intro and
you know
how much does it take to learn this you
know you have to
four years of college graduate you know
advanced math then you take this course
then you might possibly understand it
arithmetic geometry
what a name
you know arithmetic because oh
arithmetic that's just one plus one
right
okay so that's that
and these are the interesting things
okay for example ink display phone so
this is emily emily
you know
who was a great uh
guy in our forum
uh so she showed so this is a display
from inc in china you know you i don't
think he's available in usa but
china made it she bought it
okay that's i think that's maybe that's
it for today so how long have i talked
30 minutes
any questions comments let's see
how long does youtube take for the super
chats
how much oh i don't know how much
youtube takes for super chat i think you
know some people i never actually
investigated
i think there i heard people say this so
they take quite a lot i don't i don't
know
okay i think that's it uh maybe that's
it for today's uh maybe five more
minutes we shut down okay so because i'm
trying to be
more focused these days
i get more views
or something
okay so then let me tell you some about
some random things i i worked on my um
my blog okay
uh related to keyboard okay
so let's let me just use a pen for
today's since we are talking about
trackball size and replacement so this
this page
got a major update
so first of all so you want to know all
about trackballs first of all you go to
my website of all about trackballs all
trackballs you ever wanted to know
everything you wanted to know about
trackballs i have the information for
you you know so first of all you track
the most important thing about trackball
is that both sides okay so every model i
have a both sides written right there
so you have you know big balls medium
balls 40 millimeters or
small balls 34 millimeter that's very
typical all these then you have
smaller balls 25 millimeters then you
have
some other exotic things for example
this is a huge
this one is huge
um you know this is this is like this
big for kids kind of
but you can buy it and
and then
also professional ones for example this
is professional ones so first of all you
you know
then there's some exotic trackball
devices you know trackball is the
history of trackball
they were invented in the navy in
submarines you know high-tech submarines
i think it's a some sonar device tribal
that's how trackball was invented
uh then so you know the trackball is
fascinating and this is frenzy's
favorite game monkey monkey ball i never
played it though
but i i do remember so let me show you
this okay monkey ball
so we got a lot to random things to talk
about monkey ball okay so and this is
the latest
gimbal uh very expensive hundred dollars
or something so this is frenzy's picture
francis in it you know francie's picture
gamble
so anyway i want to show you yeah
trackball history so you then you have
tranquil history for example this one i
played in 1980s like 1983
1982 fantastic game i love this game you
know
on on this thing
let's see uh if we can get a picture
yeah so you roll the ball fantastic you
know and this is a great game okay
1980s arcade this one is called marble
madness okay so let's go back to tribal
history so this is all the history about
trackball for example this one 1989
old
you know granddaddy high quality huge
okay this is huge this
this thing is huge and high quality and
it comes with a
foot pad okay you can see
so here's the advertisement august 1991
in compute magazine
okay
and you know the old connection device
uh
you know and it comes a footpath
you know high quality build you know
this california vista vista street it's
uh
okay anyway
california avenue where is it
vista okay that's somewhere i don't know
so anyway so go back to trackball
history and you know i remember several
of these ones several of them for
example in particular and by the way
this one
you know today you know this model this
model is very popular among trackball uh
official miatos you know uh trackball
phonetics trackball fans you know you
know it as ltrack ltrack got sold to x
keys in 19 in 2019
you know
the company keeps changing you know so
it was
anyway so this l track right now it's
available on amazon you can buy go to my
website and buy it from there okay so i
got commission commission so this photo
is from andrew andrew hey andrew if you
are still watching
uh
so so this one so but this one existed
back in
1991 okay at least maybe earlier so it
was known as micro speed okay micro
speed you know i i do remember this one
actually you know in 1991
so let's go back to trackball history
let me tell you about for example the
the one i recognize the most is this one
because the you know this kensington
expert they call it kensington expert
mouse
is actually attractable they they they
this trackball is the most
popular trackball
in the mac
apple community throughout 1990s this
every you know mac is known for graphic
design you know photoshop adobe
illustrator mac pen mac drawer all this
drawing application they all originate
from the mac okay apple is you know back
you know because on windows you just
have text you know then does then you
started to have windows 95 and so night
windows 3 but anyway apple is you know
led by several years so
throughout 1990s the
kensington expert mouse is the most
popular and most famous every mac
users covet you know want to buy it you
know i was a student i was a college
student back then i don't i want i want
this very much but it costs a lot money
you know i don't have money so this is
kensington expert okay so dissections
you know
and they have you know then over the
years they have different models then
they started to have four buttons uh you
know four buttons then there's a special
edition a pink you know in japan you can
buy this in japan pink edition
then
then around 2000 year 2000 you know
you know this is you see all these
buttons and here this especially these
special buttons you know home
that's the era year 2000
that's the era where it's
fashionable it's very popular to a
keyboard to have lots of these special
keys home
email you know uh
folder you know so
so this is year 2000 you know kensington
expert mouse pro they come out with that
with this version
but the design is essentially the same
you know the kensington
kensington expert and this is the latest
this is uh you can buy today
bluetooth okay kensington you know we're
very famous one and let me show you
another one this one
i remember this one because because of
this ad
you know it's over over computer
magazine so this is 1989 okay so 1990s
so
you know you don't have you don't really
have internet back then you read
magazines computer magazines for example
i read mac
mac user and mac world magazine almost
every every month every month i read oh
basically every every page you know
because i'm a computer nerd so i i
remember this ad you know it says
you know
not every kind of pointing device fits
your kind of hand you know so they show
the logitech you know where you use the
same they show some other pointing
devices are designed for aliens you know
making fun
logitech is making fun of the
well-known um kensington expert
so yeah okay so
so but let me tell you about the thumb
uh trackball so usually trackball is
divided into thumb operated or
index finger operated
index finger operated is much better
because the thumb based ones you got you
got some problems you know once you so
one tip about using trackball is that
let me show you okay
one tip about using trifold is that you
want to avoid
you know moving your thumb just like
keyboard you know avoid
moving your finger so much
rather you try to move the whole hand
try try to do that instead instead of
you know just move your thumb okay
with some bass trackball you you'll get
you may develop some problems if you are
not careful
okay i think that's it for today
uh
do you prefer elise or family i answered
that yesterday are you trolling trolling
okay so that's it
okay bye guys uh yeah i think that's it
uh anything else i want to cover
yeah let me let me mention these um so
we haven't um
yeah let's use the trackball then since
we're talking about trackball so
one thing we mentioned uh is the tripod
size okay so you can go to my website
you can see all trackballs
trackball
then do it yourself chatbots and this
one is new okay i just added
fantastic
you know like many of you probably oh
two trackballs that's
you know that's exotic and uh what the
weird thing it is it's great okay i will
tell you
trackball two trackball is great
uh anyway
so one of the things i want to tell you
yeah so these are do-it-yourself
trackballs you can buy property very
expensive 200 or something you know they
emulate this classic this this one
okay this one is
supposed you know
recognized by a lot of people to be the
best trackball ever this microsoft you
know it's you know sometimes you'll see
them
on amazon
going for hundred dollars
you know for example on amazon
going for five hundred dollars
okay so
yeah so this is microsoft trackball
explorer
uh what's a year uh 2000 yeah year 2000
then the improv then pooper
was created
three years ago you know do it yourself
you know they
they
they are based on you know the microsoft
trifold explorer
and the photo from the this guy jane
bernard he sent me this photo fantastic
guy and he is the creator of the heavy
industries
keyboard so i recommend you know
so you know he so he sell google
keyboard um
i did a video about them
okay so
so what's uh yeah so go back to proofy
and uh yeah do it yourself trackballs
then trackball history and some
interesting trackball controllers
uh this one is made by apple you know
interesting history made by apple 1996
it flopped it failed you know apple is
trying trying to get into you know
gaming uh device
uh and also valve steam when steam came
up they
originally was trying it was thinking of
creating a trackball-based controller
but you know so they have different
prototypes very interesting you know
they made a bunch of prototypes some
with trackpad some with trackball and
eventually they end up they decided
track
trackpad is the best
but however even this device is
discontinued in two three years ago
so uh so trackballs yeah so what you
know one of the things i wanted to tell
you is the
um
trackball size you know you can replace
them
that's it that's it for today okay let
me go over one more minute okay let me
show you so billiard ball is a good
um trackball replacement you know by
billiard balls okay go read my page you
know search for saudi trackball you'll
find my page
um
what's the thing i want to show you uh
yeah crystal balls you know so you can
replace them with crystal balls
is anything okay that's it
okay this is a good question i cannot
resist to answer
that question is you criticize the happy
hacking keyboard for having too few keys
but the google has even fewer keys so
what's your problem you are wrong
no i'm not looking you know you are
wrong let me tell you
oh god these people you guys you know
so happy hacking so
okay i'm not gonna i i think i want to
end the video so
so let me show you okay so anyway so
this question happy hacking okay so let
me show you happy hacking keyboard happy
hacking uh
so it belongs to a normal category so
wait let me switch to my back to my
logitech mouse because
i prefer this mouse because of the spin
wheel
okay so you are saying you know you are
saying heavy hacking is
uh you know not many keys that's one of
the problem and but the google keyboard
is should be even worse because it got
even fewer keys that's not true let me
let me show you okay so google you know
you go to you know heavy
so for example google this one okay
yeah it has fewer keys than the happy
hacking you know
this is like 50 heavy hacking is like 60
60 keys google is 40 something keys okay
but
google is ergonomic it's designed you
know you you see each for each hand you
have like one two three four five five
thumb keys so it's designed for key
combination i actually i have the google
keyboard you know it's put away
i can show you you know
i i have a video you know but in uh in
the past search for my youtube google
keyboard is designed for the thumb so
for for modified modifier combinations
on the other hand happy hacking is not
you know happy hacking you put your
thumb there then you have to curl let me
show you where is the um
uh
let me you know let me pause pause for
photos
like like the amber third
so in this
there's also also these funny comics
okay happy hacking keyword anime okay so
let me go back
so um
yeah happy hacking so
you know happy hacking
you put your hand here look at you know
look at the f and j that's where your uh
middle fingers i mean the index finger
and you have to curve them all the way
back to hit hit the modifier
and it even has less modifier than the
standard
uh microsoft cheap 10 keyboard less you
know this keyboard microsoft
you know cheapo 10
you have like eight modifiers happy
hacking you only have five what the
idiocy then then you have to curve
finger your thumb all the way back then
the right side and left side you have to
curl different distance because for the
left side it's just small curl for the
right side you have to go all the way
idiocy complete
complete idiocy happy hacking idiotic
and you say go go google yeah they have
some keys designed for your thumb
you know and it's based on qmk qnk is
programmable programmable keyboard you
can set you know the thumb keys to do
many layers and so on
happy hacking the classic i'm talking
about the classic it's not programmable
what the is that not programmable
jesus
and but but now
in 2020 two years ago they came up with
a new model you know happy hacking
professional hybrid ibs
now it's program programmable and now
it's bluetooth but however it's 300
dollars
jesus
i don't i don't understand the happy
hacking people
okay i'm not gonna go further about
happy hacking you know you disagree okay
yeah you know the the the thing about
happy hacking let me tell you the why
people like it okay
first of all the the people who like
happy hacking most of them they don't
they don't touch type okay this that
that's a big that's one of the big
differences between
that's one of the one of the more
fundamental issue on how people
choose keyboards
for people who do not touch type and and
not
and who are not going to learn
they will find you know these ergonomic
keyboards they will find it useless in
fact that's worse for them
because they don't touch type they don't
want to learn they don't you know they
don't did and in fact they don't touch
ty
they don't type much okay they don't
touch
you know that's another topic because i
talked about these topics so many times
depends on how much you type you know
some people actually type two hours a
day professional data entry clerk well
on on the other hand programmers you
don't have to you don't type much for
example that the great guy
thomas
cryosang 22 you know he's a great key
switch expert you know he
he's he's the greatest key switch expert
but however when it comes to ergonomics
where is it you know he's a great
he's the greatest key key switch expert
you know he did a lot of videos i watch
a lot of his videos he's truly great you
know and he's got this
bass he's got this
bass melodious
his voice is very melodious and uh it's
pleasant to listen to him
do his videos
but when it comes to ergonomic keyboards
you know is he become an idiot like he
insists there's no using
and he doesn't touch type you watching
type
idiot
so
let me get back to the point the one of
the most important thing on how people
choose keyboard is that whether they
touch type i mean there's nothing wrong
with it okay if you don't touch type
that's fine
you know there's no
there's nothing wrong you know and you
can sufficiently type sufficiently fast
for your work for your workflow for you
for programming purposes that's fine
okay but but
that's the thing
people who do not like ergonomic
keyboard
almost always like 99 of the time it's
because they don't touch type okay so
for for you guys who don't touch type
then this normal keyboard is great for
you okay no problem okay
just make sure you understand this is a
fact okay
and people like touch typing well they
don't touch type they don't and and also
also
those who don't touch type usually also
implies that they don't type that much
okay
yeah you think you type
a lot you are a programmer but you don't
type much compared to other people
writers or data entry clerk or like me
writing tens of blogs you know 6 000
pages you don't have much okay so you
don't need it you don't feel you know
you you think you type a lot because you
work with computers but you don't
okay
so these people you know they don't
touch type they don't
type much
yeah happy hacking and what they love
about happy hacking is the topo topper
switch okay
so i have a great detail
about the topa switch okay let me let me
show you there it is topper switch
you know they like this i don't like it
i tried it dude i don't like it idiotic
you know i don't like the feel of the
topper switch
okay that's it
bye guys okay
if you like my stuff pay me okay donate
me uh paypal patreon amazon gift card
and so on okay and thank you uh thank
you guys for many of you justine
and many of you robin
bye