welcome to another episode of s talk
show today we are going to code emac
lisp so this is a big project kind of
big so we are going to write a script so
that it will go through a a directory of
thousands of 10,000 files and uh and uh
for each file add a Twitter card to the
header of the file of a HTML file so a
Twitter card
so you know what is a Twitter card
Twitter card is basically a little code
like that you have to add it to each
page so that when people post a link to
your
website the it will show images and
title you know a little summary uh and
similarly you have you know so this are
meta TX and similarly you have that for
Facebook you know Facebook you know this
so happens they they they each one
created a different format so if you
want your link on Facebook to show a
little you know thumbnail pictures and
title summary you have to add Facebook's
card what they call open
graph okay so that's what we're going to
do we're going to code emac Lis and uh
and let's
begin if you have comments and questions
ask okay so let me tell you about my
keyboards glove 80 fantastic keyboard
you can search on my website sale.in you
have I have reviews and so on on YouTube
too so this is Ultimate hacking keyboard
This is newa track Boo this is Logitech
track B and again this fantastic
keyboard is called SAR board SV l b o a
r d and I'm going to review it okay not
today search it search for it you'll see
my uh YouTube introduction about that
keyboard and other websites okay so
let's go back to my screen and let's
begin coding okay let's uh show let's
yeah okay so let's let's begin coding
this WR a script so this is a big task
so let's see what we gonna do if you're
gonna you if you are watching this
offline
uh feel free to speed up or click
around I'm going to go leisurely okay
I'm not going to rush myself so you need
to go through a directory for each file
you see to add a Twitter card one of the
main thing you have to do is that you
have to find a image file for that
particular HTML file so for example
let's uh let me show you my key keyboard
blog so you see all this ergonomic
keyboard so for example I go to this
page glove at0 keyboard
review and uh you have to find a image
file that kind of identifies with this
HTML page so for this page you know it's
probably going going to be this file so
basically for each H HTML page you have
to pick a image file to go with it okay
so that's the major that's basically the
main thing about Twitter card because
the image is just important the image is
the image that catches people's ey but
the other thing is you have to add this
title you know so title for the page
which is kind of redundant because H
because every HTML page is required to
have a title but anyway if you want you
know Twitter to show preview you have to
have this title and also you have to
have this Twitter card content summary
okay and similarly for open graph for
Facebook you know so I'm going to add
Twitter
card so the basically the the the you
know the the algorithm you know what we
have to do is um let's show let's close
that showing browser reopen close that
show showing browser so algorithm let's
let's write it
out
uh okay so that's the trt card and
uh algorithm
okay go
through order for each HTML
file insert a
F meta TX to the
header okay uh and what you need to do
is in fact
actually the algorithm I have expanded
here so go through each HTML page in a
in a directory get all thumbnail
links text okay for each you got a file
path and image file path okay it's a bit
more complic okay that let me let me
explain so for example for so how do you
you know one of the main thing we have
to do for Twitter card is that to find a
image file to go with that file so how
do you find the image file well
typically it's the first image of that
HTML page but not necessarily so for
example this is my keyboard blog page
but you know this is just the icon for
this particular link link uh so so for
some pages you may not actually have a
you don't want a image to be associated
with you know this page but for many
other Pages typically you have one image
you want to be like used as a thumbnail
for that page so so one of the problem
we have is how do you pick a file you
know so typically it's a first image of
that file but it's not always so so it
becomes very kind of nasty problem
because this is not mechanical you
cannot determine it mechanically however
what I want to do is actually you see
for the each of these thumbnail I
already have a thumbnail to go with each
so all I have to do is just find that
thumbnail so this thumbnail goes for
that page this thumbnail is for that
page and so
on so if we look at the source code of
this file let's copy the open that
source code so go to the top ergonomic
keyboard reviews and blah blah blah dish
surface keyboard so that's this part so
you can see for
each this is the first one and uh here's
a link that's that's that file open it
close it and here's the image this part
so open it you see so that's that
so so first task is just go through this
file and extract all these paired
thumbnail and Link
then for each file you got two things
you got the file path then you got a
image path so you want to put that into
a hash table where the key is the file
path the value is the image file path
then once you have a hash table of all
these files and thumbnail
images then you just go through the hash
table and open each file and insert uh
the image tag to the header to the you
know to the beginning of the file so
that's what we're going to
do so uh let's open that again uh okay
copy okay let's start to code it okay
let's go to um Talk show today's talk
show uh so you can you can if you are
here late you can see all the details
there uh let's just begin coding it okay
so so we start a
emac page keyboard log to show close um
cut okay Define
function and uh Define
function okay so so what you want to do
first you want to open this page and for
each of
these format for each of these format
you want
to okay so for each of these
format the format looks like that you
want to identify this link and ident
identify this uh image
tag
then then you build a hash table okay
so right so
you so that's one of the that's part of
the job you find the in you go you you
know you did you go to open each page
and if it is a page with the thumbnail
you identify them and you build a hash
table then you go to the next file so
you want to do this for every file in a
directory uh potentially 1,000 files so
once you get you build hasht okay
so uh we have to write it out so we have
to given
a go through each
HTML
file if
the uh grab or the
thumbnail grab all the link with
thumbnail you got two
parts one is a file
path the other is a image file path
build a hash
table key is the file path value is
image path okay
then go
through hash
table for each key open it insert the
image path as
tag ARA trt card okay so that is the our
line of the
algorithm okay
so so there are you know you know there
are several things we need to do we need
to Traverse the directory and we need
and for each file so let's say
uh work okay
let's say so that's one of the function
we need to write something like that
work
directory and uh we need to write
another
function for a given file path you want
to uh put uh you know gather all the
thumbnail link payers push to a hash
table build hash table something
yeah so here will be the name okay so so
so then over here you're going to
call
that file okay something like
that something like
that so you give directory you go
through every every file in a directory
then for each file you code this
function to open the file and build a
hash
table once it's
done uh so the hash table needs to be
public I mean kind of uh so we can say
the hash
table something like that temporarily
okay NE do
string
uh do string so you need a do
string each key is
a
absolute uh each key is a file path and
value is a image file
path both are full path okay so this is
kind of um
and we need to define a hash table okay
let's rename it
um instead of nma let's call it thumb
nail
links table okay that's more
sensible so create a hash
table um hash table make hash something
make hash table yeah yeah that is the oh
we I don't have a template for that any
comments
questions okay so thumbnail link
table uh yeah let's create a hash table
so let's look up my emac list tutorial I
forgot the syntax but actually you can
just look at the syntax by describe
function okay yeah but um hashtable size
we what it's easier if I just go to lisp
Basics my tutorial and go to data
structure hash Table and there it is
that's essential that's what you
need yeah close that so make hash table
that
okay in fact you can put this part here
since you know you are not going to
change it actually
actually we do want to so actually let's
put it
here okay
so s thumbnail links table so we got the
you know we prepare the empty hash table
which is key value pairs then this work
directory
okay yeah let's do that so how do you
work a directory okay you can also see
my tutorial
here uh let's make
it let's create a second panel here so
let's go to talk
show uh so that's the hash table today's
talk show hash table and how do you work
a directory so that is in emac lisp
uh working with
lines text
processing file and
buffer file directory get file info such
as file size and so on file path work
directory there okay so you need to call
this function directory files
okay okay let's go back to so work
directory here we going to work a
directory so
um let's name it rud okay because it's
always better to have variable names
that's not common English words because
when you do find and replace and so on
you know it's easier to find a unique
name so so so right now we need to work
directory okay so let's see recursively
or
not well in general so we do we want
recursively yes we
do okay this is uh more involved so this
see let's see this directory no sub okay
so not that this directory and all sub
so directory files
recursively so directory files
recursively yeah we got
that so the directory is going going to
be root
the let's not say root let's say base
okay because root has the connotation of
the root directory in
Unix okay so base
directory
um Regular expression only return names
that contains the pattern so we want so
the regular expression is going to be
all HTML file
so that would be dot plus
anything uh and uh back slash dot that
means a literal dot then
HTML then a dollar sign dollar sign
means end of string or End of
Line okay so that's regular expression
and include
directories uh
no you see the emac function for working
a directory is not very good when you
compare to python or Goan or Ruby well I
don't know about Ruby but when you
compare to Powell
Goan uh
python other
languages because the emac this work
directory they are very slow super slow
and uh
and and not uh
flexible uh for example one of the great
example is that if you want to list all
empty directories that's almost
impossible you know I can tell you
because I've written the code for it you
have to go through a lot Hoops in fact
the I can show you the code so list o
empty
directories okay so list M2 directory so
so there's a code there open it diet so
you can see here's a
code it's slightly Twisted
because because then you have to
um what was the uh what was the trick
uh yeah you have to actually build
a push so you have to build the list of
it you have to build a list yourself
let's
see yep
yeah anyway close that let's go back to
our code so include subdirectories so
what does that mean include
subdirectories so do I want directory
path that include sub director Neo uh
predicate
okay I need to do this faster
so
yeah this my function
so T directory that can be read ignor
all function which called
um let's let's just Neo Neo okay we
don't care about that it's just Neo Neo
so so here is how you build a directory
okay X path so you need to set it to so
a list of
path
then hold on second let me close the
door
so so this is a list of path then then
you have to map C you map a function
to uh
actually so you want to map to all file
p PA and the function name is actually
that you don't even need Lambda okay so
prettyy the code so let's put some
documentation uh let's get fancy so
let's make this purely functional so
this work directory we'll take a
directory path then you'll take a
function
okay let's name it okay work work the
directory okay so let's document work
the
directory and
call on it okay call
function that's a
documentation so now this function is
like no side
effect and for for each HTML file call
function that on it okay in fact we can
put this regular expression over as a
parameter but let's not do it uh I'm
actually like going over you
know uh okay so we got this work
directory function we got
this
um thumbnail Global variable we got work
directory function which is should be
correct and then we got this spild hash
table function okay
so let's just document
it for each
for okay uh for
each thumbnail Link in file
path push it to
hashtable
that okay let's just say that for now
okay uh but in fact let's just uh let's
just cheat and let's just say
uh let's just say key value table so
this is table value let's just say one
let's just cheat for now just make this
whole code work you know syntactically
and semantically valid then we'll change
it to do what we want so the key will be
just the file path
okay so this function now should work
build hash table for each file path
it'll just add the file path to the to
the hash table okay and this will just
work the directory and this is just a
hash table Global variable okay
fantastic so let's clean up a little bit
uh remove
that
um let's put that there actually okay so
now this is a summary summary of what we
have okay eval the okay make a backup go
to
diet uh bite compile yes by compiled
successfully deleted close okay let's
drop down oh so many backup files okay
let's uh delete them okay so anyway so
here is our code evaluate it and now we
can actually run
it uh yeah we can run it so let's okay
so how do you run it so all you have to
do is just call this function there and
give it a directory okay
so
uh let's go to talk show copy the file
path put it here there it is so it
should be a
directory okay so if we run this then we
all have a hashtag T of all file names
of all files in S Talk
Show shall we try it yes let's just run
it okay error Lambda base function okay
got Ru number of
arguments uh message
[Music]
buffer
what uh no not not message buffer so
where is
it what
so compile log C run output there uh
nothing
what messages scratch compile log uh not
compile
log what where did the error
go there load with code wrong number of
arguments Lambda based okay so something
Lambda based
B
what R again Lambda based X
function work at the based uh okay wrong
number of
arguments is that
uh let's just let's just try
this run it that works so this line is
correct map see a function and uh so
what is wrong here so also you don't
need the interactive so this is not
interactive so remove the interactive
oh yeah so we only have one function
here
so okay I got it yeah let's remove let's
not be you
know let's remove
that run it
okay it seems successful now let's look
at what's the value of our hash table
here so describe variable
there uh so it has a value okay so it's
a value but it's not printable
um so what is the how do you get the
length of hash table let's
see copy the path go back here so this
is traversal directory open that hash
table
so literal expression hash table count
okay let's try hashtable
count
eval there it is 500
entries uh in fact we can print it by
default you know you cannot print a hash
table so but we have a function here
pretty print hash okay so let's
actually uh let's print our hash table
there so run it there it is beautiful so
wait okay so we can see that's correct
you know each key is a file path full
path each value is a just one okay close
that close that so we our whole code is
is
good uh so copy that that's kind of
debug
so okay so make a
backup put it
back HTML Li it color it showing browser
show the full Glory so here is our code
so far today we have kind of the
outline uh but there's a lot to do
actually 30
minutes uh okay so okay let's continue
so make a backup let's pop it out
again
so so we now we Traverse the directory
okay so this SP hash table needs to
change um this Bui hash table so first
of all let's make we need to clear the
hash table so what is
the how do you clear a hash table hash
table let's see create a hash table
literal expression length at entry
remove entry check key exist check value
removeal entry clear hash okay so you
gotta do that because right
now you know the naming is not very
consistent CLR
hash uh but
anyway yeah let clear hash table there
and and
uh okay
actually actually when you when when you
make a hash table does it automatic
clear clear let's try it evaluate that
then evaluate this oh it does so you
don't actually need to create a hash
table it does when you actually just
yeah that makes sense because you are
creating a new hash table and assign it
to this
variable uh right
so work directory build hash table so
this build hash table part that is is
what we need to
modify because we need to go to
a keyboard you know go to a file and uh
pass all these thumbnail images
okay
yeah so open that file so we have a
thumbnail images like that okay close
it um okay so we have thumbnail images
like that so how do you going to uh
pause
it so you just search okay you go to the
file beginning you open the file go to
the beginning of file then search
[Music]
for all right you search for this
pattern okay so you search for this
pattern up to here because that pattern
is always the same for each thumbnailed
link okay then you just pause it okay
so let's write it
out so that you know you people can read
you know it's make
sense open the file
go to top search for a pattern like this
okay then grab the
link grab both
links make relative link to full
path then add
file path to
hash with image path us value okay
that's right fantastic that's what we
will do okay so let's let's do so here
is the um I mean that's the algorithm so
so first of all open a file so to open a
file in emac disp this a bit tricky
because
uh you can use find file which is how
you usually open a
file but in thisp code you you don't
want to do that because when you use
find file it will turn on I mean it will
syntax color the buffer and run lots of
hooks when whenever you open a file or
you know lots of hooks so you don't want
to do that so there's a better way okay
so let's let me uh show you
uh so you uh go back to the emac list
tutorial uh open a file so you go to the
open a file section so here's emac list
Basics you want to go to emac list
okay then the section on file file and
directory okay uh perer read file write
file so do we do we need to write file
no so read file
okay open file for read only yeah this
is the this is the better way this is
efficient way okay so instead of find
file then ker after you done you want to
do this instead okay so let's remove the
function
part yeah so you use with temp buffer
then insert okay so now let's change the
file uh change the name here
to to shorten that okay
so so insert file contents then do
something
indeed so what we going to do go to
CH Point me main that's above a
beginning and uh then we going to search
forward while search
forward uh in fact we need use to use
regular expression so we want to
research forward
okay so what we're going to search is
this pattern okay so we going to need to
search this pattern and we don't don't
need the replace so we want to search
this pattern so let's let's do
that open a new buffer so let's turn
this thing a concrete text into a
regular expression so here we will uh
use regular expression so this part we
want to
[Music]
be uh reject string okay the power of
emac ab breef so I just typed that and I
got this very difficult to type
thing
cut put here okay now in emac regular
expression needs double back slash so
you you know this a very annoying part
of emac
disp uh it's hard to figure out so
anyway you want to capture anything that
is not a double quote one or more that's
right and minimum minimum or
maximum maximum okay so you don't want
that question mark how do I know because
I've been coding regular expression for
20 plus years regular expression is
actually takes you know take actually
takes a few years to really know
we got one common hey
hey
subit is a two variable function but you
call in with one argument thank you for
catching that yeah we we discovered
eventually so regular expression so we
got that part double check that's
correct copy it and same thing here you
know that's a image path
okay then then uh thumbnail then this
part uh
again almost the same thing except that
not double quote but
um
less less than sign okay so that is
actually
our regular expression but actually not
because the whole thing needs to be a
string then you also need to add back
slash there
and oh God this is this is a pen about
emac regular
expression uh let's see is that right
yeah you do need that you do need
that emx regular expression extreme
pen uh that part okay I think that's it
let's put it here here the regular
expression part
while search for word for that okay
let's you know try and
go with complicated regular expression
almost always you have to like trial and
error so okay bound do we need a
boundary no Neil no error true okay
count we don't care
okay so go to the top beginning of the
buffer while you find a pattern like
that okay
then what you do uh is so you got uh
three captures the file path the image
path and the title okay
so so you can start to add to Hash table
so let's just add to Hash table so put
uh put hash okay so
here yeah with 10 buffer open that that
file then put hash and uh what do you
want to put in the hash uh you want to
put the first captured pattern which is
the file path
so so you say
match match string okay one that's
correct that's first pattern
okay optional we don't care so that's so
you want to
push that that's a file
path and uh the value will
be match
string two that is going that is the
image path
here okay let's just try that okay clean
the I mean uh optimize the
code
so I mean clean pretty print the code
that's it so this function we've been
working on this this B hash table given
a file path you open
it by creating a temp buffer then you
insert the file
content then you go to the top of the
buffer then you search you do a while
loop search for this this kind of
thumbnail image
pattern and uh then you grab the file
path the image path then
you push ha push hash
okay so I think that's it and
now uh now you need to work the you see
you need to work the actually why don't
we instead of walk why don't we just
call this function for now like one
shot um and give it this file path
because if there's any error we don't
have to wait for it to process hundreds
of files you know in this directory
there's actually a th000
files you see my keyboard block is
1,000 files this
this keyboard block 1,000 files so let's
simply just call this one shot to
process this particular
page okay uh but before we do that so
let's remove that so comment out comment
out comment out and Evol the whole thing
okay I
think now I always double check one more
time okay let's eval the whole thing
eval fantastic no error now we just go
to the hash table describe
variable you see it's got uh how many
items U
28/65 what does that mean I don't know
let's print hash table there so run
it go to the messages buffer let's
see
fantastic so yeah it looks like it's
fantastic beginning here to here new
buffer paste and let's make the arrow
colored so now you can easy easily
see what's going on so fantastic you got
the file path you got the image
path that's one entry the next entry and
so on fantastic it seems
like beautiful
beautiful The Power of One Shot
coding uh and the regular expression is
correct thanks to
my 15 years of coding emac this
hello
Elia uh
IIA Sao says are those two different
keyboards and you've
uh
keyboards uh I talked about keyboards in
every one of my videos so you are
probably new here so this is glub 0
keyboard and that is automate hacking
keyboard I use the automate hacking
keyboard as a keyboard Mark okay so
automat you know a keyboard Mark so I
can all these keys are doing control or
okay so but I don't have to I just you
know one key press for example next tab
previous tab close tab last
window uh refresh refresh
Tab and uh and switch to the the first
application the switch to terminal emx
switch to Firefox and so
on you probably knew here because
because I talked about this many times
so V says I think he has Mar or
something yeah okay let's go back to
emac this code we are making progress
smoothly
smoothly slowly
urly no
rush coffee need some
coffee so if you are new here you you
can check
um you know in uh wait where is the talk
show let's go to you know so let me just
let's just close that we don't need it s
talk show that's what we are doing okay
writing a emac list script to process
over 10,000 files for each file you want
to grab all kind of the image thumbnails
a file path a image path then you build
a hash table then you'll get like 10,000
entries then you go through each of the
hash table entry you open that file you
insert a header for like that's the
Twitter card that's what we are doing
okay so so
far here's a
code we break we break it down into you
know we de declare a hash table here
then we uh create a hash table so these
two should be together that's about you
know Global variable hash table this
part is worker
directory uh and for each file you call
this function to pass to get all the you
know links and add them to the hash
table so so far so good okay and here is
just the test code so far so good so now
actually now we can walk a directory so
now we're going to
create hundreds of hash table entries
okay so you need to go to SAR keyboard
directory copy the file path so there it
is so you're going to build a hash table
for thear keyboard directory let's go
there you can see this is a keyboard
directory
1,1 57 files something like that so you
walk this directory
uh yeah that should be it okay so let's
we don't need that we don't need that
okay now we run this whole buffer again
you can see on the pink window is all my
command scores and you know every time I
type something it the command name shows
up for example delete undo so you can
see undo and
delete so anyway so we run this whole
buffer that should be okay let's do it
please let it work seems like it's
working you have to wait for a while
because now it's very busy you know look
opening files temperer and stuff and
regular
expression now right now it's processing
1,000
files looks like it's done is it done
yes okay
now let's
see hashtable
count evaluated you got 770 entries
seems
correct shall we print it okay let's
print the hash table let's see what we
have okay the message buer first of all
kill it so we get a fresh one evaluate
oh wait
evaluated now go to the messages
buffer let's see the full Glory
772 lines fantastic it looks like
correct
beautiful okay now next we need more
things to do now you see each of the
hash table link you can see they are
actually
um relative file path so for example you
can see there so so it's Rel relative
you need uh the full path okay so for
each the final path you actually need
full path
okay so let's do them let's declare a
variable so let's
say file path okay so
what XF path that's full path X image
path that's a image path okay
so so we can
now what are you going to do here okay
well I mean match string expand file
name there and relative
to relative to the current file path
right right
so
uh file name sense directory file name
sense
directory yeah stupid emx there's a
function that given a file path it
Returns the directory it is in so the
name of that function is called
something like file name without
directory or file name sense
directory uh but you know it's a bit
weird naming so let's go back to
emx so you want to go to the files and
section so read
file file read file right file file
directory open that let's see what is is
function on file function on directory
copy directory make directory we want
the file path
things so there it is file name
directory okay yeah file name directory
okay that's a function
then FP path okay so this will change a
relative name to a full
path and we don't need okay let's remove
that
so yeah you have to be careful here
because whenever you do regular
expression it will change this match
data
so so when you want to grab the you know
the first capture you want to make sure
there's no no code that changes the
match data so
anyway uh so let's let's make it more
readable here
so yeah we can yeah that should be do it
that should be that should do it and
this part it's repeated again we can
make a variable but that's not so run
the whole thing
again and uh show the messages buffer so
now you can
see each one of them is a full path you
see copy new buffer paste and uh break
the lines you see the first no it's a
full path now the image is also full
path
fantastic making progress very well next
what is the
next so now we got a a hash
table
okay now
we have buil a hash
table
now go through the hash table
for each
key open the
file insert the value to the top of the
to the top of the page
okay that's
easy so now you just need to Loop
through a hash table okay so let's
remove that remove that but we need to
build it okay now you just go through
the hash table okay so how do you go
through hash table you have um again I
forgot what is you
know add entry remove entry check
existence get all keys No get all values
no
uh hashtable to list wait
what apply function to all entry map
hash you see again the naming is a bit
inconsistent you know there's no dash so
that's why EAC this you know it's a old
language 30 years old so map
hash that's a
function uh you know so it's just like
the syntax is just like map C or map car
okay function and table okay so map hash
uh hash uh wait what is
the yeah so you want to map a function
to
that okay and uh what the function will
do well it'll open the file just like
before so we don't want to use we don't
want to use find file instead we want to
use with temp buer
okay
so so let me clear up this so it's
um there okay so map has Lambda function
with create a temp buer insert a file
path which is X because each of these
key is uh wait map hash wait so map hash
pass a function the function uh takes
two arguments key and value okay so this
function has two values
key V okay so the key is the file path
so we insert the file content and and
what then you just go to uh go to CH
point mean and let's show a HTML page
example then you just search for um so
this part is a bit personal so depends
on what you know what is your HTML file
structure so basically you have this
head head tag that's Universal okay so
where do you want to add it so let's say
I want to add it before title okay I
mean that's a
choice yeah the Twitter cards is not
critical you know the stylesheet should
go above
that uh then this special link you know
for
RSS so it should
go right before the title tag okay so
now you just move the cruiser there
search search
um what what is it
um search
forward search for title tag okay bound
uh bound we don't care no error uh we we
care because we there should be always a
title if there's no title it's Error
okay yeah that's actually kind of true
so search forward search for the title
and go to CH move the cruiser to before
the title okay so what you do is match
beginning
zero zero means the whole match so match
beginning zero means the whole match
beginning position which
means right before the title tag okay so
you put a cluer there then you just
insert uh basically XV okay which is a
value the image path okay fantastic
making very
smooth but trador card has some special
requirement I mean Twitter card has a
some special syntax so let's see let's
copy that so it's actually not you know
you don't just insert a path you need to
insert something
like you
see uh in fact for my case I don't even
want to insert Twitter card I want to
insert some kind of s card because this
you know because the image file is
actually you know this my thumbnail it's
not actually a big
image so do I so um so for example
let's uh but so we need to decide what
exactly this this part will be the image
file path oh and also you need to turn
it into a
URL okay more work to do
you need to turn this value into a
into a s info URL then you insert
something like that and exactly what you
want to insert uh it's going to be
something like
s thumbnail okay something like
that
yeah then eventually I'm going to also
add the Twitter card but my main goal
today is actually
add the thumbnail because why because
let me tell you
why uh and actually we can you know we
can stop today because we did a lot EAC
this coding like the main thing is done
now the inserting part is easy uh the
main kind of job is done you know not
too many code you know 100 lines of code
not even so but let me show you why do I
need this thing so you see in my
keyboard blog and also elsewhere usually
each thing has a thumbnail it's the
thumbnail are extremely convenient
because for example ergonomic keyboard
history without thumbnail it's you know
it's not good so but for
example this page I want to for example
today let's see keyboard block let's go
to add a new entry you know that's link
linkify it okay now showing browser
so you see I add a new link here so
actually this link should be go
to uh go through
there you see I added a new link here
kesis model 100 right but sometimes I
want the thumbnail but I don't know what
which thumbnail it is and usually it's
very tedious to find find out because
the thumbnail is nowhere contained in
this file
itself so typically what I do is open
the file and find the first Big
Image like that open it okay then go to
diet then check to see if there's a file
name ending in hph s 250 250 means like
the area I mean with
so if there it is open that that that is
a thumbnail you see so but it's tedious
so
um where is my file yeah so close that
let's do it again what is
this uh yeah open it go to the first
image open it drop to diet find the 250
image there it is copy the file path
close close close now back here
so here is a thumbnail then I need to
create you know this this this
thumbnailed link so extract the file
path paste it
here put them together then call this
command there it is now showing
browser you see there it is so the the
the the big time wasting part is to find
this thumbnail image file
path but now with what we are doing
today I don't have to do that anymore
because the this file path will be right
at the top you know somewhere here like
like meta something path you know equals
to so that is why
uh what I'm doing
today okay but I think that's it I mean
we did um you know we did the bulk of
you know the heart of what we need to do
or we have to do is insert you know this
insert you know I need to turn this
image file path full path into
the link which is a bit involved because
you see I have more than one domain so
you have to find out what that F you
know you cannot just
blindly add a domain name HTT GPS you
cannot do that
because for example on your website I
don't know what's your domain you know
so when you call this command you need
to have a system that returns given file
path Returns the domain name in other
words turn the uh full file path into
the URL full qualified URL and when you
have more than one domain it gets more
complicated you see I have I already
have the code to do that but you know
but it's
not you know it's just my personal uh
website you know code in it's inside
HTML mod
so I think that's
it why don't you use Evo mod I suppose
you haven't watched my videos at all
silly very silly
question I'm using Sly Keys okay that is
my tra you know that's what my life is
worth in other words so I've been
working on this for 15 years CAF Keys uh
right now it's 4,000 lines of code and
CAF like is in almost every one of my
video I introdu it this key binding
system is much more efficient than Vim
or the Evo mod
okay s like keys so you are ask me why
why why where
are you don't why don't you use Evo mod
okay but you can try you can try sof
Keys
okay that's right default emac key
binding wheel up your
fingers and that happened to me anyway
so that's it for today I think any any
more
questions we otherwise we shut down in 2
minutes
uh close that okay if you like my stuff
donate to me okay so you can buy my emac
tutorial uh sof like key this is free
you can you know on my website you can
buy my emac tutorial like we did today
we you know very useful documentation
and also as a
reference so you can have the whole
thing about 600 Pages or
something emac
so 900 okay actually 900 in this
directory and
uh and plus 200 files here so together
is like over
1,000 files on
emac tutorial key binding and reference
is emac this okay so if you like my
stuff support me give me money okay
that's the most important uh and now
let's wrap up this code so people know
what is going on search for what let's
just
say uh
let's just wrap this up as a kind of you
know so people when people look at this
file even though it's not complete but
it's semantically complete and
syntactically valid and if you know when
they look at this they they will be able
to know what to do so right now this
code is just insert the you know the
file path into the
header I don't want to do it now because
if I run this is it's going to change
you know 1,000s all the thousands of my
file so it's you know so in order to do
this I need to be sure they work you
know I have to create test files and so
on but anyway so here's today's code put
it back in
HTML syntax color it you can see the
command names are here on the pink
window saw
HTML precode and showing browser there
it is we fantastic we complete the job
with ample anot annotations and
explanations CH Ching thank you Chris
thank you
Chris when will you in your old age play
with the with another text at Acme Acme
uh not likely I'm too old okay you young
guys you can go explore Acme I you know
I got better I got I need to study math
and proof Theory you know I've been
doing coding wolam
language em this almost every day but
you know the the proof Theory that's
something I really need to get back into
and differential geometry the you know
the real mathematics not just you know
writing some animation of calculus you
know PL curves but it's a sad thing you
know when I do math uh less people
watching anyway
anyway okay that's it bye guys let's see
let me Clan up okay that's it we shut
down so emx block close what else close
uh that's
it bye