good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show
so today i'm going to code wufang
language mathematica
and i'm going to code i'm going to code
this hyperbola hyperboloid of one sheet
so i'm actually going to generate this
image okay
the rotation of a bar
and possibly also this one this one this
one
this one and the silhouette of a cube
when you spin it like a dice
here's a photo is a hyper
hyperboloid is is that figure okay so
this is what i we are going to do and
here is an interesting
uh 3d printed toy you can make
someone else made it this curve is
interesting
because it's made of one
line that is it it's it can be generated
by simply rotating a single line
and such a surface
is called the rule surface you know
mathematically you say
for every point on a curve on a surface
there is a line on the surface passing
through it for
every and each and every point on the
curve
and here is there are a lot of
architectures
towers uh you know using this idea
concepts very popular in architecture
so this is called road surface and this
this happens also to be a
one of the conic section uh surfaces
that is the cross section of this
surface if you cut it you know
uh horizontally then it's going to be
a circle if you cut it vertically then
it's a parabola it's a
surface of revolution of a parabola so
there are several ways to generate this
curve you can rotate a parabola around
one of the axis and form this surface or
you can
simply you know rotate the line
so this is very interesting you know
this is fascinating because there's a
whole family of these
similar things for example this surface
is a hyperbolic paraboloid
it's also made of one single line um
okay so we are going to code this today
let's start coding okay good morning
everyone if you are here say hi okay
comment and uh
you know comment and ask me questions
okay so let's code it so
so first of all we need to do what we
need to do is to uh gen
uh generate the tube okay so let's go to
mathematica
and by the way let me show you this one
okay hilbert curve
fantastic beautiful okay so you generate
this
by by this command hubert curve okay so
let me show you
huber curve let's magnify let's hold on
second magnify 200
and remove that let's say one
okay so you got that
then if you say two you got that
if you say three you got that if you say
four you got that so you got an idea
it's a recursive it's a
it's a space fee it's a
space feeding curve it's called space
feeding curve
because you know this is a shocking
discovery in mathematics about
200 years ago because when you see
this is a single line let me show you a
table okay let me show you uh
table n then
okay so so a table of this expression
then n goes from one to
one to uh seven
okay so let's face so let's do that
so you can see a progressive
progressively more complex curve
it's uh you know using a simple rule
you know from one line becomes that and
and you apply this rule for each line
segment again
and it becomes that and that that that
so eventually
if you go infinite number of steps it
will
fill out the plan so what's interesting
well
first of all first of all it's
artistically it's
extremely interesting okay this this is
a
beautiful thing for example let's copy
that
let's paste it here and let's magnify
this is fantastic you can use this for a
background
okay for you know website background
or your desktop background actually i
might do that
and but mathematically it's also very
interesting because a line
originally you have a line is a
one-dimensional curve
but now if you do if you have this this
thing
infinite number of steps you know you
so is that you know the it it
can be proven that this actually fills
out the
square completely so
so the question is then is this a thing
you know how do you define your
dimension you know is it two-dimensional
or
uh sync one dimension
then later on you started to have the
idea of fractal dimensions
okay so anyway that's digression
i'm gonna do this uh i'm gonna code on
that
now let's uh let's see the pop-up window
hey ronnie
okay let's let's code this thing okay so
let's go to
uh wolfen language close that um
let's call this thing um
okay let's start here so first of all so
how do you do this
so first of all you you want the tube
okay let's mean get the pin so you want
a tube
you okay first of all you want to rotate
the tube
i mean now yeah make a copy of the tube
and rotate it make it
uh make a cylinder okay before we
actually
tear the uh tube so let's do that
so tube in wufang language it's a
building graphics
primitive okay so you can see so
here is a tube okay so
tube you got say let's see
okay so let's see starts and end
okay so hold on a second so let's see
start point
start point uh equals two so we want to
give it a point
uh this point will be three numbers
this will be let's say
now let's not say start point let's say
length
okay l e n equals to
two okay then we want to
how do you do this
let's let's do it the easy way okay
let's forget about elegance let's just
do the easy way so you want start point
okay
start point equals to uh
three three numbers
our tube's a building feature in a
language yes
it's a built-in graphics primitive for
example two
uh print to show a tube or this is all
you have to do
you know that's all you have to do
so you just say graphics 3d then
tube tube takes uh
two arguments the first arguments is two
points
beginning and end position of the of the
of the tube uh then the coordinates
then the second argument is the
thickness
is it yes the thickness of the tube okay
so
as simple as that so
so okay so we want to do so first of all
a tube
two points start in end start point okay
start point
uh will be let's say
zero zero negative one okay
and
let's say end point
and let's say 0 0 1 okay actually so
length so let's do this this way yeah so
i discovered
uh why don't we do this
so we got start point we got endpoint
now let's
uh let's evaluate it let's just try it
okay
then then then graphics 3d
that's a wrapper whatever inside should
be graphics primitives
so graphic primitives are like points
line a rectangle cube
polyhedron anything you know so inside
this will be a tube and
okay start point end point
okay
okay we got a problem oh yeah so start
point end point they
need to be inside a
curved brace curved bracket there we
have it
so we got a tube
centered around our engine going up and
down
one unit okay
uh yeah okay so so
so you see so then we need to
um okay so
so once we have it we want
to now we want to rotate the uh
tube okay okay
you see our goal is to generate this
so we before we rotate let's
translate let's move the tube to the
side then make a copy so it goes one
round okay
so
so what we want to in order to move
there is a building function called
translate
transform okay let's see translate
okay let's look at the documentation
translate string
uh attempt to translate the string into
the specified uh
translate okay that's not okay that's
the english translate we want the
mathematical translate
oh wait actually we got transliterate so
we got
we actually what we want is translate
okay let's look up the documentation
translate
g x y so g is a graphics primitive
uh translated by a vector okay so
so so now let's define a
another variable offset
let's say girth girth
equals to uh
girth radius okay equals to let's say
one
okay so we got so evaluate that girth
radius
so now we want to translate
this thing
translate this tube thing by
by girth radius
okay that is done and let's slap on a
graphics 3d
so it actually shows it
okay we got an error
oh yeah we forgot to wait translate
girth radius okay hold on a second
translate good radius this needs to be a
point
so so a point
that would be zero zero yeah zero
zero girth radius let's do it
fantastic now what's the difference
between these two well let me show you
you'll see
if i show the um
let me show you this okay graphics
3d okay that's the that's the graphics
wrapper
and here we want to specify options we
want to show axis
okay x is true so we can actually see
the text
okay now put the whole thing
inside okay
run it so now you can see the axis
so zero zero zero zero right
did it translate it didn't translate
zero zero zero zero
one two one twos okay so let's change
the length
to one
okay then let's also put axis true here
let's let's add another variable one
tube equals to
that okay
so we don't have to uh
type the whole thing okay so you forgot
to evaluate one tube now we did
evaluate so now we got the
the tube okay so um
so check the coordinate zero zero
zero zero so x y and zero
zero and z is one unit u
uh one unit in each direction okay
so far so good
now now let's try the translate thing
he said right translate okay translate
one tube by zero zero girth radius
r a d i u r a d
i n radius
okay yeah we okay so let's
let's get the spelling correct radius
not radio
okay so we what is going on so that's
zero zero that's again zero
zero it did not translate
translate graphic can represent okay
translate graphic community represent a
multiple copy of g
translated by a collection of vectors
okay
so
so here is is an example translate
circle from 0
0 to 1 0 yeah so that works
and here is a
uh sphere translated
by oh i see
so the vertical axis yeah so actually we
moved it up
by by this much by girth radius unit
that's a mistake
it should be uh x okay so
girth radius yeah so do it
now you can see you see the x-axis is
one
so we have moved this vertical bar to
the
to the x-axis one unit okay
now
now we want to rotate it okay wait wait
before we rotate it let's
um okay how do you
do that you want to rotate
yeah let's rotate this thing around the
center
and every time we rotate we make a copy
so so eventually we have a kind of a
cylinder okay
so so there is a function for that
rotate okay let's look at
the documentation rotate graphics
primitive uh given an angle
okay so how do you want to rotate
so you so this is a three-dimensional
thing you want to rotate it around the
origin
and around the axis z axis okay
so rotate about the point
x y so so rotate okay so that's a 2d
case rotate about a point x y so this is
a 2d
case so this is a 3d case rotate
the first argument is a graphic
primitive whatever graphics
then the sec second argument is
vectors a pair of vectors each vector is
a
maybe 2d or 3d so it transforms
the the vector from you know the first
vector to the second vector so
that's right okay so we can do that
now let's forgot forget about elegance
let's just get this to work for now okay
so um
so we want to rotate and translate
so what are the other ways so to rotate
3d graphics primitives by
theta radians around 3d vector w
anchored at origin okay this is the
this is the yeah this is the form we
like
better so
okay let's do that so copy the above
code
we first of all uh wait
we first of all translate it okay
we translated
there that's the code but now we want to
rotate
it okay rotate
this thing
by how many degrees 30 degrees okay
let's say 30 degrees
okay we rotate it by 30 degrees
and around what axis around the vector
zero zero one
okay so let's see if that
works okay so now let's check the
coordinate
now let's look from the top down
okay it's hard to see uh
it's hard to see so if we rotate it by
let's say 45 degrees
yep you can see we are looking at
from the top and the bottom axis is
x-axis
and the vertical axis is y here and you
can see
what and and you can see
you see this this thing is not
you know it should originally it should
be one over here
and one over there it should be there
but because we rotate it should be
somewhere yeah
one here you see here one and you see
here one
so it should be here now because we
you know on the lower left is the origin
so we rotate it so this
this looks correct
so we can i can let me show you
with technology
[Laughter]
so you can see if we look at this as an
act wait this should be a curve
right okay wait this is a bad drawing
okay so
delete delete so this is the
origin this is one
and that is one but anyways it is
something like that
okay we rotate it
uh to be to know for sure we can just
make a table of it
like make many copy of it let's let me
show you okay
so let's create a table let's put the
expression
inside
paste it here and and
here we say n goes
from 0 to uh
to 360 in steps
of 30 okay so now we change the 45
degrees
to n okay so now we should have several
copies fantastic
did you see that
our scheme is working
[Laughter]
fantastic one shot coding okay no trial
and error
error this is the the thinking method of
coding
the mathematician's way well actually
mathematicians
has many different kind of styles some
of them actually do
try and error
so anyway so we got this now
so we got this multiple copy there's one
more thing we want okay let's do more so
let's actually it's
in every in steps of 10 degrees so we
got the
serious thing so let's actually in
degrees of fight
in steps of 5 degrees okay so we got
this
fantastic thing
lots of tubes this is uh fantastic
okay now actually now let's add some
specularity color let's add some
coloring okay
let's um
let's add some fantastic color in here
okay we got it this wrong oh yeah
it should be inside
what
yeah what
what is the graphics options
what is the error
an improperly formed option head
specularity encountered okay this
this is actually wrong okay let's forget
about that let's
let's add that data okay
okay so now let's go to the next step
now we want to tilt each of the tube a
little bit
so so we begin here one tube
let's rotate this one tube okay
yeah so let's rotate this one tube
let's put let's put here okay so
let's work here so we want to rotate
just like before
where is it we want to rotate it
and
we want to rotate the one tube
here
and by
by the x-axis okay now by the x-axis
one zero zero we want to rotate
it so now so we want to rotate it by how
many degrees
by ten
by a by a number two level okay
so let's copy that let's modify this uh
one tube code
so we can comment that out so we
and we need to define a tiered level
okay
tier level equals to um
degree okay
tier level 10 degree
okay so we rotate this
tube by tier level 10 degrees
around the vertical vector okay let's
try that
oh what
no this this does not look right
this is rotated by
x-axis this should be
three dimensional start point end point
what's going on
so let's let's do this
well it works somehow it prints that
uh this is it you know i'm i was thrown
i was kind of surprised by this printout
because it doesn't make sense it
actually rotated the text
but actually it didn't work
it seems to work you see so
actually it worked
now if we try this fantastic
we got it so actually we are complete
we completed what we want now all we
have to do is just uh
adjust the tier level okay so let's
remove the intermediate
steps you know so when people look at
this oh my god this is amazing how did
you do it
so to your level it will be let's say 30
degrees
do it and do it
fantastic not enough let's say
tier level wait why is it not enough 45
that's
wait so wait i okay we got something to
fix actually this is not perfect okay
so this is not perfect now um
the the tilting is not correct okay
which way should you tilt
no the tlt is actually correct but um
so let's adjust the let's make them one
shot okay let's make them
one single
code
okay let's tiered 45 degree let's
increase the length
length two okay let's see
there it is beautiful fantastic
car too many
okay let's number okay number uh
uh number of bars number of
tubes okay let's say
90 okay so number of tubes will be
how many how many of them how many
copies of them so
and all we have to do is uh adjust this
360 divided by
i think so okay number of tubes let's
say 40.
fantastic okay that did okay there is a
we got a problem because
a circle has got 360 degrees not
365. i got confused with number of days
in a year
so it's 360. you see you see this
problem you see these two
so now we fix that do it fantastic
so here is the whole code now
we can do something more fancy okay let
me let me show you
so what we are going to do
yeah so so yeah so what are we going to
do now
is to see what is the effect of the tilt
to the overall shape okay
so you see we can make it very
very uh think in the middle like
young girl's body this is sexy
you know but it's not not too much then
it becomes a
b you know it is
so there's a term for that wasp
waste or something like that so we can
make it the whole thing into one
single expression and see their effects
by
manipulate the whole thing
um what okay
so we got you know mathematic
the wolf and language notebook is not a
great um
editor so you know i'd rather code this
in emacs
so you do the whole thing
then let's say d okay d from
so tie tiot level
tiered x from
from 0 to 45
and in steps of five
okay so copy the tilt and replace the
tier by
okay so we got we gonna we gotta do this
tier level
okay i think that's that does that
so let's
play
okay so let's play back and forth can we
do that
so that is the effect of tier level now
let's do one more thing
uh let's let's fix the
let's fix the viewpoint so the graphics
doesn't
doesn't jump up and down
so great let's save the notebook
okay let's uh do let's change the
let's fix the viewpoint okay so graphics
3d
let's say front okay do it
okay it's still you know the size
changes let's fix the size
so viewpoint let's not say front okay
let's
magnify
viewpoint
let's see viewpoint where do you want to
view this thing
so
x is
five y is
negative five
z is five okay let's try that
okay and view distance
uh view angle viewpoint view angle usage
actually yeah
part range let me let me get this
to show
so view plot range negative five to five
for
x and y and z
okay let's do it
okay now they look um
now let's change let's lower the
three four
four
four four yeah
do it yeah
plot ranges um
yeah i'm so tired of wufang language
editor so let's do this in e-max
it's much faster
okay that's it that's it for today 744
thank you for watching uh
if you like my stuff donate okay
donate by my emacs tutorial uh
you know paypal me patreon me
so that's what we want to do and we did
it
fantastic
thank you guys for watching and you know
next
in the coming days i'm going to also
also this will be interesting now you
know this
and also we can pretty we can pretty
find the code actually you know we
there's a lot
code 235 so maybe
let me do this um
you know we can pretty find the code
because now there's a lot of parameters
we can make it a function of programming
into one single line
so right now you see it's using a bunch
of variables
uh you don't have to you can make them
all just
one single line but
i'm gonna play offline okay so bye guys
uh