good morning everyone I'm early today
today September 12 2009 teen Thursday
12:30 p.m. in the afternoon San
Francisco time
good morning bathroom you good morning
Michael Michael pirogues official so
today I'm early
good morning is e-tron crazy how are you
guys doing how are you is it Ron how is
your homework good money well load the
MA so Z Tron crazy you are doing
homework so let me show you I forgot you
know I when you mentioned that function
okay so this function f X okay hold on
second let me start Excel command log
mod so on the Left window you can see
all my Emacs commands and I am I am five
minutes early what a rarity good morning
fight fire and fire hand job okay fire
hand fire hand job
fire hand is good so so what's up guys
so the Tron crazy is doing homework
there is this homework f x equals two x
squared plus C plus C now Xetra you
didn't mention what topic is this
calculus precalculus or it could be
complex analysis because you know what
this formula is about this formula is
the formula of the Mandelbrot set did
you know that is the formula for formula
for Mandelbrot set so what you do so you
take the formula and the X
is any complex number so you so you're
putting you know you plugging a number a
complex number now complex number is
pretty much a pair of numbers it's like
X&Y okay the code and x and y so you
plug in that number and you come out
another number now now C is a constant
okay now suppose suppose you you have to
feeding a number to C so so suppose C
equals to zero zero at the origin okay
now so C suppose C equals to the pair 0
0 ok now you plug in any number then you
come out another pair of numbers then
you take that number and you plug it in
again and it come out another pair of
numbers you repeat the process you
repeat the process then some good
morning pathos so Z trunk crazies it's
wrong crazy so did did you know this is
a formula for full facto so anyway so
you plug in you so you repeat the
recursion process in math mathematicians
Costco's it iteration you know you
recurse this function and now four
factors let me let me try to remember
what is the formula so so
[ __ ] number you repeat the process
yes okay so I got it so suppose let me
let me start from the beginning so let's
so this formula and the X is a complex
number
you should complex number usually by
convention you you write Z for a complex
number okay C is also a complex number
so first of all you give a value to C so
let's say C equals to 0 0 you know the
real part is 0 the complex part is 0 you
know then you plug in wait wait
you protein number and
gun I got a bit confused so Zeeshan
crazy no feedback like you tell me
something that you know or not about
this anyway so what is today's topic
today's topic is going to be bathroom
you say it's number nine number nine is
about programming style and idioms so
how long I've been talking so we wasted
five minutes so okay let's talk about
that
oh the fact I was actually you know to
talk about these fractals it's just go
to my math block this of that thing okay
I forgot what it is so go to math blog
and go to the this page and search for
Mandelbrot set Mandelbrot set explained
no complex number needed okay and let me
just read a little bit because I forgot
what is the I forgot which point is
considered in a set
so anyway this page you can learn about
mando Mandelbrot set you know it looks
like that you can you learn how it is
defined without needing to know complex
numbers
oh okay so I got it so so close that so
so this formula used first of all you
said C equals to zero zero then you plug
in a number to the function you must
always start with zero zero okay so you
you plug in 0 0 to F then it comes out a
number then you repeat you know put that
number in F and come out another number
so you repeat so you got the sequence of
pairs of numbers what do you want to see
is that whether this you know each
number is a point in the plane you know
it because it's a complex number so it's
a pair of numbers pointing up in the
plane so you have a bunch of a sequence
of numbers you want to see if the
sequence numbers escaped you know you
say escape to infinity meaning that they
becomes further further away from
infinity for you see for some value of C
the point will become you know we will
move further further away from the
origin and when that happens you say it
escapes to infinity and when that
happens then then you say this C number
is not in the set okay does that make
sense guys let's just say something guys
wait am I am I am Alive indeed so does
that make sense so if the sequence
numbers use you this function always
start with zero okay so if the sequence
of numbers goes to infinity then you say
you say that the point you know whatever
point is the C is not in the set now if
if this iteration process if it does not
go to infinity then you you say that
this C number whatever number you gave
it cave cave is in the set so the final
result looks like this okay
the final result looks like this is my
Firefox okay so let me track this down
so the final result looks like this all
the plaque are in the set meaning that
all these C values when you when you put
a C value into this formula then you
iterate this function starting with zero
zero all these black areas they do not
escape to infinity so that is the
Mandelbrot set now what's interesting is
that you see all these edges of this set
they are very complex I mean they are
infinitely complex I mean you probably
have seen pictures of fractals in fact
you know they are YouTube videos let me
show you this YouTube video okay so
actually copy that go to a talk show
type talk show today state and course a
new page okay you create a new page then
open it face it that's one of the topic
we talked about today and make a link
and make these whoops
make this L I cut put it here and show
in browser so go down and here is
today's talk show topic that's a bug
okay anyway
so anyways these are crazy crazy says I
don't know so much but I wanna learn so
do you get what I'm saying about the
Mandelbrot set like that because you
know that function that formula is
actually the formula for Mandelbrot set
I don't know what you are doing with
that for Mia but you know maybe the
teacher is trying to pave the way to the
mandible to the factors so Michael says
great explanation by the way I was at
the grave of Stefan Banach Oh
two years ago Wow another great
mathematician I am too dumb to
understand me - good morning jack
so baaaack where is his grave Stephan
Bonnar and yeah I don't know about that
guy you know that guy it just is most
famous for panic paradox which is about
being ACH
ta ra do X which is about like you can
cut if you have a sphere yeah so this is
all about panic toss toss key paradox if
you have a sphere and if you can cut it
into pieces okay you can cut it into
infinitely small pieces then you can
rearrange the pieces so they become two
solid spheres
now the yeah something like that
okay now the math is too advanced I
don't understand it
so anyway that's Banach tusky paradox
that's one of the thing in when you
studied topology okay
bhana talk husky paradox is a theory
means set theoretic geometry which
states the following given a solid solid
pole in three-dimensional space there
exist
a decomposition of the pole into a
finite number of disjoint subsets which
can be put back together in a different
way to yield two identical copies of the
original ball yeah so that's the that's
the thing you know in math you have
quite a few of these paradoxes
I mean counterintuitive but but if you
really study math that is you look at
you look into the truth and they turns
out you notice there are just true
you know similar to our instance
relativity you know like time-space
thing very counterintuitive you know
that's an example counterintuitive in
physics so passage guide good morning
says what are some good opportunities
for entrepreneur these days I would be I
would be the wrong guy to ask that so
what what are the opportunities you know
I got ideas but everyone's got ideas so
I can I can tell you a quick one okay if
you want to be a entrepreneur now that
word is very annoying I believe that was
French or engine entrepreneurs the
[ __ ] you know hard to pronounce you
have to pronounce it the French Way
entrepreneurs
so let's okay let's do random so so so
bathroom you know questions
I know bathroom you wanted to to start
to talk about programming styles so
entrepreneurs okay so etymology linka
Phi wait make a link go to the browser
now we can see the etymology of
entrepreneurs not found okay
entrepreneur not let's
oh that spelled wrong
oh it's correct entry so etymology again
make a link showing browser entrepreneur
so it says manager 18 - 18 28 manager
for promoter of a theatrical production
manager of a motor of a theatrical
production borrowing from French
entrepreneur one who undertakes or
manages yeah okay French or engine there
we have it an entrepreneur yeh quote
show in browser there it is entrepreneur
now let's close that close that close
that now go back to this Wikipedia
liveth where is his face livid livid
Paul polish Polish is the largest city
in western Ukraine Oh Ukraine and the
seventh largest in the country overall
ok Ukraine Ukraine ok like Ukraine is in
Eastern Europe you know kind of like
Russia like I have no idea what is it
like is you know I suppose the culture
is kind of similar to Russia you know so
bathroom you say is entrepreneur is just
a euphemism for someone taking your
money out of your pocket but it's even
legal well no not really
[Laughter]
forgettable just the concept start a
good business oh yeah so entrepreneur
entrepreneur so what's a good idea so
you know first of all I think there are
a lot of opportunities because
technology you know we are entering the
aih you know forget about what Silicon
Valley says are you in Silicon Valley by
the way you know the self
sisqó bay area known for all the
startups like they they are 100 you know
thousands of startups around here each
one you know is got ideas but actually
they just want to make money but they
say they are helping humanity my ass so
anyway entrepreneur so anyway so what's
a good idea I can tell you you know go
to showing browser go to go to tech
review now this is my collection of
articles related to technology roughly
your cake it's hard to cut a categorize
your blogs you know your your essays
written in the past but I kind of I try
to put you know I try to categorize them
so anyway this is this cover from MIT
Technology Review
now it says you promised me mass
colonies instead I got Facebook this is
like few years ago five years ago so I
mean what year is is now I cannot see I
have to like I don't I don't know what
your five years ago but the text is too
small so you know like 30 years ago in
science fiction's in TVs you know people
like we called futurologist
meaning that people who tries to predict
the future
you got AI experts you got computer
scientists experts you got
mathematicians you know you got all the
great scientist or economists you know
you know or academia scholars you know
things like that so that we try to
predict the future what will happen 50
years from now you know 30 years from
now and pretty you know we think that
we're gonna have we are going to have
mass colonies or colonies on the moon or
space travel you know like like the
movie to 2010 2 to 0 0 1 or was it 2 0 1
0 you know that movie that that doesn't
happen you know so all the
predictions are tends to be wrong and we
think we're gonna have AI that has human
intelligence
it's all wrong you know UT and and also
if you study statistically typically the
predictions by specialized experts tends
to all be wrong they are just wrong you
know you look 10 years back 20 years
back they tends to be wrong so you know
so this cover is funny so entrepreneurs
I got some ideas for example okay so the
I have article I got some ideas I can
tell you screenshots tracking watermark
okay there are some interesting things
here like today if you play games if you
do screenshot in war you know war
warcraft if you do a screenshot they
they have encrypted they have like
random you know they have imperceptible
dots that locks locks your ID you know
who you are things like that you know
you can see you know and also it's in
printers so you you know you guys
probably are interested in these so
check this check this article out okay
check it out oh you wanna go here so
paste make a [ __ ] wrong key so make that
and post it here so you wanna check out
that article after the video ok now
listen to my talk ok so you know I think
many of these things will be of interest
to you guys so but but the article I'm
trying to find is on a question of
training program in libraries see we
Cortana okay Google okay those are the
future of AI in my in my opinion anyway
so there
okay so so hold on a second let me read
the comments okay so in case I'm
sticking to my audience
Sabathia says did you hear about the car
production scandal in Germany no the
bosses who betrayed our customers for a
decade do you know what they got no they
got Pony inform of millions of euros for
betraying basically everyone but
themselves
okay what's Pony inform anyway I kind of
guess what you mean corruptions you know
taking money so as long as this is legal
and entrepreneur is nothing but a fraud
to me well I mean that's that's pushing
me that's that's not true you know well
entrepreneur is a general term you know
for you know as today we understand that
it's it's someone who see some idea
innovation or something that changes
Society okay in some way so they
typically start a business yeah usually
it's always a business in a free trade
world in capitalist what you know you
don't have that in communism what so
anyway so I'm trombone is someone a
businessman who have great ideas that is
usually revolutionary I mean very
different doesn't exist so he you start
a business and you try to do to that
introduce that to society
that's entrepreneurial but what you are
saying you are saying is basically some
corrupt corrupted entrepreneur that's
that's what it is
you know corrupted businessman or I mean
car company that's not entrepreneurial
car company is just businessman so what
what you are saying is a bunch of
corrupted corrupted businessmen so did
you know oh not corruption he was legal
they got money from their company's
shares what what do you mean Barney what
is Bonnie bond or something like that
but anyway yeah that but still that's
that's
option that's that's bad bad people
that's evil people that's not you know
that that does not corrupt the word
entrepreneur or if they are entrepreneur
basically is just bad entrepreneur evil
ones where do you get pony for betraying
hundreds of so I don't know what is Pony
pure Oh bonus oh yeah and also that's
very common basically all or you know
big business men you know Google heads
not necessarily but pretty much all big
wise they do a lot corruption and most
of the time you don't even know it until
maybe ten years later or something you
know when got exposed yeah but that's
not you know you just you know for
example there are a lot of bad
programmers for example all the spammers
or the span or the virus virus writers
spammers on a web no they are bad people
you agree right now you don't say oh the
programmers programmers are all
[ __ ] from from today are all
programmers are just you know to me they
are just for kids that doesn't apply you
know so on Trump for now you you you
want to corrupt the world because that's
not your thing because you are not an
entrepreneur so anyway so let me open
yeah you know I'm you know I'm not much
business person and usually I don't like
kind of I don't like them but still they
you know it's just word for in a mosque
yeah I think I Aramis East great guy you
know when people become famous you
always have haters you know you have you
have lots of supporters and you have a
bunch of haters so every time I mention
Ella musk or I mentioned Peter Peter
Jordison then a bunch of guys who say oh
he don't know nothing
he's he did this is bad you know anyways
yeah but you know I mean that's not in
any way so that that's the thing and
also when you become famous even if you
are bad you know very bad person
you also have followers like a lot of
people support you things like that okay
avoid the word what you know avoid
swearing words in the comments you know
although I you know I say that but you
know I put it here just so that people
can see so my case of saying the UNIX
[ __ ] is because well I mean you get
the context it's it's kind of a semi
joke okay you get a context form you
know for my ex you know my expression
and all that it's not serious you know
is it true that all UNIX lovers are
[ __ ] obviously it's not true that's
it's you know and in fact UNIX let me
just say this okay UNIX UNIX the
operating system is a great you know
like it or not is a is part of history
and it's in fact it is true that UNIX
operating system and many ideas from
from the UNIX people they are random
actually they are building blocks of
today's technology tcp/ip for example
even even bash unique UNIX shell you
know it's an image its own yeah and you
know on Linux and also Microsoft is
invading you know Microsoft is embedding
Linux into the operating system so yeah
so it is true that UNIX you know it's
fundamental and and also and also even
technologically some of the UNIX stuff
and ideas are great for example I guess
tcp/ip you can say it is example you
know they I mean
in general although I don't like much of
the their design and UNIX stuff I saw I
frame them a lot but it's not like all
UNIX is bad or you know it's like you
know you get you know it you know hey so
okay let me read the comments quickly
and see what what else so if we want to
go to oak mod okay so let me see let me
get a comments okay so yeah 2001 Space
Oddity oddity that's the movie you know
that's a great movie
you should have five media and should
make some basic idea profitable through
advertising marketing what is that about
so so Volvo LOD good morning valid so
have you tried to manage your knowledge
base using oak mud no and no I I talked
about this a few times in in my past
video videos yeah I talked about this
quite a lot in fact this is a video
there is a video search for Sally you
know such YouTube sorry oak mod versus
HTML I think I you know I talked about
that for one hour so in so in general I
don't use oak mud I try to do it doesn't
work out for me
I use HTML because I've been writing
youth HTML by hand since 1996 or 1997 so
I am so good with HTML so basically HTML
XHTML mod yeah there's another video
that's about saw HTML mod did I do that
I think so yeah yeah the last week or so
there's another video that's dedicated
to saw HTML mod which is what I'm using
so you see all these anyway so you might
you might check that out so I don't use
oak mod like this is a frequently a
frequently asked question you know
people see me and
they because oak mud is very popular you
know people love their a lot fence okay
oh c'mon you know because oak mod is
powerful its text-based you can do
everything you can export to HTML
latech you can you know lots of things
but for me my H me working in HTML is
similar to you
Achmed fans working in augment it just
that the format is different I'm working
directly with HTML so you know I love
people want me to owe you so much but in
my opinion okay my personal bias opinion
I use HTML mod that's more powerful
faster to write anything then you can
move for example yoke mod you can you
type you know as to rig something you
know that's a title something you know
that's a title for me you type something
and you press two keys one two three
three keys you see Home tab return your
three keys I got that if so I would say
so
using h h my own HTML stuff i i code
faster i have more features i have you
know better than home art so it's up to
you you know if you want to use so i
don't actually use augment that much as
far as for oak mod i have a basic
tutorial basic introduction let me show
you so you go to saudi Emacs just such
focus on Emacs my Emacs website you go
to practical Emacs and you scooter
scooter scooter scooter there is a
section on oak mod so you have a basic
introduction of oak mod now in case some
of you don't know oh c'mon okay here's
the introduction basically it's like in
one aspect it's like a market you know
just like markdown so you
can type the special characters to have
heading to have inline code to have code
block block
you know like programming language code
block oh you can have bold italic
underline and you can least you know so
you use this special syntax to do that
now once it's you know once you have
written this you can you can you can
press a few keys you can export it to
HTML to latech or tech or to to quite a
few other formats you know and you can
embed latech or you know math formulas
and things like that
and so that's that's augment basics then
Oak mall Oak mod so it's not so it's not
it so it's a at the most fundamental
level it's a markup system like markdown
okay it's pretty simple pretty simple
you can learn in five minutes but then
there's more I mean there's quite a lot
more so then you see every every syntax
achma typically it has a key binding you
know I got a keyboard shortcut so you
can press a few keys like on the oak
Marquis are very complicated like
control C control something something
you know to create those headings you
know so and also oak mod can be used as
a outline mod so you can for example
this this screenshot is all these are
titles like title like section chapter
chapter sections chatter sections
subsections things like that a tree so
you can show just the order tree you
know the outline you know then you can
expand it then you can move a tree move
move it to a you know subsection or move
it up things like that so that's all
that's you know pi you can there are
keys to do that so here's the basic
tutorial about that headings show/hide
you show/hide sections create new
headings move tree branch move head
yeah so you got a bunch of things you
know all these things that's so that's a
basic tutorial about these features then
let's go back then you can embed
programming language source code like
that so you can embed for example
example in OGG mod you can have a
section you know you you can a bunch of
code blocks that shows e.e Magnus code
Oh Ruby code or Python code or Perl goal
and you know it's supposed like twenty
twenty or so all these languages you
know oak CC purrs first crucial CSS you
know detail dot you know all these
languages then you you can also run the
code and I have similar in HTML okay so
let me show you so I've showed this a
few times for example let's say let's
say over here I show I want a Python
code block so I press a few keys now
look at the left window okay that's my
oh my commands so I show let's say I
want Python okay
type that type Python enter okay I got
this markup then I press a key then I
got the new buffer so I can say print
print three plus five okay I can run it
it says eight okay now close it place it
here showing browser you see I got a
code here then I can syntax color at
showing browser it's now it's syntax
color that's Python code and and I can
do emag lease for example first three
five you know I can run it it says five
at the mini buffer cut three that paste
it here
syntax color showing browser so I got
that's emag B's so I got similar in HTML
so anyway that's so awkward then go back
then you have oak mod can also be used
for to do
this is a funny comics to do that
applies to me you know I am a
procrastinator so you know I tried to
make a to-do I've been trying to do this
for over ten years like 10 20 years you
know and every time it just doesn't work
to do doesn't work for me you know a
scheduled life doesn't work for me okay
I'm a free man
I do wherever whatever you know I don't
follow sketch a doesn't yeah it just
doesn't work like I started to I try to
use oh c'mon
ten years ago you know oh to do yeah I
need to do have to do list you know what
happens so I have a to do that's ten
years old every day I still the same -
that's ten years oh that's that's not
that most of them that's not that what
happened is just like just like if I
never had any to do you know I just do
whatever I wanted to do and those things
I don't want to do but I need to do then
they don't get done so anyway oh oh
c'mon can be used for to do you know
like so you know there are a lot
features so that's my basic introduction
then Omar customization I don't have
that I don't have much here because I
don't really use Oakmont but however I
have coded oke mod extensions for
example for a project for this great guy
who paid for it he hired me to do you
know he was helping me David Pollock
okay he is the creator of the web
framework the most web the most popular
web framework for the language Scala you
know Scala is a functional programming
language on top of java java virtual
machine
so scala so he he created the most
popular web framework for scala
his name is David Pollock so five years
ago he was helping me out so he paid me
do some some some closure project and
also some eMac B's for something he need
or his team needs so I did write a
extension in fog in augment for Oak Park
babble to which is that let me show you
where source code markup yeah so you see
this source code mock-up feature as I
wrote I wrote a package you know
extension so that it will so it supports
a new language a new language called
visi I think it's called this busy CAC
busy you know a new language you know so
I so I spent you know several months
digging into the oak Mart oak mod code
and also there is a professor who had me
do also paid who had me do a passing oak
mod ok so so in this page this page is
very advanced tutorial for emag Lisp
programmers now assuming or you already
know email is well so this is written
for these people email these programmers
who wants to pass old mod why because
oak mod it's a tree right it's a
hierarchy it's a tree so what he wanted
to do is that so you take the tree you
want to rearrange the the branches in
some way for example if if a branch
involves this tag then remove it for
example then you want to export you run
you want to export we write the tree or
the trees into another format you want
to rewrite it into another format called
code this start language this this start
language used by graph V's so that it
can be shown visually
you know like the other connections you
know like good you know like a image
image file so anyway so I wrote that so
that that's that's about this page how
do you use email is to pass Oakmont so
anyway
besides you know so I did some code I
did some coding you know Oakmont stuff
but I actually do not use it so
that'sthat's that's kind of my
introduction of old mod I you know so
let's go back to the comments the
all-important comments let's see so
let's see we have to go back to the
entrepreneur ideas thing because there's
a thing I want to say I've haven't
mentioned that yet Hyperloop yeah I
heard about Hyperloop I know I don't
think it's a scan you know it's it's
your work I mean they are still trying
to work on it you know to me Hyperloop
does not seems a great idea
I mean it's because you dig underground
so that you must a lot walk I mean as
far as I know you know the future is
actually you should go you know you know
go the way of flying cause you know like
like space you know the space is much
more bigger space but however I don't
really know anything about that so so do
you
certain so do not you know bathroom you
do you actually know you know so what
I'm saying is that you know so even I
don't think Hyperloop is a great thing
but I'm not really qualified to judge
because besides computer programming
stuff in mathematics I kind of know a
lot you know like you can call me on
expert programming and computer science
kind of expert but I don't know
mechanical engineering I don't know
chemistry really I don't know physics I
don't know well mechanical engineering I
don't know
picture so you have to you have to be
someone who are kind of familiar you
know someone expert you know they they
are a lot of people you know know it's
that you know you have to be someone
notice how much it takes you know to
would be or something a bridge for
example like I don't know nothing about
it you know how do you how do you be on
a bridge
what's the process you know no I don't
know so that's that's about you know
those things so you have to be someone
you know who actually know kind kind of
this stuff then he would be able to make
you know he would his opinion would be
valuable so if you ask me I don't think
Hyperloop is is a great idea right
because I think you know space is not
much larger you you know you should have
more airplanes or flying cars you know
but you know so but I'm not qualified
that's that's why I don't I say that so
you know because and also there are a
lot of YouTube videos right we go watch
YouTube there are a lot of YouTube
videos about Hyperloop and and like
everyone is like they like they are just
yeah they are just idiots okay they
don't did they are not qualified to
comment on it but however they tell you
you know they they do they tell you you
know the Hyperloop oh this is no good oh
that is good oh yeah history in nineteen
eighteen hundred we had that in that
fair and and then you know yeah but but
what what what is there you know what is
their qualification do you did you did
you ever be on a bridge no that's that's
my view okay that's my point of view so
passive guy you never finished your
train of thought from the side you food
or poured up yes about the I'm well I'm
gonna get back on that this this this
page this page I'm gonna talk about that
just a little bit you know so but let me
finish the comments to see what
we have what yeah check this window why
don't we make it like that I happy you
see I have Auto click on that's why
that's why you constantly see as if I
you know don't know how to click so I
need to magnify this you know getting
old Aramis do you know Hyperloop ok so
that's about that
so his train of thought drives hundred
tracks at the same please cover some
usage of oak Maud yeah you know so I
give a intro I hope that's yeah I don't
really use augment that much so yeah
donate me 500 and then ask him to
discuss something something in a way you
prefer yeah that's a good good idea
well yeah seriously you know for the
money in my pocket then then if 500 you
know they are people now and rarely once
a year you know once every two years
there are people who give me that like
500 well you know like like two years
ago there's a guy who gave me $3,000
okay this haven't happened why you know
did you know this don't happen okay
don't think you know you know this
happened like 10 years yeah what once
you want something yes okay anyway three
years ago although I say two years ago
there's a guy who gave me three thousand
dollars one thousand dollars a month so
I'm grateful to that guy
now I'm not sure he he wanted to be
public I don't think he Minds you know
but usually there's this issue like when
people donate to you I don't know if
they want you know some some sometimes
they don't want to be public you know
they keep you know that you know
sometimes they don't mind
and and sometimes often people do want
it to be public that because that's how
usually donation works you know the top
donors they want their name you know
they they want to be known but anyway so
three years ago I think so this is -
2017 I think or was it 16 so since you
know someone gave me three thousand
dollars so we and well I did something
for him you know he for for three months
he has I have a ad on my website
pointing to his his page you know he's
got a project so if you check out my
site frequently you might have no
anyways so yeah so but what I'm saying
is that you know if you pay me you know
a few hundred dollars you know that's
like a you know I can do something for
you either right right you know cause
some Emacs packages or I can teach you
for example one-on-one eMac this for
example in one week you will be master
of a Magnus you know truly one hour a
day one hour day in one week you will be
your beat you learning by yourself for
half a year you know you know something
I know like some other things like oh if
you do not know programming at all you
can I can teach you for example Python
goal and you know JavaScript yeah also
JavaScript is a big thing you know from
the ground up yeah
so if you donate you know you can put to
my patreon or PayPal and send me an
email you know you know you know my
email address sorry at gmail.com or saw
at solid oak anyway
we are we talk about idioms today
actually it's kind of late now
well it's 15 it's maybe not idioms yeah
so you should say early okay well I mean
you guys say that early but we started
to talk about something you should when
when that happens you should say no I
got and you know you wanted hear about
idioms
but Pithom you says Bethenny says any
high school student from basically
physics no knowledge can calculate that
you literally have to be insane to allow
something like Hyperloop I'm not sure
about that because well the thing is
first of all Ellen musk okay he's not
idiot okay I mean he's not a dummy you
know so so let's assume okay you you are
right let's assume Hyperloop is justly
just totally won't work now the question
is now why why is Ellen Musk doing that
for one thing you know we can randomly
we can guess maybe he's you know evil
you know he's actually he know this
won't work but he's actually trying to
do this so that he get a lot money and
he's just going to eat the money is that
what do you think you know like you like
then you know we can start to think
about what's going on exactly is that is
that what you think so animus you know
the first random guesses Elemis is the
evil guy he know Hyperloop here any any
high school student would know with
physics knowledge would know I believe
warm walk but however he's doing it so
maybe he's June you know just trying to
cheat money okay that's one thing and
what what are the other possibilities
okay maybe he okay maybe he's just
misguided okay yeah he's smart guy but
you know but you know smart guys to make
mistakes throughout
you know maybe he just he deeply
believes Hyperloop who work but actually
everyone knows you know everyone who
knows physics it's just not going to
work so but but he's misguided just like
Richard Stallman okay you really want to
have a two Hyperloop is that what you
think so that's another case right so we
are trying to analyze you know about the
Hyperloop whether it's like you know you
know you you know good or not so what
what what is he okay so okay so maybe he
just you know he's smart guy but he made
a mistake he this is the wrong thing you
know so if this is true if this is the
case then what do you think about it
well I guess he's just too bad you know
what kami he's not cheating money right
suppose he's not yeah I mean he honestly
believed it he get people to investigate
and eventually he probably won't walk so
other investors money and including his
own it's probably gonna gun great wasted
well at least there's still some
benefits such as you know once you do
this you learn something engineering you
know you learn from mistakes then you
have documentation why it won't work
then you know so that's what I think you
know you have to think logically
scientifically analyzed and I don't
believe you know I don't believe you
know the typical you know YouTube or
whatever also have a loop doesn't work
no I don't believe that you know the
reason he's to it I don't know the thing
so but I think we will see okay I don't
know it's gonna be good or not but I
don't believe it won't work or something
like that because most most of those
people are commenting on these things
they don't have they are not credible
so Elemis you know he's also trying to
send people to Mars you know he's doing
kind of lot of things and and I looked
into this guy
so my judgment of him is that he's not a
bad person I
actually I trust him you know you know
he's billionaire so a lot of people and
I are typically you don't trust I don't
trust any rich people you know like for
example a lot of people hate Microsoft
especially you UNIX guys you need UNIX
people UNIX lovers free software
foundation lovers open-source lovers you
or hate hate is the proper word is the
most appropriate word
you all hate Microsoft anything
Microsoft you think it should die okay
you you will do all you can to kill
Microsoft that's a lot of you are I know
okay so anyway so allow do you hate
Microsoft and also hate Bo gates okay Bo
gates I don't I don't hate Microsoft but
however typically I don't trust the
billionaires you know I don't I don't
trust I don't think they are good person
you usually okay generally speaking I
don't trust billionaires I don't trust
they are good person also I don't trust
whatever they say typically like
typically when you have a lot of money
you can write books and a lot of people
will say oh oh yeah this is quicker you
know like Bo gate has published books
you know he he's doing a philanthropy
you know this or that a lot of money and
he says you know he's giving out his or
his money when he died you know he's
already giving out a lot paying with I
don't trust PDAs okay and I but I don't
hate Microsoft I do not think to me I do
not think Bo gate is any what was then
any any of the big corporate heads such
as some micro system so Google or
Facebook okay in fact I'm pretty sure
Bill Gates is far better a person than
the Facebook Mark Zuckerberg [ __ ]
okay so anyway Bill Gates so but however
I don't you know i don't you know i
don't hate microsoft but i do not think
i don't i do not think he's actually
what whatever his opinion
Society on the future of humanity
humanism how how to make society better
i I don't I don't trust you no I do not
think he is qualified for that at all
you know so and supposed to ella musk
for example so bo gates I think he's you
know I think he's okay person okay
justjust okay not not a bad person he
said it is better than a lot of these
all your companies you know a lot of
other people he's a better person in my
opinion they know they know all those
then they know Facebook Mark Zuckerberg
[ __ ] and Bill Gates is better than
the Twitter CEO Jack something [ __ ]
that treated CEO Jack something he is a
[ __ ] of humanity seriously speaking
he said you know the [ __ ] is a
traumatic word so let's let's put it in
a more proper word so it's more serious
so I think he's a the traitor CEO Jack
something he's a bad person okay he's a
evil how do you what is the proper
description you know not not good person
you know morally morally corrupt I would
say okay same same thing for the Mark
Zuckerberg who created Facebook so about
Bill Gates I don't think he's I think
he's just okay person and so so you know
he's only what he sees he's just good
he's very good at business that that is
it he's a great entrepreneur yes because
he he began the Microsoft the powerhouse
you know the enterprise you know back
then this is 1989 or something you know
there's not much personal computing he
began yet that's how we have it today
otherwise without him without Steve Jobs
we may not have personal computers like
today you
to realize that that's what
entrepreneurs role in society that's
what they do you know once you are in
like what not now we are in the comfort
of our you know your iPhone your phone
oh yeah I talk to people talk to your
mom in ink across the world you know
where's that from
Steve Jobs you have to thank Steve Jobs
for that okay that's you know and well
for today you can buy a PC like we are
doing PC you know that you know
computing you Linux you know learning on
the PC you have who do you thank you you
you thank bo gates okay Bo gate gates
created the personal computing
Enterprise okay hey should I thank Thank
You Bo gates for that now if you want
you talk about Linux software well you
think Nina's travels in and Richard
Stallman of course you know so all these
people well my opinion you know on them
is this or that but anyways you know
they dig they did things to society so
anyway so what where was I talking about
so yeah Bill Gates so you know Bo gate
is you know he wrote books about huge
future of humanity about how he think
how he think we how how we can improve
society I think that's that's [ __ ]
because I do not attribute anything I do
not think he knows about that at all and
similarly many Nobel Prize Nobel Prize
winners like physics or something
something typically once they won Nobel
there everyone is like oh you know this
guy you know we must you know whatever
he says [ __ ] whatever [ __ ] he says
everyone is like oh oh you you know you
have to buy it with his book that's
stupid okay
no my advice if he won award in physics
then he knows physics that there is it
anything he says about society about
humanity about morality is he is not
qualified okay for example I
you know like today I said on Twitter
everywhere everything everyone is
[ __ ] quoting are instant like oh the
imagination is more important than then
then genius or something like that you
know five [ __ ] idiots okay I
understand what he is he good for he is
good in physics that is it he don't know
nothing [ __ ] anything else he says he's
unqualified okay he has no power no
credit you know no no no foundation but
whatever he's he says about physics then
pay attention that is where he is good
at so that is how I think that you know
that is how I think about these these
famous people how I judge so let me
continue the comments
okay so I don't know what's going so
let's magnify found out useful
documentation same as you do by the
possibility to execute the code literate
programming yeah that's kind of like
literal programming in OGG mod Micah
says watch polished movie teddy bear to
understand Hyperloop and other stuff
okay
did you know that the first Hyperloop is
about ten years ago
I I think I saw that you know YouTube
they talked about that similar things
it's great investment it makes a huge
amount of money or see it requires a lot
of money and you cannot really price it
okay
Micro says I use markdown for smaller
notes and for more serious writing just
growth oh that's old school I use Acme
text editor oh wow really
and so no per game with fancy formats
Wow Acme Acme is from plan night you
know the UNIX philosophy people mio cats
haven't seen you for a long time eh hey
good morning male cats meow cats milk
milk hats is elusive you know like you
never want to show you a face or talk to
me yeah get on you know you
let's do YouTube have man I mean not
YouTube I mean video have email me I
forgot your email me Oh cat says how
fast do you type on typeracer oh I did
demo that we could do that again but
today is like already what 1 1 hour
maybe we do that at the end basically my
typing speed the the highest I have is
about 90 word per minute okay 90 what
per minute but now with our practice you
know usually it's like 70 you know like
if I just go there now 70 it would be it
so bowl ad says it's impressive how much
you got in HTML thank you
a better music okay so so let's see
comments
good morning Deon Thunderfoot so
Thunderfoot is a famous youtuber and he
is good for debunking that's what that's
what he does typically debunking but he
he's got an accent so some kind of
British accident an accent okay it's
almost like he's got a speech impediment
oh yeah I find it hard to listen to him
Thunderfoot so anyway so he does you
know debunking and stuff usually it's
good I would say
so did he do a Hyperloop did he do what
our Hyperloop yeah professional chemist
and he know physics yes and I must never
build a bridge neither so he apparently
is a stupid no he's not stupid
yeah you know you know wait so you know
yeah
what's your patron oh wow what's my
patron now I gotta show that thank you
thank you
past passage guide so of course where do
people donate to me so that is in let's
see if it's it's on this page
oh yeah patron so here so if you write
to thank you guys now I haven't so I'm
making right now
dollars a month so thank you all guys on
patreon
I know actually login regularly you know
I don't login regularly so sometimes I
got questions on patreon that's my fault
actually so you know like some people
want to ask me a question like that they
patron me but you know so I should check
patreon more more often so anyway that's
my patreon
so let's go back to the comments so
okay so back tell me about the Ella musk
well I don't know yeah
he just believes that if he is
scientific status quo is true if he was
with a static non-indian talking about
why startup sucks yes I hate Microsoft
because they try to destroy Linux not
now they have now they are well I did
are you talking about now or before now
they are embracing Linux in fact Linux
is gonna be a subsystem in Microsoft
Windows and in perhaps that you that we
are even cure more Linux but that's you
know irrelevant because Linux you don't
have desktop users in the first place
why because Linux sucks donkey ass in
every way and that I also blame blame
the Linux you know the UNIX [ __ ]
that is they are doing their own doing
you know why today after you know now
it's 30 years why we do not have a Linux
desktop that actually works because the
Linux people they have not they did they
also idiotic in so many ways I talked
about this quite a few times now usually
it's about social but also technical
because they just don't know how to do
things they are the technicals they are
extreme nerds they do not know they have
no like they they are truly idiots like
they are some savants when it comes to
design things users you know for lack of
words user interface when it comes to
user interface this Linux type of people
they have no idea like zero what is good
what is bad like zero knowledge about it
but however they think they know hundred
percent they think that's a problem they
all think they know hundred percent
about how GUI should be
so the and a lot problems and so they
may create things as unusable then also
also social problems they fight with
each other you know the window managers
you have one one hundred thousand window
managers you have 1 billion Linux
distros why I mean on the surface we are
all share we are hook for good humanity
but the Linux [ __ ] 100 distros does
not work
ok let's destroy the Linux thing that's
[ __ ] destroying everything so many
problems ok that it's not getting into
Linux soso Linux after 30 years you
still have almost zero Oh like almost
zero desktop users your mom cannot just
use it ok you know the the only person
who can use Linux desktop are the notes
just like you guys mean you ok
you have to spend one hour to to do
research Oh hard disk or partition Oh
[ __ ] [ __ ] hardest partition oh go
up whatever and oh oh our clinics go up
go to our clinics website spend eight
hours to see you know which is the
proper answer [ __ ] Linux let's that's
the daily user experience of Linux and
not just that you know I'm gonna talk
100 hours about Linux every technical
detail I can show you I can show you I
have tons of articles and today and also
the problem part of the problem is the
UNIX is the open source ideology because
nowhere why why are there so many Linux
distros because each one is very selfish
you know they cannot make money but
however then what what they can I do
they can try to become famous because
becoming famous is one way is an
indirect way to make money you know any
anyone you know you they are you two are
just selfish you know you you want your
thing to become popular that is why you
have 100 distros and each one [ __ ]
touching each other's eyes out you
happens in their community all day you
know if they fight all day oh you are
[ __ ] you are [ __ ] you know we're
gonna [ __ ] you and things like that
happens every day between
any distribution between open to be
between the gloom desktop creators you
know they fight for issues lots of
issues you know throughout the history
of Linux you know [ __ ] the open source
[ __ ] free software from foundation in
fact the UNIX philosophy idiots that's
what happens yeah yeah that's what
happens then Microsoft no not today
Microsoft is the number one open source
contributor and they bought github and
now they include Linux what you gonna do
so what do I want I want I want you know
I want good companies I want you know
software I can trust we thought you know
the open-source [ __ ] I can you know so
suppose there is a company Google let's
say Google whatever they do I can just
trust it this is true 20 years ago I can
trust it like I just use that I trusted
they want me to pay okay I pay it you
know III know they are not going to sell
my stuff they are now going to have back
doors to FBI or whatever they are not
going to do anything bad you know it's
just a software you know you just use it
and you pay okay
$10 a month okay you pay that's that's
what I want okay I can trust or you know
all the good people are good you know if
you have a software you like to share
then you share yeah I mean so open
source and free software it's not bad by
itself okay but but it has become bad
become an ideology and also all these
good things that's that's what you guys
want as well right you you know every
day you're talking about distributed
system encryption you know because why
because you do not like the Facebook
[ __ ] Facebook the Twitter [ __ ]
you know the Microsoft [ __ ] you know
all these companies doing their things
that's what you don't want you know
whether it's encrypted or not that's
secondary what you really concern is
about nobody take you know nobody goes
you know nobody knows when did you [ __ ]
your wife you know they do privacy
things that's that's that's the real
thing you are concerned you know if
everyone in the world is good people you
know they do not do evil then you
worry about any of these you don't need
you don't need concretion
why do you need encryption you don't
need it nobody is doing good bad to you
you know oh we we are all living in
peace you know in harmony but that's not
going to happen because human you know
real practical human stuff you know
that's which is not what the open source
of whistle fear foundation or communism
is is trying to sell that's you know
because doesn't walk okay sorry about
that that's that's that that just became
another serious rent you know usually
yeah I don't I don't really want to you
know like you know like my video
typically I'm fairly controlled you know
like what I mean is that you see as I
talked about before this one or talk
about schizoid I'm not a I'm not a
mosquito a personality type okay meaning
that I don't have much emotions so I
mean although you see me rent
sometimes like going crazy but actually
that's under control it's not like oh
you know you thought you know it's not
like I cannot control I do that because
I you know because I've been doing this
a few times I know you guys you know a
lot of you seeing it don't don't mind
and also also that's that is a an
opinion a frustration I want to talk
about you know about this open source
about free software foundation about you
know the UNIX philosophy I want to talk
about I want to show my opinions you
know and I I have been banned in my
opinion roamed by all these people you
know in the past 20 years you know
because back then you know in in 1998
okay for about five years I was a
dedicated fan or fanatic of Richard
Stallman you know and I was the did
delegate fan of you know free software
foundation
opposed to the open source and the Linux
I want Linux to succeed you know it
would be great I don't want I don't want
to use [ __ ] Apple because Apple is
doing turns of evil things and very
expensive you know whatever Apple is
like twice three times expensive than
all the others I don't so I don't want
Apple I don't want Microsoft Microsoft
you know too although I don't hate
Microsoft compared to all the big
companies but Co they you know you know
they are not they two things you know
they they get your you know they collect
your information they do they do things
I don't want so I want Linux I like
Linux because Linux at least you know
this few you know it's led by Lena's toe
vote he you know it's and it's open
source and in generally speaking there
is no there is not going to be FBI back
toes okay oh it's gonna be hard it's not
gonna gonna be you know some background
process that that that you know logs
what you do every day and send it send
it back to Microsoft or whatever there
is no such thing and and when you want
to like Microsoft and Apple you you have
options to turn turn those off like you
can
oh I don't want to use CV I don't want
to use wait what's the name the CV and
you know ok Google Siri and Cortana
yeah Cortana is this beautiful kannada
is this Microsoft's AI you know so there
are options in Microsoft or windows of
Google you can turn it off but they are
they are intentionally made to be so so
very convoluted and confusing because if
you don't want anything sent back to
Microsoft you have to go to website to
check ok what do you have to do then you
have to go here and do there and click
that click that and even if you do all
that that's not 100%
Pete they still do some you know send
your to send your data back to Microsoft
things like that I don't want that on
Linux I can trust I can trust you know I
don't have to go through these however
what why am i hating hating Linux
because then when you lose Linux you've
got problems everywhere else
I mean you this trust issue is soft okay
it's great you know I can trust it but
then every time the window doesn't show
up correctly then you got this X Windows
[ __ ] you got this window managers this
business that [ __ ] [ __ ] Linux you spend
every day I spent one hour just to deal
with the Linux thing on the Mac I don't
have to like it's so it's very kind of
strange on the Mac you you buy it you
just use it I do not find a problem I do
not find out but I need this to be found
size to be bigger but I cannot do it and
how do you suck I don't have any of
those problems you just just what just
works on Windows these kind of problems
happens sometimes you know so Windows is
so Mac is much better than Windows but
Windows is 10 times better than Linux on
Linux [ __ ] you know the font size that
is nice is the old doesn't work why it
doesn't work because lots of problem
because first of all the UNIX philosophy
idiots they cannot design anything
that's for GUI they cannot digit they
just cannot they their brain doesn't
work that way
that's one thing then you have the open
source free software foundation
phonetics ideology that that that kind
of make things doesn't work because then
you know the open source fight with each
other you know you don't get coherence
each one you know create their own
standards you know depending on what
what distribution of your Linux you are
using how to find out how many memory
depends on you know whether this command
or that in different shelves each distro
uses different shells different software
manage management you know system the
[ __ ]
yeah so that's another event so you know
I I just wanted to express those ideas
you know and I've been doing this for a
while but it's not repetition because
every time I try to talk something new
Leo Kardos says I imagine I mean you are
swearing okay
Dion Brieger says Lena Nunez already got
gets tons of money pumped into it
especially if you consider the main
hours of professional programmers yeah
but they you know it's got problems you
know you you know wouldn't it be great
you know imagine Linux is the free I
mean like no money you don't have to pay
you know if you have a free but why is
why is your mom not using it it should
be it's supposed to be everyone you know
it's supposed to be Microsoft would be
dead ten years ago because this is the
thought impact in 2000 year 2000 we are
thinking Microsoft is going to be dead
ten years you know after today that's
year 2000 now I don't know if you are
there you know but it didn't happen
instead Microsoft is 10 times more
powerful in fact it's going have Linux
inside Microsoft Windows you know that's
what all these are problems of Linux
okay so if you are still if you are I
know many of you are open-source fan or
free software of I think you know think
about these things people been trying to
do this we know we've been there for 20
years I mean a lot of you probably
thinking oh but if we oh we are you know
we are going to start this new thing
that will solve the problem we've been
doing that for 20 years okay thirty
years if you count the beginning of
youth Linux it's not working so I think
actually I think that's it for today so
that's our and eighty mean you know
that's eighty minutes talk so okay so
any comments questions if you want ask
me questions type it you know type my
name like the
like the bathroom you like the orange
okay type my name then I'll answer that
questions otherwise we shut down in you
know and let's say five minutes oh
actually I need to so that was milk and
I think that milk went bad so I need to
so let me get drink let me get a drink
okay I need to get my juice I'll be
right back in one minute
[Music]
cup today's juice apple grape apple and
grape juice 100% juice no sugar okay
sugar is bad for you don't don't drink
any sugared water then then this is this
is energy drink
sweet juice it's not now it's like 1/3
of my calories came from juice so
passage guy says you never answer the
question oh yeah so so much digression
and about the question of what what's an
idea of entrepreneur I mean what's an
idea I don't actually have idea so but I
do have some thought this one let me
show you technology for knowledge in
past 2 decades so I was going to talk
about this article this is some thought
I had ok about when I was younger let's
say 30 years ago 30 years ago ok there
are 4 things I wanted and some of them
has happened but a few of them has not
happened 1 encyclopedia at your
fingertip find out any factual info in a
manner of minutes this we have today
Wikipedia literally in minutes you
basically find out anything - a word of
photos of any face on demand that is
view collections of photos of any place
on earth this we also have today Google
Google Google Earth Google Maps and
Google Street View so you guys probably
know that right I don't need to show so
you go to Google Maps you came any big
city ok since some country you don't
have photos so if for example if I want
to look at New York if I want to look at
let's say Europe London I don't know
I've never been to London if I want to
you know let's say Moscow Russia Moscow
so I just go to the map right away I can
find hundreds you know thousands of
photos of Moscow on the street in fact I
can like I can I can like travel I can
walk on the street you know as if I'm
walking on the street and look at all
but you know that we also have a world
of photos of any place on earth then a
virtual 3d model of any building in the
world
now this we do not have in particular in
particular great by audience such as
famous architectures cathedrals castles
temples or even skyscrapers whole city
okay so in sci-fi movies so you know is
we we don't have this we have a little
bit of it for example this is this is
Google Earth like on Google Earth on
some places you can they they have a 3d
model but it's it's this is not good
they only have a sketch you know just
like outline of what it looks like but
what I want what what I imagine is like
a real it's almost like a virtual
reality 3d building like like in video
games okay where you can look from the
outside but you can also go inside you
know and and look at the church or
Cathedral from the inside you can almost
walk in every corridor inside the church
or building or skyscraper okay so that
we do not have you know okay once in a
while we have that for one building you
know but they are ten you know hundred
thousand great buildings around the
world we don't have that what I want is
any building like almost the let's say
the top 100 thousand buildings or places
you have a 3d model like like a 3d video
game where you can look from outside
indeed they are very detailed and you
can also go inside so passage guide
that's an entrepreneur idea so are you
up to it you know you you you you know
so you talk to you know you go to you
talk to all these architects you talk to
you talk to the CAD developers you know
or the 3d blender for example you know
and you go talk to Google and you know
you maybe maybe you start a business so
you get you create that
demands okay so that's one of the
thought that has not happened today okay
so one last thing any video including
film TV program ever recorded at your
fingertip on demand okay that's another
thing I want that has not happened
okay so passage guy this is another
great idea I think this one is more more
valuable more more I walk about then
then the 3d building idea so you want
you know like we have Olympics right we
have Olympics let's say 40 years ago
let's say nineteen nineteen sixties
Olympics but suppose I want to watch I
want to watch table tennis of Olympics
back in 1960s I want to watch it I can't
there is no I mean where do I see it no
there's no there's no such in fact you
may be possibly you go to the library
well in USA libraries are pretty good
elsewhere is maybe not so good but
anyway you you you know I want to watch
your Olympics of particular year let's
say I want to watch fencing or
particular sports you can't but it's
recorded on TV you know oh I want to
watch any let's say I want to watch a
1980s TV opera let's say there's one
called
another world Dallas okay let's say
Dallas there's a very popular soap opera
TV show called Dallas very popular in
1980s I want to watch that you can't
well you can you can go to Amazon and
buy DVDs I think I think anyway the
point is I want to be able to when you
know any any video that has been bought
casted in the past I want them to be
available on demand just like a library
you know just like today's you know
Netflix or something you know you press
the button I want to watch this and you
pay so passage guide I think that is
actually more valid idea but but however
but another thing is the thing is many
of these entrepreneur ideas the the
ultimate question is is that what people
want you know if people want it then you
have a market if nobody wanted then then
it's hard okay then you you know you
don't make money and you you know you
it's hard it's hard to do so are there a
lot people who would like to watch any
show you know any video we ever
broadcasted I don't think there are many
you know like people who cares about all
Olympics in 1960 nobody care except
researchers or scholars or historians
academics yeah we you know like we maybe
we are interested but the vast majority
majority of people you know they don't
care they they don't want they don't
want even if it's free they don't care
they don't want it so you know and same
same thing for the 3d model of any
building in a world do they want it no
they don't care you know the O'Day one
care is maybe play some games they don't
care about the actual buildings around
the world you know they don't give a
[ __ ] why would they care you know that's
the thing so when you talking about
entrepreneur I mean we are in triple new
world II usually it's about things that
people may want you know kind of like
that so that's that's just my idea
okay Andrey Andrey is here
hey I talked about that I don't know
nothing about it I don't know why you
keep saying it I mean so yeah so entry
what way are you interested in that I
mean you keep repeating that in my past
three days you know you could keep
coming in and tell me to make a video
about this p5 sound Dargis what's uh
what woody what is the issue I mean what
do you want
so is that an advertisement you think
that's you know that's that's not
advertisement just to say that in my
channel because most my followers that's
actually going to destroy whatever so
and Ju no I don't know what what you
want so I'm gonna finish reading some of
the comments and that's it for today you
never answer the question okay I did now
Bato says you say that list markers are
useless when you have pattern matching
but there are cases where having access
to all the language facilities allows
you to express things otherwise
impossible yes I agree I mean there are
some uses I'd certainly agree
Bato says as in this macros are harder
to use but you can do more with them
than just with Mathematica no I don't
agree on that
panda matching is absolutely a far more
a superset release Marcos so if release
Marcos is one pattern matching is twenty
you know as far as power in stuff panama
jean is absolutely in absolute sense
this is not metaphorical or whatever in
absolute mathematical sense pattern
matching is a superset of this Marco's
to say it's a superset is an
understatement because list Marcos is
is is a tiny fraction of pattern
matching it's just you know I can I can
like right now I can write I can explain
in five minutes
panda matching that you know the what
you know least Marco in terms Panama
gene so para matching is just you know
technical super set of lease Marcos this
Marco's is useless well not not useless
okay there are some use okay because
it's a little bit pattern matching and
also remember this is symbolic pattern
matching we are talking talking about
this is critical because pattern
matching in Haskell you know camo and
other languages those are not symbolic
there is a major difference distinction
pattern matching in list Marco I mean
panda matching in mathematica it's
symbolic panda matching which is what
list Marco is this Marco is basically
symbolic pattern matching in a very
limited form okay okay that's about you
know so you have seen my videos right I
have a one hour video on that you have
seen that right so that I think that's
it for today so Dion says maybe you
should do a video about Hannah matching
I did you yes I did I've mentioned this
a few times go to such okay let me show
it then that's it that's it for today
okay guys then that's it for today
because I think I covered all questions
okay so you go to you go to such folks
YouTube sorry okay
then go through my exodia YouTube then
go to videos then search for Mathematica
you know it's very annoying that YouTube
do not show the whole title so I cannot
search for Mathematica but but if you go
to youtube and
use a search box okay such sorry
Mathematica pattern-matching okay there
you have seen this video right but I you
know some of my videos I consider great
I mean good and it's good because like
today is mostly random chat rent but
some of them I do technical stuff I you
know I think they see this one is pretty
good and also this one this too
okay so this one is about Panama in
mathematical terms rewriting pattern
matching and idiocy of this Marco's okay
the last part is kind of click bait okay
and this this one also good this syntax
s expression meta expression
mathematical meaning of sugar syntax
that's also good these two are like over
one hour and they are focused technical
okay that's it for today so thank you
guys thank you thank you guys all for
coming by
okay so so DeYoung we have you know I
don't know about that I have to look
into okay good bye guys thank you guys
yeah I'm gonna close down okay subscribe
you know subscribe donate thank you for
the your support and you know by
keyboard for my website and stuff bye