hello guys welcome to another episode of
Star Talk Show today we are going to
code emacs lisp nothing but emac lisp
okay so emac this we are going to write
a
HTML or XML validator
so let me show you my keyboard first
this is glove 80. if you search for
Sardi keyboard you will find my review
and the video review fantastic this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard version 2. I
also have a review and I use ottoman
hacking as my keyboard macro and I also
and another keyboard I like to recommend
is Xpose okay so these are three of the
great keyboard okay so why don't I show
you for a minute
keyboard blog so you just go to search
for keyboard blog and you can go to
ergonomic keyboards and you can see here
is Club 80. Kinesis is also great
Kinesis and and then there is exposed
night I highly recommend this okay and
here is Ultimate hacking keyboard
okay I don't know if you missed it so
that's my keyboard
okay and and now
yeah so let's go to let's start to code
emac Beast so this is gonna be purely
technical for those of you uh into emac
Beast coding okay hello Huang hello co
so on the pink window you can see all my
command course and the keystrokes I'm
using soft light keys
I'm using soft light Keys you uh it's
which is a key binding system efficient
key binding model
system for emacs so you can
go there and use it so you don't have to
press Ctrl keys or meta and uh I'm also
using over and keyboard layout okay so
anyway let's begin the
um coding emac this so so uh so what
we're gonna do so we're gonna write a uh
HTML or XML validator so let me explain
okay so let's start a new page okay so
I'm using HTML mods so we add a template
so this is what HTML looks like so let
me uh clean it up so this is a sample
file XML so let's uh name it XX HTML
let's just start
so uh wait there's already exist name it
XXX dot HTML okay
so go to the directory so here's the
file open it so this is a sample file
we're gonna validate so what does you
know we are going to simply not a
complete
HTML validate data but rather we check
the well-formedness so meaning that
every
um tag for example here's HTML check
that tag matches there's no missing end
tag you know technically in HTML5 sum up
the tag
uh do not need to be closed for example
we add a paragraph here so technically
in
HTML5 you do not need the closing tag
for the P tag but that's not what we
want in XML you always need a closing
tag
or for example there is the BR tag
in and in XML any tag if it ends with a
slash then that is self-closing so you
don't so you don't need
I mean there is no closing tag for br
similarly for HR
so but in HTML or HTML5 you don't you
know you can you know you can just do
that so how do you know if a tag needs a
closing tag or not actually you don't
know you have to go by the semantic spec
so in other words there's no syntactical
way to tell if a tag needs to be close
or not in HTML but however in XML every
tag needs to be close you know it needs
to be closed or it can be self-closing
syntactically just by having a slash
there
so that's a that's a situation so we're
gonna write a command to validate to
make sure that you know we don't have a
mismatch tag or something like that you
know reverse order or uh or something
like for example
uh let's see
something a b okay so we can we can have
a paragraph here
I mean paragraph in the boat so for
example showing browser
so that's how it looks like so a is bold
but however sometimes you can have uh
let's say
okay so for example if you move the
closing B to here then that's invalid
okay showing browser it's invalid Okay
so
we are going to write a validator just
to check every tag is matched okay
so let me also mention HTML
um so if you go to kasari
I have a HTML tutorial and there is one
page about self-closing tags so these
tags in HTML they are special they don't
have very close intact they are
self-closing uh
but in HTML you don't have such a thing
you always go by syntax so HTML I mean
XML so XML is a very much Superior
technology
because you don't have to go you know
because you can syntactically
uh
verify where the attack needs to be a
closed or not
okay so anyway so let's go back to so
let's uh so let's just write a
uh some
so let's just validate a simple page
like this you know we are going to start
to write a program for this okay happy
cross close so let's put a link here
any questions about you know what I'm
coding doing emacs things ask me okay so
so here's today's talk show page so we
are going to start to write a program
okay a new buffer uh
a new buffer let's save it as XX dot e l
okay
just for now and now let's put a comment
date
uh
write a valid uh validator
for XML
to check where formedness
okay that's all we're gonna do so let's
check the uh if he
okay
focus on emac this today that's the
topic Okay so
so how do we gonna write it so let me
explain so I I I don't actually have an
experience writing a parcel but in our
case this is a very simple one you don't
need
um
to go elaborate in writing a puzzle you
know with the password Theory all you
need is some kind of text processing
okay that's what that's what we are
going to do so let me show you at the
top level
how do you do it
okay so for each opening and closing tag
you can think of it as parenthesis so
you have situation like that nested
parenthesis for example uh let me also
show the
uh
let me also show the
show the example HTML file so
so you have nested parentheses like that
or you have sequential uh parentheses
like that so you can imagine each
opening parenthesis correspond to the
opening tag and closing parenthesis is a
closing tag so you have two situations
either one either you know they are just
nested or they are sequential okay it's
sequential for example like that
so we have to so what we are going to do
is write the code so that we take you
know each of the tag is delimited by
this less than equal sign and greater in
equal sign angle brackets so we can just
consider each of the angle bracket as
deliminator you know the start point and
between them we grab
the text we grab it then
we can put it into a list or vector you
know a sequence of things then we can
you know if the first item is a opening
paren for example opening tag then we
check the next item if the next item is
a closing paren then they cancel each
out you know you can just remove them
because they are valid you know they are
well formed
so but if the next one is not closing
then you go to the next one
you know then you you keep doing this
keep checking until you find a closing
one when you find a closing one it
cancels out
okay what what so so what about the text
in between for example this you know
this title in that case that would be
something like something you know
something here uh you know
uh
something here so those texts in between
you can
actually just ignore them
uh yeah you can kind of for example if
you have some text here
technically it's actually valid you know
so you can actually you can ignore them
except you cannot have the text at the
beginning you know that would be I think
that would that is invaded technically
in XML anyway so anyway so that's what
we that's the outline okay
so yeah so let's start to write the code
let's go to the emac base so let's
um
okay this is this this video is gonna be
uh one hour I'm not going to rush
and I'm going I'm doing this live I
haven't coded this before but I do have
some experience so we think our we will
have probably something okay
so are you using any protein to write
HTML seems that you are wrapping text in
tag of course I talked about this many
times I'm using PSI HTML mod okay so
um
so you know you just saw emacs so you
just go to my Excel emacs website I want
to show it because this is my stuff
important
um you know I moved to sally.info no
longer in
urbanemax.org so you know you you'll
find it Max tutorial you go to the home
page table of contents then you have uh
XA emacs packages so I'm using HTML mod
so that's why you can that's why you see
uh you know I demonstrated
I demonstrated it many times okay HTML
mod here so you can see a lot of
features okay so it was free for like 10
years but now you know you pay to pay me
if you like my stuff pay me I'll send it
to you okay so HTML mod is what I'm
using
you can for example you can for example
you can delete for example I press a
button look at the pink window you'll
see the camera press the button you see
the head tag is good by pair you see one
here one here or I can press a button to
select
this tag you know I can press this
button you know Select Title press again
select the
the tag above it together and press it
again to select more and press it again
you'll include the whole head you know
like like so and first again the whole
HTML you know so let's saw HTML mod
okay pay me if you like it pay me to get
it
okay back to writing the valid data okay
so so yeah so I'm gonna just go slow and
explain things in in about hour we
should be able to do it I need to do
faster Okay so
oh
so so first of all
age tag
must I'm typing too slow must have a
closing tag
have a opening tag and a closing tag
okay
except
if the tag
ends in slash that
then it is a self closing okay
in XML
we're gonna assume is XML because X XML
is more the more uh simple and
well-formed syntax much more Superior
than HTML or HTML5 HTML5 is is is no
good
Okay so
and so for for my pages you know I have
written uh
after 20 years I have like 6 000
manually HTML articles in HTML and they
you know I keep them
I keep the XML syntax in mind so all my
pages
all my pages are
uh
all my pages are valid XML in theory so
we'll find out once we write the
validator we can apply it to all files
in your directory you know thousands of
files and tell me if I'm missing
something
Okay so
so here is the explanation except if the
tag ends in that so okay so opening tag
closing tag self closing tag okay now
let's explain the next one
uh
tag sequence occur in two ways
one is nested
like so
okay and uh
the other situation is sequential
I'm also using SAR emac this mod so you
can see this parade matches that the in
the end but I can delete them both by
pressing this key so you see so this is
the example of sequential
tax
algorithm
I'm typing too slow today and I haven't
warmed up
so so there are many ways to do it so
one way is you just grab the whole file
the text and split them into a list okay
so you got sequence of items then you
can uh you can just
um check them you know so
so algorithm outline but I'm not sure
that's the way we're gonna do it because
if you do it that way then you don't
have so once you find a mismatching tag
you don't have the position typically
when you find that error you need you
want to know the position where it
occurs so you can show a curse on this
line so you can go to it and fix it
but if you grab the whole text and split
into a list then that way when you find
the error you have no idea where where
it is so
so if you do it that way that can still
tell you if the file is valid or not but
you wouldn't know
where is the error unless you then you
start to search for um anyway so but
this way is very simple okay so
algorithm let me just explain
I mean let me just let's just let's just
go through okay instead of talking uh
keep talking
so um algorithm online so
one way
is to
grab whole file
split into a list
then process each item
so that's one way another way is let me
show you okay another way is you don't
you don't grab the whole file you just
start at the beginning of file then you
search for
the
angle brackets so once you find it you
can push it to a stack then you search
for another angle bracket then you push
it to a stack and once you have
something in your stack you start to
match to see if you know if you have an
opening one if the next one is closing
one if so then they cancel out remove
them from the stack if the next one is
opening one again then you push the then
you push again until you find a closing
one once you find the closing one you
remove the pair from the stack so you
continue until the whole file until you
find for example
you start to find a closing tag
where there's no opening before
um
yeah that that that's when there's an
error then when that happens you know
because your Cruiser is right at that
position position you can just report it
we found the arrow so which way do we so
but this way is more
um
more kind of complicated because you
have to move the cruiser
but I think this is the better way
because the other way if you just grab
the whole thing and split into a list
yeah there's no way to know which
position it is
yeah but that way is simpler though okay
so let's try the
let's try the text processing you know
move the clues away because
because that's likely what we want okay
so we may not be able to finish this if
not you know we'll continue maybe
another day or I'll finish offline but
I'll you know so you but however you get
the basic idea how emac this works okay
so
Okay so
let's write down the second way
open the file first then
move closer
to beginning
then
then search for the next occurrence of
angle
bracket
then grab
then grab it
it is a tag maybe opening
may be opening tag or closing
put
it onto stack
continue
okay
then once you have more than one thing
on the stack you start to check you know
anyway so that's that's the that's this
okay so
we're gonna do this okay so first of all
we're gonna start to write a function
that just checked the buffer okay
once you check the current buffer so we
start to write a function or command
that simply try to validate the current
buffer okay so this so This example uh
once we have that done then we can
trivially modify the code so that it
takes a file as input
you know then then we can use that to
check all the files in a directory so
for the first one is to write a function
that that just um
check the current buffer
with the Assumption the buffer
um the buffer does not even needs to be
a file yeah because we are all we are
doing is checking the syntax okay so
this command will call will be named
validate
HTML XML okay let's just say let's say
XML
because it's technically more correct
what we are doing
okay validate HTML XML so dark stream
let's just give today's date
okay
uh okay so let's start to write it
validate H valid date H uh XML buffer
okay
so that's a full name so let's start to
write it so so the foot so of course
first of all go to the
go to the buffer beginning
go uh go to char buff point point mean
okay point mean Returns the cruiser
position for the beginning of the buffer
typically it's one unless you have
narrow to region when you have narrowed
to region
uh then it doesn't see you know you see
just part of the buffer but actually
there's more so the when in that case
the beginning of the buffer is not one
okay so now widen
okay so that's why you have to call
point mean because it returns you know
the the current
the topmost Cruiser position okay so go
to chart point mean then search forward
you know I'm just coding it fast you
know because when you are doing a video
the best thing is just just to stop keep
coding then maybe after you have
something rewrited offline otherwise
I'll be stuck in you know thinking and
no activity so search for what search
forward so actually we want regular
expression search forward because we
want to search both either either the
you know the
opening angle bracket will close so
research forward that that is search for
by regular expression okay so we want to
search either that or that
okay so uh yeah
okay so optional bound no we don't care
about no error uh
bound we don't care Neo no Arrow
okay no error true we don't so no error
means if if it's not found what you're
gonna do so if no error is true
then just ignore it if not it's if it's
not found that's okay don't do anything
but if no arrow is near
then
if it's not found you'll stop the
program you'll say cannot find it okay
so we we want it true true no error
so search for forward will actually move
the cruiser to um so let's go back so
let's go so move the cruiser to the
beginning search forward so there is one
occurrence right there okay so
so we need to keep track the position so
let's have xp1 xp2
that's position one position two
variable
so
so remember we need to make this into a
loop
um so there's a lot to code we have to
think about
um there's a lot to code
uh okay so what we uh we're gonna do it
so let me show you let's let's
put this over here so that
we can see
and uh that's over here we
look at the code
okay so documentation
uh okay so
so we begin here so we once found it we
what we're gonna do
um
and so God
Cody the start of coding the most
difficult thing about coding is that you
are going to do something yourself from
scratch you know typically there's
already some code on GitHub so you
modify you read you modify that's much
easier but if you need to do something
from scratch yourself that's more
difficult that's the that's the actually
the skill you want to master to be a
coder you know if you call yourself a
coder you should be able you must be
able to write some project from scratch
that's what really coding means not from
you know GitHub open source modify
somebody else
so okay so yeah we I need to think so
so you find it then you find it you're
gonna keep finding the you know you're
gonna keep finding the delimiters so
so this needs to be a loop right so it
needs to continue it needs through your
Loop so
so you so you need you you I need some
kind of loop structure but what is the
thing inside the loop I mean what is one
single step so one single step is you
you start at a position Mark that
position then you find the next angle
bracket
okay then you grab the text in between
okay then you push that
that's a tag okay it may it may be a
closing tag or opening tag so you got a
tag for example this one opening tag for
title or closing tag so once you got a
tag you push it to the stack
okay so we have to uh have a variable
stack
uh so X
stack you know I X stack my naming
convention is every local variable start
with x
so that way it's highlighted it's insa
emac be smart that
makes it easier to see variable is
actually the most important variables
and functions most important for syntax
highlighting not
usually not the other things the most
important thing is you want to
easily see the variables and functions
okay
so vast majority of syntax coloring is
actually not optimal in you know many
editors on that anyway so so we need a
stack as a variable that so the stack is
going to be a list okay so uh at least
is starting with empty this okay mtdc is
written that way or just Neo okay so you
so again the steps are
um let's let's write it
okay the current position
find the next angle bracket
position then
grab text in between
that's one tag
push it to stack okay that's basically
that's the thing
that's the algorithm so
so okay so
so the current position okay so let's
set XP one point point is a Returns the
position of the current Cruiser location
okay so set 0.1 then search forward
for
yeah we assume
wait do we use you know do we assume the
beginning is already opening no because
sometimes you may have a space in uh in
front of a file so
or sometimes even common okay but I mean
the first character is not a angle
bracket okay so we cannot assume we
begin with the angle bracket okay so
actually so this is wrong there
so go to the beginning then we search
for angle bracket okay
no error true okay then we
we mark it
you know we we say that as the first
point okay
and uh
then search forward again
then set xp2
at the uh in the current position okay
so that's kind of so this part is one
unit right I think so
so then we need to grab the text in
between so how do you do that you use uh
purpose of string no properties Okay so
xp1
xp2
so you'll give it a name
so that name will be X tag okay
so
so X tag is a variable okay
and uh then
so we what we do is set X tag
should be
that okay that's a text in between
cool thank you very smart can you escape
you can also Escape closing tag yes
uh that student I just talked about that
in the bi and stuff
head oxide and chat uh hello what we
working on okay you can read you know so
we are writing so you guys are late so I
I need to push on so we are writing a
XML value data okay
so we so this is one unit of code we
need to make them into a loop repeat
this process so again
we search for what so we start at the
beginning of the buffer we search
forward for angle bracket then we Mark
that point xp1 position
then we search for the next so let's see
so we found it and we search for the
next
oh okay so what happens what what but
what if you have
um you know something
bad like that
Okay so
if you so here is a problem you see this
file right now is invalid
okay so let's see how we're gonna
validate this file so we you know we go
to the beginning we search for angle
bracket we found it
then we search for another angle bracket
we found it we pushed to stack but that
already is invalid
it's already invalid so when you search
for a
so okay so
so when you search for the first angle
bracket you that needs to be
the left angle bracket because otherwise
you will be invalid okay
so
so we already need to start to check
here
so we need to check so once you search
you'll move the cruiser to that
character
to whatever text you searched so you
need to make sure that character is the
opening one
okay over here
so
so you can do uh what you can do is uh
there is there so you want to grab the
current character
okay I don't remember what command that
is so let's look at let's go to
practical emac this my website and uh
text editing uh Mark and region get
buffer string
there it is get buffer string from
region from selection from current get
current chart there chart before that's
what we want okay
so chart before Returns the
an integer that represents the character
right before the Cruiser okay in e-max
Cruiser is actually between characters
the position Okay so
so chart before
chart before
so chart before Returns the current
chart so you so that Returns the integer
the code point of the unit code of the
character that Returns the integer so
you want to make sure that is equals to
the
the left angle bracket so
so you can use equal to check let's see
equal three three true okay so you can
use EQ to check equality of integers
okay
so you can put that there
and what is the integer for the
character
that so
that would be 60 so you can see here so
you can
you can write 6C here
okay
and another Syntax for a character is
question mark that that's actually you
know question mark that that's another
Syntax for you can see in the mini
buffer it says 6C okay
so that's the same tax so in emacs
there's no character type okay there's
no data type for a character however a
character is represented as integer so
when you have an integer it may
represent the integer or a character
depends
so emacs has a way so when you want to
compare character you can say compare it
to 60 because 60 represent the
left bracket angle bracket or you can
use this syntax this syntax is more
intuitive you know question mark
character so
if
that
then do nothing new otherwise error
arrow and before the position Okay so
error found
and
and position
okay
a position point
okay so we already starting to do some
validation there we can try it on this
file
okay so search forward if
that character is not that okay we
already found the error then
because otherwise uh otherwise so
if it's that then set the point
otherwise error okay then search forward
again
okay
this time we need to compare to the
right angle bracket
so
if it matches
set xp2
otherwise Arrow okay
so then grab the tag okay so here is the
code and shrink it a bit so this is
actually valid code already let's run it
so now emacs knows this command so we
can actually
doing it on this buffer so let's try it
meta X
avier did XML buffer let's try please
make it work do it
Arrow found at position three fantastic
can you see it the mini buffer at the
bottom
so let's show the message buffer you see
fantastic now now
you see if we uh let's let's type some
random character here
so okay so now let's run it again
XML buffer Arrow found in position 10
you see before it was position three now
it's position ten so it
already
um
that's one progress
so next
so okay so we know this code is a Lube
I mean this is a unit of code that that
so since it's a unit why don't we make
it a p i o g n so that's one unit
you know one one great advantage of this
lisp language is that
you can represent semantic unit
correspond to syntactical units so this
is like one unit of code instead of like
C or Java where they count lines of code
because it's hard there's no syntactical
the limit
delimiter for a semantic unit but in
this typically you can
so anyway so this block is one unit so
we need to repeat this block block
Okay so
so we push it to a stack okay so that's
one thing so
this needs to be a loop
so how do we uh how do we do a loop well
the condition of the loop is that
once you fail to find
uh angle bracket that's the end of the
loop okay because you can keep going
keep going until you fail to find the
angle bracket
or
when you have some error you you know
exit the program like like we did okay
so the whole thing will be a loop a
while loop yeah
so let's write while
okay when I Loop the condition
and the body okay so the condition will
be actually this
okay let's put it here that's a
search for word if it's found your
return true okay when it's not found
your return Neo so
so this is the while loop okay then we
can put the whole thing inside here
okay
so right now it's a code here is our
code
here's our complete code let's let's try
to compact it
do I make sense everything good
okay
now we evaluate let's just run it
evaluate it go back to here now let's
call it
Minix validate do it it will find a
position 10 fantastic okay now if we
remove this Arrow
call it again do it
you see the cursor went to the bottom
and nothing is done
which is exactly right that's what we
that's that's the code we have we we
haven't actually start to
check the
mismatching of the tag yet that that
needs to be done with the stack okay
so once you have this step okay so let's
let's so once you have this step
um
again
you search for uh okay let's not repeat
the thing uh what's the next thing
you see we need to start to validate to
check the
tag
oh yeah we need to push it to stack did
we push it to stack yet no no so what
you have to say is push
X tag to
um yeah
push extract to the X stack
stack right yeah so this part will also
be part of the code here
push it to stack now
okay that's one unit of code the next
thing we need to check the stack
so because so now you see
before the stack is empty now we just
push one item to the stack
we'll need start to check it when the
start when the stack is more than one
item okay let me think about it
uh I just here I have XML related issue
I was never able to solve how can I make
scheme validation for Android XML files
on Android
it does not seem to be a skin file that
can be referenced in an idea
no I don't know I don't know anything
about Android okay
so you have to you know
Focus uh don't we have any emac these
people 10 people watching okay so focus
on emac Beast so if you have questions
especially relevant to what we are doing
today
you know if you some you have you have
some simple emac these questions I can
answer quickly I'll do okay
today is just focused on iMac lives
coding so we so we now we need to so
Stacks okay so we pushed
so far we pushed one element such as
this to the stack
okay let's let's let's do this okay so
now we print
stack okay so that's a whole code doing
it go over here run it do it fantastic
so this is what this is uh what's this
is what a stack looks like
oh so the print needs to be outside the
loop okay
so
yeah so print stack evaluated go back
here close that
okay this is sample file blender code do
it go to the message buffer
okay so here is our stack open a new
buffer
make it each line by a line
split by space so this is what a stack
looks like
okay so the bottom one is the first one
so it doesn't look good because
uh because you see it's missing it's
missing the opening bracket
oh yeah that I know why because
because when we
when we search for the left one
we need to
when we push it actually we need to push
it
you know when when emacs search for the
file
it actually moves the cursor to it to
the right of it so
yeah so when if you um you know so if
you are searching for the
angle bracket
you know you're fine the cruiser will
end up here you know you start from the
beginning when you search for it
with this code the cruiser will end up
here
so
so now when you try to push the point to
xp1
you know
that's over there that's not over here
so you need to so here you need to minus
one
uh does that just uh
so I believe there's a decrement
yeah so one minus is the
function name okay
yeah so let's run a code go back here
let's go and so uh close this one close
this one close this one close time one
uh
go back here this is our sample file
metax code
go to the messages buffer copy it new
buffer then make them into each line so
here is
better but still wrong
so you can see the first one is X
okay so this is correct okay so so
that's the first tag we found fantastic
fantastic can you see tag tag second tag
third tag then this tag
then this
um then title
so this way we actually ignored all the
text in between because we don't see
them in a stack
okay so but
um
so this is also one tag
yeah so
so far
seems so good okay
uh so you can see this is a this this
tag is a self-closing tag this one is
opening tag this one is opening tag this
one is self-closing tag
this one is self-closing tag okay
I I should have a
slash there
and this one is opening time closing tag
okay
so
here is what we need to do once you have
more than one item on the stack you'll
start to you need to check it
again the algorithm is that if
so suppose you have two
items on the stack
if the first one is opening one you
check for the second item
if it's closing then they cancel out
remove them both
but if it's opening again
then you
try to get the next one okay
so how do we incorporate that into the
code
um
so we need some kind of some code
through check stack here
okay so some code to check stack huh
is tedious let me get my copy
you know I'm tempted just go to Ram to
start to ramble on other things because
that's fun and easy but but now we need
to focus on this for this video okay
some coffee
voice check video check yeah
that's right that's a good um good point
that one says don't add tags like meta
into the stack that's true
so in other words don't add self-closing
tags
so once you find the tag you can check
if they are self-closing or not
so if it's self closing ignore it good
point so let's let's work on that
because that's one step forward
um so we write a different
is self closing okay let's just say that
okay so given a string
let's just say tag stream okay
okay so one argument so
so
this function will just take a string
and
return true if that's a self-closing tag
okay
so how do you how do you uh so you need
to so for example
so for example
this is a self-closing tag meta okay so
what you do is you
you check if it ends with that okay then
it's self-closing okay so how do you
check so you you need to grab the string
substring okay
if something
string equal okay
then substring
uh actually we can just say
if that equals to
okay then
tag stream
so substring of text string from
form two so from negative two
I believe that's it okay let's check
ABCD okay run it
returns CD Returns the last two
character so that's the right syntax
okay
so now
if that equals through that then return
true okay otherwise return
other Rock rise let's say return Neo for
now okay
so we have this code
okay we don't need that actually so this
very simple code
okay
fantastic
so now we can call the code here
okay if
if it's if it's self closing
do nothing else
push to stack fantastic
okay evaluate the whole buffer go back
here close this
try on this buffer call it do it
fantastic go to the message buffer so we
got that open new paste then now we want
to
replace that by
that okay make them into line so
fantastic
so now you see one of the one of the
self-closing tag is gone
because before we had
you see this line is gone
it's not here now this line actually
they need to be you know that
you know they need you know I should
have that so this this is a minor detail
I mean this is the detail we have to
work out
you know
because in HTML5
you don't need that but and it's still
valid however in XML you need to have
that so in my code I don't have it
that's actually a mistake so that's a
good find you know so in fact I need to
go to all my
all my files
and start to add you know do a find
replace globally start to add the
backslash over this meta so by the way
this meta viewport thing that's
non-standard tag
you know it
meta viewport with
device with initial screen scale that's
non-standard tag from Apple Apple's
iPhone
it began around 2008 or so it's
non-standard okay so that's just
something Apple did so that's very
annoying
so but anyway I should add that
um that okay so anyway so that's
that's one thing but also
also by the way eventually this code
cannot rely
on the syntax because vast majority of
HTML files on the web they are HTML5
and even so that's majority like 99 of
them are invalid okay so they have four
of arrows you know if you're gonna
validate them they light up like
Christmas tree full like that that's a
scum situation of the coding industry
meanwhile we have the you know lispers
scheme you know the rust people Golan
Haskell they are saying oh wow our
language is great because this feature
because memory or because functional but
they but but their website if you go
check is invalid HTML that's an insult
to the face
okay the the coding industry you know
let's say Haskell and rust okay they are
kind of different camp and these people
too you know they they are saying our
language is great the fanaticism
everywhere or even python you know
finances everywhere but the most simple
thing about HTML validation
their home page is all invalid you can
check right now here because I did it
over the past 20 years every few years I
you know including the w3c website
10 years ago invalid HTML you know
imagine the organization that specified
the HTML specification their home page
most of their pages are invalid
including the RFC the Unix phonetics IFC
Pages invalid HTML you know I have like
I have um
tens of articles about it
let me just digress a little bit okay I
will go back to the coding okay
okay HTML validation Okay so here's one
article but you go to actually you go to
webtech history so all these Tech these
articles about 20 of them
are about HTML webtech history
the story of XML you know the and the
invalid you know Google promote invaded
HTML and uh
even the W3 HTML value data is invalid
in some cases
you know I have details so you know this
is done in the past 20 you know these
articles uh past 20 years so the web
industry the coding industry is kind of
a fast
meanwhile you hear these leaders you
know the hack on Hacker News typically
or famous coders you know they are
saying singing songs so we I wrote I
wrote rust because I think this way but
joke okay
nobody knows nobody knows they promoted
a lot of promotion and this or that but
the fundamental basic people forgot
because
this was important all the Nerds now
remember you see you see this you see
this w3s
C HTML 4.0 check mark badge in the 1990s
and early 2000s that badge is everywhere
promoted by nerds by the Unix
Tech notes by the Unix phonetics this
batch but now it's forgotten like the
Next Generation had you know
a lot of story okay let's go back to um
let's go back to coding this okay
so yeah so so that's a you know this is
a detailed point we eventually we I can
you know eventually this code for
validating XML or HTML
cannot rely on this syntactic or this
HTML syntax to indicate where the tag is
self-closing but rather you have to get
the you have to find the head of the tag
the tag name
then
verify according to
to um
and did I already close it
Saudi package okay
search for Sally
self closing tag okay
now now they don't show my page
self closing tag Okay so
okay Sally HTML tutorial
yeah
it shows my resume my resume is like 10
years old on my website
I haven't updated
um
oh my God they don't they don't they
don't show they don't show my um
stuff let's say JavaScript tutorial
that should show yeah okay because
that's more popular so you go to
JavaScript tutorial then you go to HTML
then you go to this page self-closing
tax
So eventually the code actually just
needs to check the tag name so these are
the official
set of self-closing tags so if they
match that means this uh the tag is
self-closing
eventually okay
uh but why don't we write it now because
we we have to write it but we haven't
got the general structure down yet
yeah so all we have to do is modify this
code so
so another thing we need is to get the
tag name okay so let's write it
so
get tag name okay
so this function will return the tab
name
okay so how do you do it you
um
you
use uh so given a tag
you want to return the tag name for
example meta so you want to find
um well how do you do that
okay so if yeah so I know what to do
so let's copy the code here
if
substream
if substream
0 to 1.
let's see form two yeah okay so string
index start at zero so zero to one
is equals to opening tag
wait they already always equals to open
intact so so so we want to the second
tag
so one two two so one two two
so the second tag if it equals through
that that means it's a closing tag
then
you want to find
okay but so if it's not you basically
you need to find you you need to search
for space
uh but actually some tag don't have
space in them
yeah okay so good tag name actually
I have written that before so let's look
for that code
uh
so let's go to search HTML mod okay so
this is HTML mod and search for attack
name
because I have written this
yeah so I also have written this before
yeah I have written this before so this
code
side HTML tag self closing tag this
actually check a list of self closing
tags so if you search for you know so
here is a list of self-closing tags here
Okay so
so this function is great that solves
our problem okay so
so actually let's copy the name here
maybe we want to use that okay
um then
what we want is we want to get the tag
name okay so
uh yeah so Search for Attack name let's
see if there's a function that
I'm pretty sure I have it somewhere get
tag type
okay get tag type
no
so this is my HTML mod that's right now
it's
5600 lines so now this whole line is
containing different so we get the list
of functions Now search for
tag name
go to closing tag and comment tag open
tag true get tag name there it is
open it
okay so here is the function that
get tag name let's see
okay so this function only you accept
tag begin
we need a function that also accept the
ending tag
oh
so this function actually takes a
position as input not a string
that can work too actually that's more
efficient because instead of grabbing it
and the
anyway so let's see
so this function gets a tag name
tag begin okay tag to begin the cruiser
must be on the left of a opening angle
bracket
okay and it can be opening or closing
tag okay so that's fantastic
so this function takes a cruiser
position
and The crucial position is presumably
to be on the left of a
of the attack begin it may be a open
interact like that
oh it may be like that a closing tag in
either case it must the cruiser must be
on the left of a opening angle bracket
okay
so when when that's the case you'll
return the tag name
okay so let's use this code okay now
close it close it
go go back to our code
so here is the code get tag name
uh and uh
okay I you know
oh we already coded for our
yeah okay let's finish this part so
let's see what you guys are seeing
so uh so get tag name
so get tag name we
is self closing tag no
uh
where are we so we push to stack
and now the get tag name why do we need
the tag name
uh
let's look up this one oh yeah because
the self closing requires a tag name
yeah because if we want to
call this function it requires a tag
name okay
so anyway so this is one thing to write
we need to write now let and you know
right now we have this function that
checks whether tag itself closing
syntactically that can that works too
let's go back to the overall structure
overall let's maybe we can
make some progress there
so we push to stack uh we we actually
really need to start to check the stack
because so far we don't have much
validation going on at all
let's just code Okay so
so stack here is uh what Stacks looks
like so you take
this is the the bottom
okay so you
you take
so
God
so one stack has more than one item you
can start to check out
okay so okay now I know
so when we start to check the validation
you know the like a matching parents
the the first thing you you need to know
is like we said here you need to know if
the current tag is opening or closed
that's the most important
you need to know it's opening or close
Okay so let's have a let's get the
function to do that we need to know if
that
is opening or closed because without
knowing that you can you can start to
match that you know so
again
go to site HTML mod
then
open the source code
these the functions then search for
closing
okay
okay there that's the function we want
so open intact p p means predicate it
means this function returns true or
false okay
so this function will tell us that the
tag is opening tag or not
okay this function is pretty short too
it just check characters
it just check the second character if
the second character contains the slash
it's a closing
okay so we need to use this function
okay
okay copy it let's go back go back go
back
yeah so
somewhere here
okay we being over
50 uh 70 minutes already
so let's see what you guys are saying
don't add tags like beta okay do you
don't like green tea I like green tea
because how do you validate your text
now from the stack
right we have to I mean we haven't done
anything about that yet that's what we
are trying to do so the next step is to
know if the contact is opening or not
so
X says you are over complicating this
way too much just read like
read uh like at a time
first check for the opening then then
closing
one is missing then save line number is
zeros
[Laughter]
this x guy it's very easy to say things
try to code it show me show me show me
you know I haven't so far I've been
looking for it I haven't found one
better data
that you can download and use
I haven't found one open source those
ones you know you can go to 8w3
validator those some of them you know
they have a source code but that's ten
thousand lines and they don't they they
you know they HTML is extremely complex
okay they validate lots of things
you know but what I really want is a
simple
syntactical Checker okay I don't want
the complicated
anyway you download those tools then you
have to compile it in order to compile
it you need to download 10 000 other
libraries you know
that's the situation because HTML is is
completely up
so X is saying oh you're doing too
complicated you can do it this way right
one right one right one the health
uh could we use XML past region
you know emacs
you know so right now we are doing this
from scratch we are writing the code
ourselves but emacs does have
a very good X XML
validator okay by by this XML expert so
but however the code is fairly complex
okay so you are suggesting
Andrew is suggesting this XML past
region I haven't you know I I looked
into a little bit okay so this one
xml.el is written by this guy that's not
the guy the one you want is
um let me show you the ones you want to
you know if I'm gonna use the building
thing
the one I want to use is let's search
for
x uh nxml mod okay
so look for a XML mod go to the source
code go to the top
gems clock okay James Clark is one of
the top expert on XML he wrote the C
passer very fast C parcel for XML valid
you know including that also validates
and he also is he's a big fan of free
software Foundation he also wrote this
XML
axml mod
he also wrote the previous one XML mod
so this this is the best XXX uh
XML validator as you type you know you
don't have to run a camera as you type
for example I can show you for example
let's go to my emacs blog showing
browser you see emacs blog now I go to
the directory search for XML so this
file is my atom the RSS feed you know
that's an atom
protocol which is XML so when you open
it it's in this nxml mod you can see at
the bottom and you can see it says valid
now if I type something
you know if I type something like that
you see it says invalid it validates as
you type so this so this is so this is
this written by this James Clark guy a
top expert in XML in C and in emac this
as well
but most people you know you you go
around emacs communities almost nobody
knows because they
you know they they got corrupted they
focused on the latest you know whatever
you know
anyway
so this code
it's you know this file is two thousand
five hundred lines but actually it's a
lot more because they've been the glue
emacs people has been splitted into you
know separate different libraries it was
it was 10 000 lines of code this nxml
mod 10 000 lines of code Okay so
so one way to write a validator the way
I want it is to use the existing code
but
actually I think for my purposes this is
gonna be more involved so that means I'm
gonna spend days days and days to
understand this code enabled in order to
use it meanwhile
uh meanwhile wait and do meanwhile if I
want to write what I want to do
you know today I can finish it in one
day you are reasonable you know not as
elaborate you know
his code this axml is actually real
XML valid data but you know
yeah but if I want to use that code I
have to spend much more time to study it
and I need to modify it because
HTML5 is not XML vast majority of web
pages they are in HTML5 they are you
know XML is kind of dead
you know supposedly there's a version of
X HTML5 you know called xhtml5 that's
kind of
but but basically
XML is died okay so you don't code XML
anymore
so anyway for my purposes I want a
syntactical
validator that check you know well from
this it would take me much more time
I would say 5 or 10 times more time
to use the existing code
and I also need to modify it for
practical HTML you see that's a that's a
problem
so that that's why I haven't you know I
haven't really looked into
um
the existing code and and this one is
XML written by so let's see let's you
know I think that's it for today I
cannot finish it we made some progress
you know we made some progress anyway so
this XML past region passed the region
from begin to end in buffer return XML
past three to raise an error if the
region does not contain well formed XL
that's fantastic
maybe thank you maybe that that's
maybe you know that's it
uh
um yeah but usually I have my doubts
because usually they they become
elaborate
that's a good uh suggestion though yeah
so I can look into that
you know so it's interesting let's see
if the nxml
actually use any code in this XML
password I don't think so you see now
let's go to a directory
yeah so they are in different
directories so they are separate
projects entirely so if you search for
that in the nxml directory to see if
they used it let's see so search for
that I don't think so okay search for
that no you see so they are totally
separate
so if I want to use building code now
there's another question that require
research which one you're gonna use a
lot a lot of time to study to look into
okay maybe I think that's it for today
great suggestion that when
Andrew
and do it yourself code is more often
exactly because when I write my own I
have you know very tight control I know
exactly every word you know I know
exactly what I want uh and I can do it
you know because I've been coding emac
this for over 10 years
simple you know
is it possible to solve online problem
in emacs yes it's coming up okay emacs
29 I've heard emacs29 actually solved
that problem almost or 99 of it okay so
wait for emacs 29.
I think it's you know almost uh there's
already better you can use okay that's
it for today
do you use AI to help your code no I'm
not the type in also I don't think it
will help that much
that's a big topic okay because you'll
hear a lot of people oh AI is uh you
know programming taking over programming
you you are not going to have a job
anymore that's false that's false
AI with AI code we'll
in fact
require more programmers so as a
programmer if you are a programmer you
will have more jobs now even more
you know AI is not reading of
programming jobs AI is reading of other
jobs meanwhile for programming
it's not and anyway okay that's it for
today thank you guys for watching donate
okay donate to me go to my website you
can you know it is some you know go to
my website you can buy my complete emacs
lisp and emacs tutorial you know or
so you can't have you know fast
reference immediate you know access uh
download reference emac this practical
emac this it might be examples uh and uh
you know buy my emacs tutorial or buy my
emacs packages you know like the whole
thing we did today is oh my oh my code
basically these days I don't use any
other almost almost
like you can see my email directory
there's almost no
uh no
um
no packages let's see Alpha
Apple script actually I don't need
buying Keys uh actually I don't need or
camo mod I need Haskell mod I need
actually I don't because I don't code
them mark down mod okay to wreck is okay
mob you know and use package I don't use
so anyway I don't use like none of these
I use
I haven't been using them for several
months so I don't use at these days I
don't use none of the
packages
uh because I've been you know coding
emacs to these for over 15 years
okay so buy my stuff donate or you can
patreon me Amazon gift card PayPal okay
thank you guys for watching bye guys
next video is I think
let's see Monday Tuesday maybe in two
days or so I'm starting I'm going to
start to do more
live stream regularly okay so and I'm
going to start to code wolf and language
again
uh
and they might do a political
comment commentate you know comment on
politics
um on my
Odyssey
so check you know look for my Twitter if
you haven't yet follow me on my Twitter
okay or join my Discord
okay bye