come on everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's show today's 2019
October 26 Saturday noon San Francisco
time and I need to fix my video this got
the black bar they're super annoying
this minute details of Technology you
keep dealing with it and okay is six 640
by 48 by okay so this one go away yes
this one move it down here and good
morning guys Matt so greetings so many
people here thank you for coming by and
we have a lot topics we need to talk we
need to talk about things and I'm five
minutes late sorry about that and okay
so let's begin to begin the talk okay so
let's begin let's go to let's open that
spit open go here close and split open
saw talk show so the topics are let's
see the topics are eight wait so the
topics are eight nine eight nine
seventeen eight nine seventeen and a
nine seventeen the fourth topic in
description in four okay so let's let's
get some separation okay
sorry for the introduction
and okay go to the chat go to live you
know by default is always topped chat so
let's go to night and paste it okay so
eight nine seventeen so okay let's make
a list so eight topic number eight is
JavaScript loop for each with break and
now is programming language syntactic
and semantic differences of math
function now these two topics are
related we're going to talk about that
and topic number seventeen seventeen is
none technical and fantastic language
barrier may be a greatest thing since
sliced bread
everything is since sliced bread okay
that's the way you talk okay so that's
topic number nine topics seventeen could
do that too that show in browser so
those are the primary topics so Kathy
says talk about Raspberry Pi 3 plus
Mathematica she would be interested okay
Mathematica so but is installing
Mathematica so let's begin with that
part is installing Mathematica for Z
Tron crazy
where is each on crazy so so let's see
we're installing Mathematica with yeah
so so if you use Mathematica great
raspberry three if you get raspberry it
comes with raspberry and I need to put
my sponsors today's sponsor is you go to
Saudi website then you go to programming
then you go to programming language to
tell tutorials then you go to
Mathematica and on this page at the
bottom is raspberry
hi link to Amazon you buy okay you go
there buy it that I get few dollar one
dollar something like that 50 cents
Raspberry Pi this is $80 so I get like
50 cents oh my god the condition I mean
so wolfram mathematica language you you
buy Mathematica you know you buy
Raspberry Pi
it comes with Mathematica bundle of
course you can only use it on Raspberry
Pi Raspberry Pi is pretty slow so you
know it's kind of kind of you know it's
the marketing scheme you you can explore
the language that's great but if you
cannot use Mathematica for real you
started to do a lot of computations then
you then you need to go buy it so
Mathematica so what is installed so but
is already in so up and running
fantastic bad part you're gonna show me
some fantastic fantastic things you've
done with Mathematica okay and actually
I can do some tutorials with that so so
let me read the comments quickly okay
and we're gonna talk about the things
we're gonna talk about eight nine seven
eight nine seven eight nine can can take
20 minutes and 17 is another free 17 is
a free roaming topic that can go home
forever
so let's see what the comments so what
do you know about what do I know about a
strong astronomy Co calculations I don't
know nothing about it I took to
astronomy classes spec when I was in
Community College Foothill College over
here you can actually they have a
website you know every college has a
website today
so for Fujio Community College I took
two astronomy classes you know
introduction there is solar systems one
is solar systems the other is more
general the hardy co-ed
there's a there's an end but anyway it's
not just about solar system it's about
everything else so you you know but what
do I know about it I don't know nothing
about it
astronomy and so let's see Z Tron do you
have good ideas for the first program ok
so what is the first program first
program like we showed we talked about
this so let's see something is fun
is there something fun I can quickly
show there's so many things so many
things actually actually I would just
recommend you go to a mathematical
website they have beginning you know
tutorials I mean the first thing you do
with Mathematica once you get it is you
you just play it like a graphing
calculator like is the most fantastic
graphing calculator in human history you
know you just plot you especially visual
stuff protein you can plot curved
surfaces okay I don't want just you know
it's better if I just show you
wolfram mathematica website but if we if
we do that that's gonna be tempting it's
so what is the first program so the
first thing you do with Mathematica you
just go you know you just use it as a
graphing calculator okay and you know
there's so many fantastic things you
actually yeah the great the great
resource is simply hufa Mathematica it's
just their website you know they have
documentation they have introduction
they have introductions on that roof and
math my card so I mean you use it as a
graphing calculator you just follow you
know you type whatever they say for
example these graphics you know it's
just one line two lines you know if you
count you know Mathematica is not a line
based programming language like the
idiocy of C C++ Java JavaScript and
everything else including Haskell okay
though all idiotic
they are mostly line-based
syntactic you know syntax because why
because because they killed you know
because UNIX philosophy UNIX you're the
UNIX [ __ ] pockets
they killed any possible concept of
think the the very concept of syntactic
eunuch what does syntax means you know
they they killed it so Mathematica is
not a line based programming language
and in the same way this piece not least
XML Mathematica they are not you know
like the line line based so anyway so
what I'm saying is that so you see so it
doesn't make sense to say it's one line
or not because because the entire you
know if you have one thousand ten
thousand lines of code in a mathematical
software you can think of it you can
think of it as one single line because
there is no you know there is no you can
separate you you know you can cut it
anywhere almost yeah anywhere you can
cut you know the code anywhere to form a
line so you know one line is you know so
it can be if you have a source code of
let's say 1000 line lines of Mathematica
if you can count it as ten thousand 900
or what or 100 lines or one single line
because there is no the [ __ ] that the
newline line return is is truly
insignificant there is no meaning to it
things like that so for example you are
seeing here in this screen you see it
looks like one line I mean basically it
is one line but however it's more than
80 characters so so anyway so you go to
their website you you know what's what's
new resources and so on modern computing
I talked about this a lot I so I did a
video on mathematical syntax and
symbolic languages what it is what does
it mean in pattern matching and so on so
it goes such YouTube sorry Pat imagine
you'll find that that's a good video so
you move on language you go to
Mathematica then you see Wolfram
language documentation introduction to
mathematical language a fast
introduction for programmers hands on
start okay so yeah so I would you know I
would start with who from language
documentation I guess the Wolfram
language demonstrations project is that
it's very fun okay it's yeah you can go
there as well I mean its collection like
ten thousand also of programs usually
visual programs that interactive visual
programs that shows many things
interesting math physics astronomy you
know many of the interesting things and
it's uploaded by people it's like you
know you once you have a program you can
upload it there that's what the Wolfram
demonstration projects project is is so
you go there I mean basically you you
begin using Mathematica as a graphing
calculator so you just go to the home
language system we should also actually
you know I'm trying to find something
that's you know fun and simple acts so
they have tons of stuff you know okay
this is documentation what do you want
is a tutorial kind of anyway you'll find
you'll find lots of that you know spends
few times you know cement sometimes
you'll find lots of simple code to to
graphics and yeah I want to finish this
quickly so we can move on so so first of
all you you just use it Mathematica for
fun you know party and stuff you do you
can do your homework derivatives
integrals of equations matrix matrix
stuff then after you do that for you
know for a month or something if you
depends on what you are where you want
to go but
the next step is start to program you
view goofin
you know Mathematica as a programming
language you start to program it then
that that is a entirely different thing
because you are not just you know you
are not using it to plots you know it's
wasabi is you know sava equation or plot
some interesting fun things you are
using it as a programming language so
that's the next step and that step that
step you need a teacher okay you you
kind of need a teacher or a book and big
and four and and on the Wolfram language
system documentation Center you know
it's like it's like 1500 pages okay I
read them all back in 90s 1990s three
times you know the entire Mathematica
book that's about this thick they don't
they don't print it anymore but these
1,000 something pages I read it three
times from cover to cover basically
every word so when you if you want to
get into Mathematica mathematical
programming you either need to read a
book or you need a teacher such as me
okay you can ask my questions and I
offer again I offer three hours tutorial
on Emacs lists and other things I know
you know for $100
three hours within a week spread over
distributed over a week so if you like
that
contact me okay do I know such math yes
I do I try to it's open source crap
it's a was most lousy crap [ __ ] in the
in the entire universe I tried it you
know I thought for 10 years you know I
thought you know I read about it you
know these greatest you know open source
thing for doing math but so I heard that
for like 10 years and one day about
three years ago three or four years ago
I don't have Mathematica because well
actually I do have
version Naya version 10 something I want
I need to install it because it was on
my Linux system it's a CD somewhere here
you know he's buried that in the dust so
I don't have Mathematica so one but
three years ago I was you know I need to
do some derivatives integrals you know
helping professors and I tried to
install such math and that what the [ __ ]
the experience is one [ __ ] you know
there's like like when you are trying to
use Linux like you go to their website
set your mother's days we can do it
right now
such math you know you go to their
website it's impossible to find where to
download and when you find a download
button you have like you know the x64 or
whatever you know you that you don't
know what what is what which is which
you know that's a typical of the open
source you know let's say look look at
this page let's say okay I want to
download I want to I really love I heard
this is the greatest thing and then they
pop up this [ __ ] this you know don't you
know this you know this look at this
this is 1999 you know you have several
mirrors like you have to choose like the
close it locations closest location to
you to download it and today you cannot
trust these mirrors because they can in
just inject or whatever then then you
have like this this verification [ __ ]
cryptographic code you know for nuts
like okay so I want to download so what
so I'm a Mac so what is yoga I mean what
the [ __ ] is your problem is a stone of
banner is there is a low traffic
announcing announcement meaningless and
RSS feed to stay inform the [ __ ] I don't
need to know that and I'd yeah you know
you want me to typing an email address
note for Windows installers binaries
seek it go to github what is skid hub I
don't know what the [ __ ] is github then
below are the VirtualBox
images you know these [ __ ] idiot
jargons VirtualBox images do people know
what does image you mean yeah I'm a nerd
I know what it means so what but you
know what the [ __ ] is this opens those
[ __ ] and he says pretty please
select a download server close to your
location what is the server please
select the server you know things like
that then distributed p2p shut the [ __ ]
up you know then you say it's not sure
where to download not sure what to
download follow the download install
guide you know I'm going to spend one
hour to know how to download this
software then they immediately says
windows ok dunno the window binaries
well didn't I'm top didn't you say that
we need to go to github you know so this
so this this okay this is a great
example okay this is a great example of
the Linux [ __ ] software you know
Linux proponents UNIX proponents you
know this they cannot they are unable
incapable of thinking now first of all
there are lots of philosophies you know
we assume I other Linux okay I mean
let's assume I love free software
foundation I love open source and very
much your phonetic bits first of first
of all assume that so so I love I want
to spread the gospel of sage you know
give the greatest math software so I
want to tell people so imagine I tell
people then then my met your mom okay
your mom's you know trying to find this
what the [ __ ] is is you know imagine if
you if you are the the the author of
such math creating this website what the
[ __ ] is this guy thinking I mean is this
guy premise I mean this idiot oh is it
is he not a idiot I mean tell me like
what do you think you know so this Linux
phonetic open-source [ __ ] they have
let's that's what I mean this is a great
example it's you know concrete actual
example if I me and I know many of you
are
Linux phonetics okay open-source
phonetics tell me if is is this a good
is this a good website is this a good
page becoming confused what the [ __ ] are
they talking about
in many aspects not that writing the
organization that the the [ __ ] stupid
mirrors on this this is 1999 okay in
1999 you have websites when you say Tom
this is please select the download
server close to your location below the
fact limp fact that Linux people and you
know Tucker Tucker image [ __ ] okay so I
am on a Mac for example am am I on a Mac
I just want to download Mac so Mac OSX
download mac OS binaries okay so so so
look at first it says tell me to select
a location then just then there is a Mac
tunnel binary link here so which one
where do i click this one or do I go to
one of the nearest server like what are
they [ __ ] thinking so that's what I'm
saying the Linux people okay even if we
assume I am part of you know open source
I want to promote it but they they don't
have a brand they cannot they are
incapable of thinking they are incapable
of doing anything we're okay
they are just nerds they they are good
at you know doing the this nerdy thing
inconsequential then then look they have
the big current web speed files that the
[ __ ] them so their audience like it's
like us okay the audience is for this
node niche nuts who are digging into
Linux everyday like talking about which
which window manager is the best oh you
should use t3 yo you should Emacs evac
me max versus windy this is these
[ __ ] okay inconsequential there's no
premise they are in cabled I mean they
are incapable truly incapable of
thinking the when it comes to anything
outside of you know the very nerdy
programming stuff and you know so that's
a story then I I have actually
downloaded
it's one [ __ ] [ __ ] up okay I have
downloaded before like three or four
years ago you download it and you you
cannot do know what to do that it's it's
just crap okay it's garbage
this this [ __ ] this is this is [ __ ]
open so [ __ ] great example and also let
me tell you about the story of sage okay
he is the mathematician he's a
university professor in fact I have a
article somewhere it would be hot we can
find it okay we are digressing and this
is gonna be let's hope let's hope we can
get back to the topics very languages
okay I have searched in a story of sage
the sad story of sage because the open
source [ __ ] phonetics let's search
for what did you research yeah we are
searching for sage the story of the open
source sage not message okay so let's
search again space sage none so what is
should be maths edge okay so let's
search again search math way search
again capital case sedge no okay so I
might have moved you have to find it you
have to find it in hacker codes
maybe here Jesus okay new new Emacs
window now we need to bring up the power
of Golan fine go okay so we need to find
in all my websites actually just sorry
info not all my website just sorry info
this directory and we need to find the
word you see this is a : script a
Britain that can has a feature of find
multiple words so we want to find for
search math or o sage
okay let's just do it
you're learning in the background and
let's wait to see to see when what comes
up you know so basically he's the story
is that he he
the eighties I found it so so this is in
my comp ha
so why cannot find it Oh such math okay
so let's do it again such math there it
is so you go to go to you go to the
website programming blog 2016 September
sedge ok this is a sad story of sage
math and also we think TB ok we think TB
is another sad story of open source
you probably don't hear it because it's
got voted down its compareed because the
open source phonetics nobody wants to
tell you about this you know they they
you know so we think TB is a database
okay it's a great one but they shut down
no money no money good after three or
four years I made a guy because I tried
to interview with them one day you know
they are down here about three years ago
four years ago four or five years ago we
think TB so they shut down and and let's
look at such math okay I actually
he's got okay he's here is this guy's
blog okay
he's got a article on how he's
struggling to make the sage math
open-source and survive you know he's
not making it so should I resign my food
professor job to work full-time on kocak
how did I get there you know he has
written a PDF somewhere somewhere maybe
it's this link or maybe it's another
blog okay I don't remember where yeah
okay so this is 2019 this is new you
want to find the article that is around
2016 I think yeah 2016 2016 October you
want to find out oh he has a PDF he
wrote a PDF about his story because he
is a very his open-source phonetic okay
he really wanted you know want it to be
successful you know for the open source
for the people and but he can't he
doesn't work and he's struggling and
he's talking about it you know he's so
you can go find it
if you want you know interested but
first of all I can tell you you know you
look at this state there download page
that is a major [ __ ] problem this
this this download page is what the
first problem you fix should fix these
[ __ ] idiots I don't know what's his
situation situation you know apparently
he's a mathematician and a professor you
know he knows things but he cannot do
you know this open source [ __ ]
cannot incapable of doing you know
presenting this something that at least
you know works somewhat that is a
problem
okay you want people to download you
need to fix this page you know just
don't just it's just a page download
button that's it then people click it
then you add behind the scenes you go
[ __ ] you [ __ ] yourself and figure out
what mirror to you use that's your
problem
you don't you you don't put this [ __ ]
incomprehensible thing to the page to
users you know let user think about
one hour to find out where to download
the FAQ this open-source [ __ ]
linux and particularly in in Linux
community ok I need to cool down that is
a story of sage math and open source you
know then you know I'm giving you I'm
presenting you a you know concrete
example why the open source fails that's
just one aspect that to this so today in
summary what we covered is about how the
Linux fanatics this type of people
typically open source phonetics free
software foundation phonetics Linux
phonetics what I'm talking about is
they're in capability of actually
understanding you know user interface
what people want they are incapable okay
that is what I have been trying to you
know I'm giving you a concrete example
in the past thirty minutes they're in
capability of doing that simply
incapable now we are not talking about
where the open source or free software
is good you know the the concept in or
that you know that's another topic you
know we I talked about often but today
we we have you know simply focusing down
on these people's incompetence um you
know promoting the you know
understanding you know things so that
that is one topic that is actually new I
haven't talked about this so that is one
topic okay so I guess I don't know what
people are saying you guys you know but
so there's a lot comments to go through
so if you have comment you have
questions addressed to me right now okay
so let me go through the comments
quickly within language mathematical to
specify so bar says to specify your
expression more clearly and correctly
you can download noobs which is include
Mathematica for 3ds an installer for the
raspberry you can download noobs which
includes my Franco for 3ds and installer
for Elsa
what do you mean so what do you mean you
don't know github I'm talking about you
want to sell you want to sell the search
software you want people to easily
download it understand
most people they do not know github ok
github is the nerd thing mathematician
search is a program for mathematicians
researchers they are not your typical
programmers ok they don't know what the
fact they don't know C C++ they don't
know what is object-oriented programming
ok you have to understand that open
source you need next people you have to
open understand that people they don't
know they are mathematicians they know
things that you will never know in your
life you learn you learn math for 10
years you may not be able to get it ok
but they know they are mathematicians
but however they are not programmers
they don't know what is the github ok
they might have heard of it
some of them use but a lot in general
they don't they are not familiar ok they
don't they ok maybe 50% it no but the
other 50% don't know ok so so that is a
thing that is what I mean you know what
do you mean they don't you know you
don't know Matt github yeah well I'm
well I know but I'm use I'm being
sarcastic
ok so do you think so Matt says do you
think it's wrong to donate for false so
that they keep on with their
unsustainable business well you can
donate you are actually donate it's a
good thing you know you should donate to
open source to what you believe but the
thing is it's going nowhere
I mean first of all all the open source
phonetics they say donate or donate ok
they tell you to donate and some of them
to donate but actually nobody actually
donate is statistically like one
thousand open-source phonetics they cry
open-source everyday on Twitter
everywhere they don't donate okay like
what one person donate in you know
wagging one thousand they in Tony and
how much they donate like $5 okay that's
the that's reality the open-source
phonetic [ __ ] they all say donate
with it actually
whining one thousand donate one dollar
dollar or five dollars in their lifetime
to one project you know that that's a
reality so so so first of all that is
the most important nobody actually
donate so free open source free software
around because free meaning you don't
have to pay the moment you have to pay
its stop existing like tomorrow that is
a reality that's a reality you know not
not your fantasy who open source who is
paying it Google is saying it Google pay
you you go work for Google the [ __ ]
Google with 1 billion
you know patent lawyers Apple Microsoft
you go work for them then you can see
seen the zones of open source that is
that that's how open source sauce do you
know how they are alive how they you
know where they get their fuel for this
is everyday hypocrites you know and on
the Emax community this Python community
the open source this or that they are
all paid by Google and they work for
Google they buy all the Apple latest
Apple products you know the show of
Indian cars and whatever fact and they
seen the sons of open-source
they they put all they tell everyone to
put code on github so that me I don't
work for Google I get I get no pay I
cannot compete you go to Emacs for
example Emacs or Python whatever on
github they have pretty great logo you
know animations you know this is a [ __ ]
you know in marketing you're full of
marketing stuff you know this is how why
you should use this software oh this
this project used by used by Google
Facebook by all these big
companies so they you know especially
like in JavaScript land you see that
everywhere you know it's open source and
it's used by Facebook Google therefore
you know it's the most popular you know
react web web pack you know react is
from Facebook you know them but there
are so many others you know MPM you know
I'm a sauce [ __ ] em here where does NPM
came from it came from the proprietary
company that you know in San Francisco
that's way or not not NPM came from not
is open source they are open source or
open source where does it money came
from not from donations okay from
corporations were from these proprietary
evil corporations they do everything
they can to use psychology to whatever
to market so it's from programmable
programs really so what do you think you
want to donate so about the donation
yeah you should donate you can but
reality is you know nobody is actually
doing it and you know and you know
that's that's the thing you know think
about you have to think about this way
okay donate if you are a programmer
working for Google or any small company
how much you make you know let's say you
know if you were kugel you probably make
ten ten to twenty thousand one month
okay ten is like he's like minimum wage
okay so let's just say ten ten thousand
dollars a month now if you try to
survive on the source project for
donation how much you get if you are
lucky one hundred dollars a month
okay that's ten times difference you
cannot survive on one hundred dollars a
month I mean that's 100 times difference
ten thousand versus one hundred dollars
a month that and one hundred dollars a
month that's you if you are lucky you
know you know but but you you know you
might say Oh some project you know NPM
they make around money yeah but but
that's one in ten billion whining 1
billion open source software you have em
here and they are sub
sponsored by all the Google [ __ ] they
that's how they beget big promoted you
know but it is Google that made them
popular that made it made them the case
you know NPM or whatever you know
angular or Google's you know the this or
that or Facebook basically all the
software open-source software you use
today is of that nature almost except
you know some of the groom Emacs you
know Emacs and good stuff and even you
know you know even Kuno was much very
much sponsored by corporations Sun
Microsystems back then they are like
dying nobody knows what is new anymore
today
so bar says it is from programmers for
programmers I really think you should
get over that I don't expect your mom to
be interested in but you are wrong
that's why ok I understand what you mean
so bosses is you know such math supposed
to be for programmers you know I really
think you should get over that I don't
expect your mom to be interested in such
math or whatever no that's not true that
is that is a problem ok that is not true
that is not true man you know I you know
I have to explain that you know math
software is not it's not true in so many
ways first of all when you create a
software you don't you you you don't
limit yourself to ok you know like you
create a software that you think only
these people are interested that's
that's first of all that's just wrong
you you won't go okay
you want you want your audience you you
want to is I mean in some aspect this is
part of marketing okay technically
speaking but you don't have to think
about that you know I mean yeah we are
not talking about trying to be evil okay
but but but the proper way to think is
that when you create yourself
you don't want to like artificially
think this is only for these kind of
people that's wrong because in general
that's just not true because because you
don't know the people in the world you
know like Oh diverse people like you'd
never possibly imagine that's the case
okay you put it out there soon you know
people you don't know they will use it
you don't know what's their background
you know they will use it so you don't
want to think oh this is just for nuts
okay therefore I should create a page
like this that's that that is a
artificial limitation to your software
that is actually like that so why does
some Facebook noob need to know how to
download the niche program yeah that
that is a good example of the wrong
thing wrongfully think okay that's how
you think that's not how you that that
is like you know it's not just hiding
out how you think that's that's a that's
that's actually you that's that means
you are not understanding reality you
know how society that's what I'm saying
you know open source Linux phonetics
they don't have they don't understand
society they don't see it they don't
they don't understand like you know like
the Emacs phonetics you know I've been
trying to tell them you you remove this
you know this idiotic nerdy things then
you're programmed then a lot of you know
two times three times people we all
start to use Emacs okay and they you
know you don't like you don't classify
people into oh this these people are
nuts you know and then then the then
there's the rest of normal no means okay
that's not correct I mean that's a
factory wrong way to look at things
because there's no definite line you
know that defines with what what are the
nerves what are the noemi's that's not
you know true you know sometimes I I
talk like that you know normal people
but that's kind of part of it is way of
talking this
many subtleties that's the one way to
think so so yeah so you want to you know
it's not some Facebook noob or some you
know there there will be people who will
use sage you know sage math it's like
that and also and you know also even
ammo nuts not everyone is like nerds how
do you how do you defend this you know
there are many degrees of different
people you know we even without within
the Linux community some have you know
college degree some don't some some are
really you know some some study program
in computer science some don't okay some
are just carpenters or living in the
woods we have actually a lot of those
people who don't have a computer
programming education but they are you
know because three nuts you know open
source this idea subtract people so you
want to be able to for them to use as
well that's that's the thing you know so
in summary you have to understand
reality you know that's that's what I'm
saying
after reading out loud their page and
what download possibilities they have to
offer I'm tempted to check out such math
they must still be doing something right
okay yeah that's that's you know big you
know the note thing is that you see this
you find out ok ok this is by not so you
you like it you know that that's what
happens with Linux and Emacs and all
these nuts communities you are a very
small niche insignificant forever that
that's what you guys you know that's
what I'm saying
meanwhile the Google Facebook they are
empires they control everything they
control right now they control every one
of you you have no choice you are in you
are unable to use the phone because
there's so many things you are unable
you become you up you become a someone
who Google the oldest Empire can kick
you out right away in the
you rid of you like that's what you
become and to you you think that you are
you know you are great in this nerd
community or we have this nerd community
how to hack I phone hype how to hack
enjoy you know you enjoy you know you
can create your own server and with spam
filters spent you know further out this
noemi's or whatever yeah but you are in
this you know like dystopia you know
movie science fiction you know like
science fiction many science fiction
movies dystopia where you live in a
sewage you know like you know messy like
like my house okay like my I'm gonna
show you my room my friends does the
current state of my room now okay so you
know the the the plumber came by
yesterday apparently there is a hole on
the ground so anyways you know you know
the science fiction the stove here where
you have the sewage and you know tie
lapid dilapidated you know buildings you
know where the Nerds gather you know
like or like the matrix okay the matrix
okay you leave this in this poverty you
know shanty place that's just the
situation you guys are in in this node
you think you are doing equate or
fighting the fighting the big powers
that's a sad story that's a sad ending
yeah okay that's a sad ending is you
don't want that you know instead you
want to you want to you want I want okay
what do I want to buy your phone Google
Android Apple whatever and I don't have
to worry about anyone tracking me at all
because I can trust it that's what I
want you know anyone anyone a Google
Apple Facebook if they if they do any if
they lie immediately they go to jail
that's what I want I want a society like
that that's what you should want to not
not living in this [ __ ] nation you
know do this you know petty thing
okay so today it's one giant rent I'm
not sure we're gonna continue with this
javascript technical topic because
because that would be a different topic
I thought oh sorry yeah I'm a nerd I am
a nerd but he hates nuts he hates
himself do I hate myself
not really so bar says did you check out
the open collective and how much
donations go through this photo every
single day opened collective so what is
that is that Microsoft thing nobody
actually donate is our own stable no
that's nobody actually donate you are
wrong you gotta go look at look at
reality not in a pub oh I know because I
look I actually I do
non-standard research you know I don't
follow mainstream no do I follow the
nerd [ __ ] idiot you know then Xfinity
phonetics
open source phonetics think pretty much
everyone know every already donation
that's patently that's me not let let me
not be dramatic so what you are saying
is factually incorrect basically 100%
factually incorrect so in analogy what
you are saying is that one plus one
equals two three but you you you don't
you are incapable you fail to see it you
are saying one plus one is three that's
those opinions are open corrective let's
look at what open collective you know
you you guys don't know the magnitude of
what you know you are you know this
bubble you know you have to like like I
said before open collective yeah so
let's see open corrective open
you got brainwashed by this open this
propaganda you don't see you know you
are keep saying one plus one equals two
three
just like the Emacs community they have
saying you know they they think Emacs is
the greatest editor or it's open it's an
operating system and so on the vm
community the Python community you know
the pro community they'd leave the
haskell community functional programming
you leaving a pub oh you don't see the
actual you know the world we award
opinions and what's going on so you know
let's take the example this open
collective you know a new a new form of
Association transparent by design what
is what is that the internet generation
needs organize that reflect who we are
anybody can contribute to a shared
mission and leaders and so on create
open corrective for your community okay
what the [ __ ] is is you know you have no
idea what this is going young let's do
it okay let's just look at this open
open collective okay so I suppose I mean
it's some kind of a nonprofit or
something that helps donate to open
source right you know we can see this
marketing you know this present you know
it makes me so happy look this guy
donated $20 two hours ago my god another
guy drop two dollars a month to Linux
server too late to husky tooling server
to $20 $75 oh my god this guy donated 75
in real time look this is in real time
interactive [ __ ] these idiots okay you
you have to so okay but let me at 100k I
mean I'm you know I'm putting out my
opinion so address this example this is
as an example so perhaps you are
thinking this is a great example showing
how open source is actually striving or
something okay I don't know exactly what
do you think but I don't I don't agree I
think it's
wrong okay then I think he's I think
this is the in fact this is exact a
great a good example just like the sage
math of how your brain is completely
washed okay let me explain you know you
have to think about how much you know
Google how much are they make Google
commercial organizations Google Apple
Facebook Microsoft and we don't even
have to talk about this speak wiser
because these are truly the truly big
ones you know just any any company in
you know any cooperation software
industry you look at their you know
their dreamin revenue their you know
money flow what's what's the words you
know the the net income or the
transactions whatever you compare to you
can then compare to that to all open
source you know met money transactions
that suppose for grandma's like so how
much Google you know any of the tech
industry pay two programmers compared to
how much in the open source pay what
difference is that what what difference
what is the difference it the difference
would be one to one hundred no one to
one thousand know when to ten thousand
know when to 100,000 know when to 1
million know when to one period know
when to ten billion
you know you compare all the money
programmers get paid in the open source
you know community versus the tech
industry not open source one to ten
video no one to one PDF maker billion
temps ^ a period factor open source that
is that is reality if you really want to
think you know if you really if you want
to stop thinking one plus one equals two
three think what I I am trying to tell
you right now about you know so we are
talking about money right so you know
think this open collective you know I
don't know who they are
you have been you you know then then I'm
going to start to dig who who are they
what organization who created them are
they from and to to Google what you know
this is just this is this is kind of
like propaganda that gets you happy
that's this thing you know open
collective this is this is this is just
like you know this is propaganda to make
you happy to make you believe that's
what they are exactly a group of people
with a shared mission that open
operates in full transparency oh there
we go
become a sponsor become a sponsor who
are the sponsors Facebook 11 $100,000 oh
my god Facebook they thank you so much
Facebook thank you so much Mark
Zuckerberg a rpm be 87 me thousand
dollars thrown in matters 74 thousand
dollars come home thank you google Thank
You Google sixty-two thousand dollars
compare now this now compare this twenty
dollars seventy five Jesus but look
listen to what I am saying think that do
I make sense do I make sense or am I am
I just like creating conspiracy like
impossible illogical conspiracy things
am I do I make sense here look at these
sponsors who are they and then then we
next step is to look at who who is this
who is behind this opens open collective
let's let's check let's check who is
behind this open collective [ __ ]
so what says what do you expect only
normal people and not companies to
donate and sponsor and when half of the
world has the same amount of money as 80
richest people on earth you know so why
why do I expect only normal people so so
so here's my answer okay you see this
Facebook Google a do you do you do you
think they are good people I mean like
why not right now suddenly you are
making a distinction suddenly now Google
are the good guys right that's what this
is kind of what you you know in my
opinion from my point of view that
that's what I see what you are saying so
now Google are the good guys Facebook
are the good guys but suddenly you
forget about all the evil things they
are doing like how evil you know that is
Google they are they are doing they are
heavily involved involved in politics in
killing people that's what they are
doing Google you know we are not did you
know I'm not trying you know I don't
want to go into that direction because
then it becomes political control you
know conspiracy theories you know but
indirectly that's what they are doing
Google is heavily tied with US
government you know in you know into
integrated you know they they are but
but that's going into another rabbit
hole because then we have to talk about
you know this you know the their
connections they know that you know that
that's what WikiLeaks talked about
WikiLeaks they published a book on
Google back then I was not I didn't
trust you know I wasn't sure you know
how could you know this is 10 years ago
WikiLeaks Julian Assange he met the
Google heads anyway so so you are saying
you know you are saying okay so this
donate donors they are actually great
why how I mean how we both agree with
Google is so evil now they donate to
this you think is suddenly you think
it's great you think it's great
so another thing okay so then then you
say when half of the world has the same
amount of money as 80 which is people on
the earth so what what is logic so why
do you expect only no more people and
not companies donate to sponsor when
half the world has the same amount of
money as the 80 which is people okay I
don't know what is your logic here like
what what are you trying to point out if
you are open collective in Airbnb is
giving your donation would you refuse
that's right that's another question but
the that you yeah so what so what I
think is that you are not seeing what
I'm saying okay I mean I mean our
perspective are different okay I mean if
you if you ask my opinion my opinion is
just that you don't see the point if you
open collective and Airbnb is giving you
a donation would I would you refuse if I
you know with like what if I'm open
okay that depends on like this multiple
meanings now let's let's say if I'm open
collective but first of all what is the
nature of open collective like what are
they evil or are they good you know that
that's the first question I mean so the
question is like so the question is like
if someone donates me 11 you know 100
hundred thousand dollars they someone
just gave me hundred dollars will I take
it will I take it that that would depend
know if this $100 thousand dollars is
from a well-known cancer okay where non
cancer that's you know Mafia where know
they they given I give me $100,000 do I
we I take it hmm
$100,000 but we're non cancer I mean
truly mafia like they they do
prostitution this you know
human trafficking where no criminal you
know their boss is in jail let's say for
example first of all let's start with
that example so this this mafia group
they want to give me they want to give
me a hundred thousand dollars we I take
it no because that's just I will not
take this one hundred dollars from this
mafia a patently you know well known
criminals will not do that and will not
take it well let's change let's say
Google today is gonna give me sixty
thousand dollars you know they just
cannot donate no questions they just
cannot listen you know let's forget
about this open collective who they are
what's their nature for the woman let's
just say Google Google the company is
going to give me $60 just like that you
know maybe they say that they like my
website they like my you know weird
random talk they're gonna give me $60
thousand dollars we I take it yes I will
take it I will take it Google yeah I
think Google is very evil but you know
they give me six it's sixty thousand
dollars I will just take it I mean so
this come back to what what is the exact
your attitude I mean what would you like
I don't see what you are saying I mean
if you are open collective and Airbnb is
giving you donation would you refuse
like I mean so what what does this have
to do with you know what I'm saying
about this open-source propaganda like
what how how does how does it connect I
don't see perspective do you find it
normal that 80% of have the same amount
of money as the other half of what yeah
I'm gonna address that how is it how is
that not making a huge point I'm gonna I
see your point
exactly but I don't I don't see I don't
I don't interpret that the way you do
okay let's talk about that you know yeah
so they are you know like it you know
there are few people like let's say 80
people hundred people that controls the
entirety of the world's money why does
that happen
be in my opinion let me be traumatic
because of you open source [ __ ] made
that happen
that is how they become so rich okay
that is my put it dramatically
dramatically to get into a point that to
get a point okay because of you open
source [ __ ] don't know nothing
don't know how things work you make this
happen okay that's my point of view in a
dramatic way that that's what I'm trying
to say because you don't know what's
actually going on you are saying telling
people every day one plus one equals
three
meanwhile you are thinking you don't
want one plus one equals to five so you
don't know what you talking about you
are you you are creating this this
opportunity this host for these people
to thrive to manipulate including
yourself including you know you know the
these people have Stern or whatever you
know this rich people they think oh I
don't like part remove him next day
you'll be good okay that's you made it
happen that's what I'm saying you the
world don't go by just because your
fantasy you want this way then you say
that random things you know the war
don't work that way the work the world
walk by physics reality okay so if you
want open source to succeed first of all
you cannot know what what's going on
with you know all these things so so
foot and and on the other hand I
understand your point well I hate these
giant people you know you know I I know
you you see you agree with my many
opinions in the same way I agree with me
many your opinions you know we don't
want this super rich hyper rich
controlling everything we don't want
that but out you know the the the the
the like the video you show me the other
day I what I did watch it you know I
don't think too much of that video I
don't think is significant because
that's every corporation had
doing that so so we agree on the same
problem you know the same problem you
know this is the switch fever we hate I
hate them
you hate them okay we agree but our
solution you know the interpretation is
Stephen so you know why did they happen
why because we made it so we made the
society you know the word is we make the
way we made it it's not because suddenly
they are magical suddenly they are
superhuman they can do everything that
that we they can hide things or things
we don't know no that's big not because
of that they are just like every average
human animals just like us okay they
become rich because well there is no
simple one simple way to explain how
they become rich you may say oh just
because they are bad guys they abuse you
know they they just try to become rich
that doesn't work that's not true
everyone in fact so many other people
are trying to become rich like them they
cannot you know there is power struggle
and all that do you know is somewhat
complex okay so they don't they don't
have a money tree so they don't suddenly
say oh I'm gonna be evil so they're then
then the next year they're gonna be
being on air that doesn't work like that
do you find it okay that comes to what
is this this way in a video basically
you argument against is a video everyone
does it so it's fine no it's not what
I'm thinking that's not what I was
saying so what I'm saying is that
there's a video basically but post a
link okay so let me just summarize okay
you know the word you know there are
many bad things and this super-rich they
become richer and richer in the past
20-30 years okay you know in the 90s
it's not like that
so over the past 30 years the so-called
you know people covered you know the
income this the the wealth discrepancy
that what the wealth
cat okay the way of cat it's a you know
the the jargon everyone wants to post
that the wealth gap okay so the richer
becomes Richard you know the feature so
the whole world is controlled by like
100 people or something like that let's
say this be generous so they say it's
controlled by the top ten that you know
top top 0.1% they have so much money
they have you know the top 100 people
have 80% of the world's money things
like that okay we don't want that and
and that is actually you know in the
past years you got it got worse it was
not like in the 90s it was not like that
in 70s he was you know it became that
way in the past 30 years first of all
understand that okay you know try to
research you know that is true they
became that and if you ask me you know
why it becomes right because technology
and open-source [ __ ] open-source [ __ ]
that that made Google that way open it
is open source that made Facebook so
popular anyway so so the the perspective
you know so what I'm trying to say if I
can say just you know what one thing or
two in summary you want to I know many
of you guys okay part and and many of my
followers you guys are this type of
underground you know type of people in
fact that's Richard Stallman okay you go
to Richard Stallman's you go to Richard
Stallman's
blog you know his blog you are see the
same type of opinion he is posting the
same type opinion since you know since
1990s you know basically organics
government what the [ __ ] is his webpage
got hacked or something
geez oh you said another webpage I don't
know okay maybe that's another webpage
anyway so I'm saying Richard Stallman
okay he is kind of like his opinion you
know it since 1990s he's he's you know
the the kind of the hacker type a guy
he's been putting this type of he knows
I think you know I you know I you know I
think that's similar to what what you
are thinking but and many of my
followers you know these we many of my
followers are this type of you know
niche underground open source phonetics
you know anti-government and you know
and also a lot of them a lot of you guys
I think into conspiracy theories and
things like that okay
bots video okay I can show you where it
is it's on last week's some talk show
anyway anyway so you guys you know into
this underground kind of thing you know
and many of you guys I know are for
anarchy you know enoki anarchy is also
there's many branches this is capitalism
monarchy there's communist Annunaki race
array awareness yes indeed Thank You
Kathy to use his overdramatic rage to
tell everyone who cares to remain angry
husband is of ranking is to raise
awareness yeah yeah and also that's
that's just my personality okay let's
get into so what I'm saying so which are
so many is kind of like that so so we
don't like you know we don't like so
what I'm saying is that you have to
actually know reality not following
conspiracy okay not following too
dramatic things you know not following
ideology you won't know you want to
study reality like study actual what
actually happens you know don't you know
unfold for example someone at Google
because he's ahead of Google don't just
start to playing him oh he's [ __ ]
because he's ahead of Google again
that's not the case like that like the
example used yeah so I mean so what I'm
saying is that you want to be reasonable
okay you want to be reasonable okay be
reasonable okay for example
yeah it is true you know the top 100
people control the world's wealth but
you don't just you don't you cannot
simply just start to call them [ __ ]
so they are evil they must die on things
like that that's that's not fair okay
that's not fair
in fact maybe me you if we are in their
head you feel grew up like them we are
do exactly the same you know so that's
one possibility you see instead instead
of thinking oh all the people there are
some bad people good people like that
instead of thinking like that think of
they are bad ideas and good ideas and
people are just like lotteries like each
of us is like a poor we mix them in a
big pack you know role and whoever come
out and there are channels below it and
the channel has labels good millionaire
in something-something
you know bad people open sores phonetic
so we are just sports in this big part
you know and you can come out at bottom
and dududududu the post we are just four
into the different suits so so you might
think you are poor open source or
whatever you are the good guys that's
just by chance okay just by chance if
something some is something some Adam
are in different position you will fall
down you will become exactly the those
speedy and you know Evo billionaire guys
you hate so so what I'm saying is that
you you want to it's it's it's it's a
difficult topic nobody really actually
understand how you know nobody society
works
you know that's my opinion that I'm
gonna tell you okay
from from Saudi the genius okay you you
might hear this economists you know
these professors they say something they
tell you how what works they write books
many of those books are propaganda they
are paid by a government or something
okay so I what I tell you is that nobody
actually know how exactly things work so
okay don't don't hate you know these big
bosses just because something anyway so
so it's a complex topic that that you
know it hard it's hard to okay that the
past video so bad did you post it well
but you are not to send for a Chinese
chill video available well but has a
video yeah I don't think you know parts
right but you know what bird showed me
about I think last week or two day few
days ago let's go to San talk show and
no okay its search for it so that video
is talking about yeah okay so it's
talking about the pass the pass of the
video game company you know which is on
the news about China
what is that company the one of the big
reso or razor not razor but who made
over watch what's the company's name
Brizard okay so there is a video on the
boss of Breezer yes oh I don't have it
it's such it again capitalized is it 1 0
to Z
oops
I don't have it so when it's search for
YouTube then it's just such for YouTube
okay so many so many results let's see
yeah because there there it is I think
it's open no not that you need one for
one second so delete all lines
containing that ok now let's search
let's go to the bottom
it's not a snippet it's a YouTube video
where this guy but what post it you know
so it's the this one yeah this one okay
found it so this one Sontag showed 2019
October eighteenth etiquette
anthropology at Ross convection dead
links in stoned okay I was stoned in
that video in that talk show so this
this is the this is the video let's see
if it can so the video title is fire
Bobby
Karthik Bobby Karthik is the head a
blizzard and this video is made by the
channel the Jim position okay and by the
guy James Stirling and it's February
eighteenth 2019 so does the video
there's a link show of I think my I
posted it shows so basically the video
so he's criticizing so he is criticizing
the guy Bobby Kotick the head a blizzard
because Bobby Kotick apparently he's a
super rich you know one of the super
rich and doing evil things
so James studying is criticizing the guy
he think Bobby Kotick should be fired if
you really believe you know this guy is
saying he should not just be fired he
should be put in jail you know the most
more so anyway my opinion on that is I
kind of agree I mean this is kind of the
same thing same you know same mentality
me and all you guys share you know we
don't like this you know big giant
corporation heads doing evil thing
like so I kind of agree but however this
details you know sorry when I watched
this video I don't feel like I don't I
don't care for it at all it's almost I
don't care for you know even even though
you know I agree I you know we hate
these super rich people but but this
video to me like I don't I I would not
for example I would not share it I don't
think it's making much I don't think
it's a good thing to spread big why
because because first of all to realize
you know so he's talking about this head
a blizzard bobby kotick okay evil things
that guy has done but did you know have
you ever looked let's say the top 1000
corporations in the world have you
looked at what they are CEO or the board
members what they are what they do have
you ever looked because this my it is my
opinion if you looked at the top 1000
corporations I mean actually you have to
spend time to do it not just following
the YouTube that's that's what I think
that's that's what I think things that's
what I think where things went wrong you
have to starting today starting today
one hour a day for the next 30 days for
a month okay right I tell you what to do
you look at one that the top 1000
corporations let's say let's now say
1000 because that's too much let's just
say the top 10 corporations okay now
before you even can do that there's a
question what do you mean by top 10 how
do you define top 10 look ok that that's
a research that's a research research
subject we which will take you 10 or 20
hours so we are not even we we we cannot
even begin until you spend 20 hours on
that topic but anyway back to the search
fold you know spend one hour a day for
the next for the next year one hour a
day not too much I'm just asking
one hour a day let me give you a guide
of how I think how I do things okay so
one hour a day to begin start with the
top ten corporations first of all what
what does top ten mean well there are so
many matrix like net income or number of
employees or or the gross income or the
gross revenue like how much money flows
or the net asset things like that top
ten corporations around world or you can
just limit it to your country I give you
know you are in Germany right so you
focus on German German country companies
because you know that it's more interest
to you so me in America for example I
look for Google Facebook Apple and and
once you do this you actually get a real
reality okay not not open-source fantasy
you actually get a list of companies
some of them you may never heard of they
are in top ten okay because as a
programmer you know you know everyday I
just here open you know Google Facebook
Microsoft you know they doing evil
things but you may not know actually
there are quite a few you never heard of
they did you know they don't they are
not on the news because they are reasons
okay they are reason some of them you
never hear of but in fact they are like
the top ten okay so first of all get the
top ten corporations okay you know you
try to I mean this is what I mean by
exploration you look into reality and
you know so top ten companies then the
next thing you look at their top let's
say top five leaders or whoever makes
more money top five okay auto top three
you know for each of this company how
you do that again that's a research
topic it's open you know you don't don't
don't follow like be the book oh this is
you know some book says that is the
history of Google how Google rose to the
top you know some some scholars the
professor will write a book how the is
inside the information of Google you go
by the book and you read a book and you
swallow it
Oh
like the gym position that's that's what
I think okay no no offense to you but
but but but but okay so so top ten
corporations then the next step is you
you want to find who are the top let's
say three okay the top three people in
that company now immediately you have
the question how do you define what do
you mean by top three do you mean the
top three people paid by the by the
company or do you mean the board you
know the board members or Board of
Trustees there are so many terms you
know legal technical jargon so you know
cooperation so what so hot so or do you
mean the top three stockholders you know
like so what what do you mean by top
three how do you define it that's that's
a research question you know you you go
you go not me telling me what to do you
go find find out what should you can see
the top three people is it you know is
it like who you know the C or the T or
the the the financial FeO is that that
or is it should be the founders you know
the founder may not be with the company
anymore
should it be founders or should it be
the the guy who holds the most stock you
know market you know for the company and
what is a stock you go study that you go
you go spend 100 hours on what is a
stock okay not not by you know not by
reading you know what what information
comes to you handy okay so anyways so
you you look for you know you look for
the top top ten corporations then on
Monday for each one of them you look for
the top three biggest people ok whatever
however whoever they are depends on you
you have to do the research ten hours
then for each person you research their
history okay today information is
everywhere you can find the information
not by following in the news okay
remember in fake news or the open source
phonetics news the hacker news like
how can you / start or whatever this
underground niche group okay not that's
that's that's all for example the info
war Alex Jones that's all [ __ ]
so anyway top 10 companies find the top
three people in each cooperation then
you go research their history
oh the public information I'm not
telling you to tick okay not not tax ok
the [ __ ] ducks not tanks ok not ducks
but find the public information about
these people
what have they done what's their life
story you know usually they typically
for these big people they have a
Wikipedia you can you can begin there
okay you you can begin there so I'm not
saying you have to Wikipedia but that's
one option
okay you can start somewhere else it's
up to you you can start with Wikipedia
and also Wikipedia to know that you know
they have a lot of fake news because
it's it's fried you know it's all anyway
so you Wikipedia is one option to begin
with to you know then you can follow the
links you know the research papers or
whatever oh you can you know did they
are you know internet this is when you
shoot on your internet research skills
you know or you can type in to talk net
talk the talk web like you know I know
many of you who are in this underground
so you know your friends right people
who are into silk web or Bitcoin you
know the talk web you can that's one
option to you know I'm not telling you
don't read those okay so what I'm saying
you you you read you research that
that's what I'm saying one hour a day
for ten years okay you do research so
for each person you try to find out
their history you know public
information how much make they make you
know their their life you know how much
what were they are carpenter or were
they inherited rich or whatever you know
and you I'm sure I'm pretty I'm I'm like
99% hundred percent sure you we also
find us of controversies controversy
coded by you know news media over the
past 10 or 20 years you will find that
okay so what I'm saying is that you do
this for the top ten companies the top
three people for each company and find
the life story okay that's what I'm
trying to that's what I'm telling you to
do now how long will that take
that depends okay if you can spend one
hour a day for the next week maybe you
have some conclusion you know next week
you know Wow seven hours is not
obviously not enough but you start to
get some idea like you start at this you
know maybe what are the top 10 companies
are this is the real top 10 not what you
hear every day Google Facebook you know
Microsoft they are doing this evil that
evil you know that that that's all fake
news that that that brainwashes you okay
so at least you're not what's the top 10
actual you know is to whatever however
you from your research you find out how
why they are this top 10 are significant
as opposed to another top 10 for example
the most number of employees or some
other you know anyway so top team keep
corporations that then you so how long
you spend you can spend one week one
month you can spend half a year or a
year so this is like this is not like
college you go to Cal college after four
years you are done you are you got a
degree certificate you know and yes you
know it can be your lifelong you know
for me it's kind of lifelong yeah you
know I don't have a specific you know I
just you know he's read random things so
so what I'm telling you what I'm saying
is that after you've done this let's say
a month okay 30 hours you know it's
important to spread them day by day not
you know trying to do or everything
continuously because because the picture
come out will be very different from for
may persist was performer prolonged
period
I'm telling you to spend one hour a day
for one month to look for the top 10
companies the top 3 people of each
company and find out their history their
story ok now I will guarantee you but I
will guarantee ok I will guarantee you
if you do that for for a month your
opinion on this video will be
drastically different than before okay
on on this video on the Jim position
will be drastically different than
before I can guarantee you that you can
try that
Tencent you know Tencent you know so bad
says have you ever looked at 10 cent I
don't know much about it it's it's one
of the giant corporation in China you
know and from what I know they are you
know they are not good in short they are
just they are just like Google ok they
are doing now I don't know exactly how
China system works you know in USA since
I live here for you know all my adult
life I know for the past 30 years I this
have some idea you know how corporations
you know the legal system the stock
market in the stocks you know how the
system works I at least know where in
China I don't know how they works and so
as far as I know it's kind of mixed
capitalism and partially controlled by
government ok so not like the typical
Western I think ok that's another thing
important that the thing I need to
mention because typical Americans they
all think oh it's all government secret
to control that's not like that anyway
that's that's another you know 30 hours
to research you know if if I might be
interesting that how China system works
anyway so tense and I don't you know I
don't as far as I know he's it's not
it's probably is I'm pretty sure it's
not pretty pictures okay it's not good
but you know they are big corporations
in Alibaba so I think that's it for
today and so that that is just my
opinion skies you know okay so we have
been dramatic you agree you know you may
not agree it's up to you I think that's
it for today and let me get a drink and
let's wrap up okay okay it's 90 minutes
so we didn't get to the topics that's
the topics we want to talk today is
gonna be maybe tomorrow about JavaScript
yeah
technical yes maybe tomorrow will you
focus on that so who asks this you know
Bart and some of other my regular
followers so let me get a drink and wrap
up and we're gonna shut down in three or
five minutes so today's drink is
raspberry and apple again raspberry and
cranberry and apple and actually I'm now
hungry but really I'm pretty hungry so
and we cannot forget the addictive
sugar-free though at least it's
sugar-free the condensed coffee and it
comes out Korea
it's a white clear sugar-free energy
drink power juice
you even drink raspberry yet you barely
mentioned what do you mean what do you
mean barely mentioned bad way I have so
I have this this I love nuts okay this
is this is mixed nuts so mixed nuts
let's see what they have they have cat
cashew almonds pecans Paseo nuts
macadamia nuts and peanut oil and and
sea salt
okay so yeah yeah so those nuts almonds
yeah so I love I love the you know they
are healthy so I love them they are
healthy too you know usually I'd stick
with healthy food and they are you know
they are they are a lot fat but they are
good then you know I just need them
sometimes this like like I just this eat
that for a meal that's like a meal so
what do I think about Xi Jinping so you
are asking bad so again I don't know
much about him so he is China's
paramount leader see is like Emperor you
know the King as they say I don't know
the details you know so you know as I
know yeah so III don't know that China
system actually so what I mean so a lot
of people what probably want to know
what do I think of him like do I do I
think he's a good guy or bad guy on that
question actually I don't know you know
I this is probably I don't know actually
I have no idea I want to say he's a bad
guy because you know he's the the
paramount leader you know but meanwhile
I don't I I want to fight American you
know the typical American propaganda you
know because it's fake news or
everything you hear about China
in english-language newspaper 1999
percent it's 100% fake news okay it's
not good okay I can show you an example
every day on Twitter you see examples
every day you show that to the Chinese
citizens in China they think what the
[ __ ] truly but you that but most
Americans they don't know because they
the moment they see Oh Chinese is you
know you know is controlling information
they stop they are happy they are done
with that information you know that's
what they want to believe because
because they are not Chinese in China
China is the powerful is the USA's enemy
you know it's a potential enemy or it's
the enemy just like Russia was before
you know so you know that's race that's
you know that's about that's that's like
racism you cannot stop it okay so my
opinion about you know racism is that is
something we cannot fix okay you know
the social justice can oh they are all
[ __ ] and the American obsession
about justice well about racism it's so
just wrong based racism is a thing you
cannot start American system in the
1990s you know it's it's good it's
actually just good enough so what do you
do when it comes to the inherit and
unstoppable racism you know don't you
just just just have law you know you
follow a law and that's it stop talking
about racism or as the stock like
completely stop talking about it
you just follow a law and that's it and
and remove the hate law okay eliminate
that remove that law is just law you
beat people you go to jail you lie you
go to jail you know you rape you go to
jail that's it no hate speech [ __ ] no
you know special condom broke rape
oh oh I am drunk she's drunk then they
then then we slept together then I go
jail because sushi
strong remove all that no it's just no
simple Oh things like that so so so
that's about my take about that big
issue and she I don't think he made
China a good economy the the guy who
made China capitalist the reason China
is thriving is but because ten shopping
then shopping begins 1976 beginning he
made it he changed he he threw out the
communism economy he saw era replace it
by capitalism with the euphemism you
know capitalism with with China
character with Chinese characteristics
that's what you hear you know it's a
phrase you know capitalism with Chinese
characteristics okay but that's just a
view but you've euphemism okay the real
thing is just capitalism okay China has
become the China economy economic system
is just capitalism period you know but
but they cannot say that because oh then
because it conflicts with the communism
ideology you know because because the
communism think that cab ISM is the
worst you know they are the opposite so
you can just say oh but we adopted
capitalist capitalism no you're the cake
you cannot say that so anyway so then
shouting you know you can you can
reading Wikipedia he he is the one that
changed China because in one sentence
summary what did he do he threw out
communism economy system he replace it
with capitalism almost pure capitalism
almost that is why that is why China the
game to grow so you know before they are
like eating banana peels you know things
like that they are trying to you know
and lots of death and things like that
so it is a capitalism just like America
capitalism a China so so you know the
big you know powerful
of sending people to the moon and stuff
not people but you know to the back of
moon so actually so that's it did I miss
any there are so many comments I'm gonna
read I think Oh fly sorry his lever
should be eaten by birds every day every
night and she and should we grow and
next morning the birds should pick it so
that is the story of the Greek story who
is a guy who got that fate you know who
is bound
I think it's Atlas right I think that's
a quick story of that guy who is found
and leave being eaten by birds every day
so they are so mean comments okay so but
I think that's it for today I'm gonna
read the comments of flying
okay thank you guys bye guys if you like
my stuff
remember I have PayPal in patreon okay
you know where to find it
have a good day guys bye