hi guys good morning so today is January
7 7th 2019 and I'm going to show you
working HTML course our HTML mod how I
use it like most people use oak mod and
okay so let's begin and you know maybe
I'll do something else but first of all
let's go let's just start talking about
help command log mod I'm gonna turn it
huh and I've shown this yesterday but
there's new way to turn it now so then
that then that doing that so you can see
how the commands I'm coding okay so what
I want to do this is evil Apple this is
my programming blog let's go to my
keyboard okay so key word blog I have
this Japanese keyboard layouts so first
first of all I discuss Japanese writing
system then Japanese input system then
you can see you know how to how to type
Japanese so if you read this you can
actually try to type Japanese Japanese
the Japanese language is fairly
complicated it involves Chinese
characters involve Jeff knees phonetics
a also involves actually English letters
English letters like ABC is considered
in fact part of the Japanese language so
anyway so this this page is long because
it covers the Japanese you know
introduction to writing system and then
[Music]
you know how to type check Japanese then
special keys on Japanese keyboards and
Japanese keyboard layouts now actually
there are quite a few Japanese keyboard
layout as well like in English we have
Corti and virag and Commack and Walkman
and so on but in Japanese is even more
complicated so there are actually many
varieties of different
fairly different very different input
systems to enter Japanese in you know
they usually in the name of efficiency
you know they try to design a system
that's most efficient so Japanese
keyboard layouts so there are quite a
few harm in type layout so they are
invented in the past 20 or 30 years but
you know the funny thing is actually
they never catch kata just like Barack
in fact the vast majority of Japanese
they are using a system that is the most
inefficient but actually yeah it's a
they are using a system the most most
inefficient just just like the English
Cody so anyway that this page is pretty
long Japanese keyboard layout so so they
have the okay the standard is qua TJ is
that is the most you know the the most
popular and the most inefficient but
they are suppose M typed is JSX 6004
layout and there's Nicola layer thumb
shift they are trunk layout you know
it's you know is fascinating if you are
into design of things designing of
systems yeah so but what what am i doing
what I'm gonna do is today's you know
this page is too long and it covers
basically in two type of topics how to
input Japanese and the different layout
so I'm gonna split split it into two
pages so let's work on that Japanese
Japan input method so in
in general in other languages you know
in English you just type on keyboard did
you don't have input method but in other
languages such as Japanese Chinese
Russian even Russian and Iraq rabbit or
Persian in any language using the rabbit
let you know have chat they could have
chat you know the the rabbit alphabet
they they you know you would need a
different input system input method it's
called input method so so I'm gonna
speed this this page now this page is
why it says slow there so this page is
that page right so I'm gonna split I'm
gonna create a new page it doesn't exist
yet but I'm gonna create it you know and
put part of the first page into a second
so you know know I used to do this okay
nobodyís what I do is okay let me so
open that copy close go here open create
new yes paste then you can show here how
a Japanese simple layout Pacific so far
these two pages are exactly the same
exactly the same but not me to edit it
so copy the title open Co command to
modify the title and done so you can see
the title is changed then I go to here
update the date so you can see the date
is changed well I I wanted I want to
show you this but for here so let's do
it again update title yes then update
the date yes yes okay and remove that
because this is new page and now I copy
that and copy all the way down
up to here you see like remove it so now
you show it here it's basically empty
except the templates then I go across
this I go back to the first page I open
it and I copy you know whatever part of
the things here like delete it actually
so I basically you know copy it and
delete it save but I don't want to say
because I'm gonna show you something
else save it close it then open a new
one then paste it here then then
ensuring browser you can see so that's
that's what I usually do be but because
I do these so much so often I created I
wrote an eMac please Emacs command to do
that so fix it so let me show you that
so I opened this page now I delete it
because we're gonna do this over again
so I try to open it it says create it
doesn't exist you know so I don't want
to create it so instead of that so I
just so what I now what I do now the
command is let me show you
so basically I want to clone this this
age HTML so the command is called I just
put the cursor here well first why I
create create this line you know this
line contains the file name and the
title here may I move the cursor to the
first link then ICO sacrum way it's not
copy HTML by link so that is it so I do
that
okay so that's done
actually that's done so I just noticed
something interesting when you call it
MX smacks the weight when you call that
the the command that what the command
you just caught does not show here in
this panel so that's okay that's
interesting anyway so I just created
that page you see I open it you can see
it cloned for me it's already you know
it just count for me you know just it
basically you know like the menu process
I did before but this is still good no
good let's go to the date so I still
have to remove the actually that the
name the title is not changed you see
that I know is still no good close safe
so the title should be copy open update
I don't miss yes
hello should be that day I'm gonna
remove the whole thing remove remove
showing browser you see okay that's that
so that the command I just called his
side Gmail copy again then you show you
so now it's twelve thirteen how long we
been talking for five minutes
it's and at 12:20 okay I guess I'll copy
hmm I think so
so that's the
that that is the he Mackey's called home
so you see it's your inconvenient
because once it cloned the page actually
I still have to remove the content you
know and change the data and change
title in this but I created another
Emacs command that's general general
purpose yeah let's show that because
that's the purpose of this tutorial
anyway I'm just gonna show you some HTML
command oh I was going to talk him in
fact I want to talk about you know how
most people use oak Mart yeah let's
let's cut into that let's talk about
that a little bit so Emacs who's EXO so
Emacs tutorial Oh God
Omar so you see this oak mod yeah you
know you already know oak mati is kind
of just a mock-up system like markdown
but except it's more much more
feature-rich so first of all I have a
you know ever tutorial here first of all
I explain how it's a it's a basic markup
markup system then you can then you can
use this use it as a outline system
meaning that you can collapse the
headers collapse you know and move the
headers around so Daddy that is new from
the mark-up systems then then then you
have what what else ok create headings
yeah and you also have all the shortcuts
you know he should cuts keyboard
shortcuts to create headings but
actually you can type them you know
that's one of the advantage of markdown
it's it's simple and readable
okay so you have keyboard shortcut
system you have you have keys to move
the headings
you know the branches of the tree and
okay twelve 1600 oak my programming code
yeah you can also mark up programming
code and that and the thing is you can
actually so so in this way is it's not
just markup programming code but you can
also evaluate the code so in this way
the oak Mart becomes a language
embedding system you know it's it kind
it's kind of became like a notebook you
know there's a notebook system that's
popular these days I forgot what's the
name I don't use it but it's basically
it's a copy of a Mathematica jargons
programming language it's it's a copy of
the Mathematica interface the
Mathematica interface you know look book
notebook looks like that you can have
you know text you can have headings you
can equations you can have graphics so
this this is called notebook notebook
interface it and it became popular in
the past two or three years I forgot the
name so I mean so they implement Python
language and all that but anyway oak mod
is kind of like a notebook format and
it's nice because it's nice because as
compared to what you know before the
notebook basically it's compared to
command line command line system you
know like this is command line which
they usually co-ed
and something evil OOP print repo read
eval print loop that's that that
terminology actually came from scheme
piece from the book six syntax in the
interpretation of computer programs
structure and interpretation program
structure and interpretation of
programming or programs
yeah programs that's a very popular book
back in the 1990s hack actually I read
it it's one of the best book I've read I
would you know I
yeah it is
but today the information there's so
many so much information I think it's
still worth reading if you have time but
but it's it's it's not a practical book
in the sense that you know like when you
read a Python how to you know you
actually start to program Python it's
the sick book let's let's not get into
that so we have been distracted we have
like I have like where digressed so
let's go back to the Emacs so I was
talking oak Mart yeah I was talking
about Oakmont Mathematica interface
notebook into interface so you know oh
ma you probably if you have ended you
can try it so then you can use oak mug
for to do and it has features like you
can mark
when did you start when what time you
did you start what I'm it's done list of
todos and tag and keywords yeah so so
that's in and that's the most basic
features that you know categories
categorization of features this this but
there's a lot this or more so a lot of
people you know they use Dogma all the
time
that's okay odd is in fact in fact one
of the package software that made Emacs
popular too many people otherwise who
wouldn't use Emacs but okay so Oakmont
so you know I I use oak Mart but not
much I turns turns out you know you've
oak mod is pretty structured you know
the text needs to be structured I end up
not using it much because I yeah because
I whenever I use oak Mart I just ends up
using you know just like plain text
hedges type random plain text I would
show you my file of my to do is like
it's just chaotic
just text and if I want to separate I
just use that that that command is that
insert form feed from from form feed is
the character control L so if you type
Wow let's not get into that but anyway
so I end up not using oak Mart much and
and actually because I've been writing
HTML so much since since 1997 manually
you know you know in 1997 1997 you know
it was Oba he manually like when you
want to write HTML you do that then you
want you want you know that's how that's
in the beginning then Emacs helps of
course team access sa HTML package and
you can add tags automatically but
eventually so eventually I did I got a
lot of my own code and you know so I've
been working in HTML for like you know
20 years so I thought yeah 20 something
years
so these states actually weigh but I
want to write notes I just created Gmail
raw I'm almost for example let's say so
now it's HTML mod HTML and okay so I
have a and save this page X X X HTML so
how are you today
okay question mark you know that's it
that there you have it a basic HTML page
then you know so you need a CSS you need
styles right so wait can you show you
the other panel it's important so you
can see the command what I'm doing so
let's add a style CSS let's say found
that let's switch to CSS mod way so
phone sighs okay wait so so P no wait
body P font size - am not know - M is
too big but wait wait let's just say
font
nah not found found family that's right
let's leave that switch back to HTML
it's C C so so I became just you know
writing HTML manually so so did and this
way it's almost similar to how you use
oak Mart because yeah you can you can
add code as well for example let's say I
want to add Python code so I actually
call the command that and he asked me a
language code let's say Python okay
because python is popular actually
between Python and Ruby and Perl
I think Ruby is the best it's simpler in
syntax and it's as party they are
equally powerful in but Ruby I think
it's a better language but Ruby didn't
start because well it's not good let's
talk about some other day so so Python
so you see I have a Python code here and
I call command and it's switch to equate
the new buffer and put me in Python mod
so now I can type Python here so print 3
plus 4 for example and I can evaluate it
so I get 7 so if it did if this is good
I copy it TD the buffer paste it here
and showing HTML so now I have it in
actually I can color this code so you
see it's colored so show you answer me
it's not colored here because I need the
CSS ok let's let's create one then um
what directory ok so go to my computer
block I have the CSS code here this is
the CSS file you can see if I go
you see so here is the CSS that contains
the syntax colouring specification for
like keyword I programming language
keywords and stuff so across the file I
so basically this file is one is what I
want CSS file so copy the file path oops
copy the file path copy the file path
pros close now we are back here and
paste the file path and press a key and
it becomes a link and now I don't need
this style anymore so showing browser so
there there it is you see so I'm using
HTML mod my my own so you can 26 okay
well it's I've been talking long but
since you know let's let's go you can
you can skip it you know stop watching
you know you know I like my three
tutorials I don't I never liked video
videos like today they are a huge amount
of video every tutorial like the this
video format and it seems a lot of
people like it
it's popular but I don't like it because
it you have to spend tremendous time to
watch it and of course you can skip but
even with skipping you like you don't
get table of contents you don't get like
the overview of the whole thing I rather
prefer when we run in our language or
you know technical stuff math and I
prefer to read so I rather read some
tutorial or Wikipedia so I can scan and
you know I don't yeah I generally don't
like videos so anyway so well what were
we talking we were talking so I'm
showing you this yeah so I'm showing you
this HTML MA
so let's see describe keyway describe
wait so okay describe key wait describe
key so here is the XHTML mod that's how
I get into look at the file here okay
that that this is the way I jump to my
email list files so the way I jump to
email this file I mean this is
convenient okay so this is the trick tip
you might want to use so you know there
are many tricks to open files like this
bookmarks open bookmark open so one of
the way whenever you want to open a
email is file especially your own all
you do is just do a describe function
for example HTML mod so that is the
default HTML mod that come with Emacs so
you guys you know you can just go there
and jump to the file so you see and and
then you can go to the directory you see
this is a file so this way this method
of opening files allows you to open any
basically any eMac eMac sleaze file you
don't have to put in bookmarks you don't
have to yeah you don't you don't need
bookmarks or anything so any list eMac
this file it you can open it this way so
so for me you know if you know the key
key binding for the command for example
I know my key pending for the command
HTML marcão I can just call describe key
you know describe key then I type my key
then he says okay you know that key ones
sashimi Ahmad
in tab me again I jump to my file and
the once in my file I can go to the
directory or you know look at things so
I need to remove please wait I need to
remove those backup files do you need so
anyway so yeah you can use my HTML mod
you know it's a most this mod is
actually the mod that had contains the
most line of code of you know I I have
written close to 4,000 in one file but
but actually you know my my other mod is
actually better because this mod is just
HTML is a lot processing you know you
have to pass the tag but anyway so this
HTML mod I've been using for like 10
years now so so it's like this is like
my oak mod so so everything I write is
just depends on this and also functions
outside of that file because some HTML
commands I use is not generic it's not
for the general public you know for
example let's say insert insert my own
[Music]
stuff it's it's in my Emacs in it it's
let's look let's look at so now I'm
using bookmark to open my Emacs key
bindings
now these key bindings is in my Emacs
init file and you can see HTML yeah so
for example oh yeah this HTML eyes is a
great package I use this this this
package is what makes the same text
color impossible I'm using this library
so anyway so I was going to show you my
other
HTML stuff yeah so I have other commands
here yeah for example this command i
just showed you earlier is not part of
the excit ml mod and inside midi you
know not many people use MIDI this day
so know what it is you know it's a
different you see so you have all these
commands remove Wikipedia link remove
all key beginning sonya rage
okay so let's close that because we
don't need this anymore close those new
video link of TTI's okay that's my Emacs
blog coz okay so we are back to this
problem in fact I haven't started yet so
but I think we are done we are done so
let me just finish then you can I mean
you can always stop watching yeah like I
said before you know when you feel I'm
just going to check nice writing system
so let me finish this Japanese writing
systems other type Japanese so basically
I just walk on my website this is almost
like what I do every day
and you know sometimes yeah reading
command so you know working on my
website special key
Japanese Kibo yeah so I'm not going to
you know I'm going to do this in more
detail offline but for now let's just
show you the general structure of things
how to type Japanese that's right so
copy all the way down okay so up to here
cut
so again I just cut that and go back
here here paste showing browser so
Japanese input method so you know and
this I want to make it singular not true
Japanese input method okay and then copy
oops copy file path copy file ask us go
back here and put a link and say first
wall here's a intro to chat Japanese
language because we need to know that
before you even start to learn about
Japanese input methods okay so you see
so japanese keyboard layouts so first of
all you need to hear the intro to
japanese language then you read that
okay that's so that's the basic system
then you read about different layout
okay that's it for today
thank you for watching and if you have
some comments comments if you have
questions questions actually if you like
to my video a thumb up thumb down stuff
and yeah actually if you want to watch
me do something say it
bye