hello welcome to another episode of Star
Talk Show today we are going to code
emac lisp
I'm going to there are several things to
do
so coding emac this okay so uh I'm
wondering you know there are several
projects that we may do so let me show
you uh what they are okay so go to emacs
actually go to sound talk show topic
notes so one of the problem I want to do
is write a Emax lisp command you know
write the emacs command in emac bisp
that does common and uncommon code for
example I mean html I can press the key
then we have comment in HTML you know it
may be in Python in JavaScript in
whatever language so um so one of the
things to do is to write this from
scratch
now let me mention if you go to Sardi
emac this tutorial you know just search
for it practical emac this you'll find
my website so we did
um practical emac this then you click on
write a major mod so we did three videos
four videos actually on writing a major
mod each one is independent
so and we did two or three of them three
of them this year recently last month so
check it out
and when you want to write a command to
comment you know
um you can use the built-in Library so
there's a building Library you click on
write a major mod then you click on
um
common uh Standalone comment command
Okay so there are two ways to do it one
is the common command
which relies on the build in library
newcomer.el that's in every emacs
okay so you can so if you use the
building Library all you have to do is
just add two lines you know the your
comment your programming language is
common start characters and common n
characters
that's so simple all you have to do is
just add two lines and of course load
the library
but
I'm thinking you know but in some cases
you want to write your own common
command for example in the wolfam
language Let Me Show You woofer
Mathematica uh so UFM so for example let
me start
uh wolf and mod okay so right now I mean
wolframard if I want to comment that's a
comment you can see let's magnify so
this is a comment in Wolfram language
you know uh I believe this is also used
in Pascal
and apple script I forgot
but anyway there's uh I have a lot of
you know it's used in a few other
languages also use this maybe old camo I
forgot
so this is wolfen language common so if
so when you come and seeing tags of your
programming language
is
unusual or not the typical C or C plus
plus you know slash slash or slash
asterisk
you know that's C and C plus first in
Java or for example in Python that's a
pound sign python bash Powershell that's
the most simple you know if your comment
is a bit more complex than the typical
ones then
you might have a problem using the
building Library the
newcomen.el
but actually I haven't looked into I
should look into so
so that's one of the things we should do
so do we have people watching now three
people fantastic a grand total of three
so
since we've been talking about this
already for five minutes let's just do
this okay this other project but let's
just focus on doing this today so we are
going to write a comment and uncommon
command in
in emac this for the Wolfram language so
let me go let me detail what does it
involve what does your code needs to do
okay for example comment uncommon okay
you can also select
you know part of the text and do call
comment you just comment that part out
fantastic right now it's using the
building right now you see it works but
you know I'm using subwoofer mod and
it's right now I'm implementing it using
the building library
newcommon.el but it's got some problems
let me show you what is a problem okay
so for example I comment out the whole
uh whole line let's say
some more lines here okay
comment
comment okay wait
cut it so I want to make it you know
ufam language common is multi-line
comments so you can comment that way but
then suppose some other thing here so
you know I wrote more code I want to uh
and
turns out I don't
needed okay so I select them I want to
comment again now in Wu fan language
common syntax you can Nest it then you
can Nest them so unlike C or C plus plus
you know for example the
Java
okay where is my uh
who is my asterisk
you know I'm using a glove 80 keyboard
if you don't know already last week I
did a video review I'm gonna show you in
a bit okay so for example here is a
Java comment
uh
yeah you see Java and C comma they
cannot be nested okay that is uh that is
you know that that is not not good
that's a c style that's why I despise CC
plus plus Java those kind of languages
and Unix they are like brainless okay
they are geared they are designed C C
plus plus
uh you know those languages in Java you
know C is a virus then it begets C plus
plus Java JavaScript C sharp you know
all those are
but over the past 20 or 30 years they
improved you know for example Java
about 10 years ago they started to have
Lambda you know but anyway so but you
know the damage is already huge C okay
so anyway you know see okay so
for example you have this comment this
comment I believe it was reading from C
or C plus plus I forgot hello
uh what would you do if money grows you
know it depends so
so uh
um you know one one of the common is
that and the other one is slash slash
okay
uh actually why don't we you know since
we are talking about it let's just go
elaborate let's go um let's look up
Wikipedia because they have a
uh actually it's not go to Wikipedia why
don't we just go to XA
the dot info because I have all these
languages okay uh so Java this is my
Java tutorial this is my Java logo I
designed it to reflect the the
complexity of the Java language I wrote
I did this you know
2008 so the Java comment okay and my
tutorial is pretty old my Java Java
Language tutorial so you can see there
is a common syntax actually I should
make a new page that just describe how
do you do comment in comment in Java so
anyway so here is the Java common syntax
so you have line syntax starting slash
slash or you have the
you know slash asterisk
now one of them is originally from C the
other one is added by C plus plus now I
forgot which one is which let's let you
know just for the sake let's find out
okay
so uh
programming languages Wiki you know
Wikipedia is a whole list of it here and
so comparison programming language
syntax okay uh
uh
that
the reader Wiki these are programming
languages okay there is a page
that needs them okay okay let's take
some time let's just come there it is
common computer programming okay so this
page
uh wait where is my key to magnify
yeah
anyway so
so common computer languages
okay so you can see let's see
[Music]
okay I'm starting to get boring here I
need to move on
syntaxi stage in extension directive
uses uh
normative views needs for common level
of detail block comment okay this is a
common body variation one and this is
the most idiotic ASCII art style comment
that is you use your text to create you
know
to to draw this is okay yeah so this is
from c yeah so the slash asterisk is
from the C programming language and it
cannot be nested okay
so anyway back to back to Common so
it's
but in Wolfram language it can be nested
okay now there is a problem now remember
I'm using the default uh using the emacs
newcomer.el library to implement this
there's a problem so so if I select them
and I want to comment out again the
whole if I do it
okay
it's you know it kind of did it
kind of not there's there are several
issues one is that it does the comment
for each line you see you know instead
of just adding the bracket to the whole
it did it to each line that's not so
good okay the other problem is that you
see it added a backslash here
so that is a problem that is wrong I
mean yeah that is wrong incorrect
because once if you
you know you added backslash that screws
up the nested comment inside so now when
you uncomment uh oh actually it does
work
wait
and
how does it
and let's see
yeah interesting but this shouldn't
happen you know this you know you
shouldn't have a backslash there
okay but it's it's uh it's not a major
issue I I suppose we I can live with it
you know
yeah now if I live with it then we don't
need to write our own comment anymore
uh stand alone comment from scratch
yeah so they are so there are two ways
to go now now if we
still want to if we want to fix this you
know and do and do you see it added an
extra backslash there if we if we want
to fix that there are two ways to go one
is to dive deeper into the new common.el
to see if there's some kind of
configuration
so that it doesn't add these extraneous
backslash that's one way to go the other
way is just write our own you know radar
on is kind of in some sense much simpler
because your code all you have to do is
just write a function basically you
write a function and what the function
will do is just it will check if your
cursor is currently in some kind of
comment so how do you check that all you
have to do is search backward for the
common beginning
such you know and search forward to make
sure there's no it's not bracketed by
Common this sounds easier than it sounds
actually it's a bit more complex when
you code it so first of all determine
your Cruiser is inside the comment if
it's not all you have to do is just add
the Beginning characters and end the
characters either through the region you
know a block of text or to a line okay
that's too common and if your Cruiser is
already inside a comment then you just
find the beginning and end comment marks
and remove them okay
so that is about writing your own common
command from scratch now this is
actually a very good uh emac this
exercise you know I enjoyed writing it
14 years ago because it's it's purely
text processing
okay and you can you can learn a lot
emac this using emac this text
processing powers and functions to write
them okay and I have a tutorial there
so write your own is one solution the
other solution is to look at the
newcomen.el okay
so the new common.el we have to do is
describe key press the key for the
comment and hold on a second let me show
the uh
now here is my back tick character yeah
okay there
okay so you jump to the
my personal comment command wait where
is this emac this okay not this one
actually
so actually you look for newcomer.el
[Music]
and okay let me let me do that okay so
jump took some like keys now I actually
have a wrapper that calls the command
from that package so common dream is the
command from the package newcomen.el
okay common Dash dwim
meaning do what I mean you know that's a
CD hacker type of naming so common dream
is the buildings
command in emacs that does common in
uncommon in my case I wrote a wrapper so
that I can just toggle because the
common dream default beat Behavior it
doesn't toggle it you know it requires
more keystrokes okay so anyway so common
dream you so now you describe function
common dream to look up its
documentation and then you just tap
enter to jump to the source code okay so
we can see here's the documentation
common dream
so what now we're doing now is to you
know look at this package
yeah okay
let's just look at this package let's
see is there anything interesting is
there something configuration we can do
oh look there's a fix me
okay so yeah
okay let's
let's do
that then so today I was planning to
code emac beasts but I think we're gonna
end up just
talking about it looking you know
talking about it okay so any comments
and questions posted okay for people
watching now the keyboard I'm using okay
so let me show you the keyboard I'm
using I want to promote it because I
think it's a great keyboard and they
give it to me
so I did a video review
last week so this keyboard this keyboard
I'm using is called glove 80. so you can
go to my website and read all the
reviews okay and there is a video I did
last week so you can watch it full
that's one hour review
you know it's pretty long and in-depth
one I'll review okay check it out
uh glove 80 keyboard okay so we open
last closed copy the URL back to emacs
close this page now go to guitar talk
show today's talk show here there is
already a link here okay so now show
this in browser so what to do next
okay we were planning to write a command
comment on common command but
turns out
uh turns out
the way it is is kind of okay
so
emacs blog close it switch to it switch
to yeah
minor problem but it's okay
so let's see the comment let's just look
at the source code then any quick
questions in common ask me okay
so
so the whole thing is 1500 lines who
wrote it Stephen Marnier
uh emac lisp master
I respect Heidi you know he is also a
professor of functional programming
research in Canada I believe Montreal
University
and he has been the leader you know the
main leader of canoe emacs development
for about seven years
2008 to 2000
[Music]
2016 something like that okay Stefan
Mania okay so he wrote this actually
when
wow 1999 wait no he's uh okay he's a
maintainer
okay
uh
so let's see so there's a question you
know usually I look at lisp code
so right now my issue is
do I want to fix this
you know maybe not
you know you should you know of course
but you know you got a lot things to do
you know I got a lot of things to do I
got uh
wufam language a lot of coding and let
me talk random a bit then
okay
for example let me tell you about
fantastic uh Wolfram language I did okay
so and uh math okay
so for example example
yesterday you know today if you the you
know in the past few days we did this
fantastic Wolfram language Graphics this
is geometric inversion okay
you know you talk to the CC plus people
Unix people they don't understand they
have an idea they wouldn't appreciate it
but this you know we did this and it's
just five lines of code basically you
can actually two line two three you know
I mean you can make it one line so you
can generate you know is extremely
beautiful that's geometric inversion
okay so we did several videos of it you
know this one is from last year Wolfram
language
and then we did a you know we did this
one about a few days ago
you know beautiful you know it's this
this you know actually I would say
geometric inversion the function is
actually if I have to say one pick one
that's my favorite mathematical function
yeah of all math functions of my 20 30
years of studying math I would say
geometric immersion is my favorite
mathematical function
the idea the concept is just beautiful
and creates beautiful things okay so so
I did this video you know you you guys
go check it out ufam language is a term
rewriting system so it's nothing like
you never experienced before okay and 10
times
100 times more
more high level than Pascal lisp
commonly skinless whatever okay 100
times no kidding depends you know not
even counting the ability to solve
differential equations so linear algebra
or Matrix equations you know those are
mathematical functions one line you can
you know if you are gonna Implement
those you know doing derivatives
integrals or solve differential
equations that's literally ten thousand
one hundred thousand lines for each one
of those functions okay and by default
uframe language has 7 000 functions
building
okay so those are mathematical functions
each one is like you know 100
000 lines of
let's say each one of them but let's not
count those you know let's not count
those that do mathematical functions you
know let's just count the for example
the functions that manipulate the least
you know delete best you know take a
slice of these things like that
in that case we'll find language each
each one line of a wolf and language is
equivalent to let's say 10 lines or 100
lines of python okay it is incredible
so that's why I'm saying so anyway so I
was saying you know
uh you can check them out and yesterday
I was you know in Wolfram the guy which
is one of the guy one of the guy you
know one one of those you know five or
ten top five
scientists I truly I have the most
respect and whose point of view of the
world on Artificial Intelligence on the
Universe on how physics how mathematics
is I mostly agree on I share a lot of
the way he look at things you know I
truly do and his style you know his
design of wolfam language the naming of
functions you know each you know each
programming language may it be Larry was
Pearl you know guide over just some
idiots his python you know the Java Java
is very formal I mean yeah Java you know
the naming the the the the kind of style
how you name your functions
in a programming language reflect kind
of the author you know the creator of
the language their view of how you know
things okay so Wolfram language you know
if you like look at wufan languages
um this this is fantastic okay let me
let me show you
if you look at wolfam language
um
uh you have
you know the the naming of the functions
the style how they name things I very
like it I like it very much that's
the way I look at things Okay naming of
things you know I can give you some
examples that but that would be another
topic okay and you know and this relates
to
jargons the use of jargons in
programming
community and in programming languages
and in the programming field in general
there's a lot to talk about it
scientific jargons you know the other
day I was debating with
with you know with a bunch of my you
know people on Discord you know many of
my friends people on Discord
um debating arguing about the mega by
its gigabyte meat versus maybe bite You
Know Me Maybe by kiwi bites
very interesting you know that so that's
related scientific jargon you know it's
it there's a lot to talk about that you
know how you name things how you you
know when should the jargon be
um named and how should it be named you
know things like that
so anyway we will we are going over oh
God so today's
um
so let's go back to this a little bit I
guess oh well okay yeah so what I want
to say is that there is wufan
Stefan Wolfram wrote these three parts
fantastic you know uh
blog
you know each one of his blog is like
100 pages so for me to typically to read
one of his blog it will take several
hours and that just first
scam scan scheming you know several
hours so this one
covers you know the title is how did we
get here the Tangled history of the
second law of
Thermodynamics okay I don't know physics
I don't know physics my you know I don't
know physics too much at all so but you
know but I have read you know he I have
read lots of whether he's on math on
Logic on artificial intelligence those
things I know a lot more okay but anyway
physics you know so I'm you know
typically I'm very it's just amazed by
the quantity I mean the the style and
the depth
um
of his
scholarship okay and also his style you
know his style is somewhat like you know
he is someone like my my the oh the way
I prefer where you address to the people
directly and communicate in the most
simple words possible what you are
trying to say not the typical
traditional scientific jargons which you
usually stick with a traditional style
otherwise your thesis won't pass you
know won't get out then it's it's
bottled up or okay so anyway
anyway I digress so
so I recommend this article okay so this
so for example in this article
there are three parts and it turns out a
few hundred Pages all together like one
thousand one thousand Pages or something
uh and this deep deep scholarship you
know for example all these signatures
these are by the people the scientists
who are you know known you know who are
in the study of heat thermodynamics okay
so that's the signature you know you
have to get you know this is this this
is just just on this page just on this
page alone it's not trivial things to do
okay you gotta get those people are dead
you know those are 1800s 1900s
scientists you know these people
uh s cannot William this this is Kevin I
think you know the Kevin known for the
cabin temperature you know these these
people you know and Max Maxwell
these people are well known scientists
you have to get the their signature and
a lot historical documents you know
so in this page in this part of the
article he's trying to tell you
essentially he's giving you an overview
of the history of the second law of
Thermodynamics okay so I don't know
physics myself but from reading this
I learned that you know Heat
thermodynamics is basically the study of
heat okay so what is heat what is heat
it turns out it's very quite interesting
it's it's and there's a lot still
unsolved questions okay so anyway he's
giving you a history kind of how how did
the uh you know uh second law of
Thermodynamics aren't were developed and
all the historical documents ratings
it's very interesting because you can
read them you can see some of them are
in English Okay so for example this one
this one is in Latin I guess
you know but some of them are in English
so you can see how people write back
then
of course if you know you you if you are
a mathematician if you are a PhD
um if you study a lot a lot math you
should have done this I mean you should
have seen this uh
yourself I mean uh anyway so anyway so
these are you know many of the relevant
Snippets you know here
so yeah I just so I want to say you know
I'm I always enjoyed reading his stuff
okay so and you know I know him so well
you know because I read Stefan Wolfram
you know I met him
in 1995 because I went to work for wufam
research
I was I was in intern supposed to stay
there for two months but I end up
staying for half a year and uh
was going to stay but you know yeah and
then
you know a long story but then I I I I
left because I was planning I was
supposed to I was supposed to go to UC
Berkeley but I didn't go anywhere that's
my life wondering always wondering about
so anyway so I
you know and I have been reading Stefan
Wolfe since about
1992. all the article I can find you
know so I'm that type of person Stephen
Wolfram and another guy I've read I have
read tremendously is Steve Jobs for
example all the articles I can find you
know Steve Jobs I highly admire Steve
Jobs and another guy is Richard slowman
I have read entirety basically of his
writings
of those you can find
mostly online around the year 2000 you
know the that which means the entire
canoe website free software Foundation
you know
yeah but Richardson you know today is
not too good a person I don't admire you
know I don't
I admire Stefan wolfheim very much still
and Steve Jobs I also admire and I think
both of them are great person but not
Richard Stoneman yeah richest woman I
was
I don't I don't admire him
I don't think he's good he I don't think
he's doing good things to humanity now
so anyway back to um
so I was saying so I read a lot of
writings of Stefan woofer so I kind of
know
a lot about him you know as far as the
scientific his scientific work you know
yeah not not personally not not not his
family or whatever but as far as he he's
public you know right inside no a lot
his style he's thinking his view about
you know lots of things
um
so what was I going to say so
so yeah so he wrote These you know three
a Trilogy you might you might call a
Trilogy or Trilogy of the second law of
Thermodynamics okay I'm still reading it
I haven't finished I spent several hours
I'm still reading it
but okay so you see right now we are
only have you know we are not even
halfway through this article
so lots of things okay
people
and here look at this one the logic of
chance an essay by who is this Zhang
then
is that a guy famous for the Venn
diagram
Randomness and its scientific
treatment okay Randomness is a such a
fascinating topic okay logic of chance
an essay on the foundation and province
of the theory of probability
with a special
reference to its logical
bearings and its application to moral
and social science into statistics you
know you can read
this so this is from 1888 1888 so this
is about 100 years ago the the way
you know they you know the different era
they have a different view of you know
the world so
the logic of a chance
and and here then you have this um you
know this I suppose that's a random walk
you know a very interesting diagram
so what is he saying James crook Maxwell
Zhang van you know yeah so John Wayne is
the Venn diagram yeah I'm pretty sure
English mathematician and logician best
known for the Venn diagrams okay which
can be used to visualize one or not okay
so let's go back
interesting so it uh it's so there is a
yeah so about John Vin a random walk
very interesting Okay so
so I recommend okay for those of you out
there young people you know or
fantastic spectacular you know uh
scholarship digging out the history of
the second law of Thermodynamics okay
now okay so this article is long we are
you know we are just halfway in it so
let's go to the top so let's go to the
top let me tell you some of his other so
this is part three then you go to part
one part one is the part he is the most
um
excited about in fact you know because I
know his style so well I kind of know
the way he how he thinks you know part
one so three parts okay part three and
part three are actually previewed to
part one part one
the title is computational foundations
for the second law of Thermodynamics
that's actually that's the real thing he
wanted to say so basically you know
again this is like 50 pages you know 50
you know look at look at this diagram
he's um this is done by wufam language
of course a fantastic facilities for uh
graphical programming you know
visualization
so anyway this is the main thing he
wanted to say he want to you know he's
you know in the past you know
his life his Stefan wolfham's life's
obsession is About Cellular automata and
uh basically in his view you can use
cellular automata to model the universe
and not just model in fact he believes
that the universe or the fundamental
Theory of physics is actually the
universe is just a computation so
so starting with you know his public
location the new
the new um
the new kind of science which I have
read several times
hello guys what are some good ways to
grow money
low carb
okay
so
I've been rambling all over
and uh I think we shut down in five or
five or ten minutes okay
yeah okay so
yeah we we begin to write emac this but
um
oh yeah so I want to show you a new kind
of science so just go to saudi.info you
can search it there yeah okay let's just
search it here
new science so you can see
notes on the new kind of science so this
is this book is I think it's a thousand
or two thousand Pages you know this
thick I forgot heavy I I have it
somewhere you know put away I read it
more than once you know two or three
times cover to cover okay so I have you
know so beginning with this work so
Stephen Wolfram is obsessed with
cellular automata
and you know not just cellular automata
but he is interested in computation
computation the
well basically
automata okay basically simple
computation that you know you just
compute and cellular automata is a
specific
kind of it where you you know you kind
of draw things on a cell and
you know and they evolve you can see
them evolve according to very simple
rules the rules are just like a program
you know
so he's into you know computation and
his view is that you know beginning with
this you know this was published in 2002
around there but in the previous 10
also years he been
studying this a lot you know with he
also created you know he created the
entire field of
complexity Theory okay he has he created
a journal of it and so on
then with then this book came out then
he still studied this you know and then
in the past few years he started to
create a physics project that
basically tries to find to basically try
to model the universe
you know
asking answering all the questions in
traditional physics
by basing it on
simple programs okay that's essentially
what he's saying he's doing you know and
that research you know starting like
four years five years ago that turns out
to then then it turns out then then it
turns out he also started to have a you
know it branched out into a
structure of meta mathematics that is a
foundation for mathematics for example
you know we have proof Theory we have
proof systems we have you know model
Theory proof Theory we have you know all
category Theory or you know sequence
calculus in logic and and
homotopy type
foreign
type Theory you know all these are kind
of proof system proof theories but you
know it's like they all have some
problems which each one is not perfect
if you add this then it's more powerful
then something is missing things like
that so he also created
a kind of meta
framework that
gives you a insight about why why you
have all these different proof systems
you know
so it's kind of meta so it's it's you
know
and so so that's one branch of it meta
mathematics and what he would call
rudiology okay I'm not gonna explain
then the other another Branch branched
out is the you know he wanted to find
the fundamental uh
Theory Theory you know the grand
Theory of Everything You know basically
that's that's dramatic um that's a
dramatic question
but basically he wanted to
create physics entirely
with the by the foundation using the
foundation of
of simple programs uh the way the the
the particular one he want to base on is
multi-graph okay it's called
hypergraph okay hypergraph you know it's
just a it's like a graph okay so anyway
I'm rambling a lot uh I don't think I'm
going what so I lost
um
how many people are watching for
okay I think I'm just gonna shut down
what else you guys have to say any
questions comments
so yeah so I was going to say
that he wrote this article
you know um
on the second law of Thermodynamics but
you know but if you just look at the
graphics
you know just you suppose you ignore
everything else he says because he's
creating a grand Theory kind of and uh
to some traditional physicists
they've they you know they may think
this is uh
this is not so valid you know they may
think that this is not too useful to the
traditional physicists
or mathematicians
so if you but if if you just so even if
you ignore whatever he's trying to say
simply look at the graphics now this
Graphics this is the the the the most
pestant visualization ever okay look at
those Graphics okay
not not easy and also if you ignore all
the
physics things or thermodynamics things
he's saying you just look at this
whatever he's saying
purely with respect to Cellular automata
or simple computation so it's very
interesting you know how would things
you know you begin with this pattern
given with these rules for example
here's a visual clue of how they evolve
so
you start with a pattern then you have
these rules how would it become what
would it become so you have so that's
how you have all these Graphics okay
and so if you look at his article purely
from this point of view computations
simple computation cellular automatic
automata okay it's just amazing okay
it's non-trivial work non-trivial work
you know if you are a scientist you can
just publish publish this by itself
without
dragging into thermal you know without
trying to say you are actually modeling
thermodynamics so physics okay
so it's I think it's so that's um
so I think it's very
um interesting and uh fruitful and
research now I don't know you know I
don't know whether he's
you know he's you know the universe you
know he this you know he's his theory is
going to be the actually
critical
for the future you know he's saying that
we have a multi-computational paradigm
now and today he says that we are
entering into an era of
Multicultural multi-computational
Paradigm okay and he is saying that
you know his theory his you know he's I
don't know how how big this
is you know his
his his physics project
but I you know so I don't know about
that but I know
for certainty this is a this is a
non-trivial uh you know this is a
non-trivial research just just just
purely from the cellular automata and
computer graphics and programming
language point of view okay you know you
look at those python you know JavaScript
you know D
d3js you know all those fancy things
this is 10 times better
uh you know
so
yeah so very interesting and here he's
you know I read a part of this article
here he's talking about
reversibility you know
equilibrium and you know very
interesting about how
how you can you know you cannot create a
rule that reverses you know things like
that okay
um
yeah so you know so this is a huge huge
article okay it takes many many days to
read them
I only you know and look look at look at
these Graphics okay this is
how long does it take to to do this okay
if you don't have Mathematica if you
don't have Wolfram language this take
you a days to to design redesign retro
this this kind of thing but with wufan
language it's much easier but still I
mean even still
it's not that trivial okay
yeah so amazing amazing uh I I find it
just amazing okay uh
yeah so you know
oh and here is a compression okay for
example
he you know he started with a simple
compression scheme where he explained
here okay something then he tries to
compress the image on the left
compress each line
and on the right is the result okay so
you can see
when there's more pattern on the top you
know the compression result is very
small you know you've got a great
compression but when the pattern becomes
kind of randomish
then you don't you don't have much
compression especially you know when
it's totally random
you know so very interesting uh things
even if you are not a physicist okay I I
think that's very interesting
so I'm just
yeah okay so I'm just saying you know my
random comments on his Stefan wolfram's
walk
foreign
with a new keyboard yeah well look at
you know look at my
my reviews of it last week okay
okay so today I think that's it for
today thank you guys for watching you
know I started to
do emac this and turns out we don't need
to do it
um
okay so that's it for today yeah
okay so this common.el newcomer.el is
written by Stephen Marnier which is
great
uh so actually
yeah I will have to spend time to
actually
look over it I never did so
to see
if to see that
to see that if we're gonna write a
you know to see that if we're gonna
to see that if I should use it or not oh
look at here is Pascal for example in
his Pascal this this are possible
okay so here is bugs Sparks comments in
Pearl are not properly uncommented
because they are uncommented one line at
a time honestly commenting sgml mod are
not properly quoted okay problems
uh uncommon region okay common symptoms
common coldness they will not encode
properly
okay
bye guys
yeah closing shutting down in two
minutes or so
okay so close that close that
so some common dream close that okay
here's sample
sample comment in Wolfram language
and cut it close it
okay now let's go to talk show
and open this
and then it's just
put a wolf and language code paste it
there
cut it
showing browser
okay
thanks bye bye