welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh I had some mistake earlier so I'm
three four minutes late sorry about that
and so I'm not sure what's the topic
today Julian Assange has been arrested
about seven eight hours ago about four
o'clock
well yeah three o'clock in the morning
here so that is like eight hours ago
that's too bad but hope hopefully
something good will come out of it and
today so let's see how many people are
watching zero okay yeah because I did
some mistakes audio and so are we gonna
talk about today so they are you know a
lot of topics if you you know just type
a topic you know talk in the in the box
hey guys three people great let me pop
the window out so hi guys what we cannot
have talk about today go to the saw talk
show page and pick a topic like I'm I'm
not feeling like well you pick a topic
because because today hi good morning
Isaak good morning good morning so Isaac
so what topic to talk about today
technical first of all technical and
non-technical and so if technical then
is it do you would you like to be in
learning languages
okay learning programming languages
English language like natural languages
human languages any languages I think
you mean English like natural languages
right because that's one of the topics I
have here refresh yes some new language
so so many topics here running learning
language yeah okay okay so great thank
you so let's talk about that
so I well you you are Chinese right what
you are born in USA or you know a lot of
people like to learn language well for
example in in Chinese people in China or
Taiwan they want to learn English and
Americans Americans usually don't learn
ABC American born Chinese okay so you
know usually American don't learn they
you know so called people ridicul
Americans like us Americans as
monolingual you know speaks only one
language which is actually true but that
is also there is a reason for that
because USA you know it's like the most
powerful language powerful country and
typically when you want to learn another
language you usually want to learn you
know people want to learn you know the
the language of the power of powerful
country and that's USA so we don't have
to learn another language but also
another important reason is that USA is
you know is just this big land between
oceans there's no other countries I mean
other than Mexico below and Canada
speaks English so there is no need I
mean need need is the mother of
everything so you Americans USA
Americans you don't have you don't
really have a need you know first of all
your language your country is the more
our country is the most powerful in a
world and our language is the
international language basically and we
don't have name
buzz that don't you know we basically
don't have neighbors except Mexico so we
don't have the need to learn another
language well it's you know they say in
school in high school universities
usually there's a requirement to learn a
language but yeah but that's just an
academic talk you know in practice
nobody really actually learned much of
any other language in contrast to Europe
for example Europe you got you know this
bunch of countries you know English UK
is English English German you know
Italian French and other countries and
other faces you know for example in
China China is also one giant big land
but China is not you know or was not you
know one of the most powerful countries
so they had to learn English in fact a
lot Chinese people in Taiwan people oh
you know you learned English as a Second
Language because excuse me that extends
your you know when you do business
extends your power so okay let me talk
about how to learn a language
okay now I'm also talking to Chinese
people who like to learn English because
I have a lot of Chinese followers now
when you want to now this is for my
experience and also for my readings okay
when you learn a language notice you
know there's listening skills the this
listening skills listen and speaking
skills you know and you have reading and
writing now first of all you want to
note that this reading and writing
versus listening and speaking is
entirely different thing almost to the
degree that almost they have nothing to
do with each other now if you are a nerd
okay typically if you are intro
introvert or programmer you know the
type of people you tends to
focused on reading and writing skills
you know a lot Chinese people in fact in
China or Taiwan they learned English
they they can write perfect in English
English they can read you know English
but they cannot speak and they don't
understand when you talk to them you
know I mean yeah so there's a big
difference we couldn't well if you are
introvert you tend to learn you know by
you know the grammar you know vocabulary
you know reading reading skills and and
then you get into writing skills but
they are entirely different from
listening and speaking skills like is
like totally different totally different
in a sense not just for learning but
actually it has to do with linguistics
how languages are because if you look at
the world's languages of course every
languages you can speak it but often
languages do not have a way to write it
down there is no writing system for the
language the writing system developed
later is sometimes much later like you
know a thousand years later and and if
you look at all the words languages tip
often you know there are few writing
systems they borrow you know like for
example you can write you can write you
know you can write Chinese actually in
Latin alphabet in English and you can
write you know the Arabic alphabet is is
used by many languages to to write to
write their language the Arabic alphabet
let's go to let's show unicode so arabic
so tibetan so arabic yeah so this is
called arabic script they are not an
alphabet yet so writing systems of the
word first of all you have what so
called a script then from this script
this is a rebek script for example from
this script you have
alphabets like a part of it or whole of
it makes one off a bit then another
language may pick another off of it so
you have a really big alphabet
so anyway arabic language arabic script
is is used in a big language and and
it's it's a writing system for arabic
language but as also as well for person
info for all these languages first you
know percy on kurdish as a Johnny
Sydney you know for a bunch of languages
in Turkish answer and even for Spanish
for a few you know for a period of times
Spanish is written in Arabic script and
and these languages they are not in a
sim family not net you know like some of
the Frank languages or even though their
writing system used the same system like
looks the same to if you don't know the
language but however they the languages
are not from this may not be from the
same family like totally different
languages they share not almost nothing
but they use the same writing system and
in the same way Japanese you know
Japanese writing system borrows lots of
Chinese characters you know you see
Japanese for example this is let's go to
Japanese quick Chinese Japanese oops so
so the these are Japanese phonetic
systems that's part of the Japanese
writing system but however Japanese also
uses Chinese characters let me show you
four Japanese of for example Japanese
Japanese writing system is made of made
of composed of phonetic alphabet
which are these you know red and blue
both of them and Chinese characters in
Chinese characters and English alphabets
yeah in fact Japanese writing system
they include you know English alphabet
is like part of the Japanese writing
system so if you read Japanese
newspapers you will see that this is a
percentage you know forty one percent of
them is Chinese characters
thirty-six so forty one percent forty
percent is Chinese and forty percent is
actually the phone Japanese phonetics
these called hiragana and katakana and
the rest is like 13 percent penetrations
so you got one percent English letters
so anyway so that's you know Japanese
writing system in Japanese in Chinese
they are completely different languages
they have nothing you know in common
like they don't they don't share a root
so you know for example that's that's
Japanese and let's look at another
example let's let's look at oh wait wait
a second you know here is an example
text of Japanese from Wikipedia now you
can see some of these characters I I can
read them like this one this one
basically the complex looking ones let
me magnify hold on second so that one so
this one means actually me copy it here
so you can see in Emacs go to here open
a new buffer paste enlarge enlarged
image so these two actually let's make
it HTML
okay so for example these two highlight
phrase highlights anyway so these these
two characters these two characters this
two this two characters means machine
these two characters means finger this
character means press okay like pressing
it down and I'm just reading the
characters I know that's which are
Chinese these four characters means
means symbols and signals these two
characters means delivery and mail this
character means sample these two means
means writing system these two means
basic these two means machine and this
means these four characters means
operation operating on the whole thing
and this character means use so you see
you know I know I know them because they
are Chinese characters you know they are
borrowed you know from a thousand year
ago something like that from China and
so before that you know Japanese do not
have a writing system you know for maybe
your thousand years or something
Japanese like you you know the language
to not have a writing system you cannot
write it down you can talk to it but but
you cannot write it down so but Japanese
you know borrowed the Chinese characters
then they started to use Chinese
characters as their writing system even
the two languages are entirely different
and then then they created their
phonetic system which is you know these
parts you know those are Japanese
phonetics phonetics is like alphabets
designed to represent sound so these are
Japanese phonetics hiragana and katakana
and and where does this came from they
are invented they are invented based on
you know they take they take part of
Chinese character you know and and I
mean they are created so they take they
are based on Chinese characters they
take part of the Chinese characters then
they assign a sound to it and and that's
arrangin the japanese phonetic system
hiragana and katakana so yeah so that's
an example where you know that the
writing system you know how the language
is written down is entirely almost
basically almost entirely has nothing to
do with the language itself so that's an
example of Japanese another good example
is critic I think it's pronounced critic
but I never know how to pronounce it hey
Daniel
hey Daniel Anglo is so let's see how we
pronounce critic okay like usually
wikipedia has magnify magnify usually a
Cyrillic okay it's pronounced Cyrillic
because there is the international
phonetic alphabet here's C relic okay so
the Cyrillic script are these and the
Russian you know the Russian alphabet is
is is based on it in so it's used in
these countries by despite you know
Russia and it's used in all these
languages this so it's used in Belarus
on Bulgarian Macedonian Russian was sing
sbatch and you know and so Ukrainian and
and this
you know I cannot it's hard to even
pronounce them but notice and even used
to among Mongolian Romani and so on but
notice that these two groups of
languages are entirely different
so Russian and so on they are Slavic
languages Slavic languages and the other
one you know the other group of
languages are not known Slavic so they
they don't share the same root so I mean
so my point is you know deepness of the
writing system how a language is written
down is entirely different from from the
language itself yeah so when you learn a
language you know first first of all
know that writing writing and reading is
an entirely different skill then
listening and speaking now depending on
what you what what's your goal in
learning a language okay
good morning Duncan depending on what
you're going in on your language you
might focus on one aspect than the
others for example if you want to travel
if you want to travel right you know or
if you want to do business then Yoko is
probably listening and speaking skills
that's that's the part you want to focus
small if you are a nerd you know if you
are academic you know you read all day
like me yes we you don't go out you know
you program you know then you are more
inclined to focus on reading reading and
writing you know you can read all the
history of Japanese read all the history
of German you know language you know the
you know Spanish you know
yeah but they are entirely different
skills so the next subject is to how do
you learn them yeah first of all decide
you know which one you want to focus you
know don't think that you know you just
read a lot you know let's say I'm going
to learn
let's say I'm going to learn Russian
okay I don't know nothing about Russian
so I'm going to you know like typically
I would you know start to read Wikipedia
and you know start to read novels you
know try to look up words vocabulary you
know that's one thing but I will not be
able to understand when the ocean you
know in here talks to me it would be
hard you know even though whatever the
person says if he write it down I'll
understand everything but if he doesn't
write it down I would have a hard time
to kind of you know like it's a skill
you know listening is a skill you have
to kind of you you you you want to be
able to understand what they say like
you should I mean usually they don't
they don't say it slowly like in reading
and writing you can always take your
time to look up dictionary you know the
word is fully spelled you know but in in
real conversations they are now going to
stop in spirit for you you know you have
this so it's a skill listening and you
know speaking so it's it's a different
skill so if you I mean so if you are a
businessman or something or traveling
you want to pick up the listening and
you know speaking skills which is most
suitable for intro for extrovert type of
people you know social social people
social butterfly in fact a lot of people
you know I think most people are
actually more extrovert than introvert
nerds are introvert and introvert is is
a smaller percentage of the population
you know most people for majority of
people they they like to talk to people
you know they don't you know they don't
have in in in you know they don't feel
shy or things like that
so listening and and speaking skills now
okay so first of all decide which part
you want to focus you know don't think
that you can just learn to read and
you'll be able to speak well or listen
well no that's not true at all you know
because I learned English
you know I'm a nerd I'm an introvert and
I learning English mostly by looking up
dictionaries you know brute force just
look up you know was hundred times a day
but I cannot understand news
you know when the TV is on the the the
the the anchor you know talk I don't
understand more than you know sixty
percent of it
like eighty percent of it after three
years I don't understand you know cuz
they they speak too fast but but okay I
always want whenever I watch American
movies this is like thirty years ago I
watch American movies so TV's I always
want the subtitle because that's power
to me because I read the subtitle I then
I understand you know each one I can
pause I understand each word but when
they are talking I I don't understand
you know so because of this habit that's
damaging you know because then then you
know it you know then my listening
skills and speaking skill skills they
they kind of stagnated you know they you
know you know because so yeah so so you
know make make sure you want to learn
you know focus on the part you want in
fact I would say you know at least
listening and speaking skill is actually
the most the more important one because
that that is what language is about you
know right writing system doesn't come
doesn't come up and here you know and
even today some languages do not have a
writing system I think that's true yeah
some languages do not even have a
writing system
you know writing system is like
secondary they came after the first the
first requirement the development you
know the or engine of language is to
speak you know you talk to people you
see face to face you speak you
communicate that's the first yet so
that's probably actually what you should
focus more especially for nerds because
you know you don't talk to people so for
many people they are natural you know
they talk to people and you
okay so let me talk about how to do it
how to learn this to ski to reading and
reading and listening and speaking the
food but first let me read the comments
so Duncan say studied German then later
Japanese during school but forgot
ninety-five percent of it due to not
using them yeah that's that's correct
because if you don't use them you lose
them you know when I was younger I
thought you know you know muscle
building like you know I was into that
and confu you know how they call that
muscle building bodybuilder yeah body
building it's you know it's a it's
actually it's kind of a idiom body
building you know you you you build your
muscles you know those muscle man you
know mr. universe like Arnold
Schwarzenegger you know once you have
that muscle and if you don't keep
building it after like half a year in
fact it it's it goes it goes away very
fast after you know just a few months if
you don't exercise all your muscle would
the poke they go away yeah
so I first learned that you know many
years ago when I was younger I was
surprised you know oh man you had it
went away you so if you want the muscles
you have to keep working on it every day
so in in a similar way you know if you
don't use it it is it goes away however
it does not go away 100% you know like
once you know how to ride a bike if even
you if you haven't done so for 20 years
you still have some kind of muscle
memory you know you you just have to go
back to it then after month you know for
bicycles after a few days you get get it
same thing I think it's the same thing
with programming programming languages
and natural language as well you know if
you know folks I programmed in Perl for
many years
but now if you ask me to code say okay
you know if you ask me to curl some
simple program in Perl
you know I wouldn't know how to write a
loop right you know you forgot you have
to you know but you have to look up you
know but but but mostly the skill I mean
there's still memory in so so you know
if you know a language you haven't used
it for many years but you can pick it up
much faster you know then if you are new
like 10 times faster because it's you
see a fat memory but anyway so so yeah
that's one thing you don't use them you
know that that's why in America you know
most people do not speak other languages
because you don't there's no need I mean
except maybe Spanish you know this
because there's a lot of Spanish people
in America so if you have Spanish
friends or girlfriends or boyfriends or
neighbors you know you can exercise that
I learned Spanish actually I learned
Spanish when I was in Paraguay South
America for like one year why in half
year and Central America so when I was
16 you know I learned fairly you know
some Spanish you know for one year over
a year but now it's like oh it's all
forgotten so daniel says writing being
entirely different from the language
itself is a rather strange distinction
daniel says I think you might be
emphasizing that written language is an
invented technology a relatively young
upstart so language didn't start with
writing yeah and writing is evolving to
a fly by the seat of your pants
what do you mean
okay so one tip I want to say about
learning learning English for example
another language like if you guys watch
movies I mean when I was young I watch a
lot of movies you know American movies
like superhero movies you know
back in the day there is no super hero
movies yet you know super superhero
movie students began didn't really begin
until like year 2000 when you have x-men
the first x-men well there's a couple of
Superman before but basically you know
not like today you have all the
superheroes but you know so when you
watch movies make sure okay this is a
good make sure that you always turn the
subtitle off you know like watch a movie
is just an entertainment right you saw
so don't worry about you know not
understand it understand you know not
understand what the movie is about it's
just entertainment so turn that subtitle
off when you watch your movie I mean if
you are if you want to learn the
language if you want to improve your
listening skills turn the subtitle of
never watches subtitle just listen you
know just don't worry about you know
don't like that you don't even have to
like think like that oh I'm going to
learn English therefore you know I'm
going to you know like just let it play
yeah what one of the important skill in
in sharpening your listening skill is
that you know for example just turn on
radio you know if you're learning
Spanish for example just turn on the
radio let's put it on a Spanish station
and just let it play every day just let
it play you don't have to don't even
think about trying to understand what oh
you are learning no forget about it just
let it play in the background you know a
language that actually that actually you
know the sound actually get
into your brain and then even you know
you know after week you you you'll
notice some phrase that appeal often
then you can you know look up like then
after you know you can like immediately
repeat it you know you can like just
repeat the phrase but you don't know
what it means that's okay
you know just first of all you know then
you can look up you know of course you
can look up or ask your Spanish friends
so you know but but that's yeah that's
an important thing to learn listening
skills you know just let let the
language pray you know that's and when
you watch movies yeah don't don't don't
turn on subtitle just let it play and
you watch especially movie movie
especially TV drama okay for example if
you want to learn Chinese you know they
are there thousands ten thousand
millions of Chinese TV dramas and
besides movies you know this is kung fu
movies but besides kung fu movies
there's like ten thousand you know
millions of Chinese TV dramas of all
kinds Oh Japanese anime you know a lot
of you probably watch Japanese anime so
you turn off the subtitle just very
afraid when when you know when you want
to learn Japanese so that's a good thing
to do now the other thing is that okay
listening and listening and speaking
skills they two are different so when
you keep listening maybe you can
understand the language you know but if
you never speak if you don't speak much
you will not improve your speaking
skills much because a swinging skills is
about your shaping your mouth you know
to be proficient about you know
pronouncing you know shaping your
muscles and change them quickly to fit
that language so if you if you do not
speak much you don't gain that skill
speak you don't gain speaking skill so
again don't think that learning
languages you know you can just read a
lot or you know they are all come
together know
if you just read you don't have
listening or speaking skills if you just
listen you don't have speaking skills
meaning that when you speak the natives
you know the language speak they don't
understand you because your
pronunciation is just wrong it's too
much of you know so you have to practice
that so yeah so I think that's about it
that's what I have to say about
languages listen you know learning a
foreign language you know this stage
they are turn tons of YouTube videos
like thousands they teach they teach you
languages they they talk about
linguistics I mean there are so many
things okay so there are linguistic
experts for example let's go to YouTube
for example
linguistics actually I subscribe to this
guy let's look at so how many people are
watching so guys say something okay let
me know what you think and let me know
your comments opinions and what's the
next topic we're going to talk about so
Isaac says do you know anything about
coach aqua haha
no not really is that your family
background no I don't really know that
dialect that's a dialect of Chinese and
spoken mostly in Taiwan I think yeah I
was confused about that I I can I can
understand most
Taiwanese of Fujian dialect but not that
I think not Kuja
come on don't well what does it have on
quad table event okay it ended on
yes I understand Cantonese and Taiwanese
but I don't I don't see I don't speak
them not you know pretty bad just a
little so let's look at so there you see
so are you learning Chinese Isaac so by
the way do you know so Chinese you know
so Chinese if you want to learn speaking
and understanding Chinese that's not too
hard
okay that's well it's it's probably
harder than if you learn Spanish from
four Americans you know it's easier to
learn Spanish than learning Chinese but
however still if we are talking about
listening and speaking Chinese it's not
too hard okay you just want to practice
again like I said before you know there
are a lot YouTube that teaches Chinese
I'll get too into that okay so so it's
not really hard but however the hard
part about Chinese is the reading and
writing that that is very very hard
that's tremendous hard you have to spend
five years you know you let's say you
study two years to two hours a day every
day then after five years maybe you can
read like maybe 60% of newspapers okay
you know maybe you know because Chinese
writing you know Chinese they are you
you have to know at least 3,000
characters so here is Chinese example
for example you know these are
characters and there is no unifying
theme about Chinese characters not
really okay there is some way to
character cat
rise you know Chinese characters by
radicals you know so-called radicals
which is part of the character but they
are in general this knows it's not a
systematic it's not like something like
alphabet
you just put you know letters different
combinations it's not like that at all
and in practice basically every
character is just different there is no
consistency not really okay you
basically you have to learn 3,000
characters just character by character
by rote you just to memorize them that's
how we learned it you know Oh Chinese
I'd you know I was born in Taiwan I grew
up in Taiwan until 14 years old so
that's that's that's how we learn
Chinese you know you just from you know
middle school you know you know grade
school middle school high school you
learn them every day you know you and
then you you learn the characters you
practice writing writing them in you
know that's how you know and you know
3,000 characters is like the minimal the
minimal to to be able to get the sense
of of a Chinese newspaper you know like
what they are talking about and that's
just minimal well to actually you
understand Chinese newspapers you have
to know at least 5000 to understand
let's say 98% okay so yeah so learning
Chinese you know the writing reading
part is that's quite difficult
you know that's even for Chinese I mean
I haven't written Chinese for like 10
years you know for like 30 years you
know actually I can show you me write in
Chinese with this with this device maybe
we can show that let me show you that
some of that because it's fun because
especially I mean
if you are American or you know you
never seen it so it might be fun to show
you how it's done
for example let's go through a Chinese
website okay and I learned you know when
I left Taiwan when I left I won in 1986
around there I wait not Weibo
so that's so here's a Chinese website
you know he's all Chinese characters you
know it's just like you know your new
website for English you understand other
words I do you know again Sanko wait
wait well Auto quick let's turn
that off and skin go back well actually
it's just go to bi do bi do bi do is is
like a search engine a big search engine
used in China you know from China
it's like comparable to Google in you
know in Western countries
so here's by doing what I want to search
you can type English let's say keyboard
okay so you got a bunch of so you know
okay so since I typed English it's it's
it's guessing that you know it's someone
you know who wants to understand the
English word key keyboard so it gives
you kind of like it shows a dictionary
you know so I'm going to read it you
know so champ and change in density Yan
Cheng Han soo young chimpanzee Isis Jeep
IDEs young chimpanzee means house Oh so
a chimp has the G pad so it says you
know keyboard or piano keyboard or you
know your chronic keyboard like music he
bought musical keyboard and Oh as a verb
transitive verb you know it means type
you know using the keyboard to input
using your keyboard to arrange
characters and so on but let's see you
know so keyboard is a boring topic let's
let's try to four okay now let's try to
type keyboard in Chinese so I just you
can see I just switched my input system
to ping right here and let me type it
okay that's the word for keyboard it's
pronounced Cham pan so it's pan PA and
so chimp and that's that's the
pronunciation for that's how you type
Chinese okay so the first one is what I
want and there we have it so if I type
Chinese you know the the website assumes
you know I'm looking for keyboard so
it's you know showing me all this
keyboard yeah this you know Chinese this
many Chinese websites selling keyboards
and so on you know different brands this
brand is like this Co sale I think
that's Co sale name one yes so many oh
this one is Logitech he Logitech G 6 1 0
so yeah so but let's let's see news okay
let's type Trump you know that you know
let's let's see what news they got
Chinese Tran
okay I think yeah that one time poops
you know I'm not very skilled in typing
Chinese because when I was in Taiwan
there's no you know I don't know
computers and in fact Chinese input
system I'm not sure there was before
back in 1985
there probably was but he was not
popular you know PC you know personal
computers just started barely so but I
learned typing Chinese around 2005 you
know just by reading and learning it so
so I can type Chinese but I can write
Chinese of course you know because I
grew up in Taiwan so here is the Trump
you know I just typed Trump in Chinese
Trump's name so here you can see
so here's news Trump's latest news let's
see which one should we pick
[Laughter]
okay here is a clickbait this one says
short why shampoo waste material Sheen
Johansson were tied Samoan Sun tea
everything okay he says why Trump has a
iron hot to to go to war with to go to
economic war with China and this is from
Australia newspaper so this is 2018 much
let's see why it says so apparently this
is a newspaper made newspaper from
Australia and they are published in
Chinese it's magnify
so there it is you know that's stuff so
let's let's read some comment and I'm
going to show how to how to write
Chinese I'm gonna show you that so let's
read the comment yes I'm okay at
Cantonese and Mandarin okay so you can
speak them great so daniel says news
type Assange arrested yeah in Chinese or
in English
nickname who do you subscribe you didn't
finish the topic what do you mean like
who do I subscribe oh yeah that that
yeah yeah
the linguistics thank you for reminding
me so I'm going to show you how to write
Chinese and and now let's go back okay
let's write it down let's go back okay
just write Chinese and show YouTube on
Chinese linguistics
let me gonna show you that thing and one
more thing is I already for god yes
yeah okay so so let's go back to YouTube
so so they are a lot you know huge
amount of things on YouTube and a lot of
language related channels some of them
they teach you a language like Spanish
or Chinese you know there are some
channels that teach you Chinese how to
speak Chinese I haven't watched that
much and there are a lot actually on all
Americans or English speakers who lives
in China and they have
channel and they they they talk about
you know of course they have learned
Chinese you know they lived in China for
many years so so they they talk about
Chinese cultures sometimes in Chinese
sometimes in English sometimes they
teach you let me show you a few okay so
actually so maybe it's here
science consumer electronics classic
music what is this you know Google
Google shows you all these suggestions
okay here is a guy okay he is very
popular
he is extremely popular like millions of
followers so he's a guy from South
Africa you know South Africa is a
country's name you know in the southern
tip of Africa basically and they their
language is English so he's from there
and he lived in China for like ten years
so his channel is you know how many how
many people oh he only got half a
million people subscribers well that's
big enough so he lives you know now he
do YouTube as his profession you know
he's because you know so he he lived in
China for ten years so he I think all
his videos are in English but he talks
about China you know and all kind of
things Chinese girls culture and
whatever so very popular so you have if
you are interested in China
I recommend it you know but however you
know lots of the titles are quick baits
I hate that you know but anyway it's
it's worth watching he's got hundreds of
hundreds of videos so you can check it
out I've watched like you know ten or
twenty of them but I was going to show
you okay let's let's honestly try to
find that linguistic I recently
subscribed to you know like once you
subscribe to one of these channels then
you will find related one easier like
once you subscribe to a channel that's
focus on teaching Chinese for example
then you'll find like other people's
channels doing the same thing you know
start to find so this girl she she she's
American and she lived in China for a
number of years so she speak Chinese so
sometimes in her video she owes
Gio's speak Chinese may be partially or
something so you might subscribe to her
you know and there are a lot of others
you know I noticed because what YouTube
there are billions of videos you don't
you know once you look into then you
discover like entire new world I'm
pretty sure there are quite a lot tens
or hundreds you know of them so so right
now my goal is to find that linguistic
sky okay that guy is another Chinese
very famous in China he he's Canadian so
he went to China and lived there and he
is now doing comedy like stand-up comedy
well let me assure you he's trying to
introduce stand-up comedy to Chinese
audience because China the tradition of
Chinese culture we don't have stand-up
comedy I mean this format doesn't exist
but but he is trying to that to that you
know so this guy you might subscribe and
so what's his name okay LAN focus this
guy now this guy he is a linguist
linguist language expert he does not
really teach Chinese but rather he is a
link linguist so he study all the
world's languages so he tells you you
know he talks about Spanish Turkish you
know is what you know which language is
the easiest to learn Irish oh you know
you know all all of them he also talks
about Chinese you know like that I
watched his video on Chinese and often I
mean even I speak Chinese right you know
I grew up in Taiwan of course for 14
years so but often they you know when
you hear these damn table that you you
know I learn new things because they are
linguistics linguists so they they they
teach you something like if you ever you
know if you're American and you listen
one day to link linguists talking about
English you will learn a lot of things
you don't notice because you know the
language so where you speak it you know
every day but but the linguistics you
know a linguist especially whose first
language is not English you know but he
is a linguist you know he studied
languages their formation the history
comparative linguistics and so on you
know
then when he talks about English you
know you let you you hear oh wow I
didn't know that then you know the
grammar the regularities and so on so
you know it's a similar phenomenon so
for not phenomena so anyway this guy is
a he's a linguist so he talked about
lots of things
now I do not know I actually do not know
you know I have seen them but I actually
do not know offhand YouTube channels
that teaches Chinese
but I you know I've seen them British or
let's say learning Chinese and visual
Chinese for beginners you know yeah
I'm pretty sure they are tons of them
you know this you know just such for
learning Chinese or Chinese for
beginners you know as an example you
know if you are interested in Spanish or
French you know simply in Germany you
can try to learn it that's one way then
I'm going to next topic is I'm going to
show you how to write Chinese for fun so
Isaac says who is the stand-up comedy
person Chuang no no it's this guy his
name is si
okay his name is for the person his name
is Dawson very popular like you know
recognized by China even Chinese news
media you know he's a very well-known
Canadian who lives for a while I think
he he worked as a ambassador for Canada
in China too you know but anyway yeah so
this guy so let me read the comments
British police arrested a bearded and
shouting Julian Assange yeah well we can
talk about a son maybe in the end you
know who is the stand-up comedy person
ok nickname nickname
so I saw I must I just came here to ask
that I would like to see a show on math
in art stuff okay great
today is probably too late how long I've
been talking one hour yeah
so let me do that let me plan to do that
tomorrow so yeah and you know I need to
get on a schedule like you know I wish
my schedule like what time on what date
you know first of all a schedule then
also maybe topics so on this day I'll
talk about that topics and you know
another day I'll be talking about non
technical topics or whatever that would
be good so I guess now let me show let's
show some Chinese characters let me
write it you know so not here let's go
to let's see okay this works file new
before so I need to turn off the auto
click you know I have Auto click on
meaning that when I move my mouse to
where you know when my mouse stops
moving it clicks automatically but
sometimes it's annoying so okay that's
too big let's see
opacity let's first of all pick a pen
and say size
okay it's it's not smooth because I
guess I guess because I have my CPU is
maximum okay but still we can write
Chinese for example let's write these
Japanese on the you know so I'm going to
duplicate some of the Japanese I mean
the Chinese characters
so that's this character so I'm going to
write these two character actually I'm
I'm not it's kind of a slow so I'm not
so let's see this this I'm gonna write
those okay it looks like I need to
adjust size aspect ratio yeah it's not
fast hey I don't want dynamic
okay I have to rise slowly because
otherwise they don't so there it is when
she you know it's not fun if you cannot
write it fast because because then you
don't see the scribbles I mean you don't
see for example ABC okay
ABCD you know because if you write it
fast you can you can see yeah so you
have to write so D you can see yeah it's
not good but anyway yeah well it's not
good because I think because my CPU is
maxed out on a second let me create that
and see if that helps no not really
pressure thickness
okay now it's a bit better but now it's
still missing strokes anyway so that's
Chinese so let's see
yeah that's Chinese so for example well
anyway let's go back
so as access have you heard of the sound
Jia Chinese input yeah of course but I
don't use it I use ping you know so foot
for writing Chinese you have let me show
you okay so let me talk about more about
Chinese then so if you guys have any
questions comments just post it okay we
are about done today it's over an hour
so let me talk about a bit more about
Chinese yeah because that's all I have
to say about languages you know but
since I know Chinese I can tell you a
bit more about Chinese yeah writing and
you know look to learn writing Chinese
and reading Chinese it's it's fairly
it's quite hard actually you in emacs
you can also learn how to input Chinese
in Emacs pure Emacs
I have article here you can you know you
can try to read it and you can actually
type Chinese if even if you know nothing
about Chinese you just follow these
instructions and USC now and you can
also if you are on a Mac or on Windows
you can you can type Chinese in any
editor your in browser you know all you
have to do is just to switch to a
Chinese input method you know basically
on a Mac it's like you know you just go
to your keyboard control panel and add
Chinese so let me introduce you a little
bit about Chinese input methods meaning
that it's a way to type Chinese use
keyboard you know you know Chinese it's
not like it's not alphabet based so you
you know you know so to type the
thousands of characters you cannot just
you know press a key there's no 1000 you
know 3000 keys but what do you do is use
a input method system input method you
know and there are they are like more
than 20 you know they are like more than
10 like 20 different input methods why
because you know over the years people
try to create input system to type
Chinese and you know because Chinese is
not like English you know it's not based
on alphabet which is simple you know for
English all you have is different type
of layout you know like where do you
place the letters you know you you we
have qua T then we have Iraq and we have
few others but for Chinese you know it's
not as simple as that so people have
invented people have invented many
different incompatible methods to input
an input to type Chinese but all of them
are basically can be classified into two
groups one is phonetic based meaning
that you type the characters
pronunciation how it sounds then it pops
up choices then you pick the character
that's a phonetic based system the other
one is a character based system meaning
that you type you know southern keys
that's the stroke based on the how the
character appears you know based on the
characters stroke you know and there are
many different systems you know some
some takes you know the corners of the
the characters you know it's a stroke
based system and typically that system
is usually more difficult to learn but
but usually more efficient you know
meaningless keystrokes to type character
so these there are these two categories
phonetic based and Stroke based system
but however the most popular okay so so
in a phonetic system then there are many
many different ones okay yeah just
because you know the it's you know it's
so Taiwan usually use a system called su
Yin or Papa mo fo and but in China it's
use a system called ping let's see where
you know I if you read article you'll
see the details
so anyway phonetic system then there are
many different ones then the character
based system there are also many
different ones now one of the one of the
character based system used in Taiwan is
called Sanji which is what Isaac has
mentioned which you can see this is
Apple Apple's keyboard in Saudi in
Taiwan
and you can see for each key there are
three characters on it two of them
Chinese okay now the upper right is a
Chinese phonetic system using Taiwan
codes oohing Oh Papa mofo and the lower
right corner you will see these
characters they are from they are
sangeun yeah so they are character based
input system I never learned it so so
yeah so that sets the basic about
Chinese input systems I learned and also
in China on Taiwan vast majority of
people they actually use the phonetic
based system because that's actually the
easiest to learn because you don't have
to you know you have to know is how the
how a word is pronounced like speech you
know you don't even have to know how to
write Chinese if you can speak Chinese
you can you can
put it you can type it you just type you
know the how the word sounds and you
know the characters come up yeah so most
Chinese uses phonetic system and invest
most all of them in China
use a pin system but in Taiwan Muslim
use the doing system so that's that's
about that Isaac so I'd like any
anything else anything interesting so
guys if you have questions just type it
okay so what else about languages or
about Chinese so yeah so you know here
is an example of Chinese characters they
are simplified versus traditional
Chinese characters so the deal is that
basically in China around 1950 the
commune you know the Chinese government
they created they they try to simplify
characters and this page is a comparison
you can see you know these two are the
same character these two are the same
character let me magnify you know black
and white I have two characters in
comparison and the one in black
background is the simplified version
they want to simplify because back then
the thought you know China is trying to
modernize you know the country and it's
a common thought among academia that
Chinese is too complicated the writing
system and the order for China and China
to modernize you know to you know jump
into the you know modern society to
create you know atom bombs and rockets
you know and computers you have to
simplify the Chinese characters so
Chinese people can learn you know they
in progress you know they can you know
education will improve and so on so they
began with they invent created the
simplified characters so that's how they
you know so the this page is basically a
list of all the simplified characters
about there are about 500 of them so I
grew up in Taiwan so Taiwan does not
really use simplified characters so I
learned simplified characters just by
you know I created this page parsley to
help me learning so these days I used
mostly simplified hegemony info Matic so
informatics so we are about done
actually yeah today is 70 minutes I
think we are done here what's up
informatics any any any other questions
a vote okay
ibaka Dory's it's from avocado and
Pythagoras was in Pythagorean theorem so
what's up so I I have an interest in in
languages and also I like to I learned
Spanish for a year when I was in South
America you know and I learned some I
didn't really learn French when I was in
Canada I did in Canada for three years
because I didn't learn French because
the French people you know they they
kind of want you to learn French and I'm
rebellious so that's why I don't I did
not write in French but you know I lived
in Canada for three years you kind of
pick up you know and some French and I
hope to learn but you know I'm kind of
getting old and there are so many things
in math and theoretical computer science
like proof theory I want to learn so
so informatics says late for the show
like always yeah I should have a
schedule but what time is it over there
in Morocco right so it's like 9 p.m.
night
so anyway okay so that's about it for
today thank you guys for coming
oh it's 20 walk o clock so it's 10 10 o
clock in Morocco so see you guys until
next time