Hello guys. Hello guys. Welcome to
another episode of S talk show. We are
going to code time language. If you are
here, say hi. Uh if you are watching
offline, play at 1.5 speed. I'm going to
have some drink. And uh this is a gu
that's al also known as baiu
uh of China.
So this is uh 60% or you know something
uh alcohol
56%.
Okay. So that's like vodka Chinese vodka
actually heavier than vodka. And I'm
going to code wang language. Okay, today
I'm going to code for sure. Uh, one
drink I can still code more than one
drink then maybe not. Okay, so have us
some drink
now. It's getting hot in California.
Proper Chinese.
My keyboard is Ultimate Hacking Keyboard
80. This one. Okay. Uh HK80
NIA trackable N U L EA.
Okay. You can
search my YouTube. You will find my
reviews.
So, let's uh wait. Stop recording. No,
let's switch to my screen so you can
kind of see my
screen. Oh, this this this drink is
burning. Okay. So, we are going to do
mathematics. You know, like in the past
week or two, we've been doing a lot math
and I've been wanting to code this code
and it's just never done. But I got lots
of to-do. Lots of to-do. So, I'm just
continue going to code it. Okay.
So,
okay. Let's begin. Okay. If you are
here, say hi. So, let me finish my
drink. Cheers.
Audio check. Yes. Video check. Yes.
Okay. So, we going to code. So, showing
browser. So, that's today's talk show.
And my website sadly is still I cannot
update my website. So, if you go to my
website.info
talk show.info,
you'll see that my website,
you know, so kadi.info. Okay, this is my
website and you go to talk show, you'll
see it's stuck at
February 8th.
So for one month,
I have not been able to update my page.
You see it's on talk show. But if you
look at my talk show on my local drive
showing browser it's not talk show you
see it's being updated you know so today
is March 21st you got yesterday March 20
episode 781 then you got the day before
then you know every day almost every day
I almost been doing a live stream every
day in the past month so it's been a
month you see um you know so the
February
8th is episode 759
and if you go to my website kasari.info
info. That's what you see. February 8th,
7:59
episode.
Uh so it's, you know, it's not being
updated. So because
do you guys know why? Well, because
there uh my web my website provider is
got some issues. Uh there is a command
if you are Linux Unix user, you might
know
called rync
sync. Okay. But it's but when I run a
command to to to upload my files to my
web uh service provider, it's got some
issues. I need to look into but I just
haven't been. Okay. That is why.
Okay.
Okay. And what I want to do now so
that's uh so close close. Okay. what I
want to do, I I need to do this wam
language Mathematica, the most powerful
programming language. There's so so many
so so uh much to do. Okay. So I just
want to code, you know. So I'm going to
code on my own.
Uh if you have questions any like you
can ask me any questions. Consider this
as my office hours. Okay? So you can
interrupt me. You can ask uh any
questions. So let me type it.
If you have any questions
you can ask here.
Okay.
Meanwhile,
otherwise meanwhile
I am just going to code
work on my website. Okay.
have a shot to go.
Now I'm in California and uh today and
yesterday is being hot. Starting to get
hot. Uh I guess is it summer or spring?
Spring. Uh not summer yet. Spring.
Okay. So wam language. So let's uh let's
go to it. So I want to code this. You
see I explained this many times. I want
to write a generic
what I want to do is I want to write a
program of wam language also known as
mathematica.
I want to write a program that can plot
the reflection of light rays on any
plane curve. Okay. a generic program so
that people can you know
paste in uh whatever the parametric
equation for a curve then they'll show
you know and also a light point
coordinate then it will draw
it will it will draw pictures like that
you know pictures like that this is a
circle you know reflection of parallel
rays onto a circle and or draw any of
these. This is ellipse you know
reflection refraction this is sign curve
and lots of others. This is parabola.
You got this property where if the light
source is at a specific point called the
focus of the ellipse then the light rays
will be become all parallel
you know. So that so so anyways so it
can generate lots of pretty pictures. So
you see all these images are done 30
years ago. So I'm writing a code to
update them. Now of course this code
currently you can do it. You can already
plot it you know because you know you
just use one of my packages Mathematica
packages for plane curves. This one go
to it. Let's see wam plane curve plot
package. Yeah that one. Go to it. It's
on GitHub. You can just go to it and
download. So you can download it and you
can run it. Of course, you need wam
language and it's also it's free. Just
go to the download woofam engine.
Okay. Search for it on si.info. Download
Wufam engine. You'll find it. It's on
Wufam's website. Wufam.com/developer.
Okay. You can download it. Wam language.
The most powerful. So you get this. Then
you install these plank curve packages.
Then that allows you to have plot
tangents, plot uh tangents, normal lines
and uh seeant lines and normal lines.
normal lines, seeant lines of a equal
angular spiral and seeant lines to
generate this beautiful star
uh starfish picture this seeant lines of
a hypotcoid this technicality technical
name for this curve. Okay. uh and uh
draw the reflections of a parabola
showing the light rays reflection
property. And uh another property this
is a property of a exponential curve.
The reflection the envelope of the
reflection from parallel rays from top
is this this curve. This is called can
uh uh katenoid um
uh wait kenary. Okay. This this curve
you see it's called catenary.
That curve is formed when you hang a
chain you know let's say necklace or a
chain
um the natural shape you know under the
conditions of the gravity if you you
know um
if you hang a chin that's the shape
you're going to get not parabola okay
this is called katenoid I mean catenary
and there's a lot properties to of this
curve this curve happens to the
um
anyway that's you know it you know so
it's the shape of the
you know of a chain if you hang a chain
and it can also be formed if you have
light rays from above
uh reflecting off a exponential curve
that one here this one is exp
exponential curve and what's and this um
very special about the exponential curve
because it's exponential curve is a
function e to x. Okay, e is a n uh is a
constant natural
uh logarithm base. Okay, e the constant
e tox.
So that function that function the
derivative of that function is itself.
You see that is a property about the is
exponential curve. So very interesting
the derivative of you know is there a
function whose derivative is itself
there is indeed that's a exponential uh
function that's this one e to raised tox
okay so that's this blue curve you see
beautiful but but when you shine a light
from above like like for example
sunshine parallel rays and they reflect
off then they form this curve and that
that curve is katenoid cattonary which
is formed when you hang a chin okay or a
rope fascinating
so anyway so my what I'm saying is that
you get this package this wolf language
uh package then you can plot all these
then there's um uh osculating circles
also known as kissing circles okay you
can plot it oscar ating circles of a
equal angular spiral here for example.
Then you got uh this is another
fascinating thing. Okay, this is
cycloid. Cyclloid curve is a curve. It's
a path where if you put a marble a ball
it will fall down the fastest.
Not straight line, not parabola, not
whatever you know whatever shape you may
create. Not not the exponential curve.
You know what is a shape a path where
you have a point on top and point at
bottom. A ramp so that you put a ball or
car it will roll down the fastest. That
would be
this curve. Okay. This this you you have
to reverse invert it. Okay. So this this
this curve is called cyclloid. And how
is it generated? It's generated by
rolling a circle on a line. Okay? Like a
bicycle wheel for example. When you have
a bicycle at night, you know there's a
lead on the wheel, right? So the lead
you know you can see your light then you
will trace out this curve that that is
it's called cyclloid. Okay.
And turns out the evolute of cyclloid is
itself. Okay. Anyway, I'm getting off
far. So, there's so many so many
incredible uh properties of plank
curves. That is why I created this
project 30 years ago. And uh which got
me a job at Wuam Research
30 years ago. 1995. Okay. [laughter]
Almost exactly 30 years ago. Let me
finish my drink and let's start to code.
Okay. I need to code. But right now, I'm
just telling you. So if you are a
student a college student or something
you are interesting you studying
calculus or something basic geometry you
know this this package this code is good
good to know get go there download it
okay on GitHub
by yours truly okay and download wam
language then you can you can have fun
you can see all these properties Okay.
Now and download you have to download
Wuframe engine of course. Okay. Free you
know I mentioned where to download. Now
if you are like open source fanatic you
know you are into Python or SGE math or
whatever. Well good for you. You can
still
um learn about these properties of
course. Then you can try use your Python
or SageMath or whatever your favorite
tool or JavaScript if you are a
proficient you know JavaScript coder you
know you can there's actually quite a
few frameworks to
to draw uh to plot to draw SVG or you
know you can use 3D uh webgl you know
you can so you can you know there you
can use Python you can use JavaScript
you can use sagemath whatever have a
tool you can today to learn about these
amazing properties of these plank
curves. Okay.
Uh so
you know you can use wolf language which
I promote or you can you know learn it
via Python and and and and JavaScript
and meanwhile you can uh ask AI to help
you. Fantastic. Okay, let me answer the
questions.
Uh
which topics are dominant in your
consciousness?
What do you mean? Are you still here?
Say say yes. Okay. So demood demund says
which topic are dominant in your
consciousness.
Well like my reaction is what do you
mean by that? you know like dominant in
my consciousness. Do you mean what what
is the topic? What is my favorite topic?
Or do you mean to say what is on my mind
right now? Or what kind you know what
what like what do you mean ambiguous
phrasing? You know which topic are
dominant in your consciousness? That's
ambiguous phrasing. Let me finish my
drink.
So that ambiguous phrasing, let me let
me philosophize it. Okay. You ask me a
question, let me tell you.
Oh, okay. So, rephrase. What are you
thinking about nowadays? That's much
better. [laughter]
So, in past month, actually, I not I I
don't feel good. Okay. [ __ ] You know,
this one shot of this drink is having an
effect on me. I still going to code. I
don't know. So anyway, in in the past
month, almost exactly the past 30 days,
I've been not feeling well, okay?
Because I felt kind of like depression.
Okay. You you you you know I don't want
to say the word depression because when
you say depression then people oh my god
depression you know they it's you know
like the uh the American white men
society they are thinking a lot think of
things you know but but you know I'm not
feeling good uh like I don't feel so
happy and uh in part because you know
what uh because I've been reading I've
been doom scrolling you know of the
politics of the news what's going on you
know obvious you know everyone knows
people you know everyone if you are not
like teenager if you are not a child
everyone in the world knows right now
there is wars going on
and USA is doing it uh and people are
dying and uh it's a war and it's not
good for you you know it's not good for
USA it's Uh it's it's a lot of bad
things going on. Okay. Not just one war,
you know, there's uh two
in the past two or three years.
So, and uh it's, you know, it's doesn't
it's not happy news, you know. That's
why why the Zoomer generation have a
phrase doom swirl. You know, you you
read the news God like someone is
beating someone, you know, like videos
or something. Oh god, rape. Oh god,
something you know. Oh god, corruption.
Oh, someone is cheating. Oh, the
government, you know, they're doing
nasty things. They are lying. You know,
like doom scroll, right? That the the
Zuma generation created the phrase doom
scroll to to describe like the situation
we are in. So,
so obvious. Then of course you got the
memes, you got, you know, the sad guy or
you got PE, you got lots of things,
right? So or the clown, you know, the
clown word. So I wasn't, so that kind of
affected me, you know, I wasn't too
happy. Um,
kind of worries me, you know, I wasn't
happy about it. So actually that answers
your question. What are you thinking
about nowadays? in the past month
as American would say you know to be
honest that's what American idom you
know to be honest so in the past month
you know I been you know what's on my
mind are are these political things you
know the wars going on that is uh what
I've been kind of thinking but meanwhile
so that's a path past month But
meanwhile, but I also continue to be
extremely obsessed about coding about I
mean about the topics I'm interested in
and also the reason you guys are
watching me uh programming languages wra
language this programming you know I've
been working for for example I've been
working on today
my emacs
uh emac this tutorial the most advanc
the most comprehensive
tutorial on Emacs this the programming
language you will be able to find on the
net in the world in actually there's no
book you can buy no other website that
is more in-depth more comprehensive more
quality than my website xard.info info.
Okay. So, let me uh put a plug here. So,
you see, you know, so actually, so what
I was saying is that today I was working
on rewriting this uh you know, uh one
page, you know, part of my eac list
tutorial.
So, you go to this basics. Let me show
you. Okay. So actually so you know you
go to saw Emacs blog you can search it
you'll find it on the web but again like
I said I haven't been updated what you
see is not what you see here anyway so
so you go to uh Emacs blog go to lisp
basics okay then you have quick start
you have working with emac list you have
strings data structure I mean data type
value type you have numbers How do you
represent a number? How do you represent
the boolean true and false in EMACB
this? How do you represent the variable
then and conditionals if then else? How
how do you write that? How do you write
the loop while a loop and how do you
then you started to have data structures
list? Uh then you got um you got you
know association list property property
list. Then you got symbol property list.
Then you got list structures you know
getting into detail. Then you got hasht
you got vector data type which is uh
like python would call it tupo okay in
python or in C they call it array. Okay
so in this in e emac this and common
this is called vector and also schem I
believe then you got sequence type which
is generic name for all these anyway
then you have hash table. So you click
on hasht there okay you go to JSON
reading right so this page is about
importing and exporting JSON JSON as
most of programmers would know it's like
Java JavaScript based
interchange data format okay so I have a
tutorial on that you can read about it
looks like that you know phone number
street you know data format JSON So but
in eaglist this you can read you know
you can import or export JSON right so
this is this page shows you how and
today and few days ago I've been busy
for example I've been busy rewriting
this page in particular about how to
export to JSON from lisp from emacisp
okay so now it became a page of its own
here this page you see so I've been
working on so you see the date so I've
been touching up on this basically
rewrite this page tutorial
and uh but if you go to for example you
can search si
em eac lisp json okay okay you will find
my tutorial about it there e emacisp
json import export
and the ai essays. Kali provides
comprehensive resources on emac JSON
handling particularly focusing on
practical implementation and best
practice.
AI
[laughter]
AI knows me because I've been blogging
for like 30 years. So AI grabbed my
10,000 pages of information and and AI
consumed it. [ __ ] AI. So you now you
don't have to go to my website. You, you
know, [ __ ] you just read whatever
he's saying. Anyway, so you go to my
page. So Jason, so you see there it is.
You you find it. But you see, like I
said, I have I have not been able to
update my website for a month. So what
you see see here is one month old. You
see this export JSON object
export lisp object to JSON has not been
separated into its own page. But if you
read my local version, you see this is
my local version on my on my computer.
Then it's a independent page for export
because export by itself is complicated
enough to have a page by itself. You see
there are several uh screens of of it.
You see export JSON.
Anyway, so so you are asking me what you
thinking what am I thinking about this
nowadays? That's you know
you know part of a doom scroll of
politics very nasty and very fearful.
We are talking about the collapse of
USA. Uh and possibly
we all gonna die. That's what you know I
don't want to you know sound scary but
that's World War II and there is
doomsday clock right? You guys know
about doomsday clock you know it's been
you know it's the thing is there it
there is of course there is this
possibility it's there that we just
going to destroy
You know, in other words,
you and me, we're going to be dead,
possibly soon.
Okay. So, doom scrolling and my
obsession about programming language
that continues, you know. So I've been
so I'm been working on my Emacs Lisp
website
uh tutorial and there's lots of
interesting things you know like I can
tell you non-stop like why my obsession
about
mathematics about programming about
writing systems right
you know so I'm just so into it you know
like like uh for example in the EMAC
this case uh when
you know um
you know you have different list data
types. For example, in lisp you have
vector. In in emac this in particular,
you have vector, you have hash table,
you have list, you have association
list, you have property list, you know,
and in this you have things like symbol
and you have like uh you have like true
and false t and neo. So what they become
in JSON?
That's interesting. What kind of in
other words what data type you you know
in this programming language you have
this set of data types in JSON you have
this set of data types to to be more
exact you have object you have array
object then you have true and false
boolean then you have numbers and you
have strings then you have escape
sequence for strings then you have you
also have a new special like new thing
in JSON. Okay. So in but in but
basically in this you have this data
types in JSON you have these data types.
So when you want to convert or also
known as export from one to the other or
import when you read
which type maps to which I you know
that's the question. Um so
when you dive into detail you know then
then it becomes interesting and complex
because I mean if you don't dive into
detail you may just say oh you just got
array which is a list sequence then then
you got the you know key value pairs
but in each language you know when you
actually do the mapping it's a bit more
complicated so here's a detail so I
wrote you know So I'm interested in this
topic you know this obsession my
obsession about this this is about why
am I obsessed about it because my
interest in programming languages
computer science
formal languages
uh which is part of theoretical computer
science term rewriting system
Mathematica wolf language and the
writing system of human animals which
can't you Computer programming languages
count as a subset of writing systems of
human animals which includes English for
example, Japanese, Korean, Chinese,
Russian you know the writing system the
symbols and and the symbology.
So for example I've shown talked about
this many times unic code blog. So you
can you know you can see all you know
like the writing writing system
uh I explore. So in this page for
example it's about
a writing system for phonetics to
represent the pronunciation of sounds.
So one of such system is called IPA
which stand for international phonetic
alphabet. Okay. And it looks like that.
Okay. But Americans are usually idiotic.
American don't go the international way.
American has their own way. So typically
Americans
I'm talking about the American like here
[laughter]
Americans. Are you guys still with me
like demon demunded? Are you are you are
like are you American or are you like
from India or somewhere else? because I
do know I have large uh you know fairly
fair number of fans from India and
elsewhere as well.
So anyway, so these phonetic symbols in
this case, Americans usually don't like
the IPA, you know, they they just have
their own like phonetic symbols. Okay.
Anyway, that's so anyway, this is part
of Unicode, which is the writing system,
uh, which I'm, you know, which like
programming languages is one of the
things I like and obsess about. Okay. So
that I think that answers your question.
What are you thinking about nowadays?
Okay, in summary in one sentence
uh 80 [snorts] in the past month 80% is
politics
the very dark situation of politics we
are in okay
which includes possibly end of the world
you know doom scrolling that's what I've
been doing while the other
uh 20% in the past month is My as as
usual my interest in programming in
sciences in programming languages in
linguistics in literature uh that kind
of thing academic. Okay.
Okay.
That's a long uh answer to your question
to your casual question. Do I make
sense? Now you need to answer. Okay.
Demood C8N. Do I make sense? Now the
other qu from India.
Hello older brother. Hello.
I'm Hermy. Oh, okay. I kind of remember
you from Discord.
Uh Hermy. Okay. Well, okay. I I think
you are like you just recently
uh you know uh on this you know you've
been there. Anyway, I I think I know who
you are. Hello there. Uh so I would say
a personal message to you is um
you know let's uh do what is best for
us. You know keep keep trucking. That's
what I'm that's what I'm saying. Okay.
Do whatever is good for you and me.
Cheers. Uh okay. Okay. So, next what
what is the other uh didn't they
discover this curve building church
dome?
What does that mean?
So, if you are talking about the domes
of church there are different types. So,
you are talking about architecture.
Okay. So, you the mega super ultimate.
Are you still here? Say hi. Okay. If you
are still here maybe I'll answer your
question. I mean if you are interested
because you are talking about that's
about geomet that's about architecture
the architecture the design of
domes for religious buildings. Uh for
example different religions they have
different names for their worshiing
places. Uh for example in Japan in China
it's temple.
Okay. Um well um so you got names like
temple pagoda you got church you got um
uh what you got um cathedral you got uh
mosque you got um
temple did we mention temple already
temple um uh um you know so
so depending on the uh religion you have
different names for this their worshiing
places. Okay. Now
let's go uh
and name name all. Okay. So you go to my
unic code blog. So search for x ah unic
code.
You'll find my unic code page. Then you
can go to um let's go to places. Okay.
So places. There it is. So you got
church, you got mosque
which is the church for Muslims for the
Islam religion. Then you got synagogue
which is a church for the
Juda Judaism you know Jewish people.
Then you got this Kaba which is like the
central place of worship for the most
for the Islam people. Then you got
Shinto shrine which is kind of Japanese.
Okay. Japanese temple. Okay. Then you
got the Hindu temple p temple. Okay.
This like this is usually called pagoda
or called uh so you hermit you Indian
people you need to help me. Okay.
There's a another another name for this
um
Indian Hindu temple called um
kind of the origin of pagoda. Okay,
I forgot that moment. But anyway, what I
want to say, by the way, I want to also
mention, you know, there's a racism
right here. You don't see it. The white
man [ __ ] face. the white men, the
American white [ __ ] Okay, you see
they are obsessed about, you know, this,
you know, you need to have a religion,
religious symbol for, you know, each
religion. But they are missing they are
missing China Buddhism. You see this
Shinto shrine that that's not, you know,
that's only Japanese, you know. So in
other words, you don't have a symbol to
represent the worshiing the place of
worshiing for Buddhism.
Okay? You you you covered Hindu,
Indians, Japan, the major religions, but
you don't but you missing the big one,
Unicode. You know, Unicode is like
evolving for the past 10 years. They
evolve around politics. You know, you
need Oh my Jesus. you need to represent
you know religious people you need to
have skin colors and all that right
but when it comes to Chinese you know it
is nothing why because like I talk about
the politics because USA
anyway we got we getting into another
topic let's stop here
uh what is your word per minute my word
per minute per minute it's about 70 okay
so you can also search
Kari keyboard. Search for it. You'll
find it. Kasari keyboard blog. There are
1,000 pages. Okay. So, you go down, you
can see there are uh
1,400 pages on [snorts] keyboard. Okay.
Can you see? Yeah. 1,400 pages.
So, so you got ergonomic keyboards.
Okay. So, all the ergonomic keyboard you
need to know. You got do-ityourself
keyboards, all the do-ityourself
keyboards you need to know. You got
normalish keyboards. You got like, you
know, the like normal PC keyboards. You
got uh video reviews, some of my best
videos reviews on keyboard stuff. Okay.
And you got uh laptop keyboards, my
annotated history, you know, history of
laptop keyboard evolution, things like
that. You got keypads, uh several
articles about keypads, about
programmable keypads. Okay, for example,
um I used to, you know, this you know
anyway, so I I have tons of things to
say, you know, one
14,000 articles. Okay. All about it.
Okay. So, those are about programmable
keyboard or keypads. Okay. Then you have
fun things. Fun things like the day I
lost control.
This picture and this anime, you know,
like fun things, you know, and this this
this this is a fake. This is a doll.
Okay. Then you got battle stations.
Interesting, you know, so-called battle
stations by the nerds. Um some some are
like different styles. You see some are
clean like this one. And you know
actually you need to see in full full
glory. Then you got a like musical
keyboard. Then you got uh this is this
is not happy hacking. It looks like
happy hacking. Then you got uh this this
this uh this [laughter]
this is a poor guy but he's a advanced
mathematician. He's studying homotopy
type theory,
you know, some kind of like poor guy.
Anyway, so interesting things. And this
guy is a drinker. So anyway, so that's
about that's that's like
one page of the fun things about
keyboard, you know, like
interesting things. Um then then you got
a section about the history of
keyboards. So you can read about all
history of keyboard. Then then on and
on. Okay. Then what was your question uh
about my um word per minute. Okay. So
you go typing right here. What is touch
typing? Typing habits, hand health and
index. Okay. That's this page. What is
touch typing? How to touch type? Does
touch typing cause repetitive strain
injury? Uh typing habits. How people
actually type? Survey. That that's a
study. Okay. Typing tutorial, speed test
and typing game. So, uh and the and then
typing habit and related to repetitive
strain injury. So, if you have hand
pain, you want to read this section. For
example, how to press control key and
proper sitting posture,
keyboard tenting, is it good? Do you
need it? And what's the best palm rest?
And what to do? What exercise to do?
What kind of toys can you buy to reduce
hand and pain? Okay. Then you got bad
keyboard advice from programmers. You
hear it every day because every time you
go online, you go to Amazon, you know,
keyboard review comments or or the uh
Emacs people or the VI people, they're
going to tell you, oh, you need to
switch your control and and and how and
how you should press control or you know
whatever they do. Most of the time they
are idiots. Okay, so you need to read
this article, bad keyboard advice,
common bad keyboard advice for
programming idiots.
My take 2010 written 2011. How many
keyboard do you type a day? Actually,
did you ever measure it? That's that
article. Okay. And why undo short uh
shortcut keys are bad? So, so 1,400
articles here. And your question about
typing speed that would be uh there
typing tutorials, speed test, and typing
games. So let's go. Is that there? Yeah.
Okay. So let's go there. Let's see.
Uh typing tutorials. So this website can
type tutorial. So I can tell you my
speed is typically 70
word per minute without any you know
warm up you know like if you just if I
just go to one of these website and test
right now it's going to be 70 word per
minute. Okay. or 90 you know after you
know sometimes 90 depending on the site.
So this you know I have articles about
it about what does word per minute per
minute mean like if you go to one of the
website you know you test out it's it
says you are 70 word per minute but if
you go to another site all of a sudden
you are 100 word per minute oh my god
Jesus so what why is that what's the
difference you need to read my website
because I have like detailed somewhere
uh Like I there is an article about what
word per minute means exactly. Why is it
some website says you are this some
other website says you are that. So
anyway so on this page in particular
it's about typing tutorial speed test
and typing games. So I list several
websites and and
uh I documented screenshotted my result
on them.
Okay. So you know so you you got the
type racer which is very popular you got
several others monkey type very popular
10 fast fingers very popular the typing
cat I don't remember you know but anyway
you got several okay so 91 word per
minute that's one of my that's me on 10
fast fingers 2021
okay and and then you can read you know
then there's another section one with
100 articles about my typing history.
So you can read my typing word per
minute history since like 1990
uh 1980 1989.
I have written about it. You know, you
just search for
uh
typing history or search RSI history.
So, you'll find it. Okay. Uh no. Okay.
So, what
flag key flag keys history? No. So, uh
Okay. So you want to search for
RSI. Okay. So just search for that.
So there it is. I believe that is the
main article. So typing experience
repetitive strain injury. So that's on
Emacs, right? So here is about 10
articles that details the history of my
typing my touch typing experience and
repetitive strain injury. So this is
written starting in 2013
and last updated I updated like you know
more than that but I haven't you because
my website I haven't been up able to
update this page anyway.
So what I'm saying is that so the answer
to your question is
70 or 90 depending on the website. Okay,
that is the answer to the question. Uh
how you know what's my word per minute.
Uh
the upside down chain curve. That's
right. You know, but you know in St.
Louis you know so we were talking about
this curve so let let's just show it
uh
so a visual dictionary of spatial plane
curves that's one of my most famous
project
well known for like 15 years from 1997
to about 2010 or 2015
it's linked by
over 1,000 universities, math
departments. Okay, that's this project.
Uh but then the traffic died back down
because basically Wikipedia took over
you know Wikipedia they can just copy
everything and then you know anyone can
you know contribute. So Wikipedia
took over any any math website Wikipedia
became the most popular anyway.
So this website so we are talking about
the katenary curve. So that would be uh
katenary curve. There's a famous St.
Louis architecture.
It's you know like there's a arc in USA
St. Louis. So this is a curve
catary. It looks like the red one. Okay.
The red you know let me show you. So it
looks like that kind of like a parabola
but they are not the same shape. Okay,
it looks like that. Again, I need to
update this page. This like lousy
picture from uh you know this this
picture is like 30 years ago. So, for
example, let's do in wam language and
let's do today. This should get a better
picture.
Uh okay. So, I actually I talked for
nonstop for hour and we didn't get to
code anything. [ __ ]
cosine sh. Okay. So you need to plot it.
Okay. So let me magnify 150.
So you need to say not that uh
you need to say plot
that function
and uh you need to say x from negative3
let's say -2 to2 do it.
Okay. Okay. It doesn't look much better,
but um
Okay. It's kind of boring. Anyway, so
this this curve is called catenary.
Okay. And
and but let me show you the picture
there. Okay. So there you see this is a
gateway arc at Missouri
uh St. Louis. Okay. And that thing that
thing is the catinary okay is this
curve. So is this cur is this curve.
Okay kosh x and kosh is defined by
fascinating mathematics. Are you guys
interested?
Uh
anyway, so kosh is defined by um it's
like um where's the kosh? Koshi is
defined like um
I don't I don't you know I can't tell
you right now you you know it's like you
know
uh
anyway so you know you can look up okay
so but anyway so this curve so let me
just tell you quickly some interesting
things about this curve okay first of
all what is a curve whose derivative is
itself that is this one the blue one
that's called exponential curve okay e
to the x okay
now if you shine a light light from top
they reflect off then you got this
envelope they they form the shape this
is the this is the uh ctonary okay
that's that one okay it may you know so
but you you might be saying okay but
they don't look the same you one is much
narrower. That's only because you are
looking at smaller part you know like if
you are looking at just this part then
you it seems flat. If you enlarge the
picture then you then you can see it's
like more um for example
yeah let's say four. Okay.
You see you uh let's say you see can you
guys see it? Uh let's say seven. Okay.
Seven.
Uh what?
Oh wait. Do we um Okay. You need axis uh
ratio. They change the aspect ratio.
Okay.
Aspect ratio automatic. Okay.
You see?
You see? Now it looks like uh can you
guys see? Yeah. So you want let's say
four. Okay.
You see my point is that the curve looks
different. That's only because you are
looking at different scale. Okay. But in
fact this this this two are exactly the
same curve. Okay. So this curve defined
by this kosh is called catenary. Okay.
Now what is kosh? Okay. I don't remember
but let me just show you Wikipedia.
Okay. Yeah. Hyperbolic function. Okay.
Kosh is defined by um
it's very simple. Okay. So
uh there okay. Yeah. E RA to X + E RA to
- X / 2. Okay, the where the E is the
constant of natural logarithm.
Okay, so anyway, this is the this is
this is the definition of Kosh
and it's also called hyperbolic cosine.
They are related to S and cosine. Okay,
so that fascinating. Okay.
So anyway that's kosh. So kosh the the
graph of the kosh function is this thing
and there's a name it's called katenary.
Okay that's why we are talking about
katenary. Okay. And and why what what is
a catenary? It is a natural shape when
you hang a chain like like this picture.
Okay.
You see when you hang a chain under
gravity where the chain is supposed to
be infinitely flexible. Okay. Then that
shape
is this is the plot of the function
kosh. Okay.
And what about inversion? I mean why do
you have to flip it? I I'm not sure
what's the deal. Anyway, they flip it so
that you can have a arc,
but I don't know what is there anything
special when you like make it upside
down. Like is there a particular
meaningful thing? I don't know. But
anyway, normally it you know it looks
like that it that's a natural shape of a
chain hanging. Okay. And it's called
cattonary this thing called kenary.
Okay. And that's just kosh hyperbolic
cosine. Fascinating mathematics. Okay.
So you were saying that someone is
mentioning um
is e to the x - e ra to minus x = 2 pi.
Obviously not because
Okay, I think we talked for
57 minutes close to an hour. I think
maybe we should shut down.
Did I miss any questions?
So I don't know another name for Hindu
temple but sik temple is called guru
dawra.
Oh interesting
skele delight why the sad face
now za says what is your education? You
know people are asking that I suppose
you are new here
because people um you know like people
see you know people watch me talk and uh
usually they think I'm a professor you
know like because I talk about you know
lots of like knowledge things
actually I'm not professor okay I'm not
you know but let me tell you some
interesting thing about professor you
The professor if you don't know if you
are outsider you know professor is just
like a teacher right but if you are
actually in academia
like if you work in university or if you
are a professor a real professor you
know professor is actually a uh like a
ranked title among academicians okay
just like in army in navy you know in
military
You have words like colonel, captain,
lieutenant. Okay,
they have very specific meaning. Okay,
they they they are ranking. Okay, they
they have a rank. Colonel, lieutenant,
general, you know, captain or uh or or
surgeon. It's not just like random.
Okay.
But their exact meaning depends on you
know which country and what military you
know like USA Navy uh uh navy or air
force or uh army or marines they have
different like kind of the they they
differ a little bit. Okay. And also
differ but another country then it's
more different. Okay. But the professor
but in academia
there's also search ranking. Okay. So
you have professor is one of them
professor. So if I if you watch someone
on YouTube you know he talks like a
professor. He teach you a lot of things
but
you know you can think of him as a
professor but you but you you know it be
can can become offensive if if if you
are in a certain context because you
need to use the right term because you
cannot call for example a military guy
you can say you you can mistake you know
call him a colonel instead of a
lieutenant or or vice versa you know if
he can a big big error
So
you got professor, you got instructors,
you got um then you got like I don't
even know exactly but but but then you
got uh like tenure professor then you
got um you know it's kind of like a you
know
it's kind of like
institutionalized
kind of ranked title. Okay. It's not
just like
it doesn't you know just mean a teacher.
It's not just like a respectful name.
So if you are asking me like people have
been asking me are you a professor? You
know no uh I happen to be not.
Okay. No. So I'm not a professor but
I've been called a professor.
Well, actually at one time I had a room
that says Professor Casar
was um it was good you know it was good
experience because you see because when
you are professor
like with a title professor you became
like respected just like when you are
like you know I'm a CEO of of a known
company like Google it needs not be to
be Google but like like I'm I like if I
say I'm a I work at Google then all of a
sudden people respect you you know
because you you you know uh you you have
status you know if I say I work at
Google I work at Microsoft all of a
sudden I I'll get 10 times more
followers you know or you know like that
guy like that scum who whose name is
like lead uh uh [laughter]
lead engineer like what's his name? Lead
engineer at at Facebook and Google. The
big scum.
I haven't heard him for a while. Like a
big scammer.
Tech lead. What's his name? Tech lead.
Um, you know, you guys know what I'm
talking about, right? There's a YouTuber
kind of Chinese face.
So anyway, what was I saying? Yeah. So,
um, yeah. So when you are a professor
you you get respected you know it's like
uh
life life is like different you like
anywhere you go people treat you
differently.
So ZZA says you missed two of my
questions.
What what what questions?
Why don't you use Linux? Okay, the one
of the question why don't you use Linux?
That's one of the most idiotic question
which I talk you know it's been it that
question is asked
about one out of five of my live stream.
So [laughter] So I got asked that almost
every week. Well, every two weeks maybe
like why don't you use Linux or what's
your favorite you know I mean why are
you using l Windows uh why don't you use
Linux most idiotic
question okay so
so I can tell you you haven't been
watching me you are probably new so you
probably should watch my video let's say
even just two days ago because two days
ago someone asked me that and I
I end up doing a flame uh rant about 10
minutes or 20 minutes. Okay. Two days
ago. Okay. So, you you can you can watch
that if you want to. And not just not
just yesterday, but this is like the
last month, few months, you know, this
I talked about that topic
so many times.
Search my YouTube, you'll find answer.
Okay. But I don't think you are
interested too much because you know the
the so let me talk about so there there
is this viewership and uh you know live
stream like and YouTuber that like this
relationship
uh that's another topic. Okay, that's a
very interesting topic because like to
you know today you got you know you got
YouTubers right then and al and uh live
streamers right some of them of course
very popular like like when they are
live they have literally thousands of
viewers and the the comments just flies
right
and you also see donations ching ching
you know every few minutes ching
That's nice.
So you see it's a product of modern
society that made this possible. You can
have one celebrity then you have
millions people who knows me. You know
actually I'm kind of you know I'm not
the big one. I'm a small one. I have a
few thousand followers and I've been
because I've been blogging for like 30
years. So you know quite a few people
know me. I mean even before the YouTube
because I write you know online I have a
website.
So anyway so the the the thing is that
you got this situation the relationship
you have one
blogger or
streamer or video YouTuber you or video
broadcaster then you have lots of
followers thousands or millions
sometimes. you got this relationship
kind of uh situation. This happens in
with movie stars of course too.
So but uh you see I cannot get to know
all of you like I have no idea who you
are but some of you get know to know me
very well like you watch you watch every
you know everything about this actor or
actress you know what they like and you
know you maybe you are a fan you
identify with um so that situation
happens anyway why am I talking about
this
uh anyway so the other question is I
just bought a Mac Air M5.
Do you have an opinion? Yes, I think
that's very good. Congratulations.
Because I think MacBook is Mac is the
best hardware. Okay. So, uh M5, that's
the Is that the latest? That's the um
because I I know they made the latest
one. Uh let's see
what Oh [ __ ] You know today I you know
we are supposed I'm
supposed to code code this but we didn't
do it. Oh god. Okay.
So,
MacBook
M5.
MacBook Air M5. Okay, that's so good.
That's good.
Uh, yeah, MacBook Air M5. So,
congratulations.
That's right. Yeah.
Okay, that's it.
Skeletor delight. Thank you for
watching. Um,
actually,
so you know, let me let me let me
continue. Okay, so there's no need to
stop. But if you guys need to go, you
know, go go do whatever you have to do.
You see, because I'm thinking, you know,
so so right now I've been talking for
over
for um 70 minutes.
So, so there's a question, you know,
when should I stop? Like what do other
stream like should I stop? I don't have
a goal anyway. Um,
but you know, but what I want want
actually I want to do is actually I want
to start to code some wam language. We
talked about like random things but
I wanted to actually do some code
because this this is the most important
part. Okay. The the talking is not
important. The talking anyone can talk
and talk but the most important thing is
actually get the code done. I need to
get the code done. Um
yeah. So should I like start to code
some of that or should I just like
no you know start the next um
actually not this page the code is I
want to do is here
uh should I start the next
live stream? I think maybe I should
start next live stream.
Okay,
I am undecided myself.
Um,
so we got I got some notifications.
Great time to be poor right now.
Okay. So,
should I be like coding the wolf
language or should I just stop? Do you
guys have opinion?
I still got like few people watching. So
should I actually code? Because
if we code then I need a break I think.
Where is the W language code? Yeah, we
did this
kosh hyperbolic cosine. Fascinating.
You know when when I was studying
calculus 30 years ago when I first
learned about kosh Yeah. Let me let me
tell talk about some stories random
stories.
So 30 years ago of course I'm obsessed
in mathematics. So I that's why I wrote
all these right by by the way there's
another property you can like um anyway
there too many uh then there's surface
catenoid okay fascinating okay so you
need to actually go to the other anyway
so the um so 30 years ago when I learned
about kosh
hyper is also known as hyperbolic cosine
and I was wondering why do they call it
hyperbolic cosine. I mean so what what
does this have to do with like
you know hyperbolic like does it means
related to hyperola or like
like hyperbolic or does it mean it
relates to hyperbolic geometry which is
like a another thing.
So um and I recall I later on
you know maybe a few years ago I read
about it but my point is that back then
30 years ago
it's much harder
to find information like today it's so
easy like you you guys may not know
because Wikipedia answers you know so so
many things but 30 years ago there's no
Wikipedia
there is of course encyclopedias Yes,
you can go for example Britannica. You
can go to library and read about you
know read them
but still the the information is is is
not like Wikipedia or online where you
can actually find the information you
want. So I mean the question is why are
why why is kosh and cinch
called hyperbolic functions? What do
they have to do with you know are they
you know with hyperola or is it uh
something with hyperbolic geometry
exactly why
who first called them hyperbolic you
know like this kind of questions today
it's so trivial you know f first of all
you got Wikipedia or you can just ask AI
so let's ask AI because AI will actually
tell you
something uh intuitive you can
understand right right away.
So let's see why is kosh function
called hyperbolic.
Okay. So that will give you intuitive
answer right away.
So you new generation you know you enjoy
this this tremendous technology. Okay.
Okay. So why is Kosh function called
hyperbolic? The Kosh function hyperbolic
cosine is called hyperbolic because
hyperbolic functions are the hyperbolic
analoges of the ordinary trigonometric
functions sin cosine x which are
sometimes called circular functions.
That's right. Here's a key reason. Okay.
The Yeah. So I you know I
uh heard about that but exactly why we
need to know. So geometric analogy with
hyperola instead of the circle.
Oh I see ordinary trig functions
parameterize the unit circle x² + y^2 =
1. Okay, let's write you know
trigonometry which is kind of like in a
circle
you know so you know so blah blah blah
and hyperbolic functions do almost
exactly the same thing but for the right
branch of the unit hyperola. Okay.
Okay. So for those of you
young people, you guys, you guys need to
like dive into this. Okay.
Uh
which is called hyperbolic angle. So
core identities that show the parallel.
Okay.
co- identities that shows show that show
the parallel. Okay. So this is just this
is truly actually fascinating
because okay sine xcoordinate
cosine is xcoordinate s is the
ycoordinate. Okay,
that's a unit circle. That's a ordinary
trigonometry. But in the hyperbolic
case, kosh is the xcoordinate.
Oh, okay. So,
okay.
Okay. So
okay so core identities that shows the
parallel circular
hyperbolic co^ squar minus cinch squar
equals to 1.
Oh that's the well yeah so that is the
definition of hyperola.
So that is why they are called
hyperbolic but kosh is
you know so it's fascinating but the
kosh is you see they they are the um
you see they are defined by this uh this
exponential function you know e x minus
e raised to minus x /
ex you know you you see this exponential
constant is involved
so I don't remember you know so you know
if you are learning calculus
you know back then
you know you have to understand every
detail you know exponential function you
know but I don't remember it now so I
need to review but you need to know so I
mean so what I'm saying is that this
hyperbolic kosh cosine hyperbolic cosine
or kosh function is very interesting
because it's analogous to the
trigonometric functions of a circle but
instead instead now you have a hyperola
but meanwhile so that's one property but
meanwhile when you look at the
definition
of the cinch or kosh
You can see that they involve this
this natural logarithm this this this
number is very interesting. Okay, that
that
that's where the uh continuously
compound compounded interest came from
like this number. Okay, you can derive
it
and
so so this this hyperbolic sign and
cosine
they are defined involving this this
you know the this um natural logarithm
exponential function. So, so the
question I guess is how exactly why
are these uh numbers involved
because in normal hyperola I don't see
in normal hyperola you I don't think
there is you know the exponential
function involved.
Okay. So very interesting. So, so, so
the question is like if you are learning
calculus like how how does it exactly
how how did this uh e came up?
Okay. Then you got differential
equations definition. Okay. So I think
that's that's how they came came up.
The hyperbolic functions may be defi may
be defined as solutions of differential
equations. The hyperbolic sign and
cosine are solutions
s cosine of the system.
Oh, so a function's derivative equals to
the other function. Oh,
this relates to s and cosine.
Amazing.
You see the derivative of s is cosine.
The derivative of cosine is negative
sign.
Okay. Something something like that. So
but here
if you want a function such that the
derivative of one function is the other
function then the derivative of that
function is back to the that function.
then end with the initial condition that
that
function came up.
Wow.
Oh, and it's also the solution
such that a function second derivative
is equals to itself.
Uh,
wow, that's interesting. I didn't know
about this. So you see the tremendous
power of Wikipedia which I haven't
been reading this page
characterizing properties. Okay.
Hyperbolic sign cosine. Okay.
Okay.
That's it.
Okay. Algebraic origin why they feel
exponential. Okay. Historical note. The
name Cinch and Kosh were introduced in
the 18th century
mainly by Venzo
Ricardi
around 1757
and Johan Henri
Lambert.
Fascinating.
Okay, bye guys.