Hello, good morning.
Welcome to another episode of sale talk
show. We are going to do Emacs coding.
Write a look up web command.
Okay, so let's check video check audio
check. I'm good to go. Yes, if you are
watching this offline play at 1.7 speed.
If you are watching here, say hi.
Okay, so Emacs list. So let's see so the
today's talk show page on xahlee.info
xah
l e e.info
http no s
Okay, so if you are impatient
I already have a documentation written
command to look up doc or search web. So
if you search command to look up doc or
search web you'll find it you Emacs
list. Okay, so you just go to my
website.
And there is a code and we can use right
away. So let's copy
copy the code.
So if you are impatient, you don't need
to watch this video.
Here is a code. Make it into Emacs list
mode.
Evaluate the buffer.
So that's a command look up Wikipedia.
So let's say so put the cruiser on a
word.
Let's say
uh
intelligence.
Okay, intelligent then just
meta x
my look up Wikipedia do it.
Wait. So did we evaluate the buffer? You
need okay, you need to evaluate it.
Okay. eval last sixth.
Okay, then
put the word anywhere
and call
uh what's uh my lookup Wikipedia? Do it.
It'll go to the browser
and there it is, a Wikipedia article on
intelligence,
part of a series on psychology.
How interesting.
Close, back to Emacs. So, here's the
code, okay?
Now,
so, you know, you can already find the
code and it's pretty simple, but
now we're going to need to do something
uh
for me because I need to update my uh
a package. So, for the rest of you who
like to,
you know, just have fun learning about
Emac Lisp, the programming language,
stay and uh comment, okay?
So, first first of all, this command
requires
the browse-url
library
that has the function browse-url. So,
you give a URL and that function will
switch to browser and uh
and on that URL. So, the first thing I
want to know is if that browse-url
is loaded
uh when you start Emacs because if it is
not, then you need to do require. You
see, this is important because typically
for Emacs user, Emac Lisp coder, you may
forget to add this line, require
browse-url, because in your Emacs setup,
you probably have it loaded already.
But, when you show this code to other
people, they put this in their Emacs in
it, they start it, and they call it, and
they get an error, browse-url
uh unknown function.
So, that is why you need to know
uh you need to know if that browser you
browse
URL is already loaded. So, how do you do
that? Let me show you. So, magnify, go
to the terminal,
uh then just e
uh
in Windows you say run Emacs, okay? Then
you  Q, that means do not load any
in it.
So, there it is. It starts starts
instantaneously.
Can you see?
Oh, interesting. It does not even um
it does not even start the splash
screen. Usually it does. So, let's try
small case Q.
Okay.
Yeah, small case Q.
It means does do not load any of your
any file.
But if you use capital case Q, that even
uh it doesn't load the site file.
Anyway, that's not
uh okay, I'm not going to talk about
that, but anyway. So,
so you can see Emacs has started and
it's too small. So, control alt score up
to magnify the font for all buffers,
okay?
Okay? Then now we enlarge the window.
Beautiful. The default Emacs. Now, all
you have to do is call the function
uh meta X. Now, where is the meta?
Meta X
describe
function.
Okay, then you type browse
URL.
Okay, actually it will show it, but
uh
but actually your best solution is
actually not that I mean to
uh
uh there are other ways to do it. Okay,
let me show you guys the ways.
So,
better to do is you actually
So, let's go to it.
Uh
what?
Manual install Oh, that's another That's
my package. I'm going to show you later,
okay?
So, not uh look up Where are we?
So, this is uh talk show
and
uh
Yeah.
Uh
uh talk up web not that here, okay?
Command to look up web search for free
pop it out and this browser URL is what
we want.
Okay?
Put it back syntax collect new buffer
paste uh
make it Emacs this mod Emacs this mod
and let's just say this URL, okay?
It's just the Wikipedia website. So,
copy that.
Go to the Emacs no init file.
Uh then uh god the key stroke.
Okay? Then we switch buffer control X
B
go to scratch buffer
then control Y to paste it. There it is.
Now, we want to eval that to see if it
works. If it does not work, it means
browser URL is not loaded. So,
eval is control X control E.
It is loaded. Okay.
Now, it could be because previously we
called the command beta X describe
function browse URL. So, maybe that
loads it.
So, to be sure, let's do it again.
Okay. Uh let's close that.
Okay, there is another Emacs instance.
Control alt scroll up to magnify.
Yeah, this this Windows this very
annoying uh thing. You got a tiny area
to enlarge the window.
Because I have hover to activate window.
So, if I miss the spot, it switches to
the window behind it. Okay. So, anyway,
we start it. You can see now
Now, let's open a new buffer. Control X
B.
Okay, let's go to scratch. Then control
Y to paste it. Okay. Now, we going to
evaluate that. Control
X control E.
It works. So, that means the browse URL
uh library is
loaded in Emacs when it starts, even if
you have all in it off. Okay. Now, we
don't need Emacs anymore. Turn it off.
Uh okay.
Fantastic.
Okay. So, what I want to do with this
page, I want to uh
modify the code
a little bit because
because it is using thing at point,
which is slow and inefficient by a by a
100 microsecond or something. There's a
better way to do it, okay? So, but for
now
I'll just leave it, okay? Now, let me go
to my packages, which is what I want to
do. Hi.
Hi FY.
Samael, I wonder which icon font you are
using.
Icon font.
What do you mean icon font? You mean in
Emacs?
In Emacs, I'm using so you call
describe char. So, I have that in this
key.
Uh wait.
Oh god.
Press press press.
That's the command is describe char,
okay? Then it will show all sorts of
information of the current char, which
is X. So, expand the window so you can
see the font is Consolas. That's what
I'm using in Emacs.
So,
I'm not sure what you mean by icon i-
icon font.
Explain.
Okay, so
let's go to So, I have a package that's
already written.
Uh so, let me show you. That is um
that is xah lookup web. So, you can look
up
word on the internet. You can look up
web. Uh you can look up Google. Look up
Yandex, which is search engine from
Russia. Which different search engine
are useful.
Because when you search Google, certain
information that it's not likely to show
for US Americans. But if you search
Russians site, if you are looking for
some Russian perspectives,
they will show. Then Baidu is China's
search engine if you want to search
something Chinese. So each each search
engine, they send censor certain parts,
but each one is different, especially
when they are in different country,
okay? So you can also look up Twitter.
You can also look up street map. You get
on Google Map, you can look up images,
you know, that's Google image search.
Uh look up YouTube, look up Wikipedia,
look up the internet archive. When a
website is dead, you
you type a URL and press enter, you'll
look up the image archive. So for
example,
uh let me show you that command demo,
okay? So let's say um copy the current
website and uh
make it a xali.info, and let's say
xali.info, okay?
So you type the URL
or paste it, then
it's under the cursor, then you just
xali. Look up archive, internet archive.
So my key is space it space h a, so
xali. Space space h a.
So that will go to the internet archive.
Okay, it says you need JavaScript. Okay,
turn on JavaScript so it knows what
you're doing.
So you see xali.info is back from about
the first documented xali.info
is 2010.
So you can look at my website
xahlee.info from 2010.
xahlee.org
is way back to 2000. Okay, so but
anyway, we talking about xahlee.info
because in 2010, I removed all the
programming and mathematics related
technical articles to xahlee.info.
So, you can see 2010
on the internet archive. Wait, they
didn't Wait, they didn't show any.
You see, oh, there. September 25th,
that's the first archive.
320 response. Okay, so it's redirecting
to this link.
Okay, it actually it redirects. So, this
is xahlee.info
back in 2010.
That's 15 years ago.
Fantastic.
Okay, and you can do the same with
xahlee.org.
Um so, let's try it.
So, this time call the name
xah look up
internet archive.
Do it.
So, you can see
back to 2000, year 2000, the year of our
Lord 2000.
Open it.
The file you requested was not found.
Okay.
You know,
that's very annoying. That's the
situation back then because my website
domain, they automatically add a bunch
of
like ads. These are like not mine. They
just automatically added.
Why? Because back then I don't have the
I you know, you need the index.html.
If you don't have that, it does not
automatically go to index.html
home page. So, now instead now let's
look up Internet Archive on that URL. Do
it.
Okay, then scroll back year 2000
of our road.
Let's see August 17th, the first
archive. This is 25 years ago before you
were born.
File not found. Return to XahLee. What
the
Okay, click.
Now, I don't know why that is happening
happening. This is year 2000. That
shouldn't be um
Maybe it's because I have a different
redirect mechanism. It's not picking up
by the web archive. Maybe, I don't know.
But
we can go back go back
pick a different date. Let's say 2001.
Okay. 2001 Internet Archive April 10th.
Let's go there.
There it is.
XahLee's home page. Table of contents.
This is
25 years ago.
Year 2000, May.
So, that was my web website. Now, notice
it's all mathematics. That's how I
began. The first 10 years is all
mathematics.
A visual dictionary of special plane
curves.
Fantastic and beautiful. Okay,
you see back then they have
I didn't have thumbnails because 25
years ago if you have a image that is oh
my God it's too slow to load. You know
every image it's like people are using
modems. You have to buy the you know
some bits modems.
So it's not like today of course.
Today's internet is like a hundred or a
hundred two hundred few hundred times
faster. So
you can have thumbnails. So but anyway
25 years ago a glimpse of history.
Kind of also a glimpse of my life. So
mathematics wallpaper groups this is
very popular
article I wrote. It's linked by over in
university math departments.
The discontinuous groups of rotation and
translation in a plane.
Like nerd fonts. I don't know what is
nerd fonts. You guys are too young. You
guys speak a language I don't
understand.
What what what nerd fonts? You mean
fonts used by elite programmers.
Like they think of themselves as
hackers. So you mean in other words when
you say nerds fonts
you mean like hackers fonts or the font
talks talked by programmers something
like that. I don't know. Am I correct?
Okay so then you got mathematics
graphics gallery. Okay.
So this is back then.
Okay. That's my website website back
back then like
25 years ago. Okay. So
Okay let's So let's look up the
documentation for the
um
describe function xs look up internet
archive. Let's go to see the
documentation. Here it is.
Look up current URL or selection in
internet archive. Okay?
Now, let's go to the source code, which
is this package xs look up  el.
Enter.
There it is. So, in So, this is my
package xs look up  el. And total
number of lines is 400
minus the comments. And you got these
functions look up, you know, look up
web, look up image, you know.
And you can
list matching lines defun.
Okay. So, you can see 20 matches. So,
there are 20 functions in this package.
Now,
for example, you have look up synonyms.
So, let's let's go there. So, let's try
you know, so
for example, let's demo another um
s-
So, look up so put the synonym there.
You want to know the syn- synonyms for
the word synonym. Okay?
xs look up synonyms. Okay?
Go.
There it is. Synonym.
A word having the same meaning as
another word.
Equivalent, substitute, alternative,
alternate, analogue, counterpart,
parallel. Actually, those are not
synonyms. Those are related words
because there is actually no
synonym for the word synonym.
Okay, but that demonstrates the
command.
Undo, undo, undo. Okay. So, what I want
to do personally is that I want to
rewrite these commands, you see? Because
right now
uh let me let me show you what I'm
doing, okay? Defend, defend. So, if you
have any questions on Emacs or Emac
Lisp, ask me.
So, you got a bunch of defends, defends,
defends, defends, defends.
Uh
let's say
Let's see. Let's see uh look up
Wikipedia, okay? So, internet archive.
So, you see all of them are very short
and similar because all of them actually
just call this
this internal function
xs-lookup-word-on-the-internet.
So, let's go there. So, you can see it's
over everyone is short except the
lookup-internet.
This one is long because
it serves us the backbone, the engine
for all the other lookup.
So, you can give a word optional
optional word
uh or URL or browser function, which
browser you want to uh
uh use.
So, they all depend they all dependent
on this function. So, for example, copy
that. List matching lines, paste that,
show.
So, you see uh they don't show the
context, but
but you can see. So, let's try again,
okay? Now, use xs-search.
xs-search
search up that in this directory all EL
files. Do it.
So, you can Now, you can see
how they are used. The contact contacts.
Basically, they are all in this file
cell lookup, okay?
So, what I'm what I'm saying is that all
these functions lookup, web, dictionary,
Twitter,
they all call this function.
So, that you you don't have duplication
of the code, which is very nice. Okay,
but but now I want to change it.
I want them to stop using this engine.
Instead, each one just repeat the code.
Why? Because over the past 10 20 years,
I realized
dependency is very nasty.
You know, you you rather duplicate the
code. You don't want dependencies.
Why? For example, so suppose
uh
So, we were talking about lookup
Wikipedia. So, for example, I want to
show you the your this code. You are my
friend. I want to send it to you. I send
it to you, that doesn't work because
that depends on this
uh function.
So, I can't just send you this short co-
code. I need to also
s- uh send you this function. Okay, so
let's look up the docu- the source code
for that. So, I also need to send you
this function. It's kind of annoying.
So, but if you have the code, like each
function is independent, all you need is
Emacs installed. You don't need any
other packages. Then you can use it.
So, this applies to JavaScript, to
PowerShell, to uh
lots of other languages, too. So, so in
general, dependency is really nasty.
All applications, like for example, many
applications today,
they bundle Python, the entire Python.
They bundle it with their app. So, on
your computer, let's say Windows,
chances are you have several copies of
the entire Python programming language
in inside each app. It's just that you
don't know.
Like even Discord might might have
Python like bundled.
Maybe not because Discord use the
JavaScript the Chrome Chromium and the
the
elect- electron, you know, the engine.
So, anyway, so, what I'm saying is that
dependency is really nasty. Avoid it.
You know,
if you can just
have few lines of code that duplicated,
that's fine.
You don't want the dependency, okay?
So, anyway, let's let's look up
Wikipedia.
Wikipedia, let's search Wikipedia,
okay? Let's rewrite this entirely from
scratch because this is very simple.
Uh so, save it.
Okay.
Copy So, look up Wikipedia and today
we are going to rewrite this from
scratch. In fact, I I must have done
this in live stream in the past once at
least
in the past 5 years, okay?
So, let's begin X
UTF-8.
That's
that's declaration
of
of the file encoding and lexical
binding, okay?
Uh
so, let's write this from scratch, okay?
So, let's just um
Uh let's annoying. So, cut. So, this is
original
and let's write from scratch here, okay?
So, look up current word or text
selection in Wikipedia. That's right.
And that
let's remove it for now, okay?
From scratch. So, first job you want to
do is you want to select the word under
cursor.
Sorry for the confusion. I mean, I saw
icons rendered on your Emacs frame. How
do you implement that? Are they just
Unicode?
Uh
Where did you see it? I don't think I
right now I have.
So, if you start Emacs, the default
Emacs without in it, do you mean that
thing? That's Emacs logo. So,
Uh okay, so I think you meant that some
of my pages, they they got Unicode like
that.
That's what you mean, right? Like this?
Those are Unicode characters. So,
describe character.
So, you can see
that character, the name is
left-pointing magnifying glass. That's
an emoji, basically.
So, that code point is 128269
or in hexadecimal
1F50D.
Oh, yeah. So, that's that's just
Unicode. Okay. So, and for example, show
this in browser. So, I have some
conventions.
If it is a script,
a little snippet of code on my page, the
title contains this Unicode script
character.
Okay, go back. Now, if it is a
programming language package, not just a
function, but the whole package, like a
file, Then it's got this package little
icon, Unicode, too. That's a emoji, too.
But
so you got this package, you got script,
another package, and you got this TV
here. So go there, Xah Talk Show TV.
So when there is a TV emoji in the
title, that means it's a video.
Okay, but well, but I didn't add them to
all of these Xah Talk Show.
So that's just some of my convention
using Unicode, so
um and there they are a few others. So
if you don't know Unicode yet,
let me show you. I showed this many
times. Just go to xahlee.info,
xah code, that's xahlee.info homepage.
Then go down so you can see xahlee.info
search. You got that magnifying glass,
that's search.
Then you go to talk show, uh then you go
to uh Unicode.
So click on that. Unicode, everything
you ever wanted to know about Unicode.
So you got emojis, bunch of emojis
separated into different categories.
And for example, animals.
Cat faces, monkey, see monkey do.
Uh mouse,
rabbit, doggy, wolf,
fox, lion, tiger, you know, and you got
drag, you got frog, Pepe the frog, or
China bear.
Panda.
Or pig, or you got dragon, crocodile,
uh and a hippo.
And this cat, dog, puppy, poodle,
and you have lizards. They also
represent something today. Lizard,
turtle, and turtle is very ancient
creature that appears in a lot of
ancient mythologies. Turtle.
And turtle is one of the creature that
lives long, like
hundreds of years. Turtle.
Okay. These are
and these are was used by
in the past 5 years, they are used by
young children
who got their tits or
dick cut off
and they regret it. it.
So, they are trans kids, but they don't
want they don't want to be anymore. So,
they
kind of have a damage in their life.
So, they on Twitter, you can see them
they represent they put the lizard
icon
on the side of their name
to represent, you know, what they who
they are.
So, because why? Why lizard? Because
lizard has this property it regenerate.
It's one of the creature, you know,
it
you know, you cut off its tail it it'll
regenerate.
Okay. Then you got dragon, Chinese
dragon, okay.
Um interesting. So, dragon So, you see
there's an interesting thing, social
thing going on here. You see this
Unicode is named dragon.
It did not say Chinese dragon.
However,
I think in all
font I've seen, they use a Chinese China
dragon to represent this.
Now, this one
dragon face or similar. So, you see
the dragon in
China or in Asia, including Japan,
Korea, Vietnam, South Asia, okay.
The Eastern, so we can call them Eastern
dragon. They basically came from China.
The eastern far east dragon is very
different from the western dragon.
Now, the western dragon you guys are
familiar, you know, in knights,
dungeons, and the princesses
uh
empire, you know, you you dragon usually
evil. They blow fire and they have these
like they got wings.
So, that's a western society dragon from
the western Europe or
uh kind of old Greek maybe
dragon.
But, so the Asian dragons are very
different. They look like this. Kind of
like a snake, but with eagle claws.
Okay.
So, what is interesting about this
dragon emoji character is that the
Unicode usually they name the name will
tell you what exactly it is meant to be
the character. So, it says dragon. It
did not say Chinese dragon. But, as far
as I know,
all the emoji from Google or Apple or
Microsoft or Twitter, they represent
dragon
with a Chinese dragon, I think.
I don't remember I've ever seen a um
Who's that? So, let's go to Twitter. Oh,
I don't have it on, so
anyway.
I don't I don't have Yeah, I don't have
it on. So, go to Twitter, paste that,
you can see what kind of font it uses.
So, anyway, that's a digression.
So,
I'm telling you guys to check out my
Unicode page, okay? Then you got arrows,
you know, you got hundreds of
different arrows, okay?
And you got um
So, besides emoji, they are kind of fun,
but that's it. That's about it. And you
also you got cultural dingbats like many
of these symbols are ancient. This snake
on a staff
that's at least 2,000 years old.
Okay, staff of Aesculapius.
And you see and this caduceus,
you see many of these you see in medical
uh are related to medicine, but they are
ancient, okay? Now, this shamrock is is
less ancient and also the fleur-de-lis
this
very interesting, okay? And this ankh is
very ancient, like 3,000 years
from Egypt, 3,000 or 4,000, okay?
Uh this is this No, not this flower. And
also you got these other cultural
symbols, okay?
And uh
Okay, so that's interesting. So, you got
dove of peace. That's from That's very
young. That's like
50 60 100 years ago.
And peace symbol, okay?
Okay, then then you got, you know, so
those are like emoji like emojis. Okay,
these are emojis. These are dingbats or,
you know, they they are not So, let's
see, can you turn them into emoji? Not
all of them.
You see, some of them become emoji, but
not the others.
But then you got symbols, symbology,
which is more ancient than emoji. Emoji
is just uh
in the past 20 years phenomenon, okay?
In in with respect to human writing
the history of human writing system
symbology, okay? Emoji is just like 20
years old
for kids.
They don't know nothing, you know?
But then you go back to the printer
symbols, the dagger, the double dagger,
you know, they they get older.
Uh then then, but you know, they get
older and older. Punctuations also look
punctuations and
then you got dollars and you got sex
symbols. They are also pretty young. Uh,
sex symbols they are like 200 years old
only, okay? Then then today in the past
20 years you got this drama. Oh, tran-
trans. Oh, but
there's a
difference. The the the the the
trans but but a woman but
but it's that.
But no, you you are wrong. That's called
queer.
Yeah, the big drama about this.
Because I remember
I had this page
around year 2000
12.
So, around 2010, 2000, you know, back
then I have comma comment. People can
comment, you know, remember? That's a
thing. You comment on web pages.
So, around year 2010 or 2012 I started
to receive kind of like angry comments.
No not exactly, but they like they they
they you know, and and and not on these
100 other pages. They all just focus on
this thing, this sex, okay?
Or the other, you know, people. So, I
got lots of, you know,
um
esoteric, you know,
phonetics symbols and then you go to
mathematics. Uh, let me show you some,
okay?
These boxes they are popular in 1990s,
for example, this box or
shape. But but let me show you. So, and
also the brackets, they are related to,
you know, in linguistics from writing
systems and Chinese brackets ancient
4,000, you know, Chinese characters are
like 4,000
years old.
Then you got Asian brackets, got
decorated ones. Those are
from Western languages. And you got also
got exotic bracket symbols, okay?
Then you got um Tibetan, you got Ogham,
you got Arabic ornament parentheses, you
see? Very interesting. Then you got
Greek.
Okay? Then you got uh
Then you got mathematics. Oh my god,
mathematics subscripts
superscripts subscripts radicals. And
then a lot more advanced um
number sets, natural number, integer,
rational, real, complex.
And then sets and order, you can get
fairly complex, okay? So, what I'm
saying is that I got all these other um
interesting things, okay? Braille
Braille symbols, how are they designed?
What do they mean?
And history of Braille and APL
programming language, okay? APL
programming language is
a array programming language
known for these weird symbols and
extremely terse code because every of
APL's function name is a single
character.
You know, so your APL code is just this
bunch of characters.
Okay, then you got
um you got lots of other things. Critic
critic, you know, Russian alphabet and
also used in other Russian related
languages.
Then you got Let me show you some more
interesting things, okay? Uh
Korean.
So, anyway, I got lots of these
interesting things, but around 2010 to
they all comment. I got lots of comment
on this page six.
They will say, "No, you got it wrong.
This this symbol is supposed to mean
trans." You know, back back then the
word trans is not that popular yet, but
they all say
something, you know, like something
related then then they are they are post
the history like a link to some history
about this, you know, oh this this is
the flag for this symbol, you know, they
they will try to correct me, you know,
you are wrong. That
This doesn't mean
you know, this doesn't means uh
multi-sex, you know,
things like that.
Very annoying. And they and they and
quickly they will become angry.
Because if you say, "Well, actually no,
his historically this symbol is you
know,
something, you know, if you don't
address them
carefully,
it become ugly. Okay, so that's around
year 2000
10 2012. I got lots of like
angry and also and and back then that's
a lot of that from women.
Because back then they are pushing the
feminism.
Okay, we digressed much.
So, yeah, that was from your question
about this
symbols on my page.
Okay, so well, I was going to
uh code this from scratch. Can we still
do it? Yeah, I can do it in 5 minutes.
So, let me quickly start to show you,
okay?
Okay, let me quickly uh show how to
write this. So, first of all, you want
to grab the word under the cursor, okay?
So, first of all, let X begin X end. So,
that's the beginning position and end
position and the
and and let's just uh say
uh
skip char backward, okay? We want to
skip characters backward. And, we want
to skip characters of the word syntax.
That's how you do it.
Okay? One or more characters.
This bracket
colon word means
any character that is
considered a word syntax that includes
all alphabets of any any human language,
English, French, uh Spanish with their
accent symbols or linear, you know, with
the tilde or grave accent, whatever.
And, also include Chinese. This will
also include Chinese. You want that,
okay?
What you don't want is like typically
like you might do this A to Z, 0 to 9.
That will work, too, but then if you
have Chinese or Russian or Arabic, then
they cannot use they cannot use your
function to look up word on the web
because this does not grab Russian or
Chinese or Japanese or Korean.
Okay? So, you want that, and and you
want to also include
and
uh
dash and underscore, okay? So, skip char
backward, then
uh wait, then okay, then that will move
the cursor backward, okay? Then, set X
begin
point. Point is the position of the
cursor position. That returns a integer,
okay?
Skip char forward.
I need to do this fast because we
digressed so much. Then, set X end
to be the cursor position, okay? Then,
grab the whole thing. You want to say
save excursion because
beautify the code, because whenever you
move the cursor, you want to return them
to the original position when your
function is done. Because otherwise,
when people call your function
then all of a sudden the cursor went
somewhere else.
They don't want that. So, you want to
say save
cursor. So, what that means is that it
will
internally save the cursor position,
then you can move cursor whatever, then
when this is done
you know, when this code code block is
done, the cursor will return to whatever
the original position, okay?
So, now you now you got the position,
then you just say
uh let's say
browse URL, okay? All you have to do.
Then you need to find
the URL format for Wikipedia, okay? Now,
in the case of Wikipedia,
uh they have a particular format. Let's
see, do do we still have it?
Uh no.
Do we have a Wikipedia? Uh no. So, let's
look up
uh
look over the word dictionary.
Okay?
So, that's a Wikipedia entry on
dictionary, okay? So, copy the URL.
Remove that, okay? So, this is this is
the URL.
Okay? Now
this part is a word. So, you just you
want to
%s
uh so, actually you want to call format
%s, that's a placeholder, okay? Then
that the word is then um
uh
buffer
no properties, okay?
That's That's the code, and that's it.
Okay, so we now we
So, compare, okay? So, compare
This is original, very short. Actually,
it's got more features. It allows you to
say what browser you want to use because
you might want to use a textural browser
within Emacs Emacs called EWW.
Uh
So, let me show you, okay? So, for
example, we can go So, meta X EWW, okay?
Then, it'll ask you what page. Let's say
xah lee, okay? dot info, okay? Go there.
So, this is my page in the Emacs in a
browser in Emacs written in Emac Lisp,
EWW, okay?
So, you can see
my web
It also support images. So, close it.
So, this function anyways, this is
original. Now, because now we don't want
the dependencies of that. So, now we
just
manually code it. So, this way, you can
pass this code to your friends, to the
web, and other people will be able to
use it. You don't have to You don't have
to Oh,
By the way, what what what other
function this function depends on? You
might have to search it. Then, you know,
you have to pass a different function.
Then, you have to note By the way, you
have to
you know, this function calls that
function, so you need to that code, you
know, include that function.
Complicated. So, that's a problem of
dependency. Really no good, okay? So, we
haven't tested this yet, so let's remove
that, but this will work, okay? So,
let's just say Wikipedia 2, okay? Give a
better name. Now, evaluate the buffer,
so now it works.
So, now let's see and let's search for
something uh
uh
algebra, okay? Type algebra, then
C- lookup Wikipedia.
Two.
Do it.
Incorrect. Symbol's value as variable is
void. Okay, so we forgot we um
Oh, we spelled it wrong. Not e n g, it
should be e n d. So, find and replace.
Uh
e n d.
Change. Okay. Now, evaluate it.
Now, put the cursor on that word,
algebra. Now, meta x C- lookup Wikipedia
two. Do it.
Fantastic. Successful.
Okay, I think that's it.
Uh 1 hour, so we talked for 15 minutes.
Which language is this? Emacs, this, of
course. Hello, Hank.
Hank, did you finish the end of code
yesterday?
Uh
Okay, I think that's it. Typo l83. What
does that mean? I don't know.
Uh okay, I think that's it. Okay, so
we mostly we demonstrated this.
Um yeah, so the um
Yeah, so but if you want to use a
different uh browser, you can do
something, but let's
I don't want to Let's not do it.
Because that will take another 20
minutes to explain
how to have it use a different browser.
Actually, it's not too difficult, so I
can show you, okay? So, for example,
let's copy this again.
So, instead of browse URL, you just say
EWW. So,
describe function show the
documentation. So, this is the syntax. U
URL
then optional new buffer, okay? So,
okay, that's the syntax, okay? So, you
just say U.
That's a U that that will do, okay? So,
let's
evaluate this and let's put cursor on
the word algebra.
Go ahead again.
Do it.
Now, it will open in the U browser. You
see, U browser is slow.
That's another interesting story. U
browser is actually slow.
In this case, much slower
than a real browser. You see?
Now, the U browser is still parsing
because this this Wikipedia article is
fairly long, you know, this article on
algebra.
So, the U browser is still Okay, now
finally done, okay? So, now this is
Wikipedia in the Emacs U browser.
Okay, go down. So, on article algebra,
175 languages, okay? Whatever.
Then Oh, that you know, part of the
reason it's slow is because of this
Unicode. Whenever Emacs open a page with
lots of Unicode
that hasn't been loaded before, it takes
a long time to um
to display all these different Unicode
characters, you see? Because these
Unicode characters, you see, these
different languages, which is
interested, okay? Because they are very
complex. You see, there's a composition.
That's not simple characters. This
language is like um
any one of the Indian languages. You see
You see there's a composition. It's not
just a
uh you see you see and this is what
Mongolia or something. This Arabic. You
see there's also composition. Arabic is
right to left.
And this is another Indian language, I
think. You know,
this this Arabic or Iranian Persian.
Then this is
Mongolia or something
or Tibet.
Then you got okay, Western languages or
Russian
another Arabic languages or another
language using the Arabic alphabet.
Uh
and another one here.
And this is Greek, obviously. Greek used
in Greece.
And this is what the That's
Chinese, but that's another like a
special region or something.
So anyway, this this this is a Wikipedia
in the U browser.
Uh
so you can
you know, it's it's not so good because
you see because if you
look at the Wikipedia
browser rendering of the page, it's very
clear, you know, and it's fast.
But
but in Emax, you have to just like
scroll scroll scroll. Then then okay,
then the algebra
text begin.
Uh interesting. Does it actually render
the math email? Oh, it didn't. It load
images instead. Okay.
Because this you see
uh when you see oh, those are images. So
never mind.
So anyway, so let's close it. Let's do
it again. This time will be faster,
okay? So, let's try to look up Wikipedia
too. Do it.
See how long. So, now this time is much
faster. It was slow is because all this
Unicode.
Okay, so anyway, so that's the example.
Close that.
Uh
how you get Emacs command to use you
instead of the browse URL, okay?
Uh I think that's all I want to cover.
Oh, another thing. thing.
That is if you have the word, not just a
single word, if you have algebra, let's
see uh
um
Let's say let's see group theory, okay?
In that case,
you do it, it'll just look up the word
group,
which is not what you want. You see uh
let's see. Look up You see group is a
number of persons or things that are
located, gathered, or classed together.
But you actually want group theory, so
you want to make a selection and call
it, but that won't work. It'll still go
to um
It'll go to um
It'll go to what's this a page?
Uh
What's sketch from Charles Darwin?
Close. Oh, theory. It'll go
on the word theory instead. So, you want
to make a selection when there is a
space in between words. Then you look up
Actually, it's easy to change. Let's
just change it, okay?
Save the excursion, okay? So, wait.
Um
If
Uh what what what's the name for
selection? Uh
God.
Uh let's focus on this first, okay?
Selection um
Uh what?
Uh
What?
Oh, Jesus. What the uh I forgot the
word.
In Emacs, this terminology for the
concept of text selection.
It's mark and
uh
Okay, let's uh describe variable.
Mark ring uh
mark active.
Um no.
Region, okay? Buffer substring region
beginning. That's right. Thank you.
Uh region active p. That's Yeah.
You are correct. But, here what I want
is region active p, okay? So, that that
returns true if the region is active.
Region is a word. Stupid Emacs.
Region stand for selection in Emacs,
okay? So, if region is active, then use
uh use Yeah, re- exactly.
Thank you, FY2.
So, if region is active, then you just
um then you just set X beginning to
region beginning, okay? And X end to
region end. That's the beginning and end
position. They return integers, okay?
Now, otherwise
otherwise, then you do this. Uh okay, so
let's cut that.
If then save region
then
here paste that. Pretty fire the code,
okay? So, here's a code. So, if region
is active, then you set begin end to
region beginning, region end. If region
is not active, then you
then you skip char backward and so on,
okay? So, let's So, now you no longer
need that anymore. Pretty fire, okay?
Now, it's clean the code. So, that
Okay? Now, this code Now, let's evaluate
it, okay? Now, go here. Now, go here.
Select it. Region active. Now, meta X X
out the cup Wikipedia. It will go to the
page group theory. Do it.
Fantastic and instantaneous.
Okay? Thank you, guys, for watching.
Bye-bye.
If you like my stuff, obviously, you
must pay me. You should, okay? If you
work, you know, if you have a job, if
you are not a
slacker or
need, something like that, the young
people say, then you should, you know,
if you like my stuff.
Sponsor me. Go to xahlee.info.
http no s
xah code
So, lots of stuff.
non-tech,
keyboards, all sort of keyboard reviews
and stuff, programming language
tutorials and stuff, then hacker code on
programming language design, on
documentation issues,
programming language design and mostly
programming language design on on
and the user interface design on CSS and
history of the web tech,
HTML,
JavaScript and so on, web spam, scam,
SEO,
you know, like Google search stuff and
Google
what Google has done to the computing
industry in the past 20 years, history
and mathematics, lots of mathematics.
So, all the way down, Patreon me, Amazon
gift card me, PayPal, okay? You need to
go to their website, then
use your credit card or whatever.
Support me.
Thank you, guys.
Thank you, Hank. Thank you, Hank.
Unix.
Bye.
Okay, bye.
Shut down in 30 seconds.
I need to do some clean up of my code.
You know, what what I actually want to
do myself is that to recode all this
code so that they don't depend on this
uh
you know, look up word on internet. So,
they became independent. So, So, each
each function
copy
this magic line. Each of these function
is instead of like
three lines of code, actually one single
line. You know, three line of code, they
will become
like 10 lines. But, that's okay. It is
not repetitions, but I think that's
better.
>> Shut down. Shut down. Shut down.
Here.