you streaming stuff let's see if this
works
apparently not
oh actually it is walking so let's see
how many people come by so I started
with a streaming at 5 o'clock 20 minutes
ago
then my internet went out then I noted
notice that my videos there is a delay
of the video like I noticed that in the
past few some talk shows and I think
that you know because the my voice and
my you know my head does not sync up
there's a lag about half a second or a
second and I think that is because the
camera this camera you know this is the
worst camera possible never ever buy
this Logitech you know these big
companies they become that is largely
tech 920 okay something like that and I
talked about on my black blog before let
me just show you them so web cam so this
is the one logitech c920 it's a worst
possible and also it cannot focus it
cannot focus anything close like any
anything we think it can it can actually
focus like it has Michael you know it's
it's got autofocus and it can come as
close as you know even this close and
you'll be sharp however the problem is
with the autofocus from where you know
the software inside the camera because
when you are close you know anything
near you know within half a meter you
know like on almost length then it's
always blurry
you know like for a second you'll see
it's very sharp then it becomes blurry
the final you know focus is always
blurry so that is this Logitech c920
it's one of the worst do not buy this
camera and the camera I am using right
now is a logitech you know cheap cheap
camera like ten years old you know
thirty dollars from ten years ago and it
works fine you know that that is what
I'm using but it does not have autofocus
so so what I'm going to do is a I guess
I'm going to let's do the JavaScript in
so web dev blog go to the SVG
yeah let's so let's do a live coding
live coding shape Styles path elliptic
path so what I want to do is okay so
okay copy that
let's go to JavaScript my web day blog
let's go to the top add a new section
paste it here linked by and saw start
command log mod ok so you can see all my
Emacs commands here and now let's copy
that paste it here and we want to
interactive app path Alysse SVG circle
arc okay that's right
CL CL e circle hoc let's just say that
and
code the command saw HTML copy copy HTML
by link what that does is that it copy
the content of this page to this link so
essentially creating a new page so now
copy the title go back
open the file modify the title modified
the date/time and that and basically
delete everything on this page
Chrome browser paste it here I want to
use Google Chrome browser here because I
have JavaScript out there and here we
want to start to write an application
okay so this is going to get complicated
so first of all copy the name taste it
make a JavaScript link of I so I just
created the file here there's no content
yet so this is my JavaScript script and
so what we want to do now is that we
want to create these let's see if you
can see that we want to create this SVG
tag by using javascript and we want to
create a bunch of inputs input boxes on
webpage so people can adjust those input
boxes and see a you know the actual
result
okay and it's tilted keyboard
what
wait why is that Kalugin talk show
invert so I have this article
Araki efficiency that is right but i
want to go sub half shell
because we did a talk on that yeah I'm
not feeling like
Santa shall search for invert so there
is the article here but that is not
right so this is 2019 April 24th April
24th so do we have a April 24th no we do
not have a page for April 24th that's
strange but anyway let's just open this
page open this page so this page has got
the thing we want because you can see it
copy the path
you can see the interactive application
here because I can change the value you
can see the value changes there so it's
basically got the framework we want so
let's just search for and copy it copy
it close it close it
Kibo glucose it go back to my circle arc
application paste it here and showing
browser so we got this thing and we just
want to modify this so so let's say
interactive circular see see I'll see a
hawk and the we want the parameters to
be
X and why
our x ID x sighs sighs to maximum to rx
okay so let's see how it looks in
browser okay that's not the exactly what
we want but refresh our X needs to be a
input that is right so we got the X
right the others we can be moved remove
the table remove remove remove table and
basically we don't care about the others
so we remove that as well but the
display we want so we put the display
here delete delete delete save switch to
browser refresh so we are getting
ourselves some sort of skeleton for the
JavaScript and we want to say so this is
the input box for the rx
parameter we have so we have these
parameters okay so these are the
parameters we need so so we got our X
okay and we need our Y that's right we
face our X by our Y okay and we need one
for rotate
but okay but
so when I was like a copy that paste
paste paste paste the paste ha X by lot
yes yes yes yes and we place our X by
our flag yes yes yes yes okay
and actually awk awk flag is either yes
or no with 1 or 0 so so size is 1 max
length 1 value okay that value means the
default value let's say 1 so awk flag
rotate our flag sweep flag okay so sweep
flag yes yes yes yes
okay then last two parameters is x and y
so which is let's just copy it there
remove our
no yes yes no yes yes no yes yes no yes
yes okay that's pretty much what we have
so let's show in Google browser rxry
okay so there is something there
shouldn't be wait yeah we don't want Br
so let's remove the
okay and then we are going to have a
display area so this is SVG SVG display
Heidi
okay so let's copy that ID go to the top
SVG basics mmm we don't want that let's
leave it that style okay then
SVG display we want a sieve CSS
cascading style sheet and we want this
is an ID and we want border okay for the
solid red solid thing red okay and let's
switch back to HTML showing browser
okay so rxry rotate
Hayek's ry rotate so what does it
hogs are X Y and then rotation
our flag sweep flag
okay so there there needs to be other
things but let's let's just begin with
this I mean let's get the structure
going so this we don't need section
section we don't need let's remove it
and actually this we don't need let's
remove it actually that we don't need to
remove remove and let's just go to the
SVG JavaScript
okay and
let's see how it goes so what we need to
do is to first of all we need to
intercept get these values of the input
boxes so we're gonna do constant get get
element by ID okay and I think you need
a document before it but it's Jahoda x
ha X okay
it's get element so we do have the
elements X dot values okay should be
value Y X dot value is the value of that
let's just print it and see if we got
this working in the first place so the
default value is 8 okay so let's show in
browser okay let's turn on the console
log yes
and go to the console and uncut
reference error element by ID is not
defined indeed because you need
document.getelementbyid d which is
idiotic
ok refresh 8 so we got the value of that
so that's good
now we got the value now we need to do
this for all of them we need to do this
for all of them all the inputs and that
it that is right so so here is how you
get the value let's just do it then get
the value for all of them so so on a
second let's go back here
yeah our X are Y now I don't like the
single quote so let's just replace them
all by double called rx ry and rod okay
rot ugh flat okay yeah sweep flag
and X&Y okay
so that's how you get all these values
now you have all these values you can
yes and by the way this hog flag default
should be one and sweep flag t4 should
be one okay let them be and now we need
to generate a SVG tag like that that's
what we need me to generate but before
we do that we need to get this display
SVG display die okay this should be died
so we can get the SVG display element
the reason we need we want that is
because so that you know that's where we
want to put the SVG there you know to
insert but before we can insert we need
we need something to insert we need this
string we need to generate these
elements and inside it so the way you do
that is to of course you go to the
scripting SVG I have an example here
that's the one you want to use so create
element SVG one document document
document dot create element in s and S
stand for namespace it's one of the
stupid thing from XML so here you create
a SVG document which is that then you
add width and hate okay so okay okay so
say attribute okay set attribute with
equals to set attribute with equals two
so that's how how much which do we want
1,000 show a Shelby and 1000 too big
let's say 500 okay and we need to hate
that's right then so we got with and
hate then we want to generate a path
element that's easy we do this again
constant path one let's say path one and
okay then we the path elements needs to
look like this you see so the SVG
element we don't need no longer need
path element needs to look like this and
we actually need to add a style so so
let's do that
so we are adding a style because if you
do not add style the path may be
colorless you know by default
it may not have any color or it has feel
you know it's pretty stupid
so let's actually let's see what yeah
let's deal with styles later first of
all let's just get the element up so we
got SVG one that's the container then we
got path one right but path path needs
data you know SVG path it needs D equals
to something so what you do is you just
like that you set the attribute T but
what should the value be that's the
interesting part so so that's what
you're going to generate you're going to
generate a string and add it to as the
value of D the D attribute so what
string you want to generate you want to
generate the string like these like
right now they here so let's it's do it
here it's just for it here so we can see
so in okay so let's do this we need a
start point
stop X star X will be so 500 500 let's
start at 100 and 150 50 okay so
so we gonna pass stream okay path stream
will be equals to M
now we might want to use the JavaScript
template stream for this purpose because
template string is easier to read so
javascript in depth string template
string yeah let's use template string so
template string so instead that you have
that and for every element you just do
that so this will be start start X okay
start x dot y and hey foo bar good
morning okay so I'm kind of I'm kind of
aimless today and goalless because how
many people are here three people
because I began I began broadcasting
live at four o'clock but my internet
went down you know it
we started automatically then then I
noticed my video is having lags because
of the camera so you know I'm so I'm not
I'm not actually doing any I'm just kind
of wasting time well good morning so
what what have you been doing so what I
am doing right now is you know I want to
code this I'm coding a live stream me
I'm encoding this I'm coding I'm
creating a live application
interactive application
that draws ellipse circle arc with SVG
so so what are you being up to today you
are you us right you on USA
you know I'm thinking like you know
maybe I'll delete the video actually
after today because I don't feel like
I'm doing actually any kind of a talk
show I'm just doing any random it's my
voice actually on yes okay so so right
now we are generating this path stream
USA okay cool
so do you are you are you a programmer
yeah yeah because you have kid hub right
so you are and your Emacs users so what
what do you do I mean to you work at a
company right now oh do you not working
or you know you work you're a programmer
so so like what do you what what kind of
programming do you do or and what
language so path string so that then
so path stream then we need a Oh
so the starting point is aim that's a
starting point and the L is the actually
why don't we just copy that okay wait
okay so
okay fubar says I own I own my own
company and I am a crusher crusher
script hacker oh that's fantastic
that's wonderful oh sure yeah and so I'm
familiar with SVG standards years ago I
made my own graphing library using SVG
and closure script and react out jeaious
oh that's fantastic and that was years
ago so actually I never got the hand of
using a hosted I mean a language that
compiles to JavaScript you know so today
we have a lot of them you know the
crosier script is one of them we also
have quite a lot of them almost it's
like almost every high-level language
they have a project that converse
converts the code to JavaScript I know
there's a 1/4 goal and I think there's
one for camel and movie has cow in Julia
it's like almost every language has you
know you know a compiler that compares
their language to JavaScript but when
you've seen that there's a there's a
question actually maybe I can ask you
maybe you know it's like it's like I can
I understand if I'm coding croushore :
okay or Python you know I I I could
write you know I could write some kind
of interpret translator let's say that
converts one language to the other no I
cannot write it but actually what I mean
is that you know for you know for
example you know in your language you
have lots of functions that deal with
strings so in JavaScript you have a set
of functions I deal with strings like
substring or you know index of a string
or such string and so on and same thing
in Python and
you know Golan in and closure but you
know they are slightly different but
however you can write a program I mean
if you know closure well and JavaScript
where for example you you could easily
write a programs
write functions basically that that that
when you call this closure function it
try it transform you know it the stream
function into the JavaScript version
which so this is rather easy to do same
thing for the oil things but anyway my
question is when you use JavaScript to
code code the website you have to use
lots of Dom stuff like that right now
I'm doing you know the document create
elements you know that's part of the
term from from the browser you know then
there's a set attribute and the scatter
element by ID then later we're gonna add
events so all these are Dom methods so
but if you are using closure to
translate to JavaScript how do you do
these things that part I never
understand you know doesn't matter is
crucial or goal and you know that I'm
asking because the question I have is is
like I do not imagine there is one
consistent way across languages so even
within one language like so you know
forestry manipulation or for let's say
computing prime numbers you know I can
easily see how you can have a closure
code you just translate the function to
the JavaScript function version you know
that's easy but when it involves tome
how do you do it I mean you know because
basically every web application more
than half of the code is actually about
Dom you know so closure and closure
script is an expert-level language that
takes years to master it came
make you got like ink okay that's
well that's the exaggeration
you know that's because everyone loves
their language says that you know not
God like you know nothing nothing like
that
you know Haskell people will say Hess
cow is godlike and so on
so enclosure script you don't manipulate
strings to generate Gmail you use native
data structure literals
decoratively okay no prob no
programmatic no manipulation just a data
structure literal yeah but no but I I
kind of see what you are trying to say
but that's not true you know because you
actually unless you already in trivial
programs you know 100 lines or a
thousand lines beyond 1000 lines you
have to actually deal with Dom you know
the nitty-gritty manipulation for
example let's say okay so actually so
you know I asked this question before so
some people the answer I get is kind of
like basically nobody today programs
JavaScript the way I'm doing right now
like you know calling set attribute or
you know document create people don't do
that
instead you know they use react you know
I've learned I've learned react I
actually never coded anything but I I've
went through the tutorial and I
understand what it does and which I like
it very much but however so so nobody is
actually you know creating JavaScript
like writing tom you know you are like
what I'm doing right now so instead they
use a library frameworks such as react
so in react you don't you don't call
these create elements or set attribute
but instead you well yeah basically it
is they just have a wrapper that you
know you you you use you know slightly
different syntax and they they call
their code to actually you know actually
they do Co these commands you know
this.setattribute to create the element
in a sense they manage the elements for
you but yeah but still okay so suppose
you are using closures script how do you
how do you use react with it
you know so anyway so that is my
question that you know I'm I don't think
I'm actually asking the question well
because I'm not feeding feeling so good
right now
oh okay you're trying to show me
are you are you onna is there a
possibility are you ever gonna go on
video judging from our discussion
yesterday the answer is no probably I
could never
that's a father I have with the geeks
you know like you know you know because
then whatever we are going to talk about
the way we interact the communication
between us you know whether you you know
when you want to show me something it's
gonna be extremely inefficient you know
because when you're on video you can
people see your expressions and
everything you know you it's ten times
more efficient and whatever then just
pure plain text but the reason okay the
reason I think a lot of people nerds you
know geeks they don't want to go video
for you know quite a few reasons you
know for for example one of them is
there is first of all you know they are
shy or they are you know they are
introvert so they are not prone to you
know go on video you know not in real
life but they don't want to do a video
as well so just like me except you know
I you know I'm fine with you know I
suppose I'm kind of mostly introvert but
I could do you know talking to a lot of
people that's I have no problem with
that if if it's not too frequent and I
like to talk about my opinion certain
stuff so I don't mind showing my face
the other thing is okay so a lot nuts
the ice off I suppose to to actually
talk
you need a pretty face that is actually
true you know when you're when when you
do not look maybe we you know people you
know programmers maybe you are fat you
don't look so good you know you are
nerds you know a lot of nuts you know
that is part of the reason only I mean
basically generally speaking when you
are pretty you tends to show your face
you know and that that is oh that's that
is true overall historically and today
you know it's like a general pattern of
human behavior you know when you are
pretty you tend to show yourself and
also you can see this when different on
the age you know when you are younger
young people you can see them you know
they don't talking because they are
naturally even they don't know nothing
about history or Society but naturally
they can take take off their shirt you
know guys or girls they wear bikinis you
know they go out they trounce around you
know they they taught them to take two
things because they are pretty even even
you know they may not actually know it
because yeah when I was young I didn't
know you know and when the end and that
that behavior you know showing yourself
gradually disappears when you age you
know you can see this in women you know
you know in females when you are when
they are young they show everywhere
everywhere you know but it disappears
when they become you know 30 then this
you know then then you know when they
are 40 then it's less than this and
similarly for guys you know like like
when I was younger I I could take off my
shirt I look I look good you know a heck
walk down the street you know number the
panel today you know this ugly guy you
know so the Emmy is it's not just me but
it's natural you can you know like you
can see it statistically statistically
like you just go out on the street you
know you know you just look at the
doesn't matter it's a city or you go to
the beach
you Duke all the people you know showing
around other young younger guys tends to
be showing around the ugly people fat
people ugly people older people they
don't they hide okay and this applies to
not just your face but also your status
in society you know like when you are
doing well you tends to talk to a lot of
people make contacts make contact to
your family to your friends hey do you
want to do a meet-up you know there's
things going on because you are doing
well you have money you know you are
trying your fancy car you you know but
when you are down when you have you know
when you're when you are dying under you
don't have money you don't get depressed
you have a failure you don't contact
your people you don't contact you know
you you you become good like you
disappear you don't contact your friends
you don't contact your family that's a
general thing happens you know I know
because that's what I have been you know
that's my status you know I have been
like that but it's not I mean it's just
generally true but anyway perhaps I will
make a video someday but but all you
need to do is google region closure
script I am NOT a nerd but a strong
handsome man
come on video then so let's have a and
then you know we can do Google hangout
so the thing about you know I don't want
to Google stuff you know of course I can
Google iGoogle and you know I read
Wikipedia in programming languages all
day all day and night so I mean that's
what that's one of the situation where I
talk to nerds
you know like some people please you
know like right back right now oh oh I
have you know not not just you but I
have a lot experiences like some
programmers I really like I you know
they know some stuff I want to learn
from them but at the moment you ask them
you know they don't they cannot they
cannot teach
I mean they didn't want to you know they
don't want to go to in video they want
to text then yeah if you I mean great
yeah if we're gonna do text so you use
gonna send me some things thank you I
can do that myself and I've been doing
that for 20 years you know I can you
know I can start to learn answer my own
questions about closure script about how
they interact with react you know and
they are literally hundreds you know
YouTube videos on that subject as well
that's the point
I mean the point is because we know each
other like there's a moment like right
now not just you but I have you know the
in my experience there's lots of
acquaintances and friends you know I
like so on the instance I asked them you
know did you kind of shy away or because
the the point is when you have a moment
you know someone a friend okay you
there's a moment you exchange and he you
know like I I don't need another link
you know to cook to study about this
because then I can find it what's the
point of asking you then you know if you
guys just send me a link so this range
and minimalistic react for closure
script
okay so the other thing I don't really
like closure because not because of the
language because closure heavily
intertwined with Java and JVM user is
it's it's extremely pain yes with a Java
and JVM and you know I have I have
written an essay I don't know if you
have seen it I don't know if I should
mention it because I kind of be tired
you know I have because I have I have
thousands of essays about just about
every programming language I mean every
topic and so so my talk show becomes you
know I just show my website because and
I got tired of it you know I don't want
to you know just sell my own website but
I have written you know I have studied
crochet you know I did I have yeah let's
Google hangout sometimes thing yeah yeah
do you have to are you on Twitter or how
do we how do we come to how do I contact
you
yes yes closure is okay close your
script is hosted on top of JavaScript
that's great you know I know the guy who
wrote closure scripts like well I don't
know him but I'd I know who he is he's
hundred you know he's a big Lisp fan you
know and on Twitter and he's another
example right on our topic you know he
on Twitter or these nuts you guys okay
don't like to show your face so you look
at their profile they got there they got
a picture of you know a Batman or
something so but this Crozier script guy
he's got a profile photo of some kind of
a mask with Hans nerds you know
this what are they thinking so this is I
mean
so so is it so they are shy about
showing their sample himself so shy or
something well not necessarily shy but
occasionally you know these people
I guess when when force or something
okay you you know you have to give a
talk a lecture you know in your
conference right you know today we have
lots of turns of conferences you know
you know we have hundreds of conferences
every year or the programmers gather and
you know and you know there's a lot
lectures but I'm thinking you know those
people actually are not the nerd types
they are they are these programmers this
new generation of bootcamp programmers
since since year 10 2010 I suppose you
know those people they give talks but
anyway so this closure they are not
good-looking like me thank you shut the
up so so anyway so I don't know
what I'm doing so that maybe that's
today's talk show is like screwed up
fully screwed up because I don't know
what I'm doing well I'm because there's
no go and I was you know
okay yeah sub / well poor where where
are you from look like what where are
you from in US are you in u.s.
oh okay yeah don't worry about it go
just talk in react yeah that's that's
good that's good the the but you know
know people are watching it's no good
well actually I don't know so so should
ice continue with this JavaScript or
what Oh
originally from Poland now I live in New
York City great New York City yeah I've
never been to New York New York City so
what what else it's talking maybe let's
stop javascript in you know I noticed
that every time I start to code
JavaScript I mean this it looks like my
my followers there's a little interest
in JavaScript I can kind of guess why I
kind of know why because first of all
I'm most most and most people follow me
mostly because my Emacs stuff and you
know then you know programming my
programming language stuff and as we
know the Emacs people they are not used
typically practical people and a lot in
the Emacs land a lot of them weird you
know or we say we have disproportionate
number of people who are kind of very
weird I mean among the Emacs users I
mean that's kind of a like it is it is
that way because some sort of mutual
attraction because Emacs
is weird its intent its intention its
intended to be this weird non conformal
you know there is this niche thing so
that attracts those people who are kind
of these niche kind of people and not
not all Emacs people are weird of course
but I mean there's a lot a good high
percentage of them are
compared to let's say other programming
communities let's say Python so in Emacs
immunity there's a lot of weird people I
mean I mean not just I mean okay I can't
suppose I am one of them but there are a
lot I know I actually are know kind of
you they are pretty weird you know in
some other ways that you know eccentric
people yeah so and yeah eccentric people
so what what I was saying I forgot why
am i mentioning that oh yeah so so Emacs
people most people who follow me out you
know because of my Emacs stuff and a
money max people most Emacs people are
they are you know most of them are very
fanatical about open source or free
software foundation you know and me and
also these kind of people in general so
they also typically a lot of them let's
say use Leena's Linux and also a lot of
them are not mainstream you know they
are kind of weird they are not they
don't like mean strange stuff and they
also because they follow me because I
talk about a lot about programming
language elegance this kind of thing
programming language design kind of
thing this subject is not a mainstream
subject you know this subject is not
mainstream is like what's a you know
person was the best language to get a
job like Java C C++
those are mainstream things in
JavaScript okay you know the the people
are talking about the elegance of
programming this you know smackhead
scheme those this art niche you know
they are like the fringe of society you
know me part of it was you know you
included so we are this fringe of
society you know fringe meaning like how
many programmers in the population less
than 1% right something like that I'm
pretty sure less than 1% 100 you know
that's it's a lot of people but you
don't have 100 as a programmer but
anyway um um programmers how many people
are Emacs users less than 1% I would say
for sure
among programmers I'm talking I mean you
look at all the people who make a living
by programming by coding ok and of these
people let's just limit to us a of these
people how many of them actually use
Emacs you know regularly was the editor
less than 1% you know but how many uses
let's say vs code or Adam that that's
gonna be like 10% or 20% okay so Emacs
users are kind of this niche very small
group you know ok so and also Emacs
people they also tend to be because they
are non mainstream they also take a lot
of them disproportionate number of them
tends to be poor you know poor like me
you know because they are weird they
don't they don't they don't have a job
they don't have a regular job they do
whatever you know that is they do you
know so they take people so well not not
everyone of course a lot of them you
know weird
so fuba fuba says emacs's track attracts
eccentric people I only know it well
because I studied this and used culture
ok and most programmers are worthless
followers who have no idea of their own
who have no ideas of their own they care
about getting a job and care not for the
study of computation yeah and bringing
new ideas to the world yeah I suppose
yeah
no no that's false
ha well okay I'm gonna tell you because
I'm the master of addressing these these
these fake news you know they they are
fake news in the world in the in
politics you know you guys know it right
but they are also fake news a lot of
them in the programming community I'm
the master of answer pointing out those
fake news the link you just posted I
don't need to look at it in fact I've
seen it I see it every year because I
study this kind of thing know that
that's fake news okay okay you you that
link Stack Overflow I suppose that's a
survey you know they they do that survey
yearly you know this away you know how
many people what languages you use how
many years you have in programming you
know what's your favorite framework you
know what percentage you know they do
these statistics every year and how many
people what's your favorite editor you
know how many of you use the max that's
fake news first of all the way they do
that you know they do that this kid hub
in Stack Overflow they do that to
promote themselves just like Twitter
Facebook okay because these kind of
things programmers get excited they know
that because they have statistics every
tenth time they write it this way they
did they write some content oh there's a
lot of traffic they get money you know
money that's what what happens so they
create this survey okay
then it says forty five percent of the
users are Emacs that's that's fake
that's that spec that's okay
yeah forty five the reality is what it
means is that forty five percent of
users who actually take the Stack
Overflow survey are you Mac users so so
but how many people takes a stack
overflow survey among programmers man
you know let's here to say in USA oh oh
worldwide okay among people who may
so leaving by programming okay because
when we when we want to talk about these
statistics you gotta be you gotta become
scientific you know we're talking about
everything is well-defined so by you
know our question is how many people how
many percentage of programmers use Emacs
first of all what do you how do you
define programmer you know do you define
you know who has written code you know
some code in there life is a program do
you define you know 3d visualization you
know working in chemistry you see a
programmer do you define design web
designers to define her you know usually
it's a women you know she sometimes
write code you know some CSS sometimes
but most of them have a lot of time
should design websites you know do you
count her as a programmer so first of
all you have to be precise what do you
mean by programmer so yeah so but so I
can't throw out the way I define
programmers okay so so all those people
who write code who makes a living by
coding primarily coding so anyway we're
not going to get into details so my
point is just that that 45 percent of
Emacs users that's you know for
Emacs user like us who are you know
living in Emacs and loved Emacs and we
see that we say we think immediately oh
yeah such as a lot people you know
that's in reality you actually
go to a company you survey you by all
means by any means you you want okay but
the point is if you actually seriously
to think about the issue of how many
people among programmers are actually
using Emacs it's less than 1% even even
less than one in what way 1000
okay less than 0.1% that's how many
actual Emacs users so this is another
that's the
in what 25:45 yeah 4.45 that's what I'm
saying I mean I'm saying it's far more
or less than that I'm saying it's not
the programmers who use the Emacs oh if
you counted on all computer users who
use the Emacs it's one in a million you
know if you just limited to programmers
however you define it it's less than 1%
it's less than 0.1%
okay that's reality it's nothing like
the full point what 4.5% these
people and you know that's fake news
that's what you want to believe you know
truth trust me I don't mean to you know
you know shut you down
it's it's what you like to believe you
know it's it's like Mac Mac users
Matthews are fanatics you know that I
despise the Mac users because in
America it's like just like the old
saying Emacs versus VI or language was
it's a religion you you know you program
enclosure for example okay you love it
so to you is that this is God
this is design of the car with closure
every language is worthless you know
because closure you audio all you have
to do is define the structure everything
then you have the Emacs phonetics you
have the Mac phonetics Mac OS you know
Apple Apple every day they go to
conferences you know Apple Steve Jobs
back then let's all push it this is just
like religion that's what you want to
believe you know so I so so what is my
religion I okay my religion is anti
religion it's I five my specialty my
expertise is is attacking this this
fake news every especially UNIX
and Linux and this hash code is kind of
Emacs programming community
[Laughter]
whim is popular far more popular than
Emacs for sure because first of all whim
is part of eunuchs whim is part of the
UNIX system so Emacs is not installed
you know by default fact this is true
back 30 years ago 40 even 40 years ago
and it is true on Linux Linux is almost
basically every distribution of Linux so
when you learn Unix
you know sistered mingle even 30 years
ago VI is part of it it's part of the
thing you have to learn along with all
the bunch of password you know
command-line crap you know those UNIX
you know cat tail and all that so
so yeah so so VI is part of a UNIX and
that's part of the things you have to
learn so it is obviously and patently
it's far more popular is quite a lot
more popular than Emacs throughout the
past 20 years over 30 years except
except the difference might be except in
1980s so you know 1980s or late 1980s
because that was when or early 1990s
okay that because back then when MX is
truly one of the what what today's then
you know internet science called key lab
okay Emacs is truly one of the greatest
application you know back then you know
30 years ago because it it's the you
know at its that the top of design the
top of technology you know the you know
what you call the the state-of-the-art
package you know there's nothing better
it's a it's it's you know in every every
way in every aspect okay but that but
that days has been long gone you know
that today Emacs is just
you know it's just evil mud
you know trikes are fly keys okay fubar
you know that's far more efficient than
Evo mug Evo mod not shutting me down I
don't care how many uses show a hollow
number compared to others yeah
no one says okay now people are coming
on actually I'm okay so no one says I
doubt that beam usage is so common
either I would guess things like vs code
X code major ideas are almost the entire
market yeah that is true because I mean
but I was saying him it was you know
among Linux among the UNIX you know when
your job is you know involving Linux and
UNIX back then you know VI is you know
the it is the main and still I suppose
still main editor in the Unix Linux
community but yeah you know that
although all the other editors are
taking the you know ideas they are the
entire market so the neo says hey Daniel
so Daniel says yak has an identity
problem trying to put a name on what
Emacs actually is personally I'd like to
see you max kendo capabilities a full
fledged IDE yeah yeah you know Emacs is
entirely a big topic you know what I
really like to see me is that I think
the bottom line the the real thing is
eMac B's there's no progress in eMac
this for like 20 years
you know this a little you know we added
some we added this idiotic you know
closure basically the static static
variable
but no is static scoping okay the static
Stoke scoping is one of my rant it's one
of the hacker types love to talk about
they talk I did when they think about
improving language did their brain has
no no content except these kind of
static typing you know static scope
that's a big rant okay I go into some
other day but typically this programmer
you know the yeah basically my followers
so they they just have anyways so Emacs
we email is do not have any progress
except just a few like two or three
features added in the past twenty years
and one of them is the static scope
which is in my opinion it's one of the
most idiotic a choice of improve
improvement to make to eMac B's it's the
most idiotic yet it's it is one of the
feature that vast majority of the hacker
types they'd love they think it is the
absolutely necessary thing to them also
the other thing okay related to this the
other feature if you ask Emacs users
eMac this was okay what they want they
what they think is the most critical to
fix I can guarantee that the next item
besides the static scoping variables we
already have I can can I can tell you
like right now guess you know you ask
your friend go to reddit posts to see if
I'm right the the the one feature they
want now is thread idiotic
threads
you know thread is the most idiotic
concept in programming you should not
have threads instead of you should have
you see you should have the transparent
autumn autumn Matic system of parallel
programming of course that's not easy to
do and there's no good solution for that
but that's the direction one should go
never threads never thread thread my ass
he max the antique the extensible
customizable self-documenting real-time
display antique I think most young
people just use the mouse when things
are clickable most ideas have a viproy
game lexical scope yeah like six weeks
ago scoping is what I mean yes I have a
tendency to always not get the right
word jumbo of you know like somehow
lexical scoping that's what I'm talking
about yes you know the Mexico scoping is
related to the concept of closure now do
they actually do they actually guarantee
each other in patch other I don't think
so I'm not sure but I have to I forgot
you know so do too I'm afraid to ask
because if I ask you guys are probably
going to give me answers which I do not
necessarily trust okay because this is a
this kind of is is something I study you
know in depth so the question is is thus
thus less does less lexical scoping
guarantee closure I mean are they based
so basically in in in math 20 of logic
the way we say it is that does does
lexical scoping invite closure like they
invite each other I don't think so right
it's not the same exactly the same thing
but anyway and yeah so what I want to
say the other thing I want to say my
rant is that closure you know the
programming concept of closure is the
most idiotic thing in programming
languages and idiotic feature we should
ban it because first of all closure
what closure does when you have a
closure first of all when you have a
closure your function is no longer from
mathematically speaking because it has
side effects side effect that's the
definition of closure essentially you
don't have a functional programming
anymore but for reasons these industrial
hacker types programmers they they
always love closure and the other thing
they love is Marcos which is another
most idiotic thing
No well I see what you're saying
Danielle but well I you know
so Daniel says well I mean that that's
we need to defy it
so Daniel says does lexical scoping
guarantee enclosure and Daniel says well
a closure is the combination of a
function and the lexical environment yes
that's that is true tempting to take
JavaScript as an example here yeah I
yeah that is true I mean yeah you do
need the concept of functions yeah
well right so obviously you need
functions because that's what closure
you need to function function with a you
know environment that's what closure
means but of course that's what I mean I
my question includes so what so I don't
mean closure implies lexical scoping
implies closure rather so my question in
more verbose terms is that does Lexi
does lexical scoping in price okay so
when you have a function when you have a
language what language that has a
function that has a you know definition
of a function or anonymous function and
you also have lexical scoping does that
automatically mean you have closure
that's the food I guess that's the full
sentence of the my question but anyway
that that's still not well defined
because what does a function mean
because different languages that there
is function or subroutine they vary
quite a lot so anyway that's yeah so
anyway that's getting that's another you
are confused about closures my friend
I wonder how if I feel how it feels to
be confused about closures and also to
have friends how it feels to be confused
and forgive me I can't make sense of
that purchase on outside of extra
closures are side effects fubar
we can start to argue right leg right
now like goat go online go on like it
you know show your face we start to have
a debate services full bar closure is by
definition is a side effect
I can't I can't like again you seem C C
Mon that my ass I can start to show you
my tens of articles on closure I catch
you
truly
okay anyway I'm just having fun
okay you know don't worry
so actually debating with another
programmer so I wanted to do that I want
to do you know like I flame the the the
the the you know the hacker types all
the time you know those these UNIX
philosophy types this actually those are
the people that follows me because
that's that's the area that's the
community that's the kind of subject I
go into but I just always have issues
with is common so so I'm again its
mainstream Emacs users or Haskell
closure programmers we are also not
mainstream but in this community I am
the main string of them of them so I
want to attack you know I don't agree I
mean I don't just like I'm not trolling
okay the people like to call me a talk
show my ass I'm not trolling I'm telling
you the closure can't say I'm telling
this you know UNIX philosophy these
people their idea or Emacs people they
are thinking do you know they are they
are beliefs they are that's just that's
just religion that's that's
fake news closure the definition that
the the main manifested manifestation of
closure when you have the closure in in
in programming languages the
manifestation is states that is
side-effects function don't have States
the main purpose that what you get out
of closure is States just like when you
are using a global variable except the
variable is private it's not global you
you want the states that's what closure
is for once you have lexical scoping
once you have closure then you have
object-oriented programming because you
define your class a class is a closure
then because you it has you know
internal methods and member variables
and and static variables and so on
that's what closure is you know class
then you create something
of a castle object you know that's
crucial you know that's you don't call
it closure because it got other features
so you call it class Opie you know good
evening
I mean I'm kind of I'm kind of I'm kind
of done so but you know today's talk is
kind of like it's really bad actually if
you watch from the beginning the first
so I've been talking for 80 minutes 19
minutes now that but the first 60
minutes is like crap it's just me trying
to code there's no talking and stuff so
anyway so then after an hour people
start to come out so we start to chat on
random things programming language kind
of random
so hey and I started to rent okay so
about kosher we should okay next
maybe next topic I'll talk in detail
about closure you know but by the way of
course this is I'm talking right so I
have you know you're gonna fail if
you're gonna argue with me because I am
the one you know keep talking yeah you
know your point your point is not
prominent but you know so so but you
know but but so what I'm saying so you
know I I would like to you know debate
with you know some you guys if you you
know anyone wants to about some of these
concept ideas but first of all when you
when we debate when people debate in
general okay you have a lot of hot air
because often often times when two
people debate or argue they actually
agree but however it's just the wording
there's a misunderstanding going on okay
so you know perhaps there's a
misunderstanding because we cannot
communicate well with exactly you know
maybe actually we don't have anything we
disagree at at the moment
so anyway let me read some some comments
so I think so Norman says I think that
term can be overloaded by in confusing
scope versus extent or lifetime a
variable references yes terms can be
confusing and overloaded and overloaded
is one of the overloaded word in English
I hate that word especially see no CC +
first that's ideas they have that word
they use that word overload you know
operators anyway scope versus extent ok
extenders in extending a class a
variable references debate is fun and
healthy ok the Common Lisp standards
talks quite a bit about this about okay
so Daniel says if we want to do the
closure inside of X less so then instead
of X are the easier concept yeah good
evening good evening I'm I so foolish
says functional languages don't allow
for mutations and yet have the closures
like what which one Haskell we are well
yeah sure sure example if you know so so
daniel says talk about closure a stroke
of genius to marry this procedural or
even class object-oriented syntax with
these functional topics
okay Norman posted a common list
standard is relevant to the discussion
so let's see scope and extent and it's
Magnum fine
this comment is look at their
documentation they sneaked out of date
for 30 years you know one time I RC
around 2006 I offered you know to update
the HTML but you know I'm known as a
troll you know major TRO so many of them
dislike me so they they don't of course
the reaction is it's like you know go
away but it's true you know look at all
the you know common displeased kind of
died today you don't hear people mention
it anymore but but imagine this this
HTML documentation you know in this HTML
this style you know these long lines you
know more than 800 characters per line
this is like 1999 styles of HTML and
imagine how programmers today you want
to convince them to use common DS
because then they read documentation
they CDs you think they're gonna walk
these companies so you know I try not to
swear too much but you know these are
these for having idiots you know these
anyway so this effect to the content
okay scope and the extent in in
describing various features of the
Communist language the notion of scope
and extent are frequently useful okay
those notions arise when some object or
construct must be referred to from some
distance part of a program
okay scope refers to the spatial textual
region of the program with in which
references may occur okay extent refers
to the interval of time o of time doing
which references
made me occur so they call that extent
that's that's just like dynamic scoping
that's what you know typical kind of
thing with that issue is dynamic scoping
yeah by the way I'm not saying dynamic
scoping is good okay
absolute least lexical scoping is
absolutely the way to go
we have dynamic scoping because in the
early days in the early days of
computing it's easy to implement that's
that is all just like much of UNIX
philosophy the design of Unix the
choices UNIX makes the only one reason
is because it's easy to implement that's
yet period unique UNIX philosophy in my
ass the this this principle applies to
much of UNIX every UNIX operating system
their decision and anything in C
programming language okay the way C is
this way or that way because it is easy
to implement these UNIX people
okay okay so anyway so back to the
dynamic versus stack lexical variable
okay so this Arco is mentioning it's
saying these two are different things
okay
but anyway so a simple example consider
this program so anyway so okay so this
Arco goes I guess goes into detail about
that
let's read de
so today's you know so we are just
chatting here so that's good
so mutability introduces an axis of time
to your system often times unnecessarily
complicating it yeah Daniel says
understanding scope is as easy as these
there are two kind of scope the global
scope in local scope fubar says there is
also black scope and namespace scope
depending on the language semantics
yeah so anyway so I don't know I mean so
you know so there are several comments
from you guys and you know like when I'm
doing talk like I don't I I do not
necessarily follow like who is saying
what so sometimes I get mixed so I mean
oh I see it's just a bunch of comments
so maybe some of you are she's trying to
make a point about something but you
know I yeah anyway good so I think maybe
that's it for today I want to maybe next
time I'll talk about closure okay I mean
a lot of people they actually don't know
what closure is I mean so I'm I might do
a tutorial on the basic tutorial there's
no like among us we don't need to debate
because I'm going just going to give a
you know basic tutorial about what
closure is then we could have another
talk show or you know we can do Google
hangout where we debate or discuss or
you know the the programming features
about closure about Haskell I don't know
how Scott okay oh you know we can talk
about that anyway so what so I have like
oh these two are same Marco I have like
I have three articles so for about
closure so what so this is the main one
what closure is in programming languages
so you have a closure in JavaScript
closure in Python and each one's got a
page on my their home Python - you don't
have closure you cannot do it in the
language what's closer in English the
enclosure is programming but and and
also this is important because back into
20 years ago my as thought to I you know
I was seeing this problem in groups
nobody can explain what closure is to me
because what I was asking you know I was
I came from a math background I said I
was so they talk in the Cape you know
these elite coders they want they keep
talking about kosher you know they did
kosher this or that so what is it can
you can anyone explain to me in terms of
mathematics what is it closure nobody
can nobody and they don't because they
don't even and and they they also cannot
they do not know they cannot tell me
what closure is okay I know today why
Cannot they tell me because kosher
kosher is not a mathematical concept
okay its it has zero nothing to do with
mathematics okay it is it is the way
what what closure is is act actually is
just a concept a feature of a
programming language okay it has zero
nothing to do with algorithm it has zero
to do with theoretical computer science
or even computer science itself well it
is part of designing or language so it
has something to do with designing a
language okay because it's a feature
okay it is language design it's kind of
the way you design a language but it has
zero to do with algorithms or
mathematics or theoretical computer
science nothing so so so I was asking
people can you explain to me what
closure is you know in terms of math
like you know maybe something no no
nothing Jen there's no algebra no no
whatever track algebra advanced math
Chagas nothing relates to closure
there's nothing because it's not a math
concept okay so so what it is it is just
a feature it how does this thing arrive
actually we could I mean I guess there
are people who modeled so when does
closure actually come into computer
science
it comes into computer science
when you are talking about mathematical
formalization of computer language that
is when you have the concept closure you
can say it it's part of math okay you
know so it's this is this is when when
you are trying to formalize okay
mathematically formalise a computer
programming language and when twin
assistant when when do you have
formalization of computer language
programming technology you know the
practical reason is never you know
seriously because we you know if you
such academic papers those kind of
papers are very extremely rare white is
it yeah because it because we are not
yet there first of all there is no
practical practicality there is no
practicality in formalizing a a
practical computer language I'm talking
about real languages not talking about
lambda calculus okay lambda calculus
Turing machines those are those are
fundamental part of theoretical computer
science you know those are models of
machines not conforming languages yet
member calculus is also a model of a
computation it you can think of it as a
machine that depending on your point of
view but it's also it is not well I
don't know if you can actually think of
it as a programming language but anyway
so what I'm saying so far is that right
now we do not have we don't we do not
have you know we do not have the
practice or the need to actually
formalize programming languages you know
there are some people try to study that
but it's like it's out there it's very
few it's not there so closure you know
closure basically have nothing to do
with math whatsoever is it's it's a
concept that just arises when you
actually try to implement a programming
language because you have you have the
concept of scope which is really
you know we're a variable name is you
know and and so anyway that's that's
just a rant so and what and and also I
really despise I hate the closure
concept because in practice okay in
reality in real world
what do programmers use closure for you
know the fundamental essence of closure
in practice is really just using closure
just using global variables the state is
what they are using you know they want
things to ever state that's all there it
is that's a fundamental that the the
manifestation the thing you act actually
can observe when you have a closure when
people are using closure but what
happens to it it's just that you have
States you are using it's just like you
are using global variables except those
variables cannot be manipulated
you know without using the function
because it's not global it's private to
the function you know that's that's
essentially what it is anyway so I kind
of ran also
so the new says there is okay there is
the concept of closure in mathematics
and cybernetics and also intuitively the
idea of a closed system as one which you
cannot leave or enter from is outside
may be generalized okay now I don't know
you know like you mentioned cybernetics
cybernetics that's pseudoscience okay
that's not that's not math that's not a
computer science that's kind of a
pseudoscience but anyway so foobar says
you know but I'm not saying you know
what you are saying is wrong but I'm you
know you probably you know because I'm
you know I'm the one talking so I just
say what I can you know so you know you
guys watching or you know you have to
look for yourself you know you you know
so when you only the fubar says when you
only know one paradigm we're computing
you think you know more than you more
than you actually do so are you so yeah
I'm the expression or status cuz you're
not Matthew and concept but the crochet
is a lambda expressions closure it's not
the lambdas expression kosher has
nothing to think crochet is not a lambda
expression Daniel you are wrong a kosher
carry state the state is defining
contact is Texaco scope okay I think you
know this kind of topic again you know
it's you know first of all I'm biased
probably because you know you for anyone
who are watching you know don't take my
word for it because you know things I'm
talking this you know I cannot you know
I just have to talk you know I talk
about my opinions but and also since you
guys are writing this these are very
complex concepts you know so we can go
into detail a lot more and
we have two we might and you know we
have to I mean it's not some simple
concept you can type and I can
understand exactly what you mean it's
probably when you type something about
these topics I read it I have my own
conception of what you are saying you
know so I may take it wrong the end I
start to find on my own philosophy about
it anyway so that's that's it for today
okay so well see you guys then see you
guys yep so you have ten seconds to say
whatever because I think I close the
chat then the stream will stop
so type whatever and and let's say
goodbye so lambda is a Greek letter O a
concept in a particular language learn
more language and you have we shall see
the folly in using the term so the
gnosis because I said a Crozier is a
lambda expression I'm wrong I think of
where a closure is a closure of a lambda
expression
well closure closure is a lambda
expression okay so what I'm saying is
that okay I mean this self so from what
I see okay I I say that wrong because
these two terms they there is a they are
they reside in different logic levels
because lambda expression lambda
expression is an expression now closure
the concept of closure the meaning of
closure the the if it is not an
expression okay so when you say lambda
expression no lambda expression is the
expression which which okay so so the it
is actually the the meaning of lambda
expression is in the context of textual
like Mexico or the syntax okay that's
the majority of its meaning when you say
expression in
lambda expression let me just say this
first why are the the meaning of closure
when you see the word closure it the
meaning is most semantic it's not about
syntax syntactical aspect of the
programming language the meaning of
closure you had more has to do with a
semantic part of it when when a program
runs you know what what does it do okay
but however lambda expression you know
notice the world lambda it also it means
so it means a function so it can you
know depending on how we look at it
lambda expression first of all like I
said before it's it it's part of the
expression it's a subset of the
expression so here the expression
emphasizes the concept of syntax
you know lexical elements of the
programming language so it's an
expression but on the other hand lambda
expression you can focus we can focus on
the lambda part so in this focus then it
means a function it just so happens to
be expressed as a you know an anonymous
function but it's a it's it's you know
depending on language it lambda
expression is basically synonymous with
a function so in this regard then
closure is a you know closure festival
is a function it's just a function with
the space a specific feature or you know
the syntax so in this context when you
think of lambda expression as a function
you know lambda then closure and lambda
is kind of the what were you saying are
you saying they are the same or yeah a
closure is a instance of a function yeah
I agree
so again don't take don't be offended
what I'm saying you know sometimes I go
into a rant you know sometimes I don't
get what you are saying and started to
rent my own rent so so lambda expression
is an expression and then term closure
is often used in
as this value so anyway so I'm gonna say
goodbye I'm gonna be I'm not gonna be
dragging into yeah I'm not saying I'm
just right yeah I'm just rent okay by
the way I'm not no seeing you guys all
wrong so anyway I did see you guys see
you guys next time