Hello guys, good morning. We are going
to do um install uh Emacs package for
talking to the AI chat
bots. So we installed local AI chat bots
yesterday's live stream. Uh it was very
smooth. We installed OAMA and then we
used Deep Seek.
Fantastic. And today we are just so let
me demo. Okay. So let's uh start a
PowerShell. Let's
magnify. Uh if you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble a lot. If you are here, say hi.
Love to see your comments. So we
installed yesterday. Oama. Then let's
say run deepseek.
Deepseek the AI bot from
China. Okay, there it goes. It started
then the GPU
uh usage gets high. So, so there it is.
So, let's ask it a question.
Um, explain what is
Emacs? Short answer.
Okay, it says think you know uh deepseek
got this new thing. It shows you what it
is thinking. Okay, so I need to explain
what Emacs is and with a short answer.
Um I'm not super familiar with it but I
remember hearing about it in relation to
text editors. Let me think. I know that
there are different types of text
editors like GUI and TUI which stand for
graphical user interface and text user
interface. CMC must be one of those
editors, right? I think it's been around
for a long time. Maybe since 1970s or
something
1976,
1978, something like that. The name
Emacs is uh a bit is a bit funny to me
because I remember blah blah blah. Okay,
so lots of thinking. So after thinking
it says Emacs is a highly customizable
and powerful text editor known for its
flexibility and extensive features set
developed in the 1970s. It supports
numerous customizations through
configurations and plugins called modes.
Enhancing functionality like syntax
highlighting and auto
indentation that you know those two
features are not too spectacular
compared to other uh editors especially
auto indentation. Emacs sucks compared
to other editors.
Really? Yeah. Compared to modern ones.
Okay. While noted for its steep learning
curve, Emacs is favored by many
developers for its efficiency and
encoding and text manipulation tasks.
Now text manipulation tasks that is the
primary aspect of Emacs that shines
because you can do that better than any
text editor. Uh well Vim kind of comes
in play. Hello guys.
Uh Max Louise first
uh 1660Ti is going to start smoking
today. Hi. Hello. Uh not a short that's
not a short answer. Well, one paragraph
is pretty short, you know. Pre before
that is like thinking, you know, it's
got this thinking
thing. Uh it wasn't short answer. Okay.
So, yeah. Okay. So, let's begin. So, I
want to do this in Emacs because I don't
want to go to, you know, the terminal
every
time. So, let's do that. So uh yesterday
someone suggested um uh you know in the
comments that uh we install Gtail GPT.
Okay. So let's see. Um there it is GPAL
or there is also chat GPT shell I found
and there's also uh Elama. So, but
anyway, let's do a GP tail because I
looked at the uh GitHub
today for five minutes. Uh I think I
like it. So, we'll try this. You know,
if I don't like it later, I'll install
all this. So, it says
GPTL, a simple LM client for Emacs.
Simple. I like that. Okay. So, so you're
going to install this um Yeah. Okay. So
list packages. Let me do it my
traditional
way. So you'll list all the packages. So
um so go to the bottom. You can see
6,000 packages. Go to the bottom.
Six
6,700 packages. So this matching lines
[Music]
GPL. Okay. So you got these several
things. Cosa. Wow. There's one named
cos you know that's a gaming stuff
keyboard brands. Uh text accumulation
enhancements for GPTEL. H interesting.
Now coel that's a word in English right?
I never know what exactly what it means.
Coel look up in
wictionary does it has a some kind of
English meaning let's see
dictionary cosel a pirate or pirateier
especially along the barbaric coast oh
that's what it means swift pirate ship
often often operating with official
sanction oh I See? So that's why it's
named Co. Cos. Okay. So anyway, so the
one we want is um Can you see it? Okay.
So there's Coel.
Uh so there's GPT that one. Okay. Open
it. Open
it. Okay. So uh so let's read available
install mail. Good. Interact with chat
GPT or other llama. Okay. Uh,
okay. Car think. Okay. By this guy, I I
guess. Okay. By this
guy. Uh, yeah. Let's just install. Let's
go there. Install it.
Yes. Now later. So, it's done. It says
done. Oh, wait.
Compiling. Okay. It's installed. Now
later on we will need to close that
coair. I might I'll probably gonna
um download the source code. Well, I
don't need to because Okay, so let's go
to init. Uh wait. Uh okay, close that.
Close that. Close that. Go to init my
Emacs in it. Uh where do I want to go
to? not get uh
actually go to my emac. Okay. Okay.
Here. Right here. So that's my emacs
init directory.
Emacs.d then go to
um uh refresh. Where is it? Alpa there.
There it is. GPTL. So you can see all
the source code here is here. So I
actually I you know when I have some
time I'm going to look into the source
code. Okay. So the next thing is
actually how do you actually start
it? Okay. So let's see. Let's see the
source code.
Carthic
chickal. What what kind of name is that?
What country name is
that? Okay. So, SP is SPDX license
identifier.
What? What is that?
SPDX license
identifier. Jesus. They they Zuma
created this license list
identifier. What
[ __ ] Uh, okay. So, this program is free
so far. Blah blah blah. Okay. So um okay
uh it's a client okay it works
with in the spirit of Emacs available
anytime anywhere
okay any buffer okay supports supports
all these chatbots locally
um additionally uh LLM service local
remote can also be used okay features
okay features I don't care. I mean, I
kind of read it.
Requirements. Okay. So, anyway, you go
to their GitHub, they'll
say. So you can see LM back end chat
GPT Germany or Lama or Lama Llama CPP
you know all these um backends they
support and some of them requires a key
like you know they they require account
but for Oola you can run locally you
know so so it's fantastic you got the
list of all the uh chat bots
So chat GBT is configured out of the box
for other sources. Okay.
God. So right
now the task is to find out how to use
it. Okay. So let's you know the
the Emacs text is hard to read. So let's
read the GitHub instead.
So you got all these chat bots. You got
the video um kind of introduction of
using it. I've seen that it just shows
you you
know tool use. Okay.
So a sync and fast. Okay. Contents
breaking changes
installation setup. Okay. Let's go to
setup.
setup and usage and FAQ. Okay.
Installation
setup. Okay. Uh am I going check? Uh
yeah. Yeah. So now we need need to set
up let's see chat GP GPT I don't care
other backends chat GPT is configured
out out of the box if you want to use
other backends like OAMA you need to
register and configure them okay as an
example registering a backend typically
looks like the following okay so copy oh
Jesus they don't have like copy button
Let's turn on
JavaScript. Let Google know where you
are and what you are doing. Okay. So,
there is a copy. You know, I did a live
stream to to learn how do you create
this copy button in JavaScript. Uh it
turns out is one single function call,
one single dome function call. But
however, there's a major issue. In order
to have this copy
button, you need to have you need to
your the current website needs to be
running on a server. So for local files,
you cannot do that.
Okay. So let's close that. Okay. Let's
go to talk show. So talk show
um emac this code. Let's since today we
are doing emac this let's say messages.
Okay. Let's say print uh print. Okay,
print. Let's say something. Okay, run
it. I'm going to run it and show the
result below. Okay, so press this
key. Uh
what? Uh tab I is undefined. What? Oh,
okay. Yeah.
Okay, there it is. Okay. So uh yeah. So
now put it back. Syntax color show in
browser. You can see the code you and
you can see a copy
button. Uh oh yeah. So so yeah. So it
works locally but however if you upload
you know if you go to my website you
won't see the copy button because it
requires
https kind of nasty. Okay. supposedly
for security reasons. Um, but I don't
think
so. It's, you know, anyway. So, that's
why when you go to my website, you won't
see you you, you know, like
click and paste, you know, you you don't
get that copy button uh
feature because for some reason, I mean,
for reasons they made it, you know,
requiring
HTTPS. Anyway,
so back to the um GitHubs. Yeah. So,
let's copy that. Copy. Um by the way, if
you want to see the JavaScript code, the
JavaScript code is here.
So you see the copy to copy something
all you have to do is
um all you have to do is
uh this line this function
navigator.clipipboard write text then
target parent element next inner text.
Okay. So basically the the right
clipboard write text that's all you
need. But the other thing is bit a bit
tricky because we are digressing but
because I want the copy button you see
they are inserted by JavaScript but I
don't want it to take up space. So you
need to use CSS layers of position
absolute and position uh relative to
position it. Then it involves a
translation you see uh here transform
translate. So that's all
about
CSS somewhat complicated. So let me go
to
um so I've been working on CSS a lot in
the past three days. So you can see
webdev blog go there. So a lots of
stuff. So the thing in order to do what
we are doing here let's see the
highlight uh wait what is this okay web
dev uh close you see this this this
positioning of the code uh let's see
uh generator function JavaScript
generator function uh somewhat advanced
random not children randomize this is
the fastest code to randomize a East. So
here's the code. So you can see the copy
button. Copy back here. New buffer.
Paste. You keep and and make a
JavaScript
mod JavaScript mod. So you can see. So
close that back to browser. So what I'm
saying? Oh yeah. So in order to position
get this copy button position and all
that that involves
uh by the way this is
my JavaScript webdev tutorial back in
2005 you know back then it's called H
DHTML because back then 2005 most things
are static you know you don't have like
in the browser update like today like
single page application
But it's beginning to have you know 2006
you know actually it's going for a few
years it's like cutting edge technology
called DHTML meaning dynamic
HTML of course nobody calls that today
because you know it's all that dynamic.
So anyway that's my website um you know
for webdev back in 2006. So anyway, what
you want is this position things. Okay,
position property. They will actually
create a new
layer and then you also want to
translate. Uh let me let me show
that. So you you can just go to my webde
tutorial visual CSS and you can see
animation transform. Transform is the
one you want. And uh there is translate
so you can
actually reposition an element. Okay,
that's some of the things um digression.
Okay, let's go back to
Emacs. That's about the digression about
the copy button. Okay,
but 2D
transform and the layout and
layers. So position property this is
critical
uh very
important CSS feature for page layout.
Okay, we got that. Uh then let's go back
to um what is this
XPDLs? Yeah. So let's mention you know
let's mention that
for record keeping keeping
purposes cos interesting
uh English this is vocabulary linguistic
thing
uh oh yeah so back here then we copy
that show in browser yeah so let's see
what code is
that GPTL make
anthropic. Okay,
so that's specific to this AI bot stream
T key. Okay, so that's how you set up.
Now back to okay.
So once the back end is registered your
C model names prefixed by claude appear
in GPTL menu. See below for details on
your on your preferred LLM provider.
Okay. Now what I want is so can you like
expand or
something? Okay. So copy
that. Uh wait what
uh wait paste it there and cut
that. Pop it out. Paste that there. That
we don't want. So
GPTL make or llama or llama. Okay. Any
name of your choosing. Okay. Okay.
That's good. Host local host.
Okay.
Uh well, what what is the port
number? Uh I don't know.
So So stream t stream responses. Okay.
Let's just say
that. Okay. I I don't want the comments.
Okay.
string response t model
model.
Uh well, this part I need to
change. Okay, I you know because I'm
using
deepsek. So this part I will need to
change. So it's a
list. Okay. So, it's probably going to
I'm probably going to add deep seek R1
something. Uh, so let's exit
here. Let's see my GPU usage. Control D
to exit. Okay. And uh the previous
command is
this. Okay. So something like
um okay so I think I know so this is
going to be min I don't
care this is probably that
okay we'll see now go back to browser
um go back to browser
So, these are the required parameters.
Refer to the
documentation. Okay. So, required to the
documentation for more. So, you need to
look up the describe
function GP make or llama. Okay. So name
and key curl argument header key model
something register llama back end. Okay
with name. Okay. So name is
that
yeah close that. Do it again. Describe
function name. Color it. Oh, it doesn't
color that part. Stupid.
Yeah. Keyword
argument. Okay. Model is a list of
available model names as symbols. Oh,
okay. So, they wait. So, they needs to
be symbols. Okay. Yeah, that works
because of the
apostrophe. Uh, okay. So, now go back
describe function.
Now this
time I'm going to highlight that word.
Okay, now it's properly
highlighted. So
models. Okay, so model is a list
available model names or symbols.
Additionally, you can specify
supported capabilities like like vision
or tool use. Okay.
And then you got this model name P
list. Oh, okay.
So, so close my init. Close that. So,
you
[Music]
can right. So, you can either have that
or you can also have
something
something like vision
something. Okay. So
uh wait this is a property list. So
proper property list you you kind of
something
something. Okay. So currently recognize
P list keys. Oh okay. So you got you got
description and capabilities and mind
types.
Okay.
So copy that. So this is going to be
description
fantastic something. Okay. So actually
it shows a example
here models. Okay. Um
yeah. Okay. Jesus. This is like too much
to set up. Let's copy that. Go back. Um
go back
to
so you know noticed you know you notice
that their formatting is
non-standard. This this is not you know
supposed to be have of space and uh
anyway so this is a example for the
models for this line and uh let's remove
that. So but we need to change this to
deepsek. So let's see let's let's just
um play with it.
So
minstro okay so you know you need to
find out what are these for
minstro lava 13b so okay so we need to
go to lama
website so let's read more you can pick
this back end from a menu using
gptpt else then see usage let's go to
usage
Okay. So, it's
actually a bit more involved to
um to like um a bit of random question,
but why do you have pointer trails? Uh
that makes it easier to see when you do
live stream. Uh basically that is why
and it's a huge arrow
uh you know so this this this pointer
trail tail is a feature started by
Windows back in 1995 or earlier in a
very early um Windows version. So they
still have it. You can turn it on if you
go to the settings. And uh you know, so
I never liked it before. You know, I
find it annoying. But when I started to
do live stream about half a half a month
ago, I thought, you know, I need a
bigger pointer and tell helps a lot for
people to
see. And uh so I turn it turned it on.
Then I find it very annoying, you know,
like very annoying. But actually after a
while I just get used to it. So I now I
don't even notice it. Like it used to be
like every time I do a live stream I go
to the settings, you know, settings.
Um, you know, you go to the mouse
section mouse and go to the adjust mouse
and cruiser size additional mouse
options. So you go to cruiser size, you
can adjust couser size. Then you go to
additional mouse options. Then you got
this
ancient user interface. You know this is
this this this code must be from 1990s.
Everything is tiny. You know that's
that's so bad. That's why Windows so bad
on the Mac. This never
happens. You know the Mac the entire
system update holistically. You know,
when there's new font, new font
technology, new pixel rendering system,
you know, they update everything. On
Windows, you got this [ __ ] you know,
like like you know, you try to increase
your font system wide, but this window
never does and lots of others. Then you
got then you got control panels. [ __ ]
like
um you know like like this Asian thing.
So on one hand you got these system
settings right but then then you still
have this some of these Asian control
panels. is so ve it's very [ __ ] up
windows you know you can imagine but
they promote it you know this window
pretty boys they go on stage in some you
know Microsoft conference or demo like
oh we got a shiny system metro style or
whatever but then then but actually you
got this [ __ ] you you see this tiny
claustrophobic box
[ __ ] you cannot you cannot enlarge the
font, you know, you cannot. No, can you
enlarge the window? It's like, what the
[ __ ] is
this then? Meanwhile, they say, "Oh, we
support transparency or whatever." You
know, the
crap Idias idiocy. Anyway, so let's get
back to mouse. So, here is where you can
turn on the trail. Okay. Pointer
options. Uh, trail. Okay. You can adjust
it long or short. You see
none
long cancel. Okay. So anyway, so that's
the kind of the Windows digression. So
let's get
back. Okay. Now I want I want just to
get it run to run. Okay. So let's stop
messing around. Uh I just want to get it
to
run. I like the old control panel. Yeah,
me too. But you but at least they made
they have to make it, you know, uniform
and stuff.
Um anyway, let's get back. So I want to
get this to work now. So it's too much
digression. Um okay. So let me try to
readama. So you need to read the
documentation.
Uh Olama. So this is config. This is
called registering
uh optional set as default G uh GPTL
back end. Okay, I also want
that. Oh, okay. So the previous code
just make it available. But if you want
it to be default, you need to do this.
Oh god, this
is so this section is just make it
available. But if you want default, you
do this.
Okay. Yeah. But
um Okay. Yeah. But so what? So what? So
this is setting up a
GPT model. Okay. So you set up a model
and set up a back
end. Okay. So you set up a model and set
up a back
end and
uh Okay. So this this is the backend
configuration to create this back end.
And here you set the variable model and
set the variable back end. You know this
part is supposed to be this part. Okay.
Okay. I got it so far. Okay. So that's
that. Then now let's go to
usage. GPT provides a few powerful
general purpose and flexible commands.
Powerful general purpose and flexible.
Okay. You can dynamically tweak their
behavior to the needs of your task with
directives, redirection options, and
more. Okay, there's a video demo showing
you that. Okay, but
GPTL send might be all you need. Okay,
so GPT send send or text up to point.
Oh, okay. So all the way to the cursor
position or the selection if region is
active.
Okay, then GPTL creates a new dedicated
buffer. Okay, that's how you want it.
Okay, but now for now we need to get
this setup correct. Okay. So, I think
that So, make a copy of that. And uh
then let's um copy that.
Copy. And uh let's see. Uh let's
see. Delete that. I'm not using minstro.
Okay.
So that's the this basically just this
part I need to run. Okay. Pify the
code. Okay. So comment that
out. Okay. Let's run it. Run it. It's
done. Okay. So now you can describe
variable. Um describe variable
that. Okay. This that's there's a
mistake there.
GP. Okay. So that needs to be
that. Okay. Now run it
again. Now describe variable G GPTL
model deepseek.
Okay. And
then GPTL backend describe
variable.
Uh okay.
So yeah. Okay. So here is my
value. Okay. I think that's good. Let's
just leave
it. Our original value is like pretty
complex. Close that. Okay. So now let's
run
[Music]
gptel. Meta x
gptel. Please make it work. Let's do
it.
Choose create or choose GPT aler default
or llama. Okay. Enter. Uh who are you?
Enter.
What is it
running? Okay. First try. No. Go.
Uh, do you need to type special
send control enter? Let's
try. Not defined. Shift
enter. Not
defined.
Uh, so let's see.
GPT send. Okay.
So, describe
function
GPT send. Let's see if there's a
key. Oh, control C return. [ __ ]
idiotic. Well, but it follows Emacs
convention.
Okay, so control C return. Okay, C
return. Fantastic.
Waiting and
typing. There it is.
Let's enlarge the
window. Fantastic. Think and answer.
Fantastic. Okay. So, let's
see. Simple
description
of Chinese
chess rules. Uh, well, this would be
complicated. Simple description of go
game rules. Let's see what it
says.
Oh, Ctrl C.
Enter.
Fantastic. It says, "All right, so I
want to learn how to play the game Go. I
have heard it's this Asian board game
from China, but I'm not exactly sure how
it works. Let me try to figure this out.
First of first off, what what's a board?
I imagine it's something like a
chessboard or maybe grid. I think
there's some stones involved, right?
Like small pieces blah blah blah. You
know, this thinking is kind of annoying.
Just get to the just answer the
question. Let's see. my GPU usage. Not
too
bad. So, it's still going. It's still
going. I also see it is babbling. I also
wondered I also I also wonder about the
history of go. How old is it? Who
invented it? It would be cool to learn
more about its origins and cultural
significance.
It's you know so this we are entering
this AI bot era you know it's actually
[ __ ]
thinking not exactly not not exactly I
mean it's not like
sentient but but we learned from AI
research because of the chat GPT that
you don't need to be
sentient so so all these answers seems
human you know seems int intelligent but
actually it's just statistical
process because when you learn about how
this chat GPT so-called large language
model works they are just solving a huge
equations with billion like several
billion
variables basically and mostly just
linear algebra linear algebra and
calculus regression okay that's all you
do you got this equation involving you
know some billion variables or you want
to know in order to train it is to find
out what should those variables be.
Okay, then you then you end up with one
single
equation. Okay, then you input the
argument. The equation will result you
know a function you know you'll come out
some other number a bunch of vectors
okay this number represent the result
the sentence you know because words are
turned into a
number so it's just it's just like one
one single [ __ ]
mathematical formula function you know
but but it can write poetry and all
these
So
anyway, okay. So it's so if finished
thinking then go is an Asian board game.
Go board setup, stone placement,
movement, capture. Now a stone is
captured if it's surrounded by five or
more opponent stones. This is incorrect.
surrounded by five or
more. It should be four. Four or
more, right? Yeah. Four more. So, so
this part
incorrect liberties. Okay. That's uh you
know, so anyway, that's about go game.
So, that's it. Fantastic. We've done our
job. Fantastic. So now let's um what we
going to do now? So let's put what we
learned into today's talk. So basically
just those part and optional config. We
don't care. Let's clean up. And that's
it for
today.
So cut
that. Put this
back. syntax color show in
browser. So basically just this line
just put this line in your
um yeah in your Emacs config. Okay let
let's clean it up.
Okay. So
uh so this is
uh
[Music]
gptel
config for lama
chat bus but interface. Okay. So, and uh
using model DC R1 AB. Okay, that's all
you need to do. Just set. So, put this
in your init
file
then.
Okay,
then. Okay, then.
Then
GPTL meta
X syntax code showing browser MetaX
GPTL2 to start it.
Then
C
return. Oh yeah. So what what is my
um tab UK?
Okay. Type a question then tap UK to
send
it. Showing
browser. That is the instruction.
Fantastic. And
uh and let's go back to the llama page.
Um where is it? Oh, llama. Okay. So,
let's shrink it and let's make a like
screenshot. Fantastic. Actually, let's
control let's make the whole screenshot
there. Okay. Now, go back to the talk
show and
[Music]
uh move the image here.
and rename it talk
show showing
browser.
Fantastic. Thank you guys for watching.
Any questions, comments? That's it for
today. Now remember, if you like my
stuff, pay me, okay? Go to
kasali.info.info and all the way to the
bottom. Pay me, Patreon me or Amazon
gift card me or PayPal. Click the link
then copy my email address. Copy and
paste to you know to the destination
whatever you know pay me. Thank
you. So my YouTube there's no no ads
because in my website I turned off all
the Google [ __ ] you know Google ads
stuff.
Uh, for sure it disturbs to find weird
formattings. Okay. Uh, Luis Stefan says
they stopped the upgrade halfway. Uh,
yeah, I like the old control panel. Uh,
new settings are more user friendly, but
why not get rid of control panel
completely than micro? You know why? Why
is Microsoft like sucks so bad in every
other way? It's because they don't need
to improve. You know, this corporation
exist because they they make money. When
they cannot, you know, whatever they do
is for the purpose of making
money. So when you improve a
software, more people will buy it. You
make money. But Microsoft, Windows has
at the point where they are all
saturated. You know, doesn't matter if
you're going to improve it, they don't
make more money, you know, like they
don't
care, you know. Why don't they care?
Because I mean what about, you know, if
people find Microsoft sucks, they switch
to Linux, right? You got this free open
source. So Jesus, the open-source
[ __ ] right? Linux is free. So why
how come you know if Microsoft becomes
so bad people going to switch to Linux
right? Why did does
not s serve as a uh reason for Microsoft
to keep improving? Well, the reason is
because Linux, the Linux people, the
Linux people, the their coders, their
supporters, they are
idiotic nerds to the extreme, you know,
because Linux is unusable.
Linux is usable only if you are
professional coder like you are a nerd
like me like you guys you know we we we
we code you know the like kernels you
know the bits and [ __ ] you spend like
five years to study computer science or
programming then Linux is fantastic but
for most other people like the
population millions and billions
billions of people it's useless because
you you you like you don't know what the
[ __ ] is going on you know
this and the Linux people they refuse
they don't know how to fix it they they
don't know you know they just they
simply don't know you know if you are a
Linux fanatics you you'll say well but
actually Linux Linux is so easy not
really because the real test is like you
just you know tell tell someone on the
street to install it they they can they
cannot but with Windows or the Mac they
have with Windows they they can they can
they can you know probably make it work
for Mac it's even no-brainer it's always
just works for people who never who are
not into who don't know anything about
computers okay that's the key so Linux
people they need to do that but they you
know they don't want to and they refuse
and they are focused about techno
geeking you know my language is better
than yours my dro is better than yours.
Oh, I have this or that, you know, they
they they don't know, you know, because
they don't
care. So that's the idiocy and the
problem with uh Linux. So that is why
Microsoft even though it sucks they are
okay with it you know the Microsoft
bosses you know because Linux is going
to not going to take away Microsoft
users and plus we going to have m you
know Linux inside Microsoft you know
like like the Windows embedded Linux you
know anyway that's a sad situation
because of the open-source fanatism
Okay, that's it.
Bye, Juan. You came back from your first
date. Fantastic.
Congratulations. Which is your Discord?
My Discord is on uh on saudi.info. Uh
are you asking that question?