hello everyone welcome to another
episode of guitar talk show we are going
to code emac lease today okay so today's
keyboard is exposed X pose like the
shooting ball exposed night like white
shiny Knight in white armor
okay expose
night is today's keyboard and I got my
so this is uh
uh choc Kyle chalk switch tester
fantastic from this company uh
m k u l t r a m culture Okay so
so
um so I got a new um
switch for my glove 80 okay so you got
you are going to see it uh in my next
stream in in my lots of my streams okay
so let me show you what I'm talking
about uh so but today we are going to
code uh emac beasts okay just for but
let me talk about the keyboard for a
moment moment
okay let's just search for ergonomic
keyboard reviews sorry and you'll find
so this is a keyboard I got new light
switches for it fantastic and uh and let
me show you the choke switch the company
okay so you can see my reviews and video
reviews and uh
then there's the switch part
so you go down you go down there it is
Kyle chalk switch everything you want to
know about it is here low profile low
profile switch and here are the
variations in the
activation force and because I have
repetitive string injury here hang
therefore I need a light one so I got
this one and from this company so you
can read about it just search for
excited Kyle chalk switch okay so that's
about my keyboard let's do today's
powerful thing emac this okay that's
called emac Beast
okay video check audio check ready to go
any comments and questions posted okay
uh let's check one more time so we got
the Emax window set up correctly yeah
video audio check okay
any comments and questions emac this
today okay so we are going to write a
emac this command that sort out photos
let me show you hello hello Dave so you
can see here's the directory a bunch of
photos let me show you these photos
fantastic food my wife thank you my wife
food you see so you have lots of photo
and this is ergonomic chair okay I love
this chair I've been using it in
1997 for about two years
uh but I think I'm gonna get it this is
from a friend a friend's house so and
he's got the ergonomic kneading chair
okay fantastic and he's in food
and we have dinosaur
chicken okay fantastic and this is nice
fine whiskey whiskey
and he's got a bunch of musical
instruments lots of guitars and so over
here you have one two three four five
five guitars and he's got lots of other
instruments okay so anyway the problem
is you have lots of photos you know
maybe your personal photos or maybe
images you downloaded from the web or
screenshots sometimes you want to sort
them for example I have you know
typically most of us have lots of food
pictures you know we need to share you
know what restaurant we went to today so
food pictures so you want to press a
button and this photo the current photo
will go to the food folder okay
you know John's food you know my food
sandwich or whatever and suppose you
have a chair you go to some chair for
you know the furniture or whatever
scenery if you go travel you you know a
bunch of photos you want to go to Italy
photos or friends photos things like
that so you want to press the button
and you just send that photo the current
photo to that folder okay so we are
going to write that in emacs okay let me
show you so in for example here is emacs
any questions comments uh okay so emacs
you can open the photo okay you can
magnify you can magnify your screen you
can show shrink the screen uh you know
so I want to press the button it will go
to that folder so let's write that
command now okay that's today's thing
okay so now let's go back to the talk
show page okay that's so we're gonna
write this command uh need speaking
emacs this block comments and questions
comment and questions okay so Define so
let's magnify so pink window the pink
window shows all my command course and
the keystroke for example you can see
you know these are the few commands I
just scored and on the left side is the
keystroke I'm using a varac keyboard
layout and I'm using a uh stuff like
Keys okay because of like keys
just search it you'll find that it's a
Emax
model key binding system okay so anyway
let's begin code okay
Define I'm using SAR
emagly smart so you have templates so
Define uh let's name this
sort photos basically this
categorization of photos Okay so
here you want this uh it's a dark dark
string okay version for today's date
move kind folder to a specific folder
okay now first of all you need to Define
what folder you want to move to so let's
define some okay so let's
Define VA
uh
Define VAR okay that's this is how you
declare a variable you know in emac this
it's not necessary to declare a variable
but however when you declare a variable
let's say x y z
uh it let's say value three the
advantage is that then you can have dark
string you see you can document it so
people can look up the variable for
example let's look up a variable uh
let's look up the
okay so you call describe variable and
let's say tab with okay so that is a
variable tab with
okay
okay Enter so you can see then here's
the documentation tab width is a
variable defined in c-source code its
value is four original value was eight
it so it it describe variable this
command will tell you the variable's
current value and sometimes the original
value and then there's a documentation
that tells tells you what this means
Okay so
Define so you can so very useful command
Okay describe Dash variable okay and now
and let's go back and here we are using
Define VAR so this is how you can define
a variable that can you can look up
let's try it okay so Define variable x y
z first of all the variable name so
let's see variable
um
uh what so this will be a list of
folders you want to
uh you want to move the
image two so what should the name of the
variable be
uh
image destination
Target let's say image Target folders
okay so this this way
you know you could Target instead of
destination there are synonyms kind of
but Target is short you know usually the
traditionally you say destination
so image destination folders so you
document it initial value will be Neo
and okay Neo and dark stream okay
a list of folders
full
sword folders to move image two okay
something like that
so that's a documentation but actually
the value should not we have to think
about the data type now this variable
what should um what should the value be
should it be just the least or should it
be
at least a path or should it be
a list of path but also a phone with a
name for each folder let's say that okay
so we want this path
so key value pairs the key are the name
the value is a file path okay so let's
modify the documentation so you say uh a
list okay a this means Association list
so that's kind of like key value pairs
okay uh
an assertion list of folders for some
sort file to remove range 2 okay and
then
key are strings
value is a the path okay that's a
complete documentation okay now let's
define the value okay set
um okay then so here you need a
Association list
in short it's called a list at least
okay so that's a lisp data structure so
the way you define it is like that okay
then conspire
like this okay
key
value okay so you have multiple pairs so
let's define so let's begin to Define
this variable okay so so what uh so what
let's say I want so let's create a
folder okay let's say
uh
food okay food what
so
food is one folder and let's say chairs
okay let's just for example let's create
another folder chairs
uh
let's say things okay so we got two
photos now let's copy it copy it
close
go back to the code
so there is one folder and the folder
name will be
things okay then a second folder
food
the folder name will be food okay
predefy the code fantastic
purify again fantastic okay so we got a
variable the target folders now then we
oh okay anything any comments Jack move
hi okay so far so good
so we are coding emac this of a command
to move the current image to a folder to
a distance
designated folder okay
so now it's code so here is the code
okay so we have the
these two photos okay so now what to do
um
so first of all you want to grab the
current file path of the current image
okay so let's let me let me open that
let me open a new window show the image
so you can see
so for example let's go
to my documents folder
you see emacs can show images right so
now you just press the button and it
will move this picture to the things
folder Okay so
uh
so for example let's go back go back
here okay let's code okay so the first
thing you want to do is you want to know
the file path of the current file okay
that is easy
so the final path of the current current
buffer is stored in
um
profile
what is it
uh
current buffer okay let's see current
buffer is a function Returns the current
Buffer's list object no that's not what
we want I forgot it moment but let's so
let's show my emac this tutorial search
for practical emac this okay or
tutorials
from the ground up for for beginners so
you can learn so right now we want to
know what is the functional variable
that gives you the file path of the
current buffer okay so so you get buffer
string so text processing get points
that find replace get user input buffer
Okay click on Buffer what is the buffer
get buffer name buffer file name that is
the one we want okay with the file name
is a function but it is also a variable
okay so let me let's show it
so both a final name of course I know
these uh for example copy it so in emac
this symbol or a name can be
both a function and a variable so this
is this aspect is very different from
vast majority of languages programming
languages in vast majority of
programming languages a name a symbol is
just either a function or a variable it
cannot be both but in e-mac this in
common is it can be both so let me show
you so let's say let's do describe
function
but for file name okay so you can see
buffer file name is a building function
Okay blah blah blah okay now describe
variable
okay you can see in the pink window I
call describe variable but for file name
then it says buffer file name is a
variable defined in blah blah blah its
value current value is this one local in
buffer you know and so on okay so in
emac this in common is a name
more technically a symbol can be
both a function
or a variable and a variable okay so in
in this case buffer file name they
actually do the same thing both the file
name is a function that Returns the
current buffers
file path if it is associated with a
file you know so for example this file
right now this file is associated with a
file it's a file on disk but sometimes
if you just open the empty buffer you
know
then it's not it doesn't then in that
case the buffer file name will return
Neo because it's a buffer
but it's not associated with the file
it's not a file okay so this function
Returns the file path
of the current buffer or this variable
stores the file path of the Chrome
buffer okay so we just need the variable
okay so both of our name is the file
okay uh and uh
so let's let's uh let's
let's create some variables okay so that
way it's easier to understand so here we
have a local variable
XF path F path stand for file path and X
is just my convention start a variable
with X so it's easy to tell
okay it's easy to tell it's your look
your own variable not something from
building from the language okay so
that's a local variable
uh so you got the final path and
let's let's add some check okay if file
path
it's not Neo okay if it's nil do nothing
okay if it's new do nothing if it's not
Neo then we need to
uh move it okay so how do you move it
well
you see you have several directories you
want to query user with which directory
you want to move to
okay so we have to write a command that
prompts the user something like that but
for now let's just move it to food okay
let's just do it
so
so if the valve path exists then let's
just move uh now is there a move command
I I don't know I forgot and let's see
how do you move a file in emac this okay
let's check the Practical emac this
tutorial move file uh write file read
file file path work directory walk walk
walk a directory and
okay I I remember what it is rename file
okay rename file that should do it okay
expand so you got rename file
describe function rename file rename
file is an interactive building function
in csos code okay and here's the syntax
rename file as new name both art must be
string you file has name other name file
it continues continue to have those
names if new name is the directory name
file rename file to a
like named file under new name okay
so anyway this command rename file
actually can move file
because that
big you know this is interesting point
to a human rename and move are different
things okay but it so happens when you
implement it in Unix rename and move is
the same thing so emacs somehow just
inherited that adopted that semantics
okay so anyway let's try this rename
file rename file then the file is the
XF path okay then the new name is going
to be the new name is going to be one of
this directory let's say food okay so
the new name is going to be
let's say format okay so let me show you
what I'm doing you'll understand
so here is the directory we want to move
it to
the directory plus the current file name
oh so you need to do some surgery you
need to break
you need to break up a full file path
into the directory part in file name
part so you can append the file name
part to the new directory okay that's
what we need to do
so so the code here is getting
complicated let's clean up let me show
you okay be patient with me any
questions comments hello from Brazil and
from Serbia all the people around the
world am I making is uh so far so good
the
okay the emac basic coding so okay so we
want to rename the file so we need to
break the path fire path okay so so
let's do it here so let's add some
folder path okay and it's just yeah
we I'm a bit sloppy in naming but let's
just push through so for the path
name okay let's just say that
so the folder path will be
um
so you want to fold the path
find our folder path so how do you get
the
how do you split a file path okay so
look here
uh user input file buffer right file
read file file directory functions file
path functions right there okay file
name directory that's what you want okay
okay set for the path equals to file
name directory call this function
um
fire path okay so that's your folder
path and similarly
the file name part will be
will be just a file name none directory
so you call the function
file name none directory okay and
and that's that's
and that's that fantastic okay
okay actually we need to move these two
inside here because if the file path is
near meaning the current buffer is not a
file it's not associated with a file
then you don't need to do any of these
you know only when it's
you know there's a fire path okay so you
um so for the path so that's a folder
path thus this is the file name then you
rename the file
of the full path to
true that plus
uh you want to be careful with the slash
because you want to avoid double slash
okay so
um
so okay so for now let's just add a
slash there so we you know but that's
something you want to watch watch out so
when you want to write this command deal
when you want to write any emacs command
that deal with
folder path or directory path you always
want to make sure you know there's a
ending slash so in your code you want to
double check if there's no Indian slash
and if this is a directory you need to
add it because because otherwise it
sometimes you when you join file path
you'll end up with double slash
that can be very problematic but because
typically double slash will just become
root so you want to add code to double
check that and also by emacs convention
by emacs commission any directory or
folder must should end with a slash okay
that's an emac this convention
okay but so that's one thing but what
I'm saying is that you want to add code
to double check that because you know
use the user don't know you know user
especially from Unix people they
you know it's interesting in Unix
tradition in Unix convention or Linux
folders for the file path does not end
with the slash okay that's a Unix
convention but in emac this you should
so in your code you should double check
and add it okay so anyway but for now
let's just do this
um
so now so we got so for the path file
name then we want to be named so rename
file so here you want um
yeah so that and uh
okay so actually just another argument
okay let's show you so it's more clear
okay so I think that's the code okay so
rename file to arguments the first is
the full path to the file to the image
file the second part is the
is the directory you want to move to
plus the file name of the current file
okay and okay so that will rename that
will actually move the file there but
let's try it okay and it's just so oh
yeah so there is already exist so if
okay if already exists
so it already exist don't move okay
let's just say remove here one okay so
that's it that's our code
shrink shrink a little bit okay
so there's a comment
Michael or Michelle Michael Viana says
read your article where you say if the
function keys are not easy to press then
it's not good to put frequently used
commands to them that's true what about
function keys in a laptop like Dell
inspiration
so
well that just depends on you you know
that depends on that particular laptop
in generally speaking for me you know
laptop their key layout varies a lot so
let me take two minutes
um to to talk about that okay so laptop
so you go to saw keyboard laptop so
here's a survey of the or laptop
keyboards so laptop the key layout
varies a lot so you are looking at
Google Chrome book okay for example you
have that then you have the Apple for
example Apple
one thing to notice is that there are no
gaps between function keys okay and also
another thing to note is they are tiny
they are not full size keys tiny okay
and no gaps on a typical keyboard
you know if you are looking at my for
example my keyboard this one for example
okay so you see function keys one two
three four five six seven eight there's
a gap in between you see so I can close
my eyes and I can hit the correct
function key
you know again you literally do that so
yeah you know so
on a traditional keyboard layout full
size keyboard with function keys they
are very easy they have gaps Four Keys
in each group
okay but
not so on laptop okay so let's look at
some other laptop Keys okay so that's
apples
laptop and this model it become worse
they removed function keys and you got
this useless display idiotic
Apple without Steve Jobs you know this
what is this good for this is good for
note and utilities okay
so anyways so as that's so obviously if
you have this laptop then you don't want
to press those you know screen keys
that's that's the worst worst of the
and here is the classic IBM think
pad you know so again function keys and
here in particular you see they are
grouped in groups of four fantastic okay
and but what about the current version
the current version
yeah it's not so good it's smaller and
it's a little Gap okay
so to your question it just depends on
you and in general
maybe not it it's it's it's hard to say
okay so you just try it
because
so one choice is to set a function key
you know to do something on the laptop
the other choice is then setup or
something or control something but on a
laptop those are also difficult so you
have a kind of a tough choice yeah I
mean there's no absolute easy answer
you know either you press function keys
or you or in control or FN you know
something and also of course on laptop
the function keys are no longer function
keys these days usually they are you
know screen brightness you know uh and
other things and you have to hold FN key
first or you can
turn that off so it's getting a bit
complicated depends on your personal
you know which laptop it is and your
finger habit okay
another keyboard question my hand
started to hurt from coding with Blue
switches am I screwed
well uh so you know that's complicated
question so but the easy thing I can
recommend is that stop using Blue
switches use a linear cherry red linear
switch as slight as possible so and
so there are many Cherry MX linear
manufacturers out there you know the
traditional original one is Cherry MX
red linear okay that's good but if you
use Kyle red that's not good because
Kyle red is actually much more stronger
much heavier so but if you use skate
around get around linear red then that's
good that's super good okay so Brown is
not good okay well I mean it's personal
question okay if you don't have isi you
know then you can have any preference
but if you do
already have hand paint like me right
now for example I talked about this many
times you know right here
I need I must have Cherry MX I mean I
must have basically either Cherry MX red
linear
the Cherry MX red silent even The Silent
One
he's not good enough so I'm you know in
short I must have light switches okay we
are digressing from the topic let's go
back okay I want to
maybe after emacs then we let's talk
about those things okay
and pay me guys okay if you donate you
know that's what I'm here for if you're
gonna ask me a lot questions you want me
you know you trust my answers and stuff
like that for example I have a
uh
so you go to design keyboard Design This
is a section on key switches and they
are like 10 or 20 Pages talking in
detail about each of the key switch and
there is a particular page about the
different linear red switches how they
differ okay so all that so basically if
you don't have a hand paint if you don't
if you are young and don't have any
problem you can prefer any switches you
want it's really diff depends on the
person you know you have different
preferences but if you have RSI
then you probably better with linear and
light switches okay Brown is no good
Brown is the worst okay
okay let's go back to e-magli's coding
so we are moving writing a command to
move this oh yeah so pay me okay donate
don't you know like the video what what
not the YouTube corruption but pay me is
the most important thing you know just
patreon me go to my website
saudi.info and bottom you have patreon
Amazon gift card PayPal uh you know if
you want to
specific if you know in particular if
you want you know something important to
you you want to get my opinion on it
okay so let's go back to the code so
here we
okay let's evaluate this okay we are
basically this will work I'm pretty sure
so evaluate but the buffer okay then go
to
the image buffer okay so we can look at
different images you know so now I want
to now close this okay let's see this
one okay let's let's see this one
uh wait
let's rename this file food okay first
of all
okay so here is the image of food open
it now I want to call this command and
it should move it to the food folder
okay so the command name is photo okay
meta X
sound swords
photo okay do it now invalid argument
uh okay I don't know what is what is the
problem embedded argument
so that's the current uh
file path and the new file the new file
path is incorrect you see it appended
the full path to it okay so let's go
back here let's
need to uh oh yeah so this part should
be name obviously
okay evaluate the buffer go back here
close the messages close that and split
open the file okay call the last command
do it
fantastic I think it's that now tired
tired jump to go to the directory let's
see where is this photo now that I jump
what oh it's refresh it's gone so let's
go to food there it is open fantastic so
it worked okay
our function is complete but not yet
right now it's hard coded okay but
actually we want to
prompt user to uh for which directory
okay let's do this quickly
uh okay let's do this quickly so we want
to so we want to rename the file so
so let's see new folder okay so new
folder
uh
Target folder okay so we need to define
a Target folder
okay so ask user we want to ask user
which folder so
um
so what we do so you uh
so let's go back to emacs
practical emac this you want to prompt
users so get user input interactive
phone phone get user input there
read file name no read directory name
uh no well normally you can do that but
if you use this command that means every
time you ask user to type a file path
that's no good that's tedious
that's why we Define this you know
predefined list of file path so in this
case we want to ask it a
uh
ask it select from a list okay
completing read that's what we need
select from a list okay so you want to
ask user
so set
set Target folder
okay so actually now let's move it back
to the okay let's move it back here
Okay so so food chair
okay so set Target folder to
okay completing read
know what
wait why don't I have a shortcut to
complete
hmm
let's see
okay so this is a long command so it's
gonna be something like that
completing read
pick a folder okay then collection is a
list of folders that will be
usually it should be at least but I
don't know if it takes a Association
list okay let's just try it optional
it's an optional credit card requirement
let's just ignore them okay
purify the code
Okay so
now we have the target folder
now so let's change the hot coded folder
to the Target folder okay
and here we can
what
wait did I change my keyboard
what happened uh I think we have a
I have sticky keys I think okay so now I
think it's good
okay so here rename file compact it into
one line okay
so rename file
from this original path
to Target folder and file name
is that correct yes I think so so
yeah
so
he found the buffer let's try it now
okay let's try
so let's say
okay so let's open this so
let's rename this chair first
chair
black chair okay
and the white chair okay
make them underscore I mean make them
underscore yeah so here's a black chair
close here's food close here's white
chair across okay open white chair now
corks are sold photo
pick a folder
okay now wait if I do it now it's not
gonna work because
now it's good you know you know now it
says food or things that's correct
however the value needs to be
the target folder the value would should
be the
the value of the key so you see it
prompts you the key but the actual value
should be the path so the target folder
here
needs to
you know change to the get the value
this completing read he returns the
actually what does it return let's see
what does it return When the list of
choices is a
you know Association list okay so let's
look up
describe function
uh
search for list collection can be a list
of things and at least an up array okay
and
so I suppose the value is just
um
the cons pair so the value is the pair
key and value
so for example we can check
by message print it out let's see what
we got
okay Target folder is
so we can check and let's not rename for
now
okay so Eva the buffer now dude now go
here call the command
six are sort photo meta X let's say
things
enter
okay it prints on target folder is
things okay so it just Returns the key
so we need to get a value okay so how do
you get
the value of a key in a Association list
okay let's go back here and check
but before we do that let's go to talk
show and add these links to the talk
show so we have a record of it
a chalk switch okay
uh
emacs commands what is this okay so we
want to so what we want to do now
we want to yeah emac this okay emac
beast emac beast Basics and there's a
section on Association list okay there
it is
so how do you get a
the value of a key given a key so that
would be
least get
return the first value of the key if no
exists return default only or at least
get okay
huh okay let's let's try that
so here will be
describe function let's see where is it
hmm
this is a new in Emax 27 I think
it doesn't say uh in Emax 25 okay okay
we can use that because typically you
know this is new in Emax 25 so this
function is actually something like
seven years old so I mean before that
for the past 30 years it's usually this
associ
command instead anyway the release get
is good
okay at least get
key will be
that okay and the value will be
that optional default we don't care
before we move test function we don't
care okay
okay so that's that
okay that's that's the command evaluate
the buffer
now close it
open it white chair
meta X star sort photo enter
now which folder you want to move it two
things do it
wrong arguments yeah
okay I think I think the completing read
actually
what does it return though
uh let's see the error message
okay so it actually Returns the cons
pair I think
hmm
let me just try it okay
you wound up do it do it do it
Okay so
what
so I won't know I want to know what type
it is so
let's
so you want conspi
okay let's try again now it will print
true
if it's a cons pair
do it do it cause p is new so
so it's not a
Okay so
so it actually return the key uh the key
so this completing read
actually returns a key
the key part from the association
association this let's just to make sure
let's say string P okay
stream P tests something is a string
okay
about a buffer go here go ahead do it do
it okay
stream p is true so now we are certain
that
completing read when given a Association
list it just Returns the key okay so now
we know it's a key
so you just uh
you just do
at least get again
get the target for the form
ah yeah I think we got this spot wrong
so get the target from that
okay
and what about the test function
now because Association list you have
keys and it wants to know
whether those keys are strings or
whether those keys are symbols or
something else or numbers so he wants to
know how do you compare the key in order
for it to retrieve it okay so let's look
up the documentation for
at least get so that's the test function
part
okay so when using it to set the value
optional argument remove the Neo
yeah I don't like I don't like this new
function
because
it's very confusing
defaults to equal okay that's not good
so the key the testing key function
defaults to EQ EQ is no good because for
example let me show you
okay so for example let's close that
close that so let me show you why EQ is
no good so if you say EQ let's magnify
let's say X
okay two strings X they should be the
same but
if you do EQ they return false let's do
it you see Neo at the bottom that is why
this this get is things up this
new function is it's it's not a good
design okay this function is new it's
not a good design
yes so we can we can do this by
you know optional default Neo remove Neo
test function then you want to text
function to be equal okay that will work
but I rather not use this
okay I'm pretty sure this will work okay
so let's evaluate go back here go ahead
do it do it
uh
and okay yeah so we need to actually
anyway this is getting I think I'm
talking too long now let's see what's
some comments
but not so uncomfortable like ThinkPad I
will make a test if I get uncomfortable
I'll stop using function keys yeah well
you know you should not type on laptop
keyboards
you know the more than five minutes
because it is the laptop keyboards that
got me RSI since 2005 because I was
using laptop all day and all night
exclusively for like two years then I
realized then one day there's tingling
then I you know that's when everything
went downhill so don't use laptop
keyboards for more than you know five
minutes
so sorry Max you should be slow on Mac
OS so it's just something I'm missing no
it's not okay there are a lot of people
have the idea that emacs is slow on
Windows or on the Mac
technically it's true okay
especially on Windows emacs on Windows
in particular is slower than emacs on
Linux okay emacs on Linux is the best
because that's what Richard Solomon
wants you know whenever if the emacs
version or Mac or on Windows is better
than
on Linux
Richard Stoneman will do something to it
to make to to so that you know to make
it to destroy the Emax window version
that's you know that's what you do
because he wants to only promote free
software even that means damage
something you know so
technically it's true that emacs on
Windows in particular is slow on Linux
but however it's practical practically
speaking I don't notice the thing you
know you just set up your emacs
correctly
my my emacs is probably faster than
whatever Linux C-Max you are using okay
uh
well
for a lot of reasons because I don't you
know I don't use random packages and so
on typically random you know whatever
packages you downloaded on melpa
including the most popular you know that
s package you know there's there's F
package there is
Dash you know those the most popular you
know median downloads every library is
calling them those are not good okay
that that slows you down okay
uh
so
yeah technically emacs on Windows or on
Mac is slower but
practically not not much difference
today not today maybe in the past not
today
okay so anyway so
this function is done yeah this function
is done
now
um
but it's not perfect you know as far as
coding it we already demonstrated it
works so but there's one okay let's take
let's take five minutes to fix this
final thing
so it's good
uh completing read okay it returns uh
it Returns the key okay so it Returns
the key
so what you want is I I want I don't
want to use the least get okay that's
annoying new bad design
you know because you know why
if you know if you uh
this is getting esoteric okay but if you
are emac this code and have been so for
a year
then especially if you are a list called
a common disc coder then you'll know
what I'm talking about now okay now in
common this they have this
generic place thing okay this you
see let me read it you see you can use
at least get in place Expressions notice
you see
uh
hold on a second
you see this place Expressions that is
as a generalized generalized variable
the fact that is doing this will modify
an existing Association more precisely
the first one is multiple exists
income comprehensible but basically
essentially what that they are trying to
say is that you can use this this get to
for example in similar let's say in
Python
okay let's switch to kasar python mod
okay for example when python you have a
array
let's say three four five and let's say
you want to set
the first element of that array to let's
say something okay so in Python you can
do that
but however notice there's a semantic
strangeness going on
although this seems intuitive but behind
but this actually technologically
speaking there's something strange going
on because here normally
normally when you see these syntax you
know bracket that means return the value
okay let's change to uh hold on let me
make this more clear okay
you see normally when you see a bracket
a number inside it after some list that
means retrieve the value of that list
now
now look at this whole expression so
first of all you retrieve the value at
position zero of the least X list so
this so this part gets three
now you assign three a number to
something that's error right that's no
good so that's the semantic that's uh
detail okay so when you use this syntax
in fact this syntax is not a good syntax
it's logically wrong we use it
in part because convention because
because we've been doing that for you
know C well this doesn't I I don't think
this came from C but we we've been doing
this for the past 30 years or so
so this seems intuitive but actually
[Music]
it shouldn't be okay because this part
returns a value you can return you can
assign a number to a value okay so this
is a python example now in lisp
they are trying to do the same thing
that's what this that's what this
incomprehensive
paragraph is trying to explain you know
you can use this get in place in place
Expressions so what they mean by Place
expression is like
here is a place expression that means
this expression does not actually
evaluate to a value it actually just
indicates a place a location in your
array okay so that's what this place
expression means
so that is as a generalized variable so
in here they call this part generalized
variable it's a up
okay loved by common lisp idiots okay
you see
normally when you don't see
this as unintuitive
but when you started to use the very
logical list syntax of parenthesis then
you notice it's strange
but the common disperse you know they
they don't know so they they try to they
they made this to use this illogical
syntax but in this syntax they think
that's
generalized and Powerful but in fact
it's it's just okay it up the
excellent properties of lisp
you know by this by this thing by this
by this generalized variable the common
is
that's that's that's the explanation for
this okay
okay so let me let me let me uh add that
to the talk show so this is actually a
very rare and important information in
my
in my talk show about this because
I think I screwed up
I didn't copy it yeah okay I can
rewrite it okay
so this is important because
you know anyone can teach you about
basic emac this which is what I've been
doing in the past hour but this part
about language design detail is very
rare you will not hear it from tutorials
almost anywhere this opinion about how
it evalu you know the evaluation the you
know semantics of the design over the
list okay
so let's redo this three four five so
um
okay so here's an example
of the article
in congruity of the least
element
assignment syntax
in most
imperative
programming languages okay that that's
what they did that's what they are or
imperative or
procedural
by the way language is like C python
Java are typically called procedural
languages including Pearl you know and
uh well of course there are also op but
the imperative
uh yeah I am p r a so I got it spelled
wrong imperative language also describe
this what you know you might be
wondering why imperative what does it
mean what the heck does it mean well it
just means it
it just means procedural it means every
time you give it commands to tell it
what to do as opposed to functional
programming or Decker in contrast to
declarative programming language where
you say what you want
but in Python in Pearl in Ruby in
JavaScript those are imperative
programming languages meaning that you
each command you directly tell it what
to do okay so you have to describe in
detail what to do what do this do not do
this now do this and where does the so
that's what imperative programming
language mean where does that come from
why why do you use the word imperative
very uh not intuitive that came from
Linguistics okay
so anyway so here is the pattern example
of the okay so we documented in here and
now let's go back to our list code let's
get this
done
um
okay we rambled a lot and it's already
on our over hour now so let's let's say
that's it for today I mean after all
this command is already done and it
works okay so we can use this
um
so we don't need these uh we don't need
these messages okay anyway so put it
back put a code back in a talk show page
syntax code show in browser okay that's
today's fruit
thank you guys for watching and that's
it for today
I just talked about switches for 10
minutes you are you not here
I use the trivia so so I make sense
isn't doing me Max too many pro scenes
yeah so
so like I so about switches I personally
because isi I prefer Cherry MX red
or anything lighter okay actually why
don't I just show or choke switch okay
chalk switch so you go to this page
chaos chalk switch just search for
it on my exari.info website then you'll
see officially chalk switch they don't
have anything lighter than 50 grams okay
but
some sellers for example this m culture
okay so you can buy lighter switches
from them okay which is which is what I
did
and so you have
you have Pro red you have G chalk parade
at 35 G chalk at 20 and you also have
silver at 40 and pink at 20 even super
light
so anyway I'm using for you know you're
gonna see so anyway that's it for today
I need to take a break uh thank you guys
for watching
uh if you like my stuff again pay me
okay buy my emacs tutorials and my
JavaScript tutorials
bye guys
uh bye guys so I'm gonna
shut down in one minute clean up my
cleaner shutdown in one minute
so today we did this uh these Works
let's see let's
so in fact I don't want to use this I
want to use associate Okay so so
let's look at the source code for at
least get you know at least get
um
bye guys
10 people watching