good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show so today I'm
going to review I'm gonna show you this
fantastic keyboard okay glove 80. glove
80 from Mall Ergo
a startup company
so I'm gonna review it uh it's probably
be probably going to be 20 minutes the
first 15 minutes I'm going to review the
keyboard okay let me just show you so
I'm gonna review it I'm cover I'm going
to cover most aspect of it I haven't
programmed it I haven't programmed it
yet this is programmable keyboard so I
haven't done that yet but anyway the
physical aspect of the keyboard I'm
gonna show you everything about it okay
so the first 15 minutes then after that
I'm gonna talk generally about my
keyboarding experience about ergonomic
keyboards about split uh concave surface
a contoured surface uh you know or you
know that your choices you know things
like that you know and other dogs and
all the other
so uh if you you know if you have
questions comments and say it say it now
okay
okay so so let me uh yeah so I'm gonna
show you uh uh I'm gonna go let's let me
go over my notes and see uh okay so yeah
so first of all
so this is a um Okay so
so yeah so you can see the keyboard is
very light okay it's it's lighter than
uh it's lighter than most keyboards okay
uh and I prefer it that way some Some
people prefer heavy but I like it light
and it's extremely well built okay it's
extremely well built very light and the
first impression is elegant okay elegant
is the word to describe this keyboard
elegant uh and uh so if you know if you
know if you want to know more about this
keyboard just search for glove 80 or you
can go to xavi.info and search for
glove80 I have lots of photos I'm gonna
show you later okay
can it be used as wired uh yes and no
okay so I'm gonna go over so the two
parts you know it's Bluetooth five okay
remind me if I haven't talked about that
you know but basically the left hand
side and the right hand side they talk
they communicate by bluetooth five
internally okay so even if you plug it
in the left hand side and right hand
side they they talk to each other by
Bluetooth
uh there's you know you cannot plug a
wire between them so so in that sense
it's not wired so you know if you are
concerned about security you know
Bluetooth 5 is the latest and I said you
know it's more secure than uh than than
other other proprietary
uh Wireless supposedly I don't know for
sure but anyway
so let me go over the the details so so
very light elegant study build very well
built okay and you know you can there is
a um let's see if you can see it yeah
you can you can show the indicator you
know you it's um
let me turn it down so you can see if I
turn the light off it's got
um
backlight okay lots of colors and
effects okay lots of colors you have
breathing
uh let me get to that okay so then you
have rainbow
okay let's back to the you know let's
turn it off okay so colored you know why
don't since I'm doing a live demo I
don't type turn on the color and you can
change the Hue fantastic you can change
the Hue and you can change the
saturation you know I haven't seen that
feature in other keyboards you see now
the Hue is you know the older rainbow
Hue and you can change the saturation so
if you want you know with no saturation
they just become white okay
so anyway so yeah so um
okay and then so let me go over so if
it's uh very well built okay and elegant
and not not big at all because you can
see compared to my uh you know compared
to my tiny this ultimate hacking
keyboard there and there you know it's
it's it's it's it's pretty uh small
meaning that it doesn't occupy your desk
space okay
so the let me so let me tell you the
physical qualities of it okay so so so
first of all you know it's one of those
Contour keyboard so this Design This Way
so that when you put your fingers there
your hand naturally dips onto the keys
so as opposed to a normal keyboard you
either bend it up like that you know
that's no good or you Hoover so anyway
and there's a wrist pad I'm gonna show
you okay wrist fat attached to it it's
detachable
okay so come to keyboard uh the key well
you know so it's excellent for your
fingers ergonomic uh and uh you know so
you might be wondering this is strange
if you so here is how long you'll get uh
you know my experience on how long
you'll get used to this now if you have
used auto linear layout you know also
linear meaning that the keys forms a
rectangular grid you know it's all
straight unlike the typical keyboard
they are staggered you know they are
slanted in particular weird ways but if
you have used a Ergo linear ortholinear
layout then you'll get used to this
almost right away in a few days I would
say
so but if you have not used ortholinear
layout before then it might take you you
know two weeks
to those three you know to be fluent on
on this kind of contoured you know key
well okay so that's about that
and then
some keys you know so one of the stadium
feature of this keyboard is the thumb
keys so you have let's see if I can show
it closer you see so you have
so you have shift
control this is layers shift control
backspace delete backward delete forward
delete and ALT so essentially you have
shift Ctrl and ALT on each hand okay so
this is the left hand got this you know
my camera is so lousy and so the right
hand you have also
you see shift control and ALT on the
right hand as well then you have space
and enter that is the default this the
system key means the windows Windows key
or the max command that is the default
layout you can change it of course
because it's programmable so you can
change you can put a tab or Escape here
by default it's also a good design in my
opinion the so for you programmers by
default the traditional caps lock
position is escape okay
so it is fantastic you can change it
okay it's programmable so why the thumb
keys because thumbs are very useful
aren't traditional keyboard you have two
Twist you have to curve your thumb all
the way back you know it's awkward so
that's why the thumb key design
uh then so then let me tell you so also
this keyboard tremendous engineering
went into it so you can see it's super
uh low profile you see they they they
they took the trouble extra trouble to
make it tremendously low so so it
doesn't stand up high on your tape on
your desk so you can see
you know like a pain do I have a pain
here so it's like just one pen with the
lowest key
so low profile and also the key the key
caps they are using choke Kyle chalk
switch so it's also a you know very
I think it's two millimeter activation
uh distance
okay so that's a truck switch that's a
low profile tremendous engineering went
to uh to do this it's not easy okay so
uh
so then okay USB port in power so the
way you connect to the keyboard is I
mean it's wireless it's Bluetooth 5 uh
but
um
but the way you connect that is on each
hand
you have a blue uh USBC Port okay and
then you have a power button so if I
press the power button off let's see so
press it you know the power button is a
toggle when you push it down it stays
down very excellent design as opposed to
you know switch back and forth
with that design you don't know which
side is on unless you get used to but
this design you can feel it you know
when it's on you know because the button
stays down so on each hand you have a
USBC
now this is for charging the keyboard
you know because it's a Bluetooth so it
has it has batteries on each side so
when you need to charge it you have to
plug in USBC that's for charging okay
and when it's charging you can still use
the use them
so that is the USB port in power so same
thing on the right side same thing on
the on the left side and let the left
hand side is the main component so you
know the left hand side got the brain
the chips or the whatever the left hand
side is the main component so when you
got it you just you just press it on you
know and
um
uh yeah
so uh so that's about uh port and power
and yeah so now let me show you the
removable Palm rest
okay I suppose most people they want the
you know they like the Palm wrist
for me I like it too on on this
particular keyboard uh but I'm not sure
I care about it that much but let me put
it on okay so the you know so as I said
it's extremely elegant design all you
have to do to detach and attach them you
know the Palm juice is actually just a
simple very elegant you know simple
plastic it's not some elaborate stand
okay simple mechanism so all you all you
have to do to attach the Palm rest
tongue is just to screw it okay so you
so this side goes to this side so let me
do it now
so you see it's got this thumb screw all
you have to do is just twist it
Focus
yeah there okay so
all you have to do is just
twist it
okay just with your thumb
there you have it
you know fantastic
yeah focus focus fantastic okay
okay so that's the left hand side
fantastic steady sturdy does you know
doesn't move all at all so let's attach
the right hand side
fantastic design simple and functional
that's what I like
you know I don't like grandfather clock
elaborate and wooden
so this is like high-tech sci-fi you
know sci-fi you know spaceship stuff
okay
super light okay so that's how it looks
like
you know according to the guy you know
the more Ergo people they you know they
spend a lot a lot of time five years
designing this keyboard
with 500 prototypes
you know so according to them they they
you know tremendous design and
Engineering went to it went to uh make
this kind of design possible
and uh so they are very
adamant you know they think that the
Palm rest is critical it's one of the
best feature of the keyboard but for my
you know that which I agree you know
it's it's fantastic but I think if you
are a typist you know you know there's a
lot of things uh kind of science on
ergonomics on repetitive strain injury a
lot of people have that about what's the
best composition or there's a question
if you are typist whether you should
rest your fingers on the palm rest or
you should um you know lift it you know
so I've been typing for 30 years you
know starting in 1990 1990 okay 1990
1990 by 1992 I type every day you know
I'm a I'm a QWERTY typist
um mechanical typewriter since
1988 okay so I started to touch type in
1998 on mechanical typewriters okay I
think it's the Electoral mechanic you
know Brothers the brand name is brothers
so I love typing for some reason I just
love finger work I also love piano so I
thought so I read tons of books you know
on warak before there is the internet
you know I I went and read books on
borac that's how I know the Aurora
layout and so on so
I've been typing a long time I don't
have a repetitive repetitive strain
injury at all until 2005.
2005 that's when I was typing on a Mac
laptop every day for two years that's
when I started to have tingling I know
it because by that by by 2005 I've been
typing for 15 years I've been I've been
reading all about ergonomics about
a different keyboard layout ergonomic
keyboard layout vorac and you know I've
been and repeated repetitive stranger
you know so I know all about that
already so I know I got a problem I need
to do something about it so that's when
my first ergonomic keyboard is the
Microsoft natural okay
if you just search for xali
keyboard you'll find my blog with a
thousand articles on all the varieties
of keyboard I'm going to show you later
okay so
the point is the about repetitive string
injury you know the science of it is not
very solid like sometimes you have hand
paint use and different there's no like
one solution you know oh because this
this or if you have this this problem
you you just do this then then the pain
will go away no it's not like that every
person is different you know some people
have you know thumb pain you know I've
Heard lots of uh horror stories they see
they they went to see a doctor they sent
me email from around the world from some
sometimes from from Russia you know so
people have been asking me asking me so
some people have had you know thumbs
sometimes it's index fingers and
sometimes it's a knuckle sometimes it's
their wrist and for me
the for the past
um three uh for the past five years it's
over here okay my elbow
so you can see
uh let's see where okay so it's right
here okay so it is right here
you know so if I do this
I have a crystal ball crystal ball
designed to to massage my arm right
right this point
you know that you know eventually I
realized because I was using this finger
too much to type the number three
character on emacs for expanding the
window long story okay so anyway so
the point I'm trying to say is that
repetitive string injury is very complex
and the science of it is not solid okay
you can see professional you know PhD
you know Professional Publications about
it sometimes you go see a doctor
different doctor tell you different
things okay so it's not
something's you know well understood
okay
so so my so my point about that is that
some people you know for typists some
people say
you should you know you should when you
type you should never rest your palm on
the palm rest okay that is one of the
advice okay
again depends on people you know depends
on you so some people they you know they
they slouch on a kind of sofa they don't
have a problem okay so again depends on
each person is different
so my my pers personally when I I can
feel it when I type you know when I
started to for example you know typing
competition you know when you type
continue that's the point if you have to
type continuously like in a typing
competition like like for example uh
uh actually you can you cannot see me
type because
I don't have a screen my computer screen
so you cannot see me type but anyway
when you want to type like that
continuously let's say for 20 minutes
for me when I do that I will know the
difference I I must lift my I must not
you know I must not be sloppy and risk
my Palms on the on the on the on the
wrist on the palm rest okay I must still
do it like that because whenever I rest
on them
on the Kinesis Advantage 2 for example I
don't know it you know after you know
I'll get sore I'll know it
so again it depends on people so the the
morogo people tell me that this Palm
rest is very well designed that it's
designed so that you should rest your
hand on it okay they say that I don't
know for sure because I haven't used
this keyboard I only use it for one day
so I haven't really started to do heavy
you know riding 10 blocks you know on my
website yet so I don't know for sure
this you know but I would
as usual you know for my 30 years of
typing experience I would when I started
to type a lot you know for prolonged you
know continuously typing for more than
10 minutes that's the key
continuously typing this is important
you know not not as a programmer you
know as a programmer you actually don't
continue
you don't type continuously that's a key
difference okay
so if you are a programmer yeah that's
no problem but if you started to do data
entry or for example in your game where
you have to chat all the time you know I
would you know I still prefer to do that
and normally I I prefer to use you see
this uh past Towers that's my that's
what I think is the best
Palm rest okay that is you should be
thicker okay but these days when I when
I want to type a lot I raise my hand
okay
any questions ask me okay I'm gonna uh
get to it okay so let me finish so next
so you got the Palm rest removable Palm
rest okay then you got
um let's see
very nice adjustable feet okay again
this is a very simple practical design
you know so one thing people want is
tenting tenting means
tinting means raising the middle part of
the fingers so that your
so so so so your hand is not flat on the
table rather the natural position is
more like that okay like that instead of
that so if you put your hand like that
flat on the table for five hours a day
do that for a year you got you get a
problem because that happened to me I
was using a flat keyboard and I
literally sit you know type on it not
take not continuously but using a flat
keyboard for 10 hours 10 hours a day for
for a year or two that's around 2017
2016 2017. and that's another bout of
isi I know because then I noticed you
know like every time I had eyes I
eventually I tried to find what's the
cause and for that period I eventually
realized that's because you know my hand
is flagged like that for 10 hours a day
you know so the natural more the natural
position is like that so that's when you
want that's when you want uh tenting
okay
so let's see so you can see tainting and
so by default there's like 10 degrees of
tenting okay so but but now look at the
feet okay you just twist it
uh
let's see
yeah you see
you twist it and you extend it the feed
okay same thing here you want to do here
just with your fingers no screwdrivers
required so depends on how much tinting
you want to go if you really want it
high they include
okay
uh extra bag of keycaps for example for
the Mac there's a command command key
and option if you want it for the Mac
there's key puller there's extra feet
there's extra screws so if you want
extended tenting you know if you want
really hot really high so so now
so now you adjust it you see it shakes a
bit so now you just
extended that more
no it's solid aren't we
okay more
now it's solid okay so you see now you
got tenting
fantastic simple simple design
okay that's tenting uh the magic key
okay so this key
here let's turn on the
let's turn off the light okay now here
is the magic key on the lower left side
of the keyboard
focus focus there okay now you press it
it'll show you the current status of the
keyboard okay press it there it is so
those two green lights those shows the
battery level okay the top one is left
the bottom one is right the battery
level
and it also shows
um
uh okay it's not
there it is okay it also shows it goes
off after 10 seconds to save battery so
it also shows the current Bluetooth
status you can you see you can connect
to four Bluetooth devices at a time and
the current one that's active is colored
white okay
foreign
this is the current active Bluetooth I
so I have three computers connected to
it the two red ones means they are not
they are
paired but not connected
okay
so let's turn on the night
so let's let's put the feed back to the
way it is
so I don't really need so much tenting
so let's screw them back
okay so I think we are almost done okay
so uh the magic key the showing the
status okay then what what's next so the
key switch the key switch they use is a
Kyle
chalk switch okay which is great but you
know however so they have by default I
think you can pick from
uh Kyle chalk Brown which is tactile or
red which is linear I got linear or blue
blue is
blue is creaky Okay so
but however the chalk red is the
activation force is 50 g okay 50 grams
choke choke red Kyle
chalk red key switch they are low
profile key switch okay but the the
lightest one is chocolate at 50g linear
uh that is too heavy for me okay you
know it's a personal preference because
I type so much another very critical
thing is that exactly how much you type
you know you have to use the key log
let's go to my blog and show you all
about it okay so hold on a second so so
battery backlight let me show you the
backlight and let's go back to the
switch later okay so turn on the
backlight and yeah so as I showed we
showed before you can adjust the hue
and let's see can you see it yeah just
the Hue let's see let's get it to red
okay
you know red doesn't show so well on my
camera I guess
so let's go to yellow and let's go to
green Okay so
and you have some effects
so you have breathing
then you have this
uh flashing I guess
and you have this rainbow
then you have steady okay I like this
the best in fact I don't need it
okay so that's the backlight
uh
okay that's it now let me go back to
show my full uh you know show my screen
so you can see
yeah so so you know
go to my website and read about you know
you have uh photos you have photos to uh
you know all the photos and the details
okay that's that is my review so far you
know I only use this keyboard for one
day so like the physical qualities is
all excellent you know in my opinion
it's all top-notch okay
uh
and the choke switch you know the chalk
switch is a bit heavy for me okay so I
don't you know you can see right now I
have chalk red chalk red is the
uh the 50 grams linear the lightest
I believe that's uh that's the lightest
they offer right now but I think they're
gonna you know so I talked to them you
know I want to use this long term so for
the next year
you know you're gonna see me typing on
this keyboard when I do my live stream
for programming emacs python Wolfram
language you know I'm gonna use this
keyboard
um so far I only used for for one day
you know so
uh and uh so far my experience is just
great it's excellent
um yeah okay so that's it about my
review any questions then I'm gonna
spend five minutes and tell you about uh
about uh different ergonomic keyboards
okay maybe
so
so let me read the questions
okay
see
hmm
[Applause]
what oh my first key because right now I
don't have it programmed yet but I'm
using a vorac keyboard via the system
you know the windows work layout
so where did my plus key go I don't know
yet because you need to
press Ctrl plus to magnify
it's too small so
so let's go here
so let's yeah so let me show you some
typing
let me can can you actually see it there
[Music]
um
show okay so hold on a second
Ctrl G I haven't set this keyboard up
yet so
a bit slow here so let me this is stuff
like this this is XA fly keys or just
xfk Okay fantastic
okay okay so my usually I swap the
number key seven and eight so right now
it's not swapped yet so I'm prone to
type a instead of one
so I want to type one because I want to
type the ban exclamation sign okay
so
okay so that's the that's about typing
so what I wanted to say uh
oh yeah so magnify
so yeah where is my plus key where did
the plus key go
okay insert mode
there okay so go back to that Ctrl shift
plus there it is
okay so now we read the comments
could this we use programming game like
Minecraft and such of course
David Cherry Chris Kristen Williams okay
hello this answer your treat uh
co-designer of glove 80.
Shin fantastic great to the thank you
nice to meet you
I'm making a keyboard cool
uh why do you plug left side okay yeah
yeah does the keyboard have similar
effect to your wrist like to those
ergonomic mice whenever you wrist is
turned like preventing confident
yeah that's tempting you are talking
about right all you have to do if you
want you can tend it much more you know
but
about tenting let me tell you some uh my
experience okay so some people you know
I've seen some people they are crazy
you know they want to tend their
keyboard like that
you know sometimes even 90 90 degrees
you know I think that's crazy you know I
think some amount of attending is good
enough if you still have problems that
means you need to get up get your fat
fat ass up and walk you know every two
hours walk for five minutes okay and do
exercise okay
however fantastic keyboard they are
gonna not gonna you know save your life
if you keep sitting there okay so
you know yeah you can do some tainting
but you know if you you should get up
you know and walk around
uh
do you need to okay so so Shane is uh
helping us can uh answering some
questions
yeah you don't have to so you just you
can charge either one of them
uh
so here's an interesting question a lot
of people would be interested to know
how does the thumb cluster compares to
Kinesis okay yeah
um so let me answer that okay in five
minutes we're gonna shut down okay
five more minutes uh
yeah you have full RGB you have seen it
right I just showed you 4GB
so you can have green you can have uh
purple you know red you know the camera
is gonna is showing you a different
color from what I see so right now I see
pink
um
and I showed this before you can have
rainbow let's show rainbow
okay that's one of their default Flash
mod okay
so let me let me tell you guys about a
bit about uh let's turn it off okay let
me tell you guys a bit okay you can
still see me fine so let's stay this way
so let me yeah so let me tell you guys
about the
comparison to Kinesis because you know I
assume most people you know either you
never you know so here's my keyboard I
have quite a few other ergonomic ones
you know
so for those of you who never had this
kind of keyboard
I would say this is a great one it's a
great choice you know whether you want
to buy it or not it's up to you because
it's it's very rare okay you don't get
this much okay and they are all
expensive okay they are all fairly
expensive so first of all if you want uh
you know split like that for example
this one it's not contoured but this one
is five hundred dollars more than 500
from Japan okay so so
um and uh you know
so if you want flat which is very common
okay but if you want to upgrade to the
next level you want contoured for
example these four and and that's where
it's going to be more expensive okay so
let me tell you about your choices okay
so first of all you have these four
actually just these two Kinesis made by
Kinesis you know Kinesis is great also
I've been using them for five years
why am I changing I'm not changing I'm
actually because for I'm doing YouTube
so sometimes I
you know the exposes also okay so I'm
doing a variety of keyboards so but this
one Kinesis I've been using as my main
four five years fantastic okay
so your question about how you how they
compare
you know I wouldn't say I have the right
answer that that that is my honest
question both of them I think it's great
okay you know uh
depending on what Niche you want you
know for example this Kinesis this is
one piece so if you want more tenting
you cannot do it with this one okay but
the new one Kinesis 360 you can okay
this one is pure like a solid metal this
is this is heavy okay and I also use it
it's great but it's 500 something okay
so it's a lot more expensive and
so if you want just spontaneity this is
Con by the way this is continuous
tending so you can adjust tending to uh
many mind you know by one degree if you
want but the Kinesis V60 they only have
three levels of tinting okay right now I
don't have it but I have used it you
know for for a bit so
you know I'm not doing a full review so
and you know I'm just telling you my
experience okay so you don't have many
choices you have and if you want
Bluetooth this one is out the Kinesis
Advantage 2 is out so if you want
Bluetooth it's either the 360 or the
glove 80 okay
so there's many aspects to compare you
know depends on what you know I I cannot
say
for sure that one is the better than the
other even if the price doesn't matter
okay I cannot say that
so I think you don't have much choices
but however the Motrin for example
it's also
contoured but this motion is 500
something dollars or six hundred dollars
and they are not
you know they they are like
handmade each one is handmade they are
not mass produced so it's it's kind of
ugly okay so you don't have many many
choices so these three these three and
also let me tell you so you also have do
it yourself okay for example you have
ductile
uh you have that manual form but I would
say you know some people have bad eggs
you know
if you wanna
this do it yourself you might think okay
it's cheaper not really you know if you
buy it from pre-build it's about the
same price you know the same price as
the as the commercial we made and also
those this do it yourself they are not
quality assured you know when you create
a keyboard when you want to manufacture
it you have to pass a lot of standards
and regulations you know whatever you
know like on the back of the key they
are say CE you know you have
a lot
let's see yeah you have a lot kind of
these you know see you know regulations
you have to pass they told me they also
passed the drop test you know you have
to make sure your keyboard is quality
assurance you know but that's not
necessarily the case if you go with this
you know open source do it yourself and
also if you buy them from pre pre-build
they are like four hundred dollars five
hundred dollars okay it's just as
expensive also sometimes I hear Bad
stories when you preview or sometimes
they are they have bad soldiering
uh and uh you know things like that
that's so Journey or or sometimes Dead
on Arrival
okay so if you want to do it yourself
it's the best thing is that you actually
build it yourself
okay and then I also heard stories you
know they you know although they look
like
you know Kinesis but they you know they
are I mean new details about design so
you know some people I've read you know
recently some people develop hand paints
when using
um when using the data manual form
so you want to be careful okay so yeah
so but if you want to spend money and if
you don't if you don't really soldier
that much I think it's probably best
just to buy one of these three if you
want contoured okay Kinesis or the glove
okay that's that's what I can see now as
to the thumb design
to me I don't really notice I I think I
think the I think the glove 80s thumbs
are better okay
I think it's better better design but as
far as the ergonomics I haven't really
filled uh much difference
you know well the part of the reason is
I haven't been using Kinesis for three
months because in the past three months
I've been using the Expos so
I wouldn't say you know this is so big a
difference that that makes uh you know
decision at least for me I didn't feel
particularly
big huge difference about the thumb keys
but however I do think that the glove
80s some keys are better because why
because you have six of them on each
hand and you have and and and their
default
um
they are default uh functionality is
much better
okay so that that is my
you know that's that is my opinion
okay so that's it for today I think
yeah so yeah that's it
okay that's it I think yeah I wanna I
wanna keep these uh shorts uh
it's already 40 minutes okay anything
else let's see is there anything else I
wanna say
let's see so I'm using so I'm gonna
soon I'm gonna have full integration for
soft like Keys now if you you might not
know what that is you know if you use
emacs then you know you know if you
watch my video before
then you know what I'm doing so this is
emacs for programmers mostly well I mean
and other for example this is cloud fly
Keys you know so this is my live you
know working with uh this keyboard and
right now it's
you know I'm using the windows vorac
layout so I don't have it customized yet
oh there's another thing about the
programmability okay the programmability
is fantastic it's because this glove 80
is built on the um the glove 80 is built
on the zmx zmk open source software okay
zmk open source so it's
I can I know for sure it's it's
trustworthy
and it's one of the best okay zmk
software
okay so that so okay so that's it um
yeah So eventually I I you know I I will
be using this keyboard every day
eventually and the full integration with
stuff like keys and uh
and program my own Keys you know I want
to you know I probably want to
uh change some you know I want the tab
on the on the thumb on the right thumb
tab
uh okay so let's go to sound talk show
so let's go to here
so Bluetooth yeah so this is my notes on
what to talk so
okay thank you guys for watching if you
like my stuff donate okay you you can
just go to my uh yeah this is important
so donate okay if you like my stuff
donate to me go to my sorry
dot info uh and at the bottom you can
see patreon Amazon gift card five you
know five dollars twenty dollars is nice
thank you bye
foreign
yeah so about key switch you know Cherry
MX if you are used to Cherry MX linear
red you know that's 45 grams if you are
used to that
then the chalk red is a bit heavier you
know the chalk red is 50.
you know if I'm gonna continuously type
for an hour like I typically do every
day you know I have 10 blocks blogs I
write and so on then I I you know I want
I must have
red you know you know key switch it's
intricate
before you know like 10 years ago when I
started to learn about uh yes I I
favorite I favor it over the ultimate
hacking keyboard
you know I talked you know I talked
about that because ultimately I can keep
off is you know it's not
it's not contoured and also it has much
less keys
and also one of the issue is that you
know yeah it's good to mention ultimate
hacking though you know here is the
intricate details about key switch you
see the ultimate hacking I have let me
let me open it okay so let me let me
talk about the key switch you know it
different for everyone you know you you
may have your own preferences so
the ultimate hacking keyboard is
fantastic okay I mean the the yeah it's
also great I would say
so you know but
but I prefer you know I much prefer the
Contour okay but the the one I have is
uh Kyle Red's linear switch Kyle red
okay so by specification if you go to
the you know so for example you you can
see here's the Cherry MX red spec and
let's go to Kyle uh spec
chaos switch
you know which is a clone of Cherry MX
red so you can see Kyle red is also 45 G
activation Force by spec so Kyle red and
Cherry MX red in theory they should feel
the same but not not so
Kyle red is actually much more heavier
you can feel it you know right away
right away so especially when I need to
type continue continuously you know in a
long session
it gets tired for me okay for me maybe
not for you
but for some other people when they use
the gamers Cherry MX red it's too light
you know because I have recommended two
friends you know if you have isi you
must catch area makes
red but when they actually bought the
keyboard it's too light for them you
know they accidentally type mistakes all
the time so it depends on the person
okay and the intricacy is that you see
even though by spec they all say 45 but
it's in in reality no so Kyle red 45 is
much heavier it's sick noticeably
heavier than Cherry MX red
then there is also Cherry MX red silent
okay Cherry Cherry MX red so you can see
silent red okay by spec it's also 45.
but in reality no
because I bought my Kinesis let me just
show you show you okay so God you know
my guess is right now it's very messy so
I bought my own Kinesis Advantage
because I was you know the the one I had
was brown so I get I can't use Brown so
I get a red
silent because they don't have red it
turns out
Cherry MX red silent is heavier than
Cherry MX red entirely different okay
even by spec they will say they all say
45 so
Cherry MX red is the lightest then
Cherry MX silent red then after that
Kyle red heavier okay
so you see it's all red but it's very
different chalk red is I would say is
like Kyle red okay if you know chocolate
aspect is 50g
so there's intricate intricate you know
details about the the weight of the key
so it's a very personal stuff okay
that's it thank you bye