welcome to another episode of Pixar talk
show
today is 2021 April 19th and today we
are going to continue
uh uh The Saga of exploring emacs this
Helm source code and I do source code
so if you are watching me live you can
see in the YouTube description the that
is what we are going to do today
uh and uh yeah and if you have comments
questions uh type in the comment box
okay and today so we are going to do uh
emac Beast nothing else today we are
just going to focus on that topic and uh
so I'm going to do it quickly good
morning uh nawaf
uh so we are going to
first of all I'm going to write a emac
this command that will pop up a prompt
asking you to type some words to choose
among a thousand uh academic phases
so basically using firstly matching
and I'm going to use the I do mod you
know I Do's first First Dimension for
that then we are going to start to
continue from yesterday look for uh look
at the source code of Helm mod
then if I if we are successful that will
that'll take most of the time if we are
successful then we are going to modify
our Command so that it
um uses Helms uh uh First Imagine okay
okay so I'm going to turn my camera to
my keyboard okay
so because my you know my wife is
sleeping is she's gonna go to bed so I
want to
just show you
my keyboard then you are looking at my
keyboard This is kinesis this is kinesis
Advantage 2 with a linear red switches
and this is Ultimate hacking keyboard
you can see on my website
I have reviews and videos of it and this
is Advantage 2 and ottoman hacking
keyboard so go buy it if you like it
uh okay so let's begin coding I'm going
to do this fast today hopefully we can
complete what we need so for you emacs
users the left side the pink window is
my you can see all the command I call
for example moving closer right left up
down or moving by paragraph or moving up
uh and also you can see the keystrokes
on the pink window
and I'm using soft light keys and I'm
using vorac keyboard so the letters are
not quality
okay so let's first of all begin sorry
okay let's start to do this job okay
first of all
uh create an empty emac bit buffer then
we're gonna Define uh select
phases okay we're gonna say select
phrases and dark stream is gonna be
prompt
to
let users select a icon
academic phrase and insert it okay
version today's date so this is our
Command so we're gonna start to write
this command okay uh okay let's let's
begin okay so let's prevent uh Arrow
yeah let's do that there so let's
we don't care for that let's then
okay so we need a bunch of academic
phrases so let's look at yesterday we
have prepared a bunch of academic
phrases
yeah
yeah I removed it okay so we have to uh
yeah we have to search for okay let's
search for it
p-h-r-a-s-e-s academic phrases list okay
uh
academic phrases
okay
let me just quickly find it you wouldn't
be interested in this
analysis okay and let's do that
okay
uh academic phrases
now I remember
uh yesterday I have a collection of such
phrases but
not this
yeah oh okay wait page
not least
uh
okay let's let's try this
okay these are a bunch of academic
phrases
let's just use that okay
then paste it here so we have a bunch of
academic phrases now
we will let users choose among one of
these okay now make them uh add quote
quotation to them
okay and make this a okay
faces okay
then that add a parenthesis around them
and add a quote
so this is gonna cut we paste it here
predify the code
okay so that's a code okay let's delete
a few of them let's delete the short
ones
okay
uh
yeah because we are just testing this
anyway
okay so we we have a bunch of uh faces
academic phrases now
now we want to insert we want to uh
you know we we actually we need a
parenthesis there then we need uh to say
user Choice okay
Cho
I uh
what
ah I'm not with myself I forgot how to
spell choice c-h-o-i-c-e okay I think
that's it yeah Choice okay
stupid English spelling okay so now user
choice is the one user choose and chosen
okay so now
set Q user choice
I do
uh completion
I do completion read
I do completing read okay
okay that is the command we want
and uh
so this function I do completing read
and given a list of phrases it will
prompt user the faces okay
so about the buffer now let's call our
Command select faces So Meta X
select phrases enter
wrong arguments
okay so wait uh I do completing
uh what's going on
oh the first argument should be a prompt
pick one okay
evaluate the code and it's okay evaluate
the code
meta X select phrases now we got the
list of phrases let's say uh
l a
okay l a
C so that contains the word lack okay so
enter oh we do nothing we need to insert
it so now insert
uh insert user Choice okay now try again
evaluate the code metax select faces Lac
okay Enter then it inserts that that's
what we want now yesterday we found out
that the idols First Imagine is based on
is a character based first imagine that
is if the sentence contains I mean you
type whatever and and each character you
type is consent consider the character
if the sentence contains all the
characters you typed it doesn't matter
where it doesn't matter if there's
something in between I do will consider
that as part of your you know as as the
choice
until there's unique until you type more
when when it's Unique you just uh you'll
find it okay so now but now we want a
word based uh fuzzy matching which is
using help so for example let's try help
okay
h-e-l-m L meta X okay so here's helm
so we can say
you know one of the command we just
defined is Select phrases right
now I can type phrases space select it
will also uh match our Command name for
example let's try
p-h-r-a-s-e-s space you see it's right
here
now I say s e l you see now if I enter
you know I'm calling the command we just
wrote so okay now cancel now so you see
that you see that in Hell mod it's fuzzy
based uh First Imagine is based on word
based versus imagine and also order that
doesn't matter
okay so that's that's what we are going
to do that's uh but now
we are going to start to dive into the
Helms emac this source code and to see
to see
if we can understand it
and eventually what we need to do is
that we want to modify this code so that
it uses uh instead instead of I2 it uses
Helms World matching
um
uh First Imagine
thank you George for twenty dollars
thank you
okay so let's begin let's begin the
journey so how long have I been talking
uh
and that can be it cannot be right I
already talked for 20 minutes
what
uh
12 minutes okay I I already talked for
12 minutes okay not too bad okay let's
begin because this is gonna be a long
session today so we want to start to
look for help okay so uh last time we
made some progress but let's continue
okay uh so first of all call Helm MX and
uh Ctrl H F describe function
so Helm so we start to look into Helm
source code okay Enter to look at the
source code here's the source code and
now meanwhile back here uh wait what is
this
uh what is this Woody blog okay that's
my word blog
go back to talk show uh today's talk
show wait today's talk show is here so
let's write it down okay the first
command the
Helm
core stack so first of all we look at
how meta X
okay then
yesterday we found how meta X is
actually calling
uh
it's actually calling
there how meta X read extended command
Okay up up array so let's copy that
let's make you know let's keep track
okay so how meta X is calling this Helm
MX read extended command now we look at
the source code of that okay
so here is the source code I mean let's
enter
so here is the source code and this
command is actually again calling
another command to do the work
so let's see what it is there it is okay
so this command is actually the you know
the heart of this command is actually
just a wrapper so it's calling this Helm
command okay let's copy go back and
let's record it let's put it here
actually actually
let's go back to our emac this and put
it there okay
and wait
uh
yeah here so so we want so here is the
Helm color stack okay so now it's
actually so it's actually calling help
the command the function help so now
let's describe function on Helm and go
to the source code of Helm okay here's a
code narrow to region
and it's 160 lines now if you remove the
comments it's just a 50 lines okay
and this command is actually again calls
another command to do the actual work
that's what we found out yesterday so it
is actually calling
um Helm internal you see
you see here is a local variable FN FN
is a function now and and uh and you
know is set up what value should it be
so it's either one of Helm nest
if Helm is already called or you just
call Helm again or it calls Helm
internal
so you know so first of all it says set
sets up a local variable FN then
eventually here is what I call what it
calls you know FN
apply FM playlist is a property list
so anyway so what we found is that
essentially this command Helm it's
actually not a command it's just a
function you cannot call this
interactivity because you see there's no
Interactive line there so this this
function Helm actually cause
uh it calls Helm internal to do work
okay so close that let's write it down
uh okay open reopen uh
yeah copy that and uh okay hold on
uh wait uh what
okay uh yeah so it actually says that
uh
apply Helm internal to a p list now P
list is some sort of property list let's
see what it is
so far so good
nice microphone yeah yes
uh
so let's see helm
I want to know what is the P list p is
usually a property list okay hold on a
second let's narrow to Define and let's
search for p list okay hold on a second
let's show the pink Window search for p
list okay
oh okay so it's an argument yes please
is at least like that okay property list
okay
keywords supported okay
okay so somewhat okay keep that in mind
so here is actually a sample call
okay
uh
okay let's open a new Emax window
Let's uh keep this window here
and actually uh let's see
now open last closed
keep this in mind okay
uh
so
we we you know I need to do this quickly
I need to make progress
so again we are trying to find how fuzzy
matching is implemented in helm
so here's the keywords
okay so okay let's let's continue on now
let's look at how internal okay
let's look at Helm internal
yeah describe function
then jump to the
okay actually Helm internal this is how
you call it let's write it down
uh then jump to the source code
okay so entry point helper okay Helm
internal now
narrow to Define
so this is again 100 lines okay
yesterday we have not look at
we have not looked at this command much
so let's continue
so Helm internal okay but before we do
that how is it called again how internal
optional sources sources is a list uh
for example a list of academic phrases
then input is
okay input is whatever user has already
typed I think
wait and prompt resume
pre-select buffer key map default
history okay
uh Helm internal
so let's look again now there is no
no
documentation for Helm internally well
they they there is the internal Helm
function called by helm for sources
input for for these arguments and
history Arc Helm okay so it seems that
the function Helm internal uses the same
argument as hell
now we want to be sure let's let's check
okay let's check a little bit
okay here's Helm internal and and let's
let's describe function on helm
uh it jumped
okay oh no no it didn't jump so here's
how Helm internal
and uh here is okay so let's move this
here actually
so here is Helm
so Helm course Helm internal okay
and the rest P lists
okay so Helm Internal Documentation says
the internal Helm function called by
helm
for this this this this this and this
see Helm okay so it's sources input
pumped resume
uh wait okay so narrow two region ah
okay now to region yeah
and actually widen okay
yeah it moved you know we lost the
position for Helm internal so let's
let's describe function let's see how
I'm internal
so Helm internal is line to that 200 I
mean 2 800 2800.
and uh
the function Helm is 2600 okay
okay Helm course Helm internal now we
want to make sure they use this exact is
their argument exactly the same
sources input prompt resume okay
sources input prompt resume then
pre-select yes buffer check key map
check default
check and history check okay so Helm
actually has one more thing allow nest
okay
so they they essentially use this the
same argument okay Helm and Helm
internal
now Helm course Helm internal is that
right uh
let's go down
yeah Helm course Helm internal okay so
now
now what does Helm internal uh do let's
narrow to region and let's let's see how
internal what does it do
all right
okay so how many lines hundred lines
okay so we need to I need to um focus on
this
uh so so Helm internal uh this bunch of
options commonly assert
unless so if if Helm nested
is not true then set Helm initial frame
selected frame okay uh frame is kind of
uh
panel there's something egg okay
then activate the advices
okay then
when so if advice add is defined is is
bound the function is defined then
advice add read password okay it's
related to remote
you know uh FTP or you know remote SSH
advice add
so when pound advice add then do these
things ensure line of mod is disabled in
Helm buffers to preserve performance
that's right so when you have alignment
mod it makes emacs very slow okay then
advice add line them on blah blah blah
then Helm log
okay uh okay it kind of logs okay then
Helm prompt
or pumped pattern set queue Helm pumped
Pumped pattern okay
so it looks like so far you know it's
calling it's setting Helm prompt so Helm
prompt is not a local variable you see
I'm trying to search for it it failed so
Helm prompt is a some sort of global
variable and but it's internal to Hell
mod because you can see
uh usually two dash means it's internal
to help
so so
it's
um it's setting Helm pump okay so now
then
let none essential true prevent Mouse
jumping to the upper right hand corner
of the frame I don't know what that what
bug is that
what is non-essential let's see
this y function non-essential oh it's
not even defined
okay so no essential is not a field in
emac this function it must be
oh actually it's just a variable so set
the variable no essential a local
variable to true
but where is it used
that's that's kind of strange that so
it's not used in this function
so that must mean either it's a mistake
you know they forgot to remove these
variable it's an unused variable or
it is actually some Global variable
defining Helm let's try okay
copy that describe variable no essential
yeah okay so it's actually so it's a
global variable in emac lisp no
essentially it's a variable defined in
simple.el
documentation wherever the currently
executing code is performing an
essential task
okay this variable should be noneal
only when running code that should not
disrupt disturb the user okay
okay yeah it is some kind of uh user
interface related thing
so if it's not essential then
Okay blah blah blah I don't okay I don't
care about this
this uh code how maybe use default as
input okay now I I think now we are
getting into the
important part unwind protect
conditional case and wine protect is
kind of error handling it's like uh
uh you know throw and catch okay in
that's a lisp version of
uh condition case an SD bug
you know I hate the word unless okay so
basically it means continue to condition
case if not debug okay if not debug
then so if it's not debug then
Source name current Source uh Helm okay
I need to go faster help buffer help me
initialized okay help initialize
resume input default sources okay then
comment we don't display Helm buffer
here to avoid popping up a window or a
frame when
exiting immediately when
only one candidate disavowed having the
helm frame fashion
okay let's first compute candidates and
if more than one display Helm buffer
this is done later in Helm read for mini
buffer okay
again remember our goal is to find the
fuzzy match engine using help
so all these uh so far is just interface
or wrappers okay
uh post command hook okay Helm read from
mini buffer okay so this part is
probably important okay so let's copy
that
because Helm read from mini buffer you
know in in emacs leaves in glue emacs
list there's a read for mini buffer
command which is a general command to
prompt user and let user input something
so apparently Helm defined its own
version so that's you know and it's
coding that and that is important so
let's write it down
uh let's write it down
okay let's look at the source code
quickly Helm read for mini buffer okay
so how many lines of code again 100
lines of code okay
so anyway Let's uh let's put it here and
let's go back to read
uh the the source code of
wait
yeah
what where are we yeah go back to read
the source code of
Helm internal right so Helm internal
cause Helm read for mini buffer
so starting here you know before
you know the helm you know Helm MX calls
Helm MX read extended command that in
turn calls Helm to do the work that in
turns cause harm internal to do its work
then at that point the helm internal
cause cause Helm read for mini buffer
but I don't think that's all because at
this point
it's like splitting into two uh I think
because
reach for mini buffer is just reading
for mini buffer Europe but but you also
need to update you know as user types so
so there is probably
um
okay let's go to okay help help me
internal narrow to region
uh
okay read
for mini buffer
okay so now we are near at the end of
the code
Helm meet for mini buffer okay go back
here paste the actual call
okay now go back here
so here it calls him read for mini
buffer
okay then
okay here may be a bit complex so
program one unless so if not Helm quit
then Helm execute selection action okay
Okay so
so I'm guessing you see when
okay you see this command Helm read for
mini buffer does not seem to return I
mean whatever it returns is not
you know set into a variable or captured
or fed into another function
so that means
when Helm read for mini buffer is called
possibly it sets some other variable
then
the code later on will read that as
input
okay so uh read passes so okay
let's press song okay
and see
yeah so you see
basically now the command finished
uh you know it's doing log and uh
log and update and the reset Helm
pattern
and help me ignore errors and yeah so it
finished
Hemlock save maybe so maybe it
so let's look at Helm read from mini
buffer now
I don't get it because
you know when you make this call it
doesn't whatever it returns is not
captured or something
you know at least you should call you
know uh
you know apply a command
to the return value of Helm read from
mini book so I don't know so let's look
at how read for mini buffer
describe function
okay and go to it
here's a code now to region
and it's 100 lines okay
Helm read for mini buffer
um
now what is the
what is the uh argument let's see
prompt input pre-select resume key map
default history okay
so yeah like I said before at this point
it doesn't seems to be
you know pure functional programming
anymore because
it's okay let's continue reading the
code
read pattern with prompt prompt and
initial input input for pre-select
resume key map
default history see Helm okay
so it's telling you to read about Helm
with Helm buffer
uh
history time blinking matching parents
Helm log
ham resume
no I don't you see I don't get it where
is the code for pattern matching
you know when Helm presents you with
lots of choices where's the code that
actually filtered them out
because that's what we are trying to
look for
of course we are actually in the very
early stage of looking at Helm source
code
uh
so I'm not like trying to complain or
anything it's just that
we haven't found it yet
so when Helm execute action at once if
one
okay uh select window Helm mini buffer
with set the hook
Helm maybe update key map
so is there anyone like following along
with me do I make sense
oh yeah I
five concurrent users
okay so key let's continue reading the
helm source code
okay so wait let's let's magnify okay
continue reading the helm source code
uh Helm create If no candidate Helm Mt
buffer true okay ensure false update
when no candidates
okay help reset default pattern okay
so we might want to search for the word
pattern because that's
that's the word Helm uses you know it's
related to First imagine so here it is
okay so we found this
set Q Helm input
then Helm pattern
okay now where is ham pattern defined
okay there's just only three occurrences
in this function
so Helm pattern is apparently again
another uh global-ish variable used by
Helm so describe variable Helm pattern
there it is the documentation Helm
pattern
is a variable defined in Helm lib okay
value is empty documentation the input
pattern used to update the helm buffer
yeah
okay so apparently when you call you
know one of the helm commands so it's
not doing things in a functional in a
pure functional way uh probably because
of reasons for reasons because when you
call helm
you know how meta X
it
you know you have the mini buffer at the
bottom where you type something
uh for example p-h-r-a
but however it has another buffer
that updates as you type
and this buffer is not a mini buffer
so this is a user interface that's uh
different from gnu emacs because in
Google emacs the update happens in the
mini buffer
most of the time I get yeah there are
exceptions I guess but anyway so
what I'm saying is that so Helm creates
a these different buffer called
candidates
that updates as you type
so that means you know so that means on
one hand we have the helm
you know read from mini buffer that's
taking our
uh whatever user types on the other hand
so it
it probably you know it has to update
the other buffer but how is that done uh
how is that done so it must be
I don't know how I'm not sure how it is
done it must be some
some sort of like parallel
uh or concurrency uh going maybe yeah I
yeah I don't know so
so Helm pattern
Helm pattern so you know maybe it's
updating some
variable and uh another command is
actually
uh checking the variable whenever the
variable changes another command is
running in the background or something
that updates the Helms
candidate buffer
so possibly that's
how it is done you see uh Helm create
you know I don't know I'm just like kind
of guessing right now
so
you know because we just only we be only
we begin to look at the helm source code
so run with timer and the
yeah so I'm not actually seeing any
deeper level of function course that
you know that's kind of a Call of
something so I'm not saying seeing that
so you can see
Helm execute action at once if one
okay Helm display buffer okay
a Helm display buffer when this then
help this book display buffer hand
buffer
uh Helen buffer is another
Helm buffer is another
local variable
here
and because but it's it's not declared
local in this
function in this Helm read for mini
buffer therefore it must be another
Global variable uh for Helm mod so let's
look at that
describe variable Helm buffer enter what
did it say
uh
Helm buffer is a variable defining Helm
lib okay its value is uh as the risk
helm
okay so documentation but for showing
completions so that is the
you know that that is the candidate
buffer I think
okay so let's look at the file Helm live
Helm lib okay
Hamlet how many lines of occurs 1700
let's look at the helm directory
so we have been looking at helm.el
uh
and we saw the mention of Helm lips so
just how far down we have to look so far
we have not found
the fuzzy matching code like not at all
so how big is helm.el
wait uh widen
helm.el is
7400 lines okay
now okay so so now what we do
so we we try to track the function but
now we are at the point there is no more
true track and we still haven't found
where is the
code for first imagine so so I'm just
starting to look random so now let's
uh
least matching lines let's look at all
the functions in
in this file helm.el
let's see get a sense what they are
okay ham log
Helm gets Source held selection okay
okay so you can see
you see I I see the word here pass okay
pass Keys okay that's false Keys that's
not
passing user input
we are trying to find some kind of
word for pattern or regular expression
or First Imagine
this huge number of functions
oh there it is okay so
so here okay here
fuzzy match candidate
Helm fuzzy search pattern okay now we
actually we we have found
we have found uh the kind of functions
we are looking for I mean at least
closer we you know how much functions
let's let's let's go there
okay
matching candidates
yeah so we can see at this point that
Helm has a engine it implements its own
engine non-trivial engine to
to have the feature of you know you know
uh fuzzy match
uh you know and then you have also Helm
Flex match
so quite a lot lines of code thousands
probably
so here we have Helm Flex style score
okay so it has a scoring system
uh Flex scoring system scoring algorithm
of flex style in Emax 27 okay
so here we can see regular expression
mentioned
yeah so
at least in part it uses regular
expression to do the match
now another question I have is whether
it exclusively rely on regular
expression or not
no so what does that mean so if it
exclusively rely on regular expression
that means whatever Helm does with
firstly imagine it actually generate a
regular expression then use the regular
expression to do the match
but if it does not rely on regular
expression
then that means how must have written
its own
sort of passing and you know basically a
compiler you know a
a passer
and again that's not trivial
okay so so we so at least we have found
some of the let's look at the command
fuzzy match okay
so let's see firstly match Helm firstly
match candidate okay check if Helm
pattern
firstly matches candidate
oh
uh check if Helm pattern first he
matches candidate this function is used
with sources built with Helm Source sync
this function is used with
sources
okay build with Helm Source sync okay so
by Source it means like a bunch of
candidates
so I'm guessing this means for example
if you are using Helm MX then the
candidates are or
emacs commands
so that's pretty much you know building
emacs but sometimes you want to have
let's say completion of uh a new
language is words
so
emacs do not have you know them ready to
be available so you need to use you need
to use Helm Source sync kind of to
create the sources so I suppose that's
the case so if that's the case then then
you call him first image to
to get a match something like that
okay and it is using
um
okay so you see at least it you know at
least part of it is based on regular
expression because we see Helm first the
regular expression cache
and uh okay so it's a bit complex it
even create cash
okay so it does create cache
so another command Helm fuzzy search
pattern okay
same as Helm fuzzy match but four
sources built with Helm Source in buffer
okay
uh
let's look at next one okay and what's
the next one Helm School candidate for
Panton
a science score to candidate according
to Patton
okay score is calculated okay
I think I got a taste of
them
uh now
okay wait now
okay let's look at this one Helm First
Imagine D4 sort Function One
the transformer for sorting candidates
in firstly matching okay
it sorts on the display part by default
yeah so
so Helm you know when you call one of
the helm function command
has you type
it shows you know the updated result in
the candidate buffer but it also
reorders them
yeah he also reorders them on the Fly
so basically that's what this uh you
know that's why it's talking about sort
sorting candidates okay it sorts
candidates by their scores as calculated
by helmsco candidate for patent
set use real to noneal to sort on the
real part okay
okay yeah so we can see
the
the first image engine actually hum has
an engine of it
and it's non-trivial oh my God it's
truly
yeah then you have Helm first the
default highlight match so not only you
need to match them and show the result
but you also have to highlight them on
the Fly
so we have a giant uh
code base here to do these things okay
yeah so it looks looks like you see this
4 000 I mean 4500 lines
they are all
you know they are almost all about
matching how much function
Okay so
so then we have hell match from
candidate
okay how much from candidate
okay
then we have Helm compute matches Helm
compute matches what does that mean
start Computing candidate in source
Okay so
so far as we can see
you know my
um
you know what we found out before seems
to be true
that you know help me helm
you know when you call him read for mini
buffer
it sets a bunch of values like patterns
and uh
candidates and apparently this other
code must be checking it on the Fly
in parallel
I don't know for sure yet but
you know
um
okay then we also have Helm render
source
okay let me read the comments
hello anime again
uh
okay let's uh hold on a second let's
let's let's take a break for a minute
so you can see me here
hold on a second
Okay so
thank you
we need a drink
okay I'm so like I'm super busy right
now
this uh coating is not done yet
we uh we spend
almost an hour now looking at it
and it's not trivial let's see would it
be better
and if I do that
uh
okay you cannot see much anyway
so hello you look great from that angle
good morning good morning float
P net good morning sir I've enjoyed many
of your live streams but for the first
time I'm actually watching you live I I
live in
omia Sweden great fantastic yeah I
haven't been doing a live stream at over
you know during these hours so
so some of you guys will find it uh I
mean that's that's why you don't see me
live
now I have a little bit cross-eyed so
let me cover one of my eyes
so I can see better
so now let's go back to uh Helm shall we
let's go back to helm
so so far we we found that
you know we found that Helm has like so
much code
that does the
fuzzy matching
uh in helm
and let's look at the Helms function one
more time okay
uh
let's list all matching lines Define
so 290 functions essentially so you see
it's long so let's have a overview let's
see what they are
so Helm configuration
Helm multi-key different
Helm customize group Helm log Helm
action at nth
Helm save Helm log save maybe Helm debug
Helm print
Helm default directory
Helm add action to Source if
okay
have normalized field okay let's scroll
down
uh Helm normalized field to help get
current source
okay Helm pass Keys Helm resume Helm
empty Source Helm apply function from
source so these are all about you know
lots of them about source
and about setup and about log Helm log
ging stuff
now what exactly does hemlock do like
where does it log utility logging log
message Helm debug is
the Neo okay so it
messages are written to the helm debug
buffer okay so log is mostly from four
debugging purposes okay so we can ignore
Helm log you know so it turns out Helm
is a huge package I mean not trivial
because it
even writes its own you know debugging
and logging code yeah
huh
so so okay Hemlock we can kind of ignore
then
set sources uh set Source then
uh empty Source okay then Source blah
blah blah then resume
then
uh let's see
let's do this the way uh current
position
all the windows scrolling window in
Direction initialize then initialize
toggle suspend update
suspend update the backward no update
okay then clean up then song name blah
blah and let's go down
uh process candidate number limit
candidate get display process pattern
Transformer okay
so now get candidates
no okay so the part we are interested
the most is probably here fuzzy match
firstly search okay so keep that in mind
maybe that's the part I need to dig
deeper
match function yeah mostly it's over
here
then
okay then it says you know uh render
Source collect matches uh then Helm
update
update the display redisplay buffer
remove candidate cache insert header
okay so then output filter
okay then
display my line then how move whatever
that is okay that's moving closer a
bunch of Cruiser movement
uh Helm previous page next page uh okay
okay
so I think
yeah in large window they I think we
okay
now we have completed scanning
one of the source code file of helm
and that is helm.el
I believe that is the core or is it not
the core yes that's the core that's a
core of Helm package I mean meaning that
the
you know the the major features of
helmet are done by these files so we
have looked at all the functions defined
in this file and yeah we got a sense of
it and there are about 10 or so
functions that does related to First
Imagine okay
now what about so at this point you know
there are many you know choices where to
go depending on your style so for me so
we can
start to look there okay there are I
think three things we can start to look
one is to start to look at
you know uh to look in detail
what are these firstly matching
functions too and who is calling them
you know I think that will
get us to actually start to understand
how does Helm
uh
uh match candidates
you know so we are seeing a lot of
regular Expressions here
uh yeah so so that's one approach start
to dive in depth start to look at the
fuzzy functions in hell that's one
approach the other approach
is actually what we want to do
the other approach let me show you okay
so uh
you know our eventual goal is to be able
to modify all
select phases code to use uh to use helm
to use Helms first image matching system
instead of using I do completing read
so in that case
we can directly try to find you know try
to look for a function
that does that and just replace these
bits essentially replace this
uh the function called by something in
help something like that or maybe you
add two or more two or three more lines
so that we
we actually complete our goal but this
way it will be without understanding
understanding exactly how Helm does the
fuzzy match okay but that's a good
alternative
uh oh my God this is taking a long time
sit Ali
Daddy
okay so we already spent an hour God
this is taking uh
much longer than I thought
uh let's see
how many people are watching that I
think maybe I go offline and do it
I don't think uh this is uh interesting
so what what should we do so
so this firstly match functions okay
it's pretty deep okay
uh because
you know you for me to look at them
you have to understand a lot emac lists
and regular Expressions you know uh get
hash okay
yeah
um
so that's something I have to do
offline probably
then
so the other approach is just try is to
just try to find a function in helm
that does the equivalent of I do
complete read
okay so let's search for completing read
okay let's see if we can find that in
Helm source code
Okay so
so there
uh
maybe something similar I'm not sure
okay yeah it's let's just try random
okay so actually
so I think this is what we need to call
helm
sources Source prompt buffer
okay why don't we do this
let's just call this command
okay so for example uh let's see okay so
for example let's
copy our function copy it paste it so we
have two version two versions now in
this version let's say helm
select faces
with help okay
and in this version we are trying we are
just going to try to call Helms commands
uh by hack so right now I'm doing trial
and error coding you know like
not having a good understanding but
let's just try
okay
so so sources will be of course sources
will be phrases
and the prompt will be just the pick one
that's our prompt pick one
pick a phrase okay then buffer let's say
hmm
okay let's say uh academic phase buffer
okay so this
okay
then history we don't care for history
so
let's say Neo okay
so would that
I don't think that will work because the
helm function actually does not return
like we talked about before
it does not actually
like returns something for you
instead of instead of yeah it doesn't I
don't think it returns let's see
Helm is automated compile this function
okay so uh then uh that that mini buffer
to execute Helm okay
main function to execute helmet sources
here this is this like
that okay that keywords that that that
that that
extra local bar keywords are supported
see other keyword section below basic
keywords are the following
so this is one of the following list of
sources symbols whose value is a list of
sources yeah
okay so let's see oh a symbol
so it actually needs a Sim
a symbol or variable you know that's
that's a confusing part of emac means
it's not clear here whether it's a
symbol or
um
Amino code into the documentation it
should be a symbol so okay so let's say
symbol let's let's put symbol there
input initial input for mini buffer
prompts okay okay
okay okay okay
then obsolete
okay okay okay okay okay okay okay
so you see it does not mention anything
about return value
as we as a presumed before it doesn't
rely on
you know returning something it relies
on some kind of it updates something and
some other function is
you know looking
with it looking into it so let's just
try it okay so let's remove that then
okay yeah but but then but then how do I
um how do I get the value because I need
to get a value
you know the the user choose interface I
don't know uh
okay so so let's do set choices okay
okay let's just do that okay
uh eval the buffer
then call it select face Helm okay call
it
select
faces Helm okay Enter
it asked me to pick a phrase but I do
not see my candidates
and say t
yeah t-h-e no candidate
let's say e okay Enter
your own type of argument child or
stream
ciao string P Neo
so let's
call toggle debug on Arrow and now let's
call that command again enter pick a
phrase e enter
so here is the arrow
the error is
run type argument ciao string okay
insert new okay
so the arrow actually came from our own
code
this line
because apparently Helm returns nothing
it just return near so our user choice
is new so when you insert Neo that's the
arrow
yeah that's okay so again you know
I know this problem already
the helm
is not returning anything so how do we
actually get
I don't know how do you actually get you
know
let's try again you see it doesn't show
any candidates right
okay I'm I think I'm gonna stop
today's kind of
we looked at the helm source code for
for like close to 90 minutes and uh
we didn't go far
there is no tangible fruits
yeah so it's
um
yeah so at this point there's another
approach that is now I need to actually
start to
read carefully each one of each one of
these functions documentation I think
that would be the key
so I'm gonna start to read
in detail the documentation or the
source code of Helm MX
then Helm MX read the extended command
you know actually we should do that yeah
you know but overall
this is um you know for those of you who
do not have lots of coding experience
you know if you are a student for
example
uh this what we did today is actually
very typical day of uh coding job
you know even though we spend one hour
19 you know we spent 90 minutes it seems
we don't have any tangible results but
that's normal because you spend a lot of
time to read code to understand and
usually there's no documentation in you
know in real life coding
is you know most half of the time
there's no documentation you just read
the code and find and solve the problem
so if you know so if this is a normal
day job
I only started you know one you know
every day has eight hours I only you
know spend one hour on it
so given another two or three hours I'll
probably started to
understand and be able to use uh some
help functions to do the first Imaging
we wanted
Okay so
so now I think I'm going to stop but let
me look a little bit more okay so
let's see let me wrap up let's see what
else I want to say or do
um let's look chat okay let's see random
chat any comments you guys and thank you
George again for chikching twenty
dollars
fantastic and if you guys have not
already joined saw Discord okay
uh joined this because I Discord
uh you know lots of interesting people
uh there
um
so let's play with my camera let's see
if I can
[Music]
if we can get
a better vantage point
this is night coding
uh oops
Okay so
for a change you know uh so let's see
hello hello anyone still here five
people watching two likes
okay I think that's it for today so
I'm kind of annoyed a little bit annoyed
that we
you know I didn't
I did you know I didn't expect it to be
this complex
you know Helm has you know like the
entire you know that's what Helm is for
it has basically the whole thing is
about
uh pattern matching
let's put this on
yeah the whole thing
it's very interesting though because
firstly pattern matching firstly pattern
matching is one of the very useful thing
that began to become fairly popular
about 10 years ago
because
you started to see lots of applications
using that and I presume they are quite
a lot libraries doing that
first imagine you know there are several
types I haven't studied them in detail
for example there's Flex matching
then Helm's way I don't know if there's
a proper word for Helms
way of First Imagine then there is I do
you know I do uses a different way
uh you know different from
so
so if I if our jar if if you know my job
basically my job is to you know I need
to do this
for a project I need to write a
basically a command to
uh you know academic phases to to choose
the academic phase and I want to be able
to use Helm's way of
of fuzzy matching
so that's what I need to do
so like I said before you know one way
is just actually you know since I'm a
nerd I'm interested about First Imagine
to dive into detail see
exactly what type they are you know
actually we can actually let's look at
Wikipedia okay
let's see what Wikipedia say about fuzzy
matching
now uh is there an article on Wikipedia
approximate stream matching okay that's
uh
I suppose that's a term in computer
science approximate stream matching
often colloquially referred to as fuzzy
stream matching it's fuzzy string
searching is a is the technique of
finding strings that match a pattern
approximately rather than exactly the
problem of approximate string matching
is typically divided into two sub
problems finding approximate substring
matches inside a given string and
finding dictionary strings that match
patterns approximately
finding dictionary strings that
that match the pattern of sharks
approximately what does that mean I
don't know
the okay the closest of a match is
measured in terms of the number of
primitive operations necessary to
convert the string into a an exact match
okay this this number is called the edit
distance okay so it's starting to get
become Technical and precise
uh problems formulation in algorithms
okay
okay and one line versus online versus
offline okay
so actually so this is
um
yeah so this is actually a pretty common
problem you can see there are quite a
few
algorithms
for example plagiarism detection needle
ham Wilson algorithm okay so you got
quite a few locally sensitive hashing
okay
uh okay then then you have this article
string metric
in mathematics in computer science a
stream metric
is a metric that measures distance
between two text string okay okay so
yeah so there are quite a few different
way to measure to determine whether two
words are
you know uh it's a match or not you know
in other words
this is a kind of a more formal way of
of saying
the difference of pattern you know first
imagine used in I do mod and used in
helmet they are different why because
they are using two different string
Matrix you know the way they measure uh
distance
so
but I don't know if there is a name for
the precise algorithm that uh that Helm
uses or I do
and I don't necessarily expect one
because you know that's the real life
coding you don't necessarily
you know you just make it work uh okay
so
okay that's it for today
uh do we have any more comments we do
so
okay a keyboard question then we're
gonna shut down okay
uh I'm thinking about getting the food
pedal for the Kinesis Advantage okay I
know it's pretty expensive but would you
recommend it if cost was not an issue
okay I'm gonna answer that then Campbell
hey hey Campbell
Campbell button great to see you here
Campbell button is a Emax this expert
actually camber button is a blender
developer for for for quite a few
for many years right so camera button is
a
you know one of the blender
uh country contributor which is written
in C I think C or C plus plus
so can can be a button so have you so
Cambria says by the way for your
information emacs 27 has new functions
string distance maybe of Interest okay
that yes that would be that would be of
interest let's let's see so finally we
have someone
let's check
fantastic okay well wow in C code look
string distance is a building function
in C source code fantastic so string
distance string one string two uh
optional byte compare return okay return
levance 10 distance okay
so this is useful in case
if I end up you know if I end up not
wanting to use a Helm then I'm gonna
this will be useful
also we haven't looked at the I I do
source code yet so again that's gonna I
don't know how long that's gonna take
but this is like real live coding that's
uh
fantastic so camp and Campbell is a C
and C plus plus in Python expert great
okay now let me answer the keyboard the
question then that's it for today okay
so if you like my stuff again you know
you just go to my website
uh you know because uh
emacs tutorial or emacs you know today
we're talking about emac Beast so I did
a kind of tutorial I did I did lots of
videos uh by now so you can patreon me
or buy my emacs tutorial practical emacs
tutorial okay uh you know I teach you
emac this from the ground up or the the
most basic practical ones so you can get
up to speed very fast
in a week you'll learn all the essential
the most essential commands and what
they mean
okay thank you so let's let's go to
keyboard okay let's talk about now
keyboard is much easier to talk about
than than than code okay so so uh the
question is about the the question is
about
the pedal okay I don't use pedal myself
for this one okay
and this is fairly expensive
and let me okay so the first thing you
want to know is that so I have a review
here actually I did a video kind of long
time ago
so I did a review of this pedal so the
first thing you want to know is that
this is not for you know most people
will think okay one of the pedal will be
control the other one is the old and the
other one can be shipped something like
that so you are thinking the pedal is
going to be modifier Keys No okay you
cannot do that
the by default the Kinesis around Elite
2 foot pedal do not allow you to do that
you cannot set any of the pedal keys to
be modified okay so what does it do well
they do for example you can set them to
any key that's not modifier for example
they can be left click
you know Mouse click left click right
click middle click or or or pressing F1
F2 things like that okay or caps lock
turn on caps lock things like that so
you cannot use them for modifier keys
for the pedal why there's a good reason
for that too so by default as far as I
know you cannot do that
uh possibly you can if you hack it I
don't know but by default you cannot use
the
the foot pedal for modifier Keys why why
it's a good thing because you know
there's a story where there's a kid
who said one of the foot pedal for push
to talk when you if you are a gamer you
know you press the key to then you can
your microphone is on you can chat then
we are done you you D you leave it then
you know your microphone is shut
so he got used to that then one day he's
driving and talking to his mom then he
does a push to chat hey Mom we are you
know you you know what happens next you
know there's crash you know so so it's a
so be careful of that so I wouldn't Reco
I you know in fact I
even if it can I wouldn't recommend it
because and I don't think it's a good uh
efficiency in terms of efficiency
because imagine you you you stamp on on
a pedal then
you press the key you know it's not very
efficient
as I said before I rather recommend like
you see my keyboard before in this you
know just have lots of marker keys but
foot pedal is still useful because I
have it I use it for example I have set
up so that one is a previous application
uh like like I can show you
um
I don't have it set up now but
but if you can see my keyboard
okay so one of the pedal is previous uh
previous window okay so previous windows
so if I go here previous window previous
window you know it can be some window
here
previous window you see very useful
and the other is Max screen okay like
that key
and the other one I forgot about the
other one is
but uh
[Music]
yeah but that's what they are I mean so
that's what I use for them for uh you
know Max window previous window toggle
toggle Max window and the other one is
the meta X oh yeah Emax metax is very
useful you you it's possible you can set
them to be codes so one of them uh I
think I had meta X so that's my
recommendation you know whether you like
that or not it's up to you
okay thank you guys
uh thank you guys for watching bye
yeah okay bye