good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show today is July 17th 2019 today's
Wednesday and now it's eight o clock ten
after eight I'm ten minutes late
and today we are going to talk about
random subjects when random topics
something about keyboards something
about programming okay and let us begin
then something about keyboard and
something about programming sucking on
this like you suck your mom's tits
that's and okay so keywords in
programming so let's go to keyboard
block I'm gonna show you something about
okay programming and let's go to
keyboard okay so let's go to keyboards
let me adjust the windows so you can see
properly properly versus improperly we
want to we want things to be proper so
keyboard so you got this window and then
let's pop this out come on in people to
people so keyboard we're going to talk
about keyboard and programming random
topics and basically I'm covering what's
new
you know something new and interesting
then we will talk about it so first stop
is keyboard
worst Apple design okay let's look at
let's have a look at that
worst Apple design okay you know since
Steve Jobs Steve Jobs is really truly a
great guy he's a I mean I don't mean
necessarily a great guy but in but he's
great in that he is a innovator he's a
visionary he is one of the true
visionary like there are some true
artists for example trains and David
Bowie they are true artists in that word
you know in the sense of the world the
the fundamental sense of the word
artists they create art they are
creative David Bowie and Prince for
example not Madonna for Madonna for
example no and today's pop you know
artists not none of them pretty much you
know so but Steve Jobs is a true
visionary
he is an innovator you know visionary
and but since he died now it's ten years
now since he died Apple ID you know it
seems to me they are just going downhill
look at these Apple designs you know
they got these stung goes you know
okay tongue goes down goes ooh
ask me about my tongue goes you know so
what you know and also one of the most
insulting thing is that you know Apple
create invented or popular popularized
the magnetic charge you know you you
power you know magnetic coupler you know
I don't know how you call that you know
basically it's magnetic so that when you
trip over the wires
it doesn't pour your laptop's down
that's truly you know one of the great
invention but they'd be moved at imagine
you know they
this great invention I think they
patented it so that other people cannot
make it but they removed it in the past
few years it must be four years by now
five you know so they removed that
magnetic power think you know what are
they thinking what what what what you
know since Steve Jobs died you know
extreme idiots then you then you started
to have this tango thing you know let me
tell you why this happens okay I've been
using well I was a fan of Mac since 1991
my first Mac is Mac - si I paid three
thousand total for it you know I think
$1000 for the monitor monitor two
thousand dollars for the computer and
back then the the monitor that $1000
was it two thousand I forgot which is
which but anyway that $1000 monitor was
the best well kind of the best at a time
you know 1992 or 91 and you know it's
Apple RGB you know color monitor and
it's got how many colors 256 something
like that and it's you know how many
pixels resolution it's 640 by 480 is 640
by 480 so today today that that monitor
would be how much would that be
you know today that monitor would be
smaller than this panel you will be yeah
the width is about 640 yeah about this
wide maybe a bit smaller and 480 so it's
a you know so that was in 1992 and that
monitor is a thousand something dollars
anyway let's look at Apple again so I've
been using Apple you know I was an Apple
fan since 1990 since 1980s like you know
you have to that like you know like
today you have news right you know back
then you have 1991
internet just began you don't really
have websites uni there's no website yet
but the internet begin you have used
user groups you have Usenet and you have
what was I going to say you have oh yeah
so you know like today
whenever Apple had a new product or
Microsoft create a new product Oh Google
you know Chromebook or whatever you know
you know it on Twitter or on all the
social media networks you know everyone
is like talking about it
Oh especially the phone you know today
it's phone it's not about laptops it's
like Oh Apple or Samsung created s8 or
whatever you know phone oh these
features this is what CPU what speed you
know that you know if but back then you
don't have internet so what do you do of
course people still still follow all
these news but you have magazines you
have like for example Mac word PC would
Mac user magazines like that let me show
you some Mac users okay Mac user Mac
word and PC word for example these are
some of the magazines back then so that
is it
PC word and you can see they don't have
they should show some covers yeah like
this one Mac word so back then you have
these magazines which you know every you
know they they are monthly they come out
every month and you know they detail
every news every latest Apple product
you know the spec you know what you know
then technology how it works you know
that so and so and Mac user Mac user is
another magazine Mac user here anyway so
I you know I follow this magazines my
point is that you know I ping you know
as a Mac fan like today you know you
follow all the news like you know
some Mac fans for example they know
every detail like they can name every
product model every year what you know
what's new what change you know what's
the difference between this year's and
last year that I get big and tell you
you see that every day almost on the you
know
Twitter's stuff but back then we have
that we do that too you have to remember
but it's like magazines and until 1997
then it's Internet you know more and
more Internet so so but what's my point
my point is you know all this energy you
do it every day that you like you do
this every you know every in you know
constantly every every week you know you
know every detail of apples moves you
know what's new what new product they
have any rumors you know one big thing
about mag is everything like rumor is a
big thing they people wants to know what
Apple is doing you know what's coming
out in next year what's Apple's plan
anyway so you look you you know so back
then you have this user interface debate
you know back in 1991 Windows this you
know there's pretty much no user
interface I mean no graphical user
interface on Windows anyway I digress a
lot so anyway let's get back so Apple so
let me get to the point I want to say
buddy so Tong goes you know Apple
through throughout 1990s and throughout
I would say even 2000s when Steve Jobs
is around they are truly innovative ok
they created the other first they are
the first computer to have USB for
example the first computer to have a CD
drive the first computer to have a mouse
I mean not not necessarily the inventor
but the first consumer level you know
they they produce the stuff for the
masses for everyone you know they to
ever the mount so Mouse graphical user
interface
you know you
USB fire firewire you know whatever you
know the ports you know the latest
technology for the ports Apple was the
first and and it you know typically
usually after two or three years like
typically after three years then the PC
or window machines started to have it
you know because because Apple made sure
apples began yet and and and made sure
that you know it is here to stay
and the rest of the industry follow
Apple so Apple is truly innovative you
know they the desktop publishing the
graphical user interface the graphical
user interface that's immense and as you
know in 2008 Apple made the iPhone
popular and before that it was the ribs
you know rip music the iPod you know
Apple truly made it popular to the
degree that the industry accepted you
know it becomes the everyday thing it's
all because of Apple you know even
though there are stuffy small expensive
and so on so I got seven people watching
say hi okay and any comments just posted
okay I like that to post your thoughts
so Apple so Apple is very innovative you
know the graphical user interface that's
tremendous and window do catch up you
know they so Apple began then with the
window you know Microsoft started to
have Windows you know windows with a
graphical user interface in the mouse
you know but you know and so anyway so
Apple so yeah so Apple has a history of
innovation but you see this in
innovation is not like you know
innovation is different from you know
let's just use whatever the latest
technology okay that's different from
that innovate successful innovation like
Steve Jobs has done for Apple and for
the world in
in a sense for everyone is that you
don't you don't just like find out you
know what's the latest technology and
create something people don't you know
people do not necessarily people don't
care about your technology people don't
care about new technology and if you
press on it people usually do not want
any change they don't want change okay
they they don't want any take new tech
like oh you have to do it this way this
is noon they don't want it so successful
innovation it takes quite a few things
you know Steve Jobs he has a talent for
it first of all you have to be you have
the idea and you know something it must
be done in a practical way that it you
know is something people want
that's what Apple did that's why I Poe
is successful okay something Steve Jobs
created something people want I mean
close my window blinds there so that's
that's that that's a first thing then
you know you create something people
want you know you by using technology of
course you know and but also you must
have great this is necessary condition
you must have great marketing skill you
know it's kind of like a businessman you
have to have that skill you know you
know as a marketing skill and of course
the willingness to do it for example we
you know I'm a programmer I'm a nerd
most of us you know allowed my followers
you guys are also programmers nuts and a
lot nerds you don't have you don't have
marketing skill you know you don't have
you know you don't have business you
know you don't have persuasion skills
and also you may not even want to you
know like if you ask yourself would you
be you know would you do that if you're
gonna be very rich but it means you have
to change your personality you cannot be
like you cannot be your engineer type
you know concern about truth or
facto precision or you know and and
interest pay attention to Sciences you
cannot do that if you know because each
person you know and you know are you
willing to you know sometimes make a lie
you know so that you make a sell you
know things like that you know you may
not this may not be your it's not
necessarily like whether you have the
skill or not but rather you have to have
the you know they say the the phrase is
you have to be willing and able you know
able is you know the ability you do you
have the ability to be put to be a
Salesman that's one thing the other
thing is are you willing you know so
that you know but so Steve Jobs yeah so
he's you know he's a great creative
innovator you know entrepreneur
entrepreneur that's what they say
so they created so so Apple created
though this innovation but since Steve
Jobs died ample you know it seems to me
much of the innovation as far as I see
it's gone it's like so so what has Apple
became since Steve Jobs died you know it
became you know it's it just became it
became a company who follows fashion
fashion and latest technologies such as
this such as this iPod touch bar nobody
wanted you know nobody needed nobody
wanted it's just a piece of technology
they think it's cool
that's what you know Apple since Steve
job died you know created you know
things like this touch bar and also this
their keyboard the butterfly keyboard is
one of the worst you know it's it's
worsening first of all it the technology
the keyboard the product is no good
people don't like it you know it's like
so thing you don't have you know you
don't have depth to you know you don't
you cannot you know you don't have this
you know when you press a key you you
have certain satisfied
action you know you press something down
but you don't have that on the butterfly
keyboard that's one thing so it's a bad
product but other the other thing is
that Apple becomes sinister you know
they do always you know evil ways to for
example the butterfly keyboard they make
it so that it is impossible to replace
it I mean for example a key is broken
and it the key is easily broken when I
just get into it things like that it you
know it's not to repeat or doesn't work
anymore and it is not possible to
replace a single key like you have to
replace the whole keyboard and Apple
made sure that nobody can sell their you
know into it except them you know
because they want to make money they so
they become very evil and this this
incident is very popular it's everywhere
you can read you know articles about
that
so butterfly keyboard is crap and you
know the rumor has it that the next year
awesome
you know this year I don't know when the
next Mac is is not going to have the
butterfly keyboard anymore they are
going to have you know they are gonna do
away with it
so anyway butterfly keyboard is bad you
know this Apple touch part crap nobody
wants this and you know and look at this
how you know you know impossible
you know fantastically idiotic can't be
Apple you know Apple created this you
know this situation and look at this
Mouse you know this is this all happened
since Steve Jobs died and then the Dongo
situation you know
so Apple became just a company that
follows fashion and using latest
technology
you know he they lost they lost the
vision the you know the the practical
vision of Steve Jobs
so that's Apple it's very bad so Apple
so what's up dice so
comments questions type it okay type
with type type type it so Apple is very
bad now let's talk about okay this news
if you are using Kinesis which is what
I'm using okay I need to show you this
look this is my keyboard and let me show
you slowly you turn around and you see
me then my keyboard this is my keypad
it's a number the numerical keypad but I
use it as a function function keypad for
example I can for example I go over
there I press about it let me see I
press the button it's closed
you see press abandoned closed and I
press this button to reopen last closed
reopen as close you see this is
fantastic I press this button switch
left switch right you see left left left
left left left you see right right right
right right
close that close that you see what curse
that you see fantastic and then okay
this folks for example this page is too
small I enlarge it I shrink it you know
in all shrink it's all one finger
operation that's the thing I talked a
lot about in my keyboard articles you
can you can see logic principle of
explosion that's fantastic topic a good
morning clean deck having seen you for a
while what do you think about Linux
integration into Windows what can I say
I mean I suppose it's very good you know
for Microsoft because because then you
have this operating system that you can
play games or you can you know do
coding open-source oriented coding you
know so it's good for people and it's
good for Microsoft because they are
going to make more money but on the
other hand as we know as we likely agree
we don't like big corporations because
Microsoft they don't give a flying [ __ ]
about open source or the goodness or
whatever ethical issues their goal is
just to make money and you know so and
they created this so you know it's good
for them and I suppose about people we
all start to use it instead of Linux
like you don't you don't need you know
it's like it's like gradual like once
you try you know maybe today you tried
Microsoft you know Lee Linux on
Microsoft Windows if you find it that it
works fine then gradually you just don't
use your Linux box anymore like next
year you got a new computer you thought
ah I'm too lazy you know so it's it's a
way that microscopy
you can say that it's a way Microsoft
take away Linux users yes
yeah I talk about a lot you know let me
finish this so but by the way if you
don't already know I'm you know I I was
open source of free software foundation
phonetic back then but not today I think
the open source and free software they
are no good they they become ideology
and they are harmful I just like to I
want to mention that because anyway so
that's what I think about Microsoft with
Linux integration I haven't used it I so
I don't know much about it I don't have
money to you know I don't have money
today so I don't know I cannot you know
try stuff for the hope I have a new
computer so anyway so so let's stop and
and by the way that reminds me someone
else asked me a question about ago Docs
like what do I think of Oh
so I'll talk about that let me open that
just in case I forgot keypads let's see
often is it fun keyboards Do It Yourself
there so someone want ask me what do I
think about ago ducks you know some of
these topics I talked about several
times in the past but you know I have a
video every day and not everyone watch
it of course and you know but the
interesting thing is that you know you
add you know it almost any any singer
performer comedian you know or lecturer
you know like you teach calculus or
whatever almost any one of them
celebrity they have to basically like
when they do a tour they interview they
have to answer the same question
repeatedly you know like before I
thought about this I thought it's a
waste you know they'd say it's a waste
of resources like that like it should be
like you say something once then
everyone can you know for example watch
that video oh you have written about
some issue once an essay you publish it
somewhere then everyone you know so that
question is you know done for once for
but then I thought that's not a case
because actually in practice in real
life and in fact it's a it's a normal
situation you know just because look at
look at look at teachers you know like
for example calculus teachers at
university college you know their job is
to repeat the same thing every year
because every year you know why why
because every year they are new people
freshman you know so called fest
rapprochement in college meaning first
year college students they don't I
learned that they don't they don't call
it freshmen anymore today yes since like
three or five years ago because of
course you can have you can have a word
with men yet you know so you have to so
you so what do you call you can you call
fresh people you know so here's a
we are verging on to linguistics so if
you cannot use the word Fishman then
what you gonna say you know so you have
to say fresh people but that's that's
wrong you know you can you know it's it
doesn't sound right fresh people so you
just say instead you just say first-year
students I suppose that's what they in
sophomores affirm or is second-year
student the college student you know
that's an English word for a second year
college student and that word is also
very interesting you know suffer more so
what what does it mean suffer more you
know where does the word come from it
came from basically it means say my
morons okay so let's look up let's go -
lets go - okay we digress a lot which is
Startalk shows SOP oh my ear lets the
let's go to etymology okay sorry team
ology linka phi and show in browser so
we have etymology of Safa more I spelled
it wrong so it's not going to work I
don't think yeah not fun so so how do
you spare us a form or anyone s OPH Oh
mo re let's try that yeah that is
correct so so etymology linka Phi okay
and make a paragraph showing browser and
the quick let's look at the etymology of
Safa more 1680s student in a second year
of University study literally arguer
altered the from humor 1650 from South
film okay okay
archaic variant form of sufism oh okay
and probably by influence of a folk
etymology directive a derivation from
Greek suffer wise more
okay wise morons wise for the original
reference might be the might be the
dialectic exercises that formed a large
part of education in the middle years
and acts at Oxford and Cambridge two of
the [ __ ] universities in UK you know the
elite universities like today's Harvard
that they are corrupt I don't know about
Oxford and Cambridge but I know that in
USA Harvard and many of the other
colleges are utterly corrupt anyway
they're there you have a sophomore the
etymology of sophomores okay so why is
fools or argue oh okay so altered from
okay so it's either argue oh it came
from the word argue argue oh oh with
some traces to wise
fool so anyway suffer more you know that
that's what so we're talking about
freshmen and sophomores get back to
what's the previous topic what is the
previous topic
so anyone so we were talking about we
were talking about how how Apple sucks
and I go ducks we gonna talk about uber
dogs we gonna talk about how long have I
been talking 30 minutes okay that's okay
I need to green deck you talked about
keyboard yeah we were talking about
keyboard we were then we talked about
Microsoft and Linux integration then we
talked about oh yeah so repetition
yeah repetition in answering questions
like sometimes I got the same question
answered you know asked of me many times
I did some time answer that before
somewhere and then I was thinking you
know why does this happen it's like as a
nerd you know it's very inefficient it
should be you know answer once then
everyone can see it but then I was
thinking about the you know the nature
of human life you know in fact that this
repetition this repetition very
inefficient you know as a nerd you think
of it it was very extremely inefficient
because you know this repetition is
actually the the heart of life it's the
it's the process you know think of it of
it as a process instead you know not not
as an engineering thing you know because
you know like for example the calculus
teachers you know in colleges they have
to repeat the same thing every year
because every year there are new people
you know people younger people get born
and they don't know nothing they have to
start from the beginning and then older
every everyone else gets older and older
and you die
so there is this process going on you
see this is like
this is you know this is you know this
is the condition of how the this is the
condition of the world so this
repetition is actually not that odd
thing so anyway so let's talk about so
that's about that you know so this you
know some of these I covered yesterday
these keyboards and but today let me
show you this is a new okay this is this
is the main thing let's talk about this
then we're going to talk about yoga Docs
and FML Mouse yes mmm Oh mas let me let
me talk about mmm Oh mouse just a little
bit okay mmm all mouse is fantastic
because I have this one actually let me
show it to you hold on a second
it's all tangled up in this pile of
things
so you see so I got this one I'm sure I
should plug it in because then your
light up you know you see all the
buttons light up you know so that's I
don't use it now because let me explain
why so so this multi button you know
this got twenty buttons I got so this
one is got twenty buttons and it's great
but there is so you can you know so that
you know this is great some some people
now you know the programmer idiots you
know those people who espouses Linux VI
kind of all terminal or even Emacs
people you know they they are kind of
idiots they you know they tell you like
every day is like oh don't use math
don't use maths and and you know but
they are not efficient you know I tell
you anyway because for example you know
okay they are a lot topics you know I I
have to talk about I'll explain but
sometimes I just 6 X I just skip some of
the details because otherwise you know I
talk for 10 100 hours so anyway so this
this mouse it's great that you know the
gaming you know this so code they call
this cat massive multiplayer online
gaming mouse ok typically that's what
this this mouse is called mmm Oh Mouse
like massive massive multiplayer online
game mouse in this mouse you know so
it's you know so first of all Mouse is
in many cases Mouse is more efficient
than keyboard okay for example if you
want you if you have a geometric object
or if you are viewing a keyboard in 3d
you want to rotate rotate
3d or for example you want mass is most
efficient you know it's just because why
because let me tell you the mathematical
gist of why okay
the logical gist because a keyboard
mathematically a keyboard what you have
is basically on and off that's it that's
the whole essence of your control
keyboard long and off and you have many
of them so at any time you can like turn
it down or turn it off
that's what keyboard keys you know
keyboard keys are all about it's you
know meanwhile a mouse is such that you
how do you say how do you call this how
do you say this how do you describe it a
mouse
the the phone you know if you look at it
from a math essence kind of weight as an
input system the mouse is that you it's
not just on and off you know like
keyboard on or off you have like hundred
100 different onion off you know but
it's not like that but rather you have a
continuous variable signal okay so so
think of it as a okay so we think of
it's like a two dimensional continuous
variable signal okay so it's so so think
of it is one two hundred so you have two
two parts each one is from zero to 100
and it can be any any number in between
and at any time you have these two
numbers sent through the computer when
you use the mouse so so that in so in
this sense you can see it's the data
from the mouse is far more rich than the
keyboard okay and and anyway most
provides continuously variable speed
variation input device okay first plus
you have buttons on and off you have you
know at least you know two or three or
five or more
so anyway the mouse you know let me talk
about that okay I discussed this in
detail which will be at mouse okay I
think that's under the mouse section let
me show you the articles about the deep
about input systems what they mean
mathematically somewhere here okay and
by the way so here we can also see track
boss they are very interesting because
it's similar to Mouse but however the
the control and variation it's different
you know
so here are the track boss but there is
one thing I want to show you that is
about where is it so let me go track
boss
let's see track wars typewriters
miscellaneous ok let's go to
miscellaneous so any comments questions
type it okay so okay so you have this
space navigator device which is very
good but that's and space navigator
device came from this thing I mean this
is this is its pre pre pre desert you
know it came before it so it was a boy
it's like a ball but it's it's not a
trackball though the ball doesn't spin
or move rather the bow is just you know
it's just Jojo basically essentially
it's a joystick but in such a way that
the joystick can be poured up and pushed
down and it can also be twisted so
that's what this is and it is used by
NASA
I think the first application is by NASA
you know is a space spaceships and stuff
and then eventually they became you know
they came down to this phone but anyway
the reason I'm mentioning this device is
because
because I know from this device I can oh
yeah this Arco this is the article I
want to talk about remember we were
talking about the keyboard versus mouse
and you know I'm trying to explain in
terms of math you know logical you know
exactly this in terms of the signal and
stuff why they are different you know
and why Mouse is more efficient for many
many tasks Mouse is just more efficient
meaning you can do it faster with Mouse
and less string you know fingers your
muscle strength you know so for example
I mentioned for rotating 3d object if
you are a cat user you know you do you
know you do drafts of you know Oh
cameras so if you to game design 3d
character design or movies animations
you know you need to use many of the CAD
software and you need to rotate objects
and in in Mouse is you know just is a
proper tool in other words you know you
wouldn't want to you know hammer now
using a screwdriver that's what happens
with these Linux idiots and them you
know the the Imperator in those facts
like the oh I want to control everything
by the keyboard you know this and rat
poison and you know these window
managers Linux you know this this type
of people but remember I'm not I'm not
totally dissing I'm not dissing keyboard
okay I'm not at all in fact keyboard is
you know that is why I have all these
shortcuts you know a single key press
you know what I'm talking about is get
rid of none thinking those you know
common pop myth you know that in these
elite geeks mind such as another great
example is they want to they want to
tell you to swap your caps lock key with
control key okay that's one of the most
idiotic thing don't do that unless
unless you are using a laptop keyboard
then okay that's a good solution if you
are not you
a laptop keyboard and you should not
okay laptop is the primary way to get
you repetitive strain injury okay so
don't use a laptop keyboard if you are
not using a laptop keyboard you should
never set caps lock to control don't do
that you know I have a lot of articles
you can just search saw the caps lock
control you will find it I'm not going
to talk about that today because you
know because I beg digress or a lot but
anyway in this article i disgust you you
know you can read it and you'll see the
differences between the input systems
from the point of view like from the
point of view of what signal what kind
of signal and the the properties of the
signal they are sending they are
creating for example we talked about
keyboard which is basically onion off
you know you just have 100 kind of
parallel on and off so that's that's in
terms of signal that's what you got
keyboard and mouse you have you know two
basically two vectors variable weight
vectors and you know and and then what
about track track pad you know like
today a very popular track pad or what
about a trackball how they differ then
you read this article you know I try to
explain I try to give a sense of how
they differ what about a joystick you
know for you know you have a joystick so
how you know how does it differ from a
mouse I mean first of all for most
people how they differ you can feel it
you know you don't need the explanation
you know you know it especially if you
have a gamer you probably have a lot
opinion so a mouse is better for you
know first-person shooters you know
joystick or the controller so-called Kim
you know game pads controller those are
inferior you know but but so most people
know you know they know which is you
know good for Mouse they know which is
good you know Kibo is the best when is a
mouse best when it's a joystick
Joystiq is best when you for example you
know for example when you play arcade
games you know pac-man you know those
statistic and in other places as well so
what I'm so for the one I'm trying to
say is that you see these different
input devices now we talked about the
signals they send you know how you know
so so that aspects that that aspect the
signal they transmit you know and how
fast they can you know what kind of
signal that aspect tell you a lot about
a suitability of a input device that's
one thing though that's not all that's
only like half of the thing the other
thing is like how you can control those
signals for example keyboard let's talk
about keyboard you know remember
keyboard keys are just one on and off
okay on and off
now let's say let's focus on just one
single key on and off now suppose you
want to do it hundred times a second you
see as a human we cannot do it you know
like when you play arcade games you know
he used to like we have to press the
buttons like you know do we try everyone
tries you know but you know as humans
you cannot do hundred times a second you
know you cannot but on the on the mouse
for example let me let me show you an
example okay here is what you can do
that you see this wheel this mask wheel
this mask we all can it can you know for
example let me show you let me you know
go all the way up
can you hear you know I'm just for
example let me show you the my mouse
you see no it's quickly you see I just
keep spin you know like doing that that
way is far faster then you can you know
hit a key let's see for example let's
see space okay let's see you know see
yeah you know I try to do it of course
you can also hold it down today but
that's a different thing
you know that's different that's a
software interpretation when the keys on
keeps long it just keeps sending it but
you know we are talking about physically
you know you cannot do that much but
however if I said my mouse such that
when I spin a wheel I don't know if you
can hear it you know this way you can do
like far more far more sending of
signals then you know pressing it off so
that's the difference you see even
though both of them are simply one in
zeros that's an example but anyway so
what were we talking about okay so six
people so guys as I'll say something
okay so you know so are we so let me let
me finish talking about that thing that
let me fix that so you can just don't
get screwed up okay so this way okay so
let's get back to the we were talking
about 3d math models of 3d input control
okay so you have you have the signals
you can look at this what kind of
signals what you know how this you know
how you know that you can look at this
at the signals point of view and you can
also look at the physical control how
the human hand is able to control with
respect to the signal it sends so anyway
that's that's the that's about different
input devices
you know Mouse joystick trackball
trackpad you can look at all of them in
keyboard you can look at all of them
from this perspective you know then you
can see you can easily see which one is
you know you can see that they are very
different and certain suitable for
certain tasks
for example another example is paint
drawing you know drawing tablet for
example you see I have the drawing
tablet here you know I can again start
to move move my mouse oops I need to put
it back okay so you see that's a that's
a paint a black tab you know so if you
draw you know it makes a huge difference
you know because you know so so what I'm
saying is that you see you can see that
this is about it's about the signals but
that's you know as far as signal goes
this is very similar to Mouse you see
this tablet pen digital paint is very
similar to Mouse but different how so
what what is it different because with a
mouse you see the point a must
it cannot jump from place to place it
cannot jump you see the you look at my
mouse pointer it must always smoothly
move you know it forms a path but with a
digital pen I hope so I made you know
with a digital pen you can like make it
jump to faces you know so so that that
is the different different that's one of
the difference that's a difference on
you know as far as the signal is
concerned you know it's one of the
difference you know that the other
difference is that with a pen pick
because the human the the physiology you
know it allows you to control the
pointer much more finely you know you
can write intro with this but it's very
hard to do with them the mouse you see
so you can see so there are two aspects
one is the signal you know kind of the
mathematical aspect of what kind of
signal how can't jump okay and not can
you change speed you know things like
that on the other hand is the shape of
the input device how they relate to the
human physiology that also matters
significantly and that is a major
difference between digital pain and the
mouth so trackball okay for example so
actually I don't eat we talked about
actually so we so we were talking about
the you know something you know the
differences between input devices okay
let's get back to the multi player
gaming mouse okay the massive MMO Mouse
this is great okay the MMO Mouse is
great but one problem you know it's
great because it's so many buttons you
know so many buttons that allows you to
let's plug this in so that you can see
the so you can see it lights up yay so
you see let's see you see it lights up
and it's let's see if I can change it
yeah you see yeah that's nice red it's
red blue white kind of purplish white so
you see that's my that's this this mouse
MMO Mouse is this is great one by the
way okay bye-bye it from my Amazon key
you go buy it now so it so multi-button
fantastic but but this here's a problem
you know it's not exactly wise it's a
depending on how you use it you know so
if you are a heavy user you know
basically the point is that the button
is not as easy to press as the keyboard
key you know big key it's a bit more
harder okay harder to press so even
though when you are using your mouse you
can use the buttons to control actually
I should you know so you don't have to
lift your hand like for example if I
want to close window so I'm you know if
we some of you are browsing I'm looking
around you know quick oh you know
looking around then suppose I want to
close the window then you have to
no suppose you want to do copy and paste
you know so you select then you move
your hand back to the keyboard then
control see they move to the back to the
mouse then you go here and control V so
you have to switch your hand for mouse -
keyboard often but we've had multiple
button mouse you don't have to anymore
so everything is one single key press on
the mouse that's the point of the mouse
but the problem is that the the buttons
are not you know it's not that
ergonomic okay if you use it for you
know if you really use computer a lot
you don't want to rely on using these
buttons much because they they are not
like keyboard keys which is very easy to
press they may require some kind of
pressure like and you don't want to do
that often you know so that's that is a
problem about ma mm Oh Mouse so I
actually I should end this video because
I've been talking nonstop for quite a
while but that the new of the news about
the keyboard is this Keystone keyboard
this is so funny
there is so much going on with this
keyboard is highly recommended ok
Keystone keyboard you can go to my
website and ok look at that this
keyboard is analog keyboard meaning that
the keys are Oh
as we mentioned before you know a button
is usually on and off but not that's not
the case with this cable these are
analog keys meaning that it's not just
only and off there's like levels it's
like a gas pedal you can know how much
you pushed okay so so an analog keys and
actually I'm mourning if I should end
the video so so because
yeah because it's 9 o'clock here so
analog keys so jungdae board I just read
your article on reading manuals I have
the same problem of studying the text as
opposed to the idea such oh so so hold
on a second let me cover one of my eyes
I think I because I'm going cause I so
what fold a toilet paper folding fold
and look no I can it's so John says I
just read your article on reading
manuals I have in which one because I
have I think I have quite a few I have
the same problem of studying the text as
opposed to the idea do you have any
advice on overcoming that so yeah I
don't know which which article and what
do you mean reading reference manuals
yeah but what do you mean by because I
don't remember which article I have
actually quite a lot about reading about
manuals oh I've yeah I've read few of
them from cover to cover so do I do it
ok so do I have any advice on overcoming
that yeah don't do that
you know don't never you know don't do
don't read manuals from cover to cover
in fact as for novels you know maybe
novels yeah cover to cover yeah you know
but you know so I used to have the habit
since young you know do I need to read
cover to cover from the first cover act
the actual cover from the you know
whatever you know you must be the
beginning then the preface you know then
the table of content every you know
every every word yeah just scheme so so
yeah definitely
so that's
that's that's a bottom line when you
read a book yohko is just just kid you
know quickly get what what it you know
the gist what the good parts you know
whatever the quality value of the book
so you want to get that you know once
you get that you know spin you know ten
minutes so you know whatever however
amount in you know a few hours or
whatever you know you want to try to get
the point first you know then if you
have more time you can you know you can
be Pete or you can then you can beat
cover-to-cover okay so yeah so that's a
that's us that's what I say
yeah so that's about that and good
morning in Bethel New Bethel new your
stream start late it's 6:00 a.m. here so
it's 6:00 a.m. your place so which means
you are somewhere in UK am i right
Germany I think I asked you before
Germany yeah so you are nine hours ahead
and so what do you mean late so anyway
we let's talk about yeah so yeah so I'm
gonna let's talk about I you know I've
been talking for an hour
you can't I have to I kind of have to go
and but so today's talk showed I mean so
we talked a lot about actually much you
know it's all about keyboards and lots
of things about anyway so this keyboard
is very interesting it's got analog keys
okay and right now it's on it's on a
Kickstarter so you wanna well if you are
interested in keyboard you want you
might go check it out and you know maybe
support or buy them analog keys okay
and by the way a monarch is this one is
not the first there's a one before
called booting and I also have link here
you can see this this came out earlier
like two years you know this one first
it's analog
keys and also this guy this this this
this guy is a great keyboard expert his
name is Caius and you know he that's not
his real name of course but he's but you
can you know if you go to my website
you'll see the YouTube because right now
I'm on local I don't have JavaScript on
so anyway
booting is a analogue keyboard you know
and and great you know this choir song
he's a keyboard switch expert you know
he's a expert on keyboard switch and he
you know he he's expert you know he know
a lot about it and he highly recommend
this analog keys and so so now but that
that companies in Europe this one wooden
I think it's Europe Switzerland or
something I don't know I don't remember
but but these Keystone is from here us
San Jose I think you know down there so
you want to check it out you know would
Inc I mean the Keystone keyboard so it's
using Howe effect switch so we should
talk about that but I kind of so today
we kind of so I was talking or I was
talking I spend a lot of time roundhouse
how Suki Apple has become yeah the apple
design stuff was the apple design then
Keystone keyboard and this one is just
pretty and and some of the cute keycaps
okay so this is great cute ki calves
this is poor and poor and no in the
mushroom and the pump okay so I think
that's it for today you know I I wanted
to talk about programming but when I
haven't got into but I gotta go I yeah I
know your crock I gotta go
take where his dick ways and me wanted
to join your stream lately but 6 a.m. is
true too early late ok oh so is it too
early for you oh it's too early for you
you mean
ok so let's so let's do this so tomorrow
I'm going to be on at let's say fork for
[ __ ] California time does that work for
you so 4 p.m. 4 p.m. California San
Francisco time so that would be that
would be 12
that would be midnight for you like 1
o'clock a.m. so that would be 2 too late
right
so yeah I think tomorrow you know I
could be 3 p.m. but but not earlier I
don't think 4 o'clock means midnight yes
it's fine
no 3 p.m. San Francisco time we all be
equals to Gemma midnight okay so that's
you know so but I'm thinking so so me
Mina is fine so 2 o'clock 3 p.m.
tomorrow
ok 3 p.m. tomorrow so do you guys what
topic do you are you interested
programming or keyboards or any ok let's
do so tomorrow let's try 3 p.m. them ok
yeah so I let me know I like you guys
programmers are you like what kind of
things you've the you need to be
interested because I talk about lots of
random kind of ok programming languages
comparison ok ok so let's do that so
tomorrow guys tomorrow 3 p.m. San
Francisco time thank you guys for
watching hope to see you guys tomorrow
and see you guys tomorrow bye