fantastic welcome to another episode of
some talk show
uh so we are going to the main topic is
wufam language mathematica and let me
introduce you several things okay uh
good morning guys so several things you
are looking at my
new keyboard expose you know this is
this is not new
uh this is um
i had it for for for over two years two
three years but this is one of the
fantastic keyboard okay let me let me
explain so let's write it down
so let's magnify my font so you can see
larger and let's
turn on global highlight
highline mod so you can see where my
cursor is and let me talk about xposed
keyboard okay
so
uh so
so you're looking at this is xbox
keyboard and this is ultimate hacking so
you go to keyboard blog and you can see
let's uh let's make these
three
columns okay
so you are looking at
um
you know i have to
you know this i put these expos on my
desktop and i have to get used to it
somewhat a little bit but it it is one
of the best okay exposed so there's two
models xbox knight is a new one i have
but which i'm not currently using now
because that's a brown switch they sent
me the wrong switch i have to have the
red switch this is red switch fantastic
this is you the the old one
and every time i use it it's great okay
and this is ultimate hacking keyboard
ultimate hacking keyboard he's got the
best
key marker software uh better than
anything else so let me show you
so you are looking at
so we're going to talk about wufang
language okay comments and questions
posted there okay ufam language
fantastic uh and so you are looking at
the xbox keyboard and you know there's
several uh profiles so this is the
normal standard quality
then this quality for mac this is this
is my keypad that's what i'm using it
for
keypad or the
keycode you know banking code
so and because i'm
okay the story gets complicated you know
my my keyboard story so right now i'm
using expose but this expose this is the
very first one xbox oh did i show it
i've i didn't even show it okay so this
is exposed night
so you can see
but
let me show you the very earliest one
okay
uh
let's see my key marker still works yeah
so this is my very first one so 2017 so
i had it for almost three four years now
and this and this is the you know when
they send it to me it's actually still a
prototype so it doesn't so there's no i
cannot program the keys therefore i have
to use windows
vorak keyboard remap you know operating
system remap so
you know very complex story so you have
keyboard firmware you have operating
system remap and you have let me show
you power toys you know power toys is
for microsoft software that lets you
remap keys so i have to do that
long story so remap the number keys and
and and this is not how i do the switch
windows you see there's no you know
never do old tab i talked about this
many times
so
never do all tab
so what i'm going to say so
so i have to use operating system key
remap for vorack so that is why so you
are looking at power
toy and also you are also looking at
auto hard key so let me let me show you
okay
uh
so this is my auto hard key script with
xsa autohotkey emacs mod
so you can see i have one key pressed to
maximize window not the full screen full
screen is idiotic okay this is full
screen but you don't see the tabs and so
on you know you
like i can switch tabs
uh but with the typical windows full
screen let me let me talk about that
later okay mattress fantastic
so many stories to tell so
full screen
the window idiotic they are they have so
many ways of full screen so full screen
f11 you know full screen then you have
maximize window uh window up arrow
window down arrow it's so idiotic okay
so but rather what you want is a key to
toggle maximize window so that key is
set up to to that
and you cannot do it with
either keyboard firmware or operating
system hold on a second let me close the
door
[Music]
so you cannot
you know so so you have to have uh you
you have to use auto hotkeys on windows
on mac and
and on linux you have to use something
else uh i have full tutorials on them
you know if you just look at my keyboard
website so anyway so this is all hotkey
so let's search for
toggle so
so this is this is a
this function is toggle maximize
minimize window okay so you need hot
hotkey for that
so um
so close that
and keyboard firmware usually keyboard
firmware uh or
operating system software doesn't
a kiwi map cannot do it because you need
to determine
why do you need oraha key to toggle
maximize window on
on microsoft windows because you need to
determine whether the window is already
maximized so you need some kind of
software it's not just simply remap no
is it keyboard marker i mean even you if
you have fantastic qmk software you
cannot do it open source
so you need auto hotkey because you need
to determine whether your current window
is maximized or not if it is then
if
it if it is then you have to press the
window down arrow key otherwise
window up arrow key so that's why you
need oraha key and you need uh and power
tool is also fantastic okay
so you know i have an article on all of
these so if you just go to
keyboard software keyboard layout uh
software how to
and uh microsoft windows so here i
introduce power toys okay so let me copy
so so let's focus on what we're gonna
talk about
because so go to today's talk show
so we talked talked about x both uh
ultimate hacking keyboard and
we talked about power toys and we talked
about auto hard key
and
okay let's get the link
so power toys copy
okay we got a lot to do uh power toys
and
auto hotkey tutorial
you see
and ultimate hacking keyboard
uh yeah i got a lot uh to tell you guys
about ultimate hacking keyboard
and uh
expose
so you see this is my new setup so i'm
i'm not sure where to put that it's kind
of
far
so auto hotkey and uh
exposed okay so expose expose knight go
buy it okay all these are great okay
and the kinesis advantage
360 is also great now let's show
so that's the topics we talked about so
and today we're gonna uh who how many of
you are here for wufang language
so i'm using
soft light keys and voila keyboard vera
layout and i'm using
emax mod
so um
okay so
you know so we we're gonna talk about
wolfen language
uh is it true you injure injured your
finger while blah blah blah blah blah
that's 4chan idiot okay you keep reading
for a chance idiot you know read my
youtube you know watch my youtube like a
month or two ago i talked about where my
this finger got damaged because i was
playing with my wife you know
the fortune factor [ __ ] you know
these millennium generations zoomer
idiots they go 4chan and talk random
things
you know
because that's a style when you post
for example
you have to be dramatic that's a nature
of 4chan and then
you know being dramatic is one thing but
this zoomer idiots they have no idea
what's you know where is the line
then then you you start to lie you you
know you you do lots of things
uh
so i'm going to yeah so actually i want
to code wufang language because we
haven't done that for a while so let's
not um so let's do that okay
so um
expose and let me uh talk about the
matrix a little bit so
you know my wife you know she cleaned
these bad you know beddings every month
or two and she discovered you know a few
days ago it's wet underneath underneath
underneath this this memory foam
uh
mattress this is actually called
mattress topping you know matrix is the
most idiotic idea the matches you know
like usually very thick 10 inches
you know and
extremely heavy you know it's degenerate
comfort you know why do you need you
know for me
i sleep on the on the floor on carpet
for the past 20 years
basically starting from year 2000 to
year
i sleep on carpet okay just copy this no
not even bedding you know maybe some
thing you know like exercise mat you
know these modern days you have exercise
mats you know
that is sufficient for me or sleeping
bag okay i don't i don't want i don't
want a mattress i don't want a soft you
know comfort you know
this is spawn of steel
okay but however my wife needs a
mattress
so so we got this you know
and and and this is from costco 190
or something
you know it the brand name is tam tam
tempuric
pedic something like that so it's
actually called
a mattress topper what what a idiocy so
you have 10 inches mattress but then
that's not enough you need a mattress
topper
what the [ __ ] are these american people
think i don't understand what the [ __ ]
are these people thinking match 10
inches mattress is not enough you need
the topper
anyway so we just got you know i want i
want a hot bed but my wife needs you
know something like you know soft so we
got this and she and she discovered it's
wet underneath and we are we are all
very puzzled like how
like did someone sneak in
and pour water
underneath our bed
there's no reason i mean wha what's
going on so we are so i'm i was so very
puzzled we are
so it turns out this is pretty common
when you have a matte uh mattress you
need you know the the bed frame they
need ventilation like usually when you
see bed frames it's like a bunch of bars
slated you know the term is slated like
a bunch of bars or metal wires
so that you know it turns out when you
sleep you sweat and you sweat a lot you
know over time they sink into the uh the
mattress
so that's why you will see lots of uh
mode
you know
you know uh under the mattress
so
we discovered that so you need so we so
this is our
bed frame it's just a wooden board so
that is why there's no ventilation so
that so
so i did you know i spent like two days
you know several hours and with the help
of our discord friends where's where's
our discord
you know with the help of discord
friends you know so they
so people suggest to me i realized you
know you need
you know is this is fairly common so
solution is that you know either get a
new bed frame
or
you know or there's this product it
turns out this this product okay so
let's turn javascript so google knows
what you are doing
so there is this thing you know for
those people
on a
homeless you know
for these homeless people i
i've been sleeping in my car for like
two years around 2005
uh back then when i had a car but
anyway that's history okay so so or a
boat you know uh or a boat you can see
you know on a boat situation where it's
a boat photo so anyway on both or you
know
in a car so you need this kind of pad
that provides a ventilation for the
mattress
okay so that's one of the solution or a
new bed frame
okay so actually we went over so we
should be talking about technical stuff
so let's um
what do i think of about the
accessibility features of window like
zoom and it's no good okay i don't i i
never use it well it's i mean if you are
blind if you are disabled then it's
useful
uh that is windows plus key okay
yeah windows plus then you got this
you know window plus so window minus
i don't use it okay i am
okay that's about the make
mattress story so it's all on my
keyboard blog okay so you go to xr
keyboard
blog
then some recent articles so let me talk
about this okay so then then let's go on
to a wolfram language coding
so bank key code okay you should check
out the reason you know those of you
like 30 crap okay read this article okay
then uh mechanical keyboard and
repetitive strain injury okay so let me
tell you
that
when you
have hand pain
you know there are many solutions
related to keyboard of course you have
to be healthy go exercise do aerobics
sweat
things like that and watch your posture
but
as as far as keyboard is concerned what
you want is first of all you want
mechanical key switches that's the most
important okay we re read this article
mechanical keyboard and repetitive
stranger okay
that's the most important more important
than letter layout like borac comag and
crap this
you know
most important is the keyboard switch
you want a mechanical keyboard key
switch okay
more important than split
layout then tenting keyboard tenting and
and and any sort of that thing
so go out now buy a cheap
if you don't know anything about
keyboarding you know go out and buy a
cheap chinese cheapo okay
forty dollars mechanical key switches
on amazon you know go back from from my
website you know chinese cheapo and
waterproof and so on you know
do it right now okay if you don't have a
mechanical key switch you don't want
mechanical feel okay that's not good
uh and i don't like happy hacking you
know this topper switch but you know
that's
also okay i suppose
uh because you know keys reaches lots of
personal preference anyway so mechanical
keyboard okay
that's the most important mechanical key
switch
uh then here's my mac software key
keyboard software guide okay let's skip
that
uh
vertical gaming mouse this uh recent
update about this okay
uh
and there is from our friend link
from russia
love from russia
so there's a russian keyboard meetup so
russian
you know they have their own uh kind of
uh community for you know do it yourself
keyboard so
and
so he's you know link showed me several
you know on discord
uh you know what russian people do
so there here it is ultimate hacking
keyboard some of you some of them you
recognize for example on the right hand
right
lower corner you have ultimate hacking
keyboard and this one is the moon lander
you know it's an ergodox variation
uh and
and
apparently russian they like the google
i mean that not google what's
um
what are those names i forgot uh those
are for i have a full documentation uh
zhong and kong okay
russian they like these thirty percent
jung and kong and this and this one is
very weird you know john keyboard they
have these extra keys out on the side
you know instead of one row they need to
add one just one key there
this is idiotic
and you know i was asking you know
i was asking link you know he likes
thirty percent keyboard but i was i was
one time asking on voice you know you
4chan or whatever nerds go on well go on
voice show your real name and show your
id be a man okay don't like oh i don't
want to go on voice i oh oh you know idi
so anyway link told me on voice that you
know he he also uh
we are talking on video as well so he
told me you know this
thing that extra key you can just
actually
you can just um
ben you know just like break it
if you don't want that you know i'll
break it on pcb so anyway so this is
john keyboard they're very funny
and
so so there it is okay so john keyboard
okay so let's go back to russian
keyboard so
uh and uh
kong and john keyboard and uh
so i'm still working on this page you
know so i started to write about this
page with links help
and he also showed me
this one of his own design this is freak
freak keyboard
this is a 20 keyword so you need coding
to enter you know to to enter it
so this is
link
himself made this
and you know and this code design is
from his friend you know someone you
know
so this one is called clutter nets
called keyboard clarinets okay so
you know you it can be used to type
russian and english
you you can switch
um
and
here's a variation of the same thing so
you know except so this so this you see
is to be used on the phone so you
you know take your phone and clip this
to the back of the phone and you can use
your finger to type that so this is a
variation
of
of this keyboard so basically you are
just seeing half of it you know it's
symmetric so you are just seeing half of
it and you press these codes to enter
letters
so that's uh that's the links keyboard
claddiness code
keyboard and there's a
github i believe there's a github
uh links so you can go to my website and
you can find all the links
but i'm still working on this page so i
don't know if i have
clarinet
yeah here so
so here is the github for the called
cloud nets
keyboard
okay so that's about russian
close that
let's copy that let's go to uh
let's put it in talk show today
okay
at this rate we are not going to do fan
language um
many things to talk about so
so here is what we talked about russian
do it you just do it yourself keyboards
and let me tell you about something
about syntax soup you know when it comes
to programming this is one of like my
common theme in my talk show you know in
my talk show what i talk about i talk
about programming
programming languages programming
language design programming programmer
culture you know the hackers the unix
philosophy idiots
pro you know programmers culture hackers
and the the new generation male engine
and zoomers and programmers you know
so
and i talk about symbology you know
programming language and symbols unicode
for example i talked about unicode often
uh you know you can find them all on my
website unicode
[Music]
for example this is upside
down unicode and you can
see
let's try some fancy okay so
select all delete
so here comes the room
alphabet okay so you can copy and
cut
so it serves as cryptography
secret
secret writing
you can use between your girlfriends
and then
so unicode you know so what is unicode
about it's about symbols you know it's
about all these symbols writing systems
so let me for example let me show you
the all useful all kind of brackets
you know i use them extensively for
example
for example in emacs i want to search
for
or what's occurrences of haskell and you
can see this is
find package you have to pay okay pay me
to get it this is the most efficient
most convenient so you
you press
arrows to jump about and press
enter to open it
so you can see
so you can see it's using the special
characters you can see that here you see
that's unicode
so what unicode is that that unicode is
called
called left square brackets with
underbar you see
so let's magnify again let's magnify
let's see the full glory of the unicode
so you see
and
then here is another one it's a bracket
with the middle bar
so that's all here so let me show you so
so the full power of unicode fantastic
practical use not emoji [ __ ] okay not
you know emoji is a male melange
thing and with zuma's they love it you
know emoji then skin color
then then you know
then gender
but
but here the unico here is the most
practical thing you know also the
brackets you can use so that you have
you know instead of like instead of the
typical let me show you okay
and
instead of you know typical templates
system you have to use like typically
uh dear name for example sometimes you
get spam mail you'll say
okay
why why why what's uh why do you want to
use in unicode instead of the double
bracket or things like that because
double bracket may occur you know so the
more unique symbols the less
crash
it will happen and also
more precise so you can always just find
for example in my package i can just
find that
occurrence of that character and no that
is a occurrence
you know so
you have
you are better at avoiding collision
okay of course collision will always
happen
that's when you are searching
whenever you have recurrence or nesting
occurs
for example you are searching a text a
file that's the output of your tool so
then
that's when you might have problems but
anyway so you can see all these unicode
brackets you see and this one for
example
this one is another uh
you know uh
character
a unicode character called medium left
pointing angle bracket ornament okay so
you can also find it here
fantastic you know practical use of
unicode
copy
go back here
close
paste here
and
show in browser
there it is that's uh that's what we
talked about and
what you have witnessed witnessed is the
self-find text command
the most
useful and efficient and featureful
and convenient
tool when you want to search or find
replace in emacs okay you have to pay me
so if you like my stuff support
um
go there and buy it okay so copy that
better than grep better than silver
better than
rip grape you know
if you are using emacs
okay paste it there then
so unicode practicality you know so so i
was saying we were talking about why am
i into these things so i mean the main
theme of south talk show you often find
is
symbols you know programming
languages
programming
activity
programming language design
and uh
writing systems chinese work i mean
chinese russian ranking systems japanese
i've article on that
and
input systems and keyboard you know
keyboard also involves
for example let's go to keyboard okay
keyboard for example
input systems so for example layout
design
keybinding design
so
for example here's the layout design you
have work you have all kind of weird
things you have chinese input system you
have japanese input system you have
layout efficiency this is when you need
to
for example select all
t you know one single character t
this
is when you need to know which character
occur the most often or the character
frequency or
even if it is
programming language source code
for example you want to know which
character
happen
more often in programming language
c or javascript or haskell or list you
know for example i can copy
this entire html and go here
select or paste it
so that's the character frequency for
for this page for it uh html so you have
to go to look at a javascript
so for example let's go to a javascript
unicode emoticons javascript
okay that okay this is pretty short okay
so you copy that
go here
select or paste
and
show punctuation
and no english alphabet so that's the
punctuation frequency of javascript
you know so
why do you need to know that because
when you design you know keyboard input
systems for programming languages you
need to know for example where to place
comma or you know the com the question
you know some
keyboard layout they swap the number row
with the symbols so when you want to
type
a
parenthesis for example you don't have
to press the shift but however when you
pre want to press a number key you have
to press the shift so is that swapping
more efficient
or not for example the vorac layout for
programmer that they are used
does this swap is it good or not
this is how you study and find out and i
have an article on that about whether
it's good or bad so things like that so
i'm interested in symbology
writing systems you know so it's all
related to my exotic show topic and one
of them
which we were talking about is
programming language syntax
programming language design
and in particular uh hold on a second
programming language design okay and in
particular
close that okay
show this in browser
back to emacs
delete this block
showing browser okay so one of the
when it comes to programming language
design
one of the
fundamental aspects of programming
language
is the syntax
okay so i have a
whole bunch of articles you know tens of
hundred
you know 100 over 100 articles on syntax
issues alone now most people they think
most you know this unix philosophy or
the you know those into programming
languages for example disperse
these idiots they will say
they think that oh syntax is actually
not important that's the worst idea
that's a
patented force
syntax is the most element most
important element in programming
language design
i did several
talk
you know each one is one hour on that
issue
in the past half a year okay so you want
watch them so syntax is the most
important element of programming
language design syntax okay
you know i have so many articles so i
cannot you know i each one i can talk
for half an hour so but in summary for
example you look at this that's
symbology that's a simple
manipulation which in turn relates to
formal languages and the heart of
computer science
that's all about
syntax okay single sequences so you have
algebraic money so you know some of you
like haskar for example
and if you go one more level up then
haskell what you get is algebra syntax
algebra that's what this picture kind of
shows syntax algebra where
it doesn't have semantics anymore it's
all just symbols formal language okay
all just symbols like for example lambda
calculus and
combinators that's what they are formal
languages
or it's just pure syntax syntactical
manipulation syntax algebra that's the
best language okay
you ask our idiots list idiots
without syntax without this parenthesis
for example you will never have these
markers you know this person are
obsessed about oh this smart markers is
the best thing
however
you know they forgot that that's why
because syntax because lisp has
parentheses therefore you got this
you know markers that's idea
follows up
without this parenthesis you'll not have
these markers okay similar ideas for
term rewriting systems and so on
mathematica or language and so what
we're gonna talk about today
so i was saying so syntax so this is one
of the language you know one of the
aspects in fact most important aspect of
programming language design so here you
are looking at complaint proving that's
that's all my articles about programming
language design so you have first of all
syntax syntax soup then you have
semantic noodles
semantic issues you know
then then you have lisp you know all the
all the relevant things to the least
phonetics
so i did several you know talk shows
about that
then you have python python idiocy one
of the most idiotic language
it's made popular because google google
saved it
otherwise it's not going anywhere every
time you know
yeah i talked about this before but
anyway
so i was saying syntax is the most
important thing okay that's my obsession
about programming language design and
one of the um one of the
you know so recently i made some update
here
about functions and operators okay let
me let me go over that one
so this article
programming language design why do you
need operators so i discussed the issue
why do you need them okay so
uh i'm not going to go over so you know
and then you have the actual practical
real world code example of javascript
doing matrix linear algebra matrix
multiplication you know today you have
machine learning in machine learning
linear algebra is one of the most well
not linear algebra but statistics you
know math mathematics it's one of the
most important element in machine
learning neural networks so
starting about 10 years ago you start
you started to have lots of programmers
who started to all mathematicians got
into programming or programmers started
to learn
mathematics you know
in particular statistics and probability
theory because that's what
neural networks machine learning they
are based on
they are one of the technology for
artificial intelligence okay
so
you started to and linear algebra you
know is fundamental especially for
programming computer graphics so here's
a javascript that does
matrix multiplication and you know
and matrix and vectors
make vector edition for example so this
is when you actually you want
you want
the
feature a programming language you you
need you want the feature you desire a
feature where the programming language
lets you define your own operators
critical when you do lots of these you
become critical you want the programming
language to be able to let you define
your own operators okay most language
cannot especially let's see java [ __ ]
okay
c java javascript python idiotic well in
python you can
i think you can
you know so i have articles about that
which for example this article okay
unicode in function name and operator so
this this article is a survey of all
these languages cc plus plus score java
javascript python pro ruby or camera
haskell emac julia wufam language you
know a survey of this language on
several aspects one do they let you use
unicode
characters in variable names or function
names do they
so
here's a survey then that's that's the
first question then the second question
is do they allow you
to define your own operators or
sometimes it's called operator
overloading from the c idiot c and c
plus plus idiot you know they use jargon
operator overloading
overload overload their ass
they don't know what they're doing so
anyway but anyway but but operator
overloading is a form
is one of the form
of a feature of a programming language
to let you define your own operator
which is
important okay you know
and then the third question is
so do they yeah so the question is do
they do the programming language lets
you define your own operators that's a
question okay
then the third question is if they
if the programming language lets you
define your own operators does it allow
you to use unicode
for example the unicode summation
circle plus
cross plus integral sign
or the um
or the
delta um
you know do they allow you to use
unicode as the operator which is
critical you know because
you
you usually you don't want operator
overloading because that confuse is
confusing you know because the same
symbol now has multiple rows depending
on the data type so you usually
the c idiots okay you don't want that
you want to be able to use
unicode characters to define your own
operators so this article
discuss that a survey
and
language is the best of course i have
actually code examples you can run
you know java and java pro python you
know you can run
and turn them up and hascal is pretty
good haskell is doing pretty good and
you know haskell so you have ocamo
and it also depends because 10 years ago
high school cannot ask
you know 10 years ago
haskell cannot actually
doesn't actually deal with unicode well
you know if you have unicode it doesn't
work well but you know it improved and
so on
because why do how why because i know
because in 2008 at 2008 i ate i tried it
you know and haskell failed
but the new generation you know they're
gonna tell you oh you are wrong because
you know blah blah blah
and uh okay so anyway jude wufang
language is best there
so i want to so
i want to code some wolfen language i
guess so we talked for 15 minutes let's
do some move from language then let me
read the comments okay
magnifier close
power drink
cheers
so there's a
question about bitcoin well
what i'm going to say is that donate
okay if you enjoyed my video
buy me a drink
bitcoin or otherwise
bitcoin you know cryptocurrency is
another topic we can talk about for days
but usually it's um
you know lots of idiotic opinions but
anyway ensure you know i think
cryptocurrency is here to stay and it's
good however it may become it's being um
it's being um
threated by
by the government or by the you know
powerful mainstream corporations they
spread lies they create
old coins they create essentially it's
becoming you know it's like the internet
internet originally like 30 years ago 20
years ago is designed such the idea
the gist the essence the power of
internet is that now everyone can have a
website you know it's you are free to
visit any thousands tens of thousands
website they all communicate you know
but now
but not after 30 years in the internet
is just like five websites
google facebook you know twitter amazon
ebay
you know five ten websites you visit
all those you don't visit
how did that happen like like for 99
percent of people who use internet
basically just you you only use 10
websites
make a corporation you know they they
are the
mega empires
how did that happen and and then the
idiot the manager and then you have the
open source idiots they say oh you you
need to go to git lab oh you need to use
matrix the [ __ ] it is these people
that made the way it is today
it is these people you know
because they don't know but they don't
know they think they are like the
warriors they they think they are the
fighting no no you can you're gonna make
it worse it is these people you [ __ ] it
and becomes cloud everything becomes
cloud why because the free software
foundation open source phoneticism
you know you you want to say oh you
cannot make money and well
lots of lies you know and once and they
say oh it's not about money it's about
freedom but on the other hand it's
actually about about money because
nobody pays pay me guys you know you
don't pay me instead of asking me but
one 1 000 questions i'm gonna ask you
know i'm gonna answer for
for 10 years which i did
nobody pays okay
then you have opinions about oh what do
you think then but but but in the
reality is
the web or programming they become worse
and worse yes there are no open source
now microsoft is the biggest open source
by lines of code the entire
powershell.net and and linux subsystem
you know microsoft do you think it's
good
no it's not good of course microsoft
they
they do lots of things you know these
yeah it's open source by name but it's
actually it's technically it's open
source you know by by the license too
but is it good for you no
you know
so the original the the good aspect of
open source has been throtted
you instead of you just have idiots like
you guys like the 4chan or whatever or
open source phonetics saying oh you need
open source you need open source
meanwhile the microsoft powershell
and.net is open open source but they
kind of
they don't they don't approve it
what's going on
you want open source there it is
microsoft word missiles and google
google they massively
you know monitor whatever you do they
know where you slept with
your phone your maps you know
oh
a lot you know open source
open source android is based on linux oh
look linux is so powerful it's used by
[ __ ] all the phones yeah it opens
yeah yeah by the google empire
gets into you gets into your pants
and you like open source idiots these
idiots and the web now it's all every
link is tracked
you know they have the short link short
links and and so on so on and on
so
you know the internet
originally it's actually you know the
idea is that you have the
anyone can publish and and free
information flow but now
you just have 10 websites by these
empires and they put lies you know they
they put massive lies you know that
they watched your brain you grew up with
that
and you you still think you are doing
good you know you are you are just you
know you are just there
so
internet so
similar thing is happening to the crypto
uh currency
why because originally the idea of
cryptocurrency is that nobody can
control it okay nobody can control it
there's no central power
uh you know therefore no government
government can control it you know
but now it because this because it's
very technical stuff so so so what so
what can the government do all the
corporations google for example google
facebook or china okay so what they can
do well they're gonna introduce you like
things like we're gonna have a new
open source cryptocurrency no new old
coin there are so many like hundreds you
know bitcoin is ethereum then bitcoin
branches they split then
you don't know you you know you
literally have to spend several years
dedicated to study crypto currency you
know
to to actually know what's
what is actually good
but most most of you you know nobody has
that time you know
like one one or ten million maybe one
one guy in 10 million maybe you you
become you can be
you know look into the detail but most
of us cannot even i don't know so far i
wanted to but i don't have time i didn't
know what's exactly what's good so
anyway the point is that these
corporations they just spread so many
things
so they so so now there's a
you know bitcoin new branch or whatever
you don't know which one is an actual
good
thing you know you don't know or
ethereum or whatever you know
you don't actually know which one is a
good thing
so
but they spread this massively you know
and especially one great example is
today you have web three
web
okay that's a propaganda okay but you
don't know but
you honestly don't know unless you
dedicate your life several years to
study that one particular issue but then
you don't know other things okay so so
that's why so
so this so you have this so many old
coins
so what you're gonna do you nothing you
can do so you
maybe you you followed some and you
think this is a good
path
but it turns out it's it's not it's
actually just controlled by banks
yeah so you know
so what what's going to happen
[Music]
is that yeah right you have
cryptocurrency
which is becoming very popular but
however what you didn't know is that
that cryptocurrency is controlled by
mega corporations by banks they are very
very highly interested in these things
they spread you know that like all these
you guys people posting the mainstream
you know you don't know what you're
talking about
you think it's good but
what will happen may happen
is that
yeah crypto cryptocurrency is gonna be
popular but you don't know it's actually
whatever you are using is actually
controlled by the major banks just like
right now just like the us dollar but
you don't know it you think you are
doing good
just like open source same thing just
like internet
so
what can you do to solve this you have
to have a brain that's basically you
have to spend pain okay no pain no gain
you know stop your fortune [ __ ] you know
stop your dribbling this or that [ __ ]
stop your dark thing [ __ ] stop your oh
let's use we we need to discord sucks
let's go use matrix oh gitlab is spoiled
by microsoft let's go let's switch let's
go to you know github is spot by
microsoft let's go to gitlab let's go
you know open so [ __ ]
you you [ __ ] [ __ ]
made this
thing's worse you have to you know you
have to spend your year spent one year
two years three years dedicated to to to
to dive into to look into things then
you know
what is actually good or what is not
just by having a technology it doesn't
help like the internet like the open
source
and now like the bitcoin
they become
they become evil empires yeah internet
is still here yeah technically you are
still you you are able to go anywhere
you know to to visit all the sites but
what actually happens is that fast
majority 99 people they're gonna just
use ten websites including yourself
idiot
uh
okay so
today it turns out and out to be a rant
so i'm not going to do wolfen language
you know this is not good for i don't
want to talk about wolfram language now
so let's uh so ultimate hacking keyboard
it's the best keyboard for uh marco okay
so let's because that so that's it for
today
so
so manny lou asked me about bitcoin you
know like do i regret or not don't don't
ask me personal questions like what's
your point what's your purpose
what i desire what i want is you donate
me you know a few bucks even just a few
hello justine scarfi
the mathematician from from canada
you know justin always comes in and say
hi but but other than that nothing else
so trusting i wish i hope you are doing
great
so um keyboard layout you know vorack is
still good you know quality is not good
but i mean
i mean the point about key switch is
that comparatively you know you have to
think about if you have hand pan you
have to think about which one is the
most important
key switch mechanical keys switch is the
then
it's about the split and tenting
i would say that's the second most
important
then you might think about then actually
then
it's about keyboard shortcuts the
control you know control all those kind
of things you don't want your fingers to
always keep control so so band key
chords okay that's a third importance
because keyboards
key chords keyboard shortcuts is
actually if you are a programmer or
photoshop user or video editor
you actually use keyboard shortcuts more
than more than you typing letters
so
so so that's about keyboard shortcuts
you know so you have to
study
all those issues key binding design so
this is this section this chapter is
about all these articles about
key binding
keyboard shortcuts
input systems
or you know shortcut keys like that
dedicated shortcut keys are they good or
not you know for example one of the
things you want is
for example the most uh obvious example
is
for volume control you want a physical
knob okay that's the best you don't want
you know the button like as especially
you you don't want the fn
you know this
fm
if it increases you know you don't want
that the volume
you know you want a wheel a volume wheel
so this page
is a survey or the physical
keyboard wheel or volume
design so you have rollers so you have a
knob
uh you have knob okay
then you have
mouse wheel kind of thing uh
then you have this disc kind of knob
this kind of wheel
you know key
keyboard um
wheel design
so let me paste that
to
so we have a record of what we talked
about
syntax soup okay
then we talked about bitcoin
cryptocurrency
internet
open source phoneticism
and look at this video okay this is
about you know when you talk about
mechanical key switches you know there's
a big community you know people about
talk about how the key feels it's like a
major thing you know you can talk about
it for years you know many people
collected you know all kind of keyboard
switches you know
and similarly
for the wheel
this also it's it's actually a
ish a big issue because this guy this
guy on youtube very funny
you know this guy actually revealed like
tens of
you know the volume knobs on stereo
audio equipment like each one he
tries to trace it
and and test how it feels you know
so it's actually a issue because for
example mouse wheel so you're looking at
my mouse
so you're looking at the mouse so this
one is spin wheel okay so let me show
you so you see
you see um
you see it's a spin wheel or you can
click this button
then it becomes notched
so there's an issue when you design when
you have a wheel there's an issue
whether it should be not
notched or
or free phone they they are good
you know there there's uh advantage and
disadvantage depending on which command
you want that wheel to map to you know
for example if you want volume wheel
then it's better if it spins and if you
wanted to scroll
uh pages then often spin also is better
if you wanted to switch weapons for
example in game then
notch is better so depending on your use
case you know what command it maps to
so this you know the issue about tactile
aspect of the
wheel
which relates to the keys you know the
volume up and down keys you know you
want a wheel okay so so many of these
issues so that's it for today okay
thank you guys thank you guys thank you
luis bo
and thank you velodema
okay bye guys one hour so
yeah so we close in two minutes um
so let me just
sure what we talked about so we talked
about uh what is this
unicode support okay unicode
character in programming language names
and uh
let me paste that
okay
close that keyboard wheel do we have it
here no
so
copy the url switch back to last window
oh we have it here okay
close
find and replace in emac list
side find close
exposed keyboard
thank you guys bye have a good day
conjoin the list
you know i'm used to the kinesis so on
the kinesis keyboard my hands are like
that but now on the expose i kind of
like right away i have i feel like i
have to
kind of crunch
you know scrunch you know my hands
together
close
uh
so x keyboard close ex
expose knight keyboard it's fantastic
because
ultimate hacking keyboard is fantastic
uh
autohard key
there it is
close close
and russian keyboard do we have it here
okay that's it bye guys
so
what's your opinion
what is your opinion is the one
programming language should learn
besides go and wufang for daily stuff so
go is good go is
generally good wufang language is
good in particular
so go is good if you are a programmer if
you are a professional programmer let me
okay let me answer that question last
question thank you for the donation
that's the
that's
that's the answer for the money
so golan if you are a programmer
professional programmer golan is one of
the languages that's a great language
versatile and also low level or high
level depending you know you can use it
for both golan better than python better
than python okay better than python ruby
javascript
so golan is a generic good
professional programmer learning it okay
if if programming is your job
golan is the versa great okay better i
would say better than java better than c
plus plus better than c
better than c sharp okay go land learn
golett
okay i can't say for c sharp because i
don't really know c sharp but better
than c plus plus java in my opinion okay
anything
better than rust anything involving
dealing with memory management
management garbage crack that's i don't
like it okay there are some there are
uses for those programming languages but
in general i don't like those
low-level stuff so go land versatile
okay
now wufang language is that
is particularly good if you are a
technical person
working in technical field you know
maybe even artificial intelligence
machine learning or if you are a
mathematician
engineer
physicist
or if you are a scientist biologist
but you are not a professional
programmer you know like you don't know
see or what what is object oriented what
you know like the programming technical
details you don't and you don't care you
know you don't care whether you should
be functional programming or object or
or con
contract based you know whatever you
know programming language you know
but you are a scientist engineer
mathematician or you are a technical
person for example a lot you know of you
you are doing 3d modeling you are doing
video editing that's your profession you
know video editing you know technical
stuff like you have frame you have frame
rates or maybe you are a game game gamer
you know you are
you you you create gamer you know uh
modifications things like that so if you
are a technical person or engineer
wufang language is the best okay
versatile it's it covers everything
one lines of ufam language equals to 100
lines of gold land i mean even one one
thousand ten thousand lines of gold
golan or python or lisp okay because if
you consider uh language okay that's the
versatile and you can use wufang
language to do crypto
analysis you know you can use
language to create
bitcoin wallet or whatever
cryptocurrency you know every everything
anything and also
usually just one single line because
wufang language they tries to
put everything
possibly a human wants to do the
knowledge of human animals
related to programming
in
into the language so everything is just
a function you don't have to load
library you don't have to know when you
want to traverse a directory or when you
want to do a hash table or
or cryptocurrency you don't have to know
oh which library do i need or regular
expression or which library oh third
party
nothing like that
everything is one line out of the box
wufang language okay
i did i did more than you know i did 10
videos about wolfen language watch that
so golan wufang language okay i
explained their
why they are good
who should use them okay
uh what else okay so
so it depends on who
you know what do you want to do so these
two are great okay
um
for example okay so
golen wufang language is great
now another thing i like is powershell
but whether you should learn powershell
or not
it depends because powershell if you're
on windows if you do a lot of shell
scripting then powershell is
you want to learn powershell it's
because it's a great design far better
than bash it's like
bash unix shell garbage that's 30 years
old
garbage piles of [ __ ] that's unix
things passions you know passion z shell
you know that
so powershell is a 20 years better shell
and it's most most most useful is if you
are assisted me on windows okay
of course it's also available it's open
source
available on linux and mac as well but
on linux and mat mac you know the native
shell is rather
bash or z shell so
you you rather want to use native but
anyway powershell is a great shot okay
but you may not yeah i mean
it depends on what you want to do okay
so javascript let me talk about
javascript javascript
um
javascript is the
today javascript is the most
popular language okay
the most popular languages are
javascript
python
javascript python
c c plus plus java basically that you
know the top the top five javascript
python
java
and php is also very popular
so anyway javascript is very
uh popular very very popular one number
one because if you count number of
libraries on github
i think javascript is the number one
programming language with the
most number of libraries but in
javascript is idiotic because javascript
libraries is each one is five lines they
count that as a library
but anyway javascript is very very
popular you'll find a job with
javascript web dev you know because web
dev you need you need to do webdav for
the phone everyone is using your phone
or you know
website you know javascript
so javascript is very very popular but
however javascript language i spent the
most time writing of all my tutorials my
javascript in-depth you can buy it okay
pay me buy it
my javascript in-depth uh tutorial is
the most in-depth you know i read you
know the
tech spec you know of several versions
cover to cover you know
so javascript i spent the most time i've
spent like two years
you know
writing this javascript tutorial but the
javascript the language
sucks okay it still sucks
even though it improved a lot but among
the
man for example
javascript
you know i'm not even sure i can't even
say javascript is better than python so
javascript is like very popular and if
you do web dev you know if you are a
professional programmer and if your
field involving anything with a web dev
or phone you need javascript so you you
can learn that but the language is not
good okay it's
for example if you want to do something
personal a personal project
you know something you are really
interested you know creating a keyboard
layout or whatever personal project
i i wouldn't use javascript
language is bad okay
so what uh so what is
my general recommendation okay so
and lisp i cannot really
recommend it neither but if you are an
emacs user of course this emac this is
tremendously helpful necessary but
emac this is not general
and uh
you know if you learn emac this the only
thing you can do is just
be more efficient and at emacs like you
know like for example i press the key i
do lots of things you know that you've
seen you have seen me
you have seen
the power
of mastering emacs lisp you know in
every oh just about every one of my
video
but however outside of emacs emac this
is useless
you you you it's not the general purpose
language okay there are general purpose
lisp for example commonly skinned this
but they are known
you know they they are a dead end okay
you're gonna waste your time studying
those that's my opinion of course lots
of you are these fanatics
uh
and
and okay so that's about this so
yeah i'm not sure i
can recommend lisp in general so
so python let me talk about python
python just like javascript is one of
the most most most popular language
not because python is good or some
quality about python python is popular
only because google
no other reason the guido von russom the
creator of python is idiotic okay python
is popular
why
is it because it's a good language
because it's easy to learn no
python is popular ruby for example ruby
is much more simpler more elegant more
easy to learn than python okay ruby
more elegant more simple to learn easier
to learn better documentation
than python okay they are about the same
you know they do about the same thing
but why is python popular because google
in year 2000 google
back then the only other choice is pearl
pearl
is one of the most crappy
you know lousy unix philosophy [ __ ] okay
like you know cryptic you cannot
understand it and filled with code you
know more than one way to do it oh
laziness is a great virtual programmers
you know lots of crap
so back then in year 2000
the
pearl is almost the only choice in
programming i mean as a scripting
language
but google
google decided you know they are going
to use python python acting is not
it's not well known it's little known
so then google becomes very successful
because they they write great software
back then okay not today
today so rotten
and back then google is very ethical
remember do no evil that's their slogan
but that's organ has been officially
erased about five years ago erased from
their
you know their company
legal document
anyway google began around the year 2000
1998 also great company fantastic
company
great ethical practice do no evil and
they write the greatest best software
all the software though all the
engineers at google are the best
programmers they know what they're doing
like me
okay google that's back then in year
2000 so back then
google you know they pick java okay java
is also dying nobody's using java but
google
saved both java and python google picked
java
you know back because because the guy
larry you know two of them larry um
paige and
larry and you know two of them they they
are stand for graduate you know dropout
and they
in their computer science you know
class one of the language they learned
is java so they just went you know they
went with java
and they have to choose a
scripting language so they picked python
so
then all the programmers oh oh google is
using python you know then the python
website says look google is using python
you know so everyone started to learn
python
google
made python
popular back in year 2000 okay that's
the first time
but python is not a good language okay
but then but then
then ruby on rails ruby became very
popular kind of
then
python is going nowhere like the guido
van rossum
he envisions python to be the
the the best language for all the
you know new programmers to learn
because he thinks it's easy to learn he
thinks he's got the best design but the
python the kaikido around russell is
it's not he's not he's not too bright
okay
he's his efforts in trying to spread
python to other corporations and
education
establishments failed basically nobody
is like actually using python much from
his efforts
you know and he also pushed python to
the raspberry pi and so on
but in my opinion he doesn't
his effort in pushing python as the
educational language kind of failed
but however google it is google
made python popular because back in 2010
when the machine learning and ai became
popular google again
made python you know the google channel
libraries you know python became the
interface to lots of google's ai
technologies libraries written in c or c
plus plus
so python so
so that's why today
every time you talk about machine
learning or the python you know it's
like all about python that's that's why
google google saved python twice
the first time in 2000 year 2000
okay google pick python made python well
known to the general public the second
time is around 2010 when machine
learning ai quiz
blow up you know the big data back you
know these these are the jargon words
big data
petra bags you know oh we need to
analyze big data you know your database
is some petrified
machine learning ai you know so google
turned out
libraries because python is what they
use internally for their mostly you know
so they they created libraries
in python which interface to their
machine learning stuff so
that is why python became
otherwise it's dying you know otherwise
it's dying because and also because the
python 2 2 python 3
fiasco the python idiot the guido von
russen idiot
and
um
so
so let me show you this article
python python 3 adoption you know guido
van versa he has a vision he think he's
the best design
you know
i'm into design i looked at i know a lot
of people you know who are ex known for
design of things you know for example
the
jonathan something who designed lots of
apple things you know programming
language design you know i
read and you know i read all the
programmer
uh programming language creators what
they are thinking and so on you know
stefan wu family and many others
so i mean to design but from what i see
in my opinion guido van rossum
his idea he doesn't know about it he
he doesn't
he's not a good designer i wouldn't say
his his language python failed being
simple failed being easy to learn but he
think they are
failed in so many ways then he think you
know he he he's he's kind of passive
aggressive he thinks that
python is the best design oh python 2 we
got some errors we need to fix it so
we're going to create python 3 a new
language
then pattern 3 you know for over 10
years it's still you know not much
adopted you know
but eventually you will but then google
google created a tool
that instead of upgrading python 2 to
python 3 google created a tool
that
that compiles python 2 to go lan
[Laughter]
python 2 right on 3.
so
so you know i um so about programming
language so my recommendation that's you
know
so i talked about that um
i talked about you know
yeah so that's about that's what i think
numpy and pandas yeah those are from the
machine learning crates then they
becomes very big that's because that's
all because google 10 2010 when the
machine learning um
began you know
started by mostly google
okay
bye