good morning everyone
let's see I'm alive yes indeed and
welcome to another episode I'm exotic
show today is July 23 minutes after
midnight so this is three minutes
July 20th and today we are going to talk
about please you know the list language
the list syntax so actually I'm and I'm
not ready yet let me actually be back
yeah the lisp syntax let me show you
some of the things we're gonna talk
about so programming languages so this
yes so we're gonna talk about well yeah
at least you know Lisp language family
and this syntax and stuff let me show
you actually I need to be back in five
minutes
so this lambda two this is skim this
fantastic logo now okay so
okay let's see if do I have people zero
people good so I will be back in five
minutes
and hope to see you soon
hey guys hey Danielle
hey mister ether flow great name
so how're you guys doing
so today so we're gonna talk about Lisp
syntax this syntax sex which stands for
a symbolic expression and M expression
which stands for meta expression and
it's a fascinating fascinating topic and
right now it's midnight here so I have
to keep my voice low living apartment
cheap apartment in Mountain View
Mountain View California which is close
to San Jose and the rent is $2,200 I
share with roommates it's one bedroom a
two-bedroom $2,200
okay so let's talk about this let's see
yeah there are some things I want to
cover okay let's go to my programming
block let's begin begin at the beginning
Alice says so okay so so are you guys
ready ready so they did there is the so
racket scheme Rocky's scheme this they
are planning to ditch the parentheses
syntax you can see I don't know exactly
what's the deal yet but they have news
it's over you know it's over social
network people are talking about it they
are
you know so current leader I think is
Matthew flat he's the current leader of
racket language and they are creating
apparently they are creating a racket -
version 2 and I think so they are you
know they are thinking you know maybe
they want to change the Lisp syntax you
know normal nested parentheses or
something like that I mean they are
exploring the possibilities so you know
he is talking about it you can read it
here but you know this these people you
know this me many questions so let me
Nimish
let me write down what we gonna talk
about okay what I want to talk about so
so racket 2 is planning a new syntax ok
that's first thing then you know I'm
going going over to what what I'm going
to talk about so so talk about the mr.
namazi so rank is scheme this is
unscripted you know real-time talk so
you are seeing you know say me you know
my thought flow is walking live no
censorship no like no 5 minutes delay no
bleep of offensive words you know the if
there's any offensive what's coming out
you get it directly ok so I have quite a
few things - ok let me think
okay guys type something type something
that that invokes my you know my
enthusiasm on this subject this is you
know this you know actually this subject
is not too popular because Lisp you know
this is kind of a dying language not
many people
into it okay
let me think I wanted to talk about okay
let me just stop talking random that no
way it's actually that's more fluid
usually that way I get more things to
start to talking so anyway so this so
racket
you know racket scheme is a this
language it's a it's a branch of scheme
so let me show you
also what is racket the racket scheme is
let me show you I have a article here so
here you can see the lisp family of
languages so in 1955 you you know mock
John McCarthy he created he thought of
invented lisp now the original purpose
of lisp is sort of math based language
so this is actually the I think it is a
first language based on mathematics I
mean in a sense that they are trying to
anyway I'd anyway it says one you know
it's it's a language based on ideas of
mathematics as opposed to number
crunching for example one of the first
language that's for number crunching is
Fortran I don't remember what year is
Fortran 1950s
you know something around there so
anyway this this is one of the first or
the first math based language so you
know McCarthy John McCarthy and it's you
know the the the the reason it's
invented is partly because the
artificial intelligence research you
know it you know people we are starting
to do artificial intelligence Neil
Langan oh is Daniel Anglo is always
gives the you know some like popular
opinions I do not necessarily agree you
know it's like you hit often you hit the
spot I want to talk about
because that is exactly the topic that
does this the hot spot I want to talk
about about you know people's you know
lease VA's these first think other
people you know those people who don't
like parentheses they think those people
don't get it you know they think they
are beginners but actually that's not
true
in fact the Lisp you know you guys know
what's these parentheses right in fact
you know that these parentheses expertly
Spurs you know one up you know the the
people at the top the master of Lisp
they always you know it often it is them
they they want to create a new syntax
that's not nested parentheses because
nested parentheses has lots of have many
a few practical problems so the
practical problems of purely nested
bracket paren okay put in syntax okay
that's that's one of the issue let me
talk about that and okay so so this
begin you know in 1995 then you have
several versions you have Mac Lee's you
know interlace me you know yeah like the
few I know actually I have something you
know eMac list I know very well Emacs
Lisp is over here so it became 1987
around there okay and and Common Lisp is
one of the most popular Common Lisp and
scheme this basically this the most
popular dish today is scheme this Common
Lisp eMac this you can you know if you
want to include that it it may not it
may should not be because in my piece is
actually just a scripting language
within Emacs it's it's basically
practically useless outside of Emacs
so so scheme least common least emag
this and closure Lisp today these four
are basically the most popular you know
and in fact closure is is actually the
most popular in in actual industry you
know the closure and Emacs least in fact
if you if you count popularity Emacs
this you know if you count the number of
people who actually code code the
language eMac this is probably the most
popular because you know every a lot
there are still a lot of people using
Emacs including me and we code you know
eMac this because it's practical even
though it's not it's not really a
full-fledged programming language you
essentially you only use it within Emacs
the editor so so here's the list history
no God you know so what am I going to
talk about so so let's go back to the
you know it's go back so racket scheme
this they are they are they want to
create a new language okay so here is
the things I want to hear are the
articles I want to talk about list which
address your your comments and then your
language so one of the first thing is
the Lisp infix syntax of a so you know
like I mentioned you know a lot whispers
you know these fans these phonetics
often you know yeah typically these
fanatics they you know they think the
Lisp parentheses by the way if you guys
don't know what this look like that look
if you guys don't know what this look
like let me show you
let's see because I have a lot of Lisp
code this is what Lisp look like
so let me show you so let's go to the
beginning so this is one of my soft like
he's this package so this is what this
looks like you know it's all parentheses
for example let's go so define for
example this is a block of code and for
example this is a if statement so if
this condition is true then do this
otherwise do that you know that's so
that's this let's see if I can you know
so lots of lots of parentheses
parentheses this is parentheses hell so
and commonly scheme disclosure they all
look similar you know basically lots of
parentheses actually let me show you a
funny thing a funny picture let's see by
the way guys comments okay post your
opinions or whatever or even if you have
opinions that's different for my posted
you know post settings good to talk
about let me show you there is a very
funny picture Oh God okay so me means I
want to talk about so unleased actually
I have a here is a correction of
articles I've written about this you
know why so many because I'm I you know
I in 1990s I programmed Mathematica for
10 years you know and Mathematica is a
language it's based on Lisp and APL I'm
not going to show up here but it's based
on Lisp in APL so Mathematica you know
is actually of you you know you could
say it's a family of Lisp because
Mathematica is a list because every
every characteristics of Lisp you will
find it exactly the same I mean not
exactly but you of you'll find it in
Mathematica you know like many people
question you know the often in this
community there is a question like how
do you which you know what is Lisp
for example logo the local language the
dealain language the you know for
example local language didn't language
they are you know they don't use nested
nested parentheses syntax but however
they are actually you know the they are
based on you know they are essentially
Lisp but with a different syntax so you
know often when people debate you know
online they you know people come out
talk you know and programmers they want
to say they debate about things so we
saw exactly how you define this the way
I defined this is that you have a few
characteristics okay so let me type it
out this Lisp characteristics okay and
one is nested paren okay and symbolic
you have symbols by the way yesterday I
did a one-hour talk show that is about
this pattern matching and symbolic you
know what what's the meaning of symbolic
language Lisp and pattern matching and
this mark was yesterday so check it out
yesterday's video so what's the
characteristics of this you know when
can you say your language is this oh you
know belong to the family of these so I
would say one is nested parentheses 2 is
it must be symbolic you know it has
symbols I'm not going to explain I did
explain it yesterday and
nested so what are the other characters
what are others you guys might suggest
symbolic nested parentheses least
oriented okay that's a fundamental thing
least everything is at least and
functional programming okay so I would
say this for this these are the main
characteristics of Lisp any language if
they satisfy this fall I would say it's
Lisp
so first of all you know nested
parentheses in you know if you really
can't nested brackets let's say let's
say purely nested let's not say pure
because some you know Lisp is actually
not pure so nested brackets why do I say
bracket instead of parentheses because
Mathematica for example Mathematica you
don't use parentheses but rather you use
the square bracket everything is you
know whole the whole thing is nested
brackets in fact the syntax is 100% pure
nested brackets it's even more pure than
than this because Lisp has several
exceptions I'm going to show you okay
let's talk about surety of nested
brackets okay Mathematica versus Lisp
leaf syntax is actually not pure okay
not not pure or regular okay let's
that's one thing we cannot talk it so
anyway this so we cannot talk about so
these characteristics these okay then
let's talk about pure nested brackets
yeah let's let's talk about it let me
show you why this is not 100% maker the
syntax so
so let's go back to fundamental problems
of Lisp okay this Arco now you see
so in general when we think of Lisp we
think of everything like this you know
so you have parentheses then you have F
a function name then you have arguments
so everything is like parentheses you
know each item in the parentheses maybe
another parentheses you know nested so
typically we think of Lisp syntax as
that you know sometimes you hear at
least per se this has no syntax you know
that's silly
every language has a syntax and and so
so we typically we think of this as lab
but actually it's more than that it's
irregular it's not regular for example
comments least comments is like that
it's based on starting with a semicolon
and ending with a new line
that's not nested parentheses now you
look at this this is called a cone cell
cancer you know your parentheses thing
you have a dot now that dad is not a
symbol it's not you know any character
it must be your thought you know like
two items and in between your dot that's
called can say okay that's not regular
that's because then suddenly you got
these dot as part of the syntax you know
it's you know so it's not regular then
you have this quote syntax okay you put
this you put this tick ' you know in
front of parentheses that's not regular
and then you have back tick now you if
you if you don't know Lisp you I'm not
going to explain this is this you know
language detail but anyway you have this
backtick basically essentially it means
okay you have this tactic okay then
inside the parenthesis you have comma in
front of a symbol so essentially what it
means is that when you have a back tick
in
means hold evaluation of the following
expression
you know don't evaluate it except at
places where there's a coma so when you
have this that means don't evaluate
don't evaluate the X here but to
evaluate the X over here because there's
a comma in front this is called what
does this code I'm not sure I forgot the
name backwards you know anyway so anyway
you have this syntax backward with coma
that's not regular okay then you have
coma with the @ sign you know like this
that's not regular okay then you have we
have to the vector data type right
that's right yeah the vector data type
then you have you know square bracket so
I'm not going to and and this you know
these all these so far we talked about
happens in Emacs Lisp and Common Lisp
you know and also I'm not sure in scheme
this you know some of them may be
different but anyway at least it happens
in common this email is okay then you
have in scheme lists you have others
okay so my point here is that this
syntax is irregular okay contrary to
most people you know this think this
first think so so so we've talked about
we talked about okay how this syntax is
not pure okay let's see
we covered that then I'm going to tell
you I'm going to show you okay first of
all it's not pure and so what's the
problem I mean so so there's a
significance of the consequence I give
some examples for example in my opinion
it's confusing
it breaks syntax semantics
correspondence you know Lisp
whispers usually like to say Oh in Lisp
you know data is program programs data
you know the idiotic okay
the the reason in this view have this
code home homeo iconicity okay the
reason of that is actually not because
this was something it's the heart of
that property is because the syntax is
hundred percent regular for example
another example is XML okay that is the
thing it's not because of the data or
your data is program programs data
that's actually that's not undefined you
know you will not find a you will not
find a you know a precise definition of
that concept in in the context of list
you know you can go to Wikipedia homie
iconicity
you know they will try to define it but
the way they define then you will see
that assembly language also qualified
your you have a bunch of languages
that's not you know Nestle parenthesis
they all qualify us homeo iconicity
factor programmers jargon
let's look it up
I can't Nisa T whom you know I can't
miss this term start to became popular
around 2008 you know around that there
it is you know you can go and read
Wikipedia about that but I am going to
you know talk about that homey like
Arnie City okay but but basically if you
look at that you you will see let me
show you you see so all these languages
qualified Julia prologue you know repo
red snowball you know
Leticia XSLT so it basically is CeCe's
it stops becoming what you like to
believe you know Lizbeth they like to
believe you know that nested bracket
qualify but by this definition you can
see it they don't you know you become
something else then you know so anyway
so I explained so what so I'm going to
eat so this syntax is actually not pure
okay not regular okay I explained that
let me explain
then we also explained homeo iconicity
okay okay let me let me do this Romeo
iconicity the property the list property
often phrased as program is data is
called Romeo Akane City this is actually
yo defined okay you define and this term
this term became popular around 2008
something like that okay and and it's yo
defined if you look at Wikipedia you
know then you will see you see that lots
of other languages not based on nested
bracket also qualify as
homeo icon homie iconic okay iconic okay
that's that's one thing we okay so
that's that's one thing we explained
okay now the next item pure so-so are
they are languages that's you know we we
have showed that this syntax is actually
not regular because because of you have
the you know these all these
irregularities and we also explain homeo
iconicity the heart of the heart of the
concept program is data is actually the
heart of the lisp concept program is
data is actually due to regularity of
nested syntax now this is my opinion
okay I you know you know sometimes you
know I may wonder you know if this is
like you know you may question you see
you know are you just cooking up things
you know it's it's up to you to decide
okay so in my opinion that the heart you
know because I I'm not a renowned you
know computer scientist so when I say
something that's contrary you know
people doubt it but but the in my
opinion I tell you the heart of the list
concept program is data you know data is
program that is actually due to that
property is due to the regularity of
nested parentheses as syntax okay not
not anything else not not do anything
else
okay so so let's talk about so so what
language so okay before we talk about
Mathematica there is also so so what's
wrong with irregular syntax and what's
Oh
for example I show you the UM you know I
talked about several issues with the
irregular syntax you know so and and I
talked you know in these articles I
talked about the advantage of pure 100%
regular syntax for example one of the
quality I mean one of the good thing
about that is you know program is data
you know Dana is program like XML okay
XML around 2000 you know throughout year
mm it's very popular idea but it got
killed by HTML 5 which is not good okay
but anyway so the advantage of 100% pure
nested syntax one of them is that you
have the program as data idea okay you
an intern you can do symbolic pattern
matching like computer algebra we talked
about yesterday
and also you have Universal formatting
okay for example like go format okay
universal automated you know and and
also you have the property of syntaxes
markup language you you you could do
that for example what what do you mean
syntax is markup language for example
HTML you know or XHTML whole math ml
that you know when you have a purely
nested syntax it becomes easy to use the
syntax as a markup language it becomes
simple okay so anyway so side we talked
about soul in so linked so lists Lisp
language syntax is not regular we can we
have seen examples so what our language
Mathematica you know it it is a language
whose syntax is hundred percent nested
you know no irregularity it's it's for
example let me show you
example okay
let me show you an example here so you
can see here is an example of
mathematical code look at this section
okay
you can see everything everything is in
this form okay everything you know F
square bracket then whatever inside
whatever inside is nested you know F
square bracket whatever F square bracket
whatever and they may be separated by
coma so in Lisp you you separate items
by your space but in Mathematica you
separate items by a coma in Lisp you
start a expression with a parenthesis in
Mathematica you know with a parenthesis
in this view start expression with a
parenthesis and the first item is a
function name now in Mathematica you you
begin with the function name then
followed by a square bracket then you
know nesting so that's the difference
you kind of add swap you you take the
Lisp you know the this function name you
take it outside the parenthesis then you
change the parenthesis to a square
bracket and you change any space to a
coma
that becomes Mathematica syntax okay now
this is Mathematica syntax you can code
it Mathematica this way if you want but
actually nobody does that
so and okay my point here is that
Mathematica syntax you see this is pure
there's no exceptions there's no here
you put a back you know you back you put
a apostrophe for quote oh there you put
a you know there's nothing like that
so that's you know that's an example of
the pure MF Mecca syntax okay now the
next thing I want to talk about yeah
here's the important thing I want to
talk about before we do that so you know
you see Mathematica syntax there they
are isomorphic to the Lisp you know
syntax imagine a pure 100% pure Lisp
syntax without you know without all
these irregularities if you have that
then Mathematica syntax is isomorphic to
the list
syntax meaning that for example this
madman this Mathematica code you can
transform it to the list code like this
so you know if if we imagine it's Lisp
it would look like this you know you
just you take the any function name you
move it inside you know the bracket you
know like that and you you know you
change the you know square bracket to
parenthesis and you replace the comma
sign by a space then you have that so
you see this two isomorphic you know in
math we say isomorphic because there is
a one-to-one correspondence you know so
so one big thing I want to talk about is
the sex and what is M exp okay meta
expression 6 and mental expression
that's one thing I want to talk about
okay before I do that let me read the
comments oh my god I've been talking for
40 minutes already haven't think I
haven't digging yet
so so yeah Daniel says I can explain
the main reason why people hate least
complete ignorance of release is the
reason that's not true that's totally
not true okay let me address that right
away so you know anyway so this you know
because I was trying to do some kind of
more organized but usually random chat
is I get if I do random check chad
usually the flow continues so oh yeah so
why so so we have this page I I did a
survey of this infix syntax so he you
know in this community especially
communities many seasoned whispers hold
idea that those who dislike these nested
parentheses syntax outsiders you know
who don't get this that is incorrect
factually incorrect so this page lists
list lists Lisp projects or languages
that implement alternative syntax to
solve the controversial nested
parentheses problem okay so I you know I
you know throughout history that list
history you there you are many many
people you know at least experts you
know people in this community they want
they need because there is a need the
because why nested parentheses you know
it's got practical problems let me talk
about that first what is the the
practical problems of purely purely
nested syntax okay so what is the
problem for example if you want to do
mathematics you know for example three
plus five
you know let's say squared
seven you know suppose you want to do
that in this it gets you know it's
unreadable you know this this just you
know as simple as this one it becomes
unbeatable in fact I have many articles
on that let me just pull up example
somewhere here okay let's go to
phenomena problems of now let's go to
yeah yeah okay the concepts and
confusions of prefix infix postfix and
Lisp notations now this article discuss
the differences or the history or the
kind of math background of these
different notations what they mean so
you can see we have you know a picture
here example but right now what I want
to say is that oh yeah so so I want to
say that you know the least nest purely
nested syntax has you know some
practical problems one one the most
obvious one is that when you want to do
a lot math for example you know the the
quadratic formula you know in any any
formula becomes unreadable when you
write it them in the Lisp style for
example I have let's see
well I I have it some article in okay
where is the Annika the meaning of
operators okay let's let's search sorry
the meaning of operators okay in that
article I have example showing you how
okay I have two articles here this one
is what's the definition of operator in
computer languages now that's an
interesting article in fact you know
there is actually no definition of
operator in computer languages they each
one differ there is no precise
definition that's interesting article
but it's not really you know it's it's
another thing to what we are talking
about we so here what's the function
what's the operator so okay so here you
see examples me being over here so you
see here example of traditional notation
using operators okay and yeah so you can
see so here let me show you where
okay there is another article actually
not this one
oh okay here no ads so here is
the list the expression this is a
quadratic formula in this week's
depression you see it's not readable but
if you okay anyway so so what so what is
we talking about so yeah so here is
about the practical problems of purely
misfit syntax this is this is the main
problem because you know this is the
main problem when you do math this
syntax is you know not readable for
example like like in Emacs
you know you have calculators you know
calculator everyone needs to use you
know every Mac OS you have a calculator
windows you have one you know people
need to calculate groceries
and in and you know the way I do it I
usually don't use those calculators
instead I just open up for example
JavaScript for example save it in you
know I open a file in JavaScript and if
I want to compute I just say three plus
four and run it you know that's how I do
calculators you know three plus four
minus 10 times 20 for example that's how
I you know this way the advantage of
this you have because it's because you
have an editor you know you can change
things you see the whole history and you
can do variations you know if you want
for example - 2100 you know this is how
I took mean you don't want where I want
the calculator so I'm using javascript
right now you see but for some times I
was using Python and for some time you
know I thought you know let's just use
these
you know for example Emacs Lisp because
in eMac this I can at anytime I can you
know compute without opening for example
3 + 5 ok evaluate that we see 8 in the
bottom you see 8 so you know I thought
let's just use it this but it's
impractical because for example if you
want to do this ok then you have to O 3
plus 4 then - ok - 10 then you have to
okay yeah you have to actually wait the
whole thing you have to say times then
27 you see you see so that on a second
so for example let's do that so let's
let's Wendy's ok Wendy's JavaScript what
is the answer negative 193 okay now
let's try the Beast
okay the syntax is wrong I mean yeah ok
so 3 plus 4 minus 1000 K 3 plus 4 minus
10 okay - 10 x 20 so this is actually
should be 10 times 20 so the whole thing
should be like that so let's run it
193 you see so you can see it's it's
problematic you know it's impractical so
that is the that is the let me get this
okay so that is the example okay example
this okay
the example in JavaScript okay
is that in this is okay for example that
is the practical problem of the nested
syntax one of the problem they are this
is a main problem there are other small
problems and okay okay so yeah okay
green deck says what about calculate you
know kak mod which is a very popular
utility in Emacs I don't use that I used
that I used to use it 10 years ago you
know before you know but I stopped using
that because the email you know we are
digressing but let me talk about that
for the Emacs CAC CAC mod is very
popular it was the most actually the
most advanced piece of software in the
entire computing history ok this this is
in nineteen let's say 1990s ok it's it's
actually the most advanced one let's say
one of the top ten most of advanced
piece of software but as time moves on
you know
hakamada's you know stays that way and
basically Emacs just stagnate it's
stagnated anyway so I don't use that
because because today you know since
let's say five years ago you can use
JavaScript Python you know you have much
far more flexibilities than using kaak
kaak mod you know like I mentioned
before you know like it's let's do this
okay so that's JavaScript code that's
email is okay for example okay let's say
javascript okay so javascript you know
if I want to do sine cosine you know I
can I can start to code you know math
pie you know I can in other words you
know I can load libraries I can do
algebra what you know it not not so much
in JavaScript but in Python for example
I can you know you know when you talk
about your Python packages for doing
math or more advanced algebra it's far
more powerful than then and also
the other advantages is that when you
have a code you know instead instead of
using hoc Mart which is like a
calculator but rather you write code it
is small much more flexible you know you
can keep a history and so on and another
advantage is that you can learn the
language you you know for example you
just picked up a new language let's say
Judea whole app whatever you know you
can learn it so anyway so that's this is
so so I got I haven't got to the main
point I want to talk about which is M
expression that is that is actually that
that's the the more important more
interesting but okay so let's see what
we've talked about this syntax is
actually not pure okay
and the list property often called
programs data okay we talked about that
and purely nested brackets for example
Mathematica okay and and then the
practical problems of nested syntax
okay let's that's what we just covered
then we also covered why not use
okay because it's simpler
more flexible because because using a
real programming language such as Python
is simpler more flexible more powerful
ok calc has not been updated for like
over 10 years I mean they still maintain
it but the features and it's it's not
you know not not today today is not good
ok we covered that so let's talk about 6
and what is M M expression actually let
me read the comments first ok so oh yeah
so daniel says why people you know so I
talked about the so yeah so at least you
know the nested parentheses actually so
you got problems and almost every year
you know this whispers they have they
have tried to create an alternative
expression in fact the least invented
John McCarthy when he created least you
know when he got idea he wanted you know
there are two syntax one is s expression
which is nested parentheses you know we
are used to it it's called you know the
S stand for symbolic symbolic expression
and the other syntax is called M
expression that's that stands for meta
expression now John McCarthy never
actually fully specified what M
expression is going to be like but today
on Wikipedia you can see some of the
historical documents and discussion what
is kind of like ok it's never specified
fully as far as I know
so actually but it was never actually
implemented because people started to
use s expression and they'd like it you
know so any expression is kind of you
know according to Wikipedia it's
indefinite you know it's put into
indefinite delay you know it just never
picked up but the important thing to
know is that actually John McCarthy the
the alternative syntax is actually his
idea that is not is part of this okay
then you have you know 1973 you know all
these people are well-known computer
scientists because I looked up you know
history so this guy created G G he
created C gol Segal is an alternative
syntax for the Mac Lisp programming
language okay by this guy funk and
Ronald Pratt okay his his you know the
oldies are computer scientists the you
know and then you have Mathematica you
know we're known today because Wolfram
Alpha
you know wolf and research Stefan goofin
so then you have you have didn't which
is you know you have lot I'm not going
to go through so so what so what's the
point the point here is that you know
Lisbeth you know they they think you
know so why why are lispers have this
force you know idea about how this
should be nested parentheses and how
anyone criticized it is you know
beginner that you know lispers like to
say oh you know beginners always think
you know they should have alternative it
syntax until you know later on then they
finally got list then you know they
accept the next a parenthesis that's
just okay that's totally untrue
and okay so so that so so that's about
that okay and I'm going to talk about
meta expression okay let's talk about
meta expression so so so you know meta
expression is the idea from the list
inventor but he never got implemented
except it's done in Mathematica
okay Mathematica has that you know
Mathematica you know if you read Stephan
Wolfram you know he created Mathematica
the history you know that the the the
Mathematica you know is based on Lisp
and APL language APL is the API is
language with lots of the weird syntax
let me show you it's not sure it I don't
have time today so what time is it 15
hour already
so guys type something okay type type so
what I want to say yeah ami expression
okay so so in Mathematica Wolfram
steppenwolf I'm he he actually
implemented M expression so before like
we showed before this is mathematical
expression okay this is purely nested
you know pure there's no exceptions you
know you start with a symbol then
bracket square bracket then whatever
separated by comma okay this is
Mathematica expression but but
Mathematica and syntax actually it's
they have what's called so what is ami
expression so so this one the the nested
syntax you see it's like Lisp you know
it's you know in this view code sex but
in Mathematica this expression you call
it full form
okay full form
meaning you know it's fully spelled out
full form but Mathematica offers an
alternative Mathematica syntax is
actually like equipped they have a layer
they have the M expression layer so this
code you see here you know start with
the set D weight can be written like
this exactly can be written like this
these two are syntactically equivalent
now this is a critical idea okay they
are syntactically equivalent but meaning
that any part of this expression in any
part of mathematical expression can be
transformed into the M expression you
know so in other words you can say it
can be transformed between sex versus MX
they can be transformed by just pressing
a button in the editor I don't have
Mathematica installed here but but
Mathematica you know editor looks like
that notepad okay so so this is code so
so in this you have the idea sex and M
expression but in Mathematica they
actually did that but they don't call
that you know they don't cause you know
sex and and they deco it you know the
full form this is full form and this is
called input form okay and any part of
it can be transformed to the other by
just pressing a button you know you you
can select part of it for examples for
example this this part squared you know
two numbers square root of two numbers
you can select it press a button and it
becomes this you see let me get rid of
you see so you can start to see how they
correspond you know they get so they can
be transformed on the fly because they
aren't seen tactically equivalent they
are let me name mention another thing so
so you have in Mathematica you have the
full foam which is like sex sex then you
have the input form which is like M
expression okay they can be you know
they are isomorphic they can be
transformed you know any part or the
whole thing all the whole entire source
code you again you can select the entire
source code like ten thousand lines
press a button they can be transformed
into full form or input form or standard
form they have another form you can see
this they look like two dimensional
traditional math notations they are
rendered into two dimensional
traditional method notations now this
form is called Mathematica cause it
cause it standard form so again any of
these forms can be transformed into each
other you know on the fly the standard
for me is a bit special because they it
requires rendering because you know it's
like tech it's two-dimensional it's you
know it's not on the other hand the full
form and the input form are just
sequence of characters so so that's
Mathematica you know it's very
so that's Mathematica so the important
thing I want to talk about is the
equivalence the meaning of syntactic
equivalence and the meaning of sugar
syntax there's a huge confusion among
programmers about sugar syntax okay let
me let me show let me write it down here
the the confusion of the confusion of
the concept sugar syntax
and the meaning of syntactic Cree he
creeped lens okay so that is the thing
I'm going to talk about so let me
actually let me read the comments okay
maybe I talk about Tim a minute saying
that that will be it for today it's kind
of late here so hold on a second let me
let me read the comments so some people
who use rainbow four indices highlight
into this yeah so yeah yeah I tried
rainbow parentheses side I didn't find
it particularly necessary you know I I I
find it this this way is fine you know
you just highlight the parent yeah the
the issue you know the I mean every you
know everyone has opinions you can use
the rainbow parent I don't use it
because for me I think the you have so
many colors it's actually not not easy
to see which one matches what as as one
would imagine you know I would imagine
when I first discovered that you know
rainbow oh it's great because you can
immediately see which one correspond to
which but it turns out it's not that
simple
I mean yeah so that's just my opinion
so Daniel says this without parent comes
up pretty regularly and never catches on
I've learned to love the parents okay
yeah that's my you know one of my points
oh so you see this racket to people you
know they the you know the racket to
people they wanted to you know they are
trying to think of alternative syntax
for racket to you know you know this so
you know it happened you know it's
happened again
and so does this one thing I don't
understand you know because because
because to me the the issues you know
all these firsts about these syntax in
alternative alternative syntax to me it
seems to me can be easily solved by a
dot adopting you know the idea of syntax
layer that is M expression you know you
have sex it's a similar expression you
have M expression the way Mathematica is
done to me
you know Mathematica solve the problem
in the most elegant way so I do not
understand you know all these you know
many of these are you know these experts
in computer scientist I do not
understand why they you know they do not
you know what what is their thought
about this you know what why didn't they
were to adopt the idea of you know ami
expression you know syntax layers you
know so and today you know the racket to
people you know today is led by Mathew
flat you know he's you know he's a
professor and you know computer
scientist so I don't understand so you
know I want to ask him you know like I
want to him he asked him you know why
didn't you thought you know what do you
think about you know the meta expression
layer you know as John McCarthy suggests
you know but it's difficult because I
cannot you know it's difficult to get
the answer because I cannot just go ask
him because he you know in this
community community he doesn't know who
I am and in this community you know
anyway so but anyways all these people
the racket researchers you know they
must you know a lot of them must know
they must be a way of us for sure you
know they and many of them
first you know no mathematica they have
the experience but why didn't they
what's you know why didn't you know the
Emmy expression get you know adopt that
what why didn't they
but before we talk about em expression I
want to emphasize the idea of syntactic
equivalence you know that's that is part
of the M expression as implemented in
Mathematica it is important to know you
see this when you see this and this it's
important to emphasize understand that
these are syntactically equivalent that
that means that means the underlying
structure is still this you know there
is no like when the compiler sees
Mathematica code the first step is to
transform everything into the full form
you know into the symbolic the nested
paren
you know think so so in so so this so so
we could say this this is a sugar syntax
this is the sugar syntax in the most
purest form now let me explain this is
important because many people got it
wrong because for example so for example
in Python let me explain the concept of
sugar syntax and meaning of syntactic
equivalence for example x equals to 3
versus x equals to 3 with our space in
between the equal that's same tactical
equivalent in main in most languages
because you know the space doesn't
matter and for example this quote X
versus
this is a backtick X those are syntactic
syntactically equivalent because when
these compilers sees these it before it
tries to find out what it means it
syntactically turns that into a list
like this so they are syntactically
equivalent now let me show you so what's
a example of not same tactic equivalent
for example in C you have C you have I
press plus vs. I equals to I plus 1 now
in C language or Cephas press you have
that you know see I plus first oh I
equal to I plus 1 that is not
syntactically equivalent because it
tells the compiler it actually do
different things but but even to us you
know the outcome the effective outcome
is usually the same that's the key thing
you know he is the key they are not
saying actually equivalent when
something when two syntax are
syntactically equivalent that means they
have they are hundred percent
semantically equivalent to because when
the compiler tries to pass it you know
it just transform one to the other so
there's no it's the same thing exactly
the same thing 100% but on the other
hand for example this C thing is not
it's not the same and let me show you
another example another example in
JavaScript in JavaScript
let's say function f X something okay
versus versus F equals two function X
okay here is the example in JavaScript
these two are not syntactically
equivalent even though most of the time
they have exactly the same effect so
this is the important thing about sugar
syntax you know sugar syntax is a
popular term so people you know a lot of
people think oh this is just the sugar
sugar syntax of that oh this this is
just sugar syntax of that oh this you
know but there's a distinction you know
some of them are syntactically
equivalent at the syntax level you know
before the compiler do anything you know
they just transform them to the same
thing and on the other hand many syntax
shortcuts they are totally not you know
syntactically equivalent so so back to
Mathematica so I was saying so he math
America this you know this full form of
sex and this M expression or you know
the input from they are all these three
are seen tactically equivalent that's
the important thing to get you know
anyway let me read the comment and I
think that's it for today because I've
been talking for actually an hour in 15
minutes okay so let's see so this seems
to have too many useless names in it
space not very example if for example
truck in versus block by the way there's
also Park in one in this you know in
email is let's see if I can show you
that
one okay yeah so you can see you
see there's a frog one here's the here's
the documentation you know
so anyway by the way in math America you
have the same thing for example pranking
in Mathematica is is that okay so in
this you have fog something something
code in Mathematica is called I am
pretty sure if I recall correctly its
compound expression data
so this traces back to what I was saying
so the if you find the characteristics
of Lisp you know being a symbolic for
nested brackets a function of
programming and what's the other
characteristics I mentioned nested
brackets symbolic list oriented
functional programming if every item is
in Mathematica you know as you've seen
nested brackets in Mathematica symbolic
check in Mathematica is just like this
every every identify is actually a
symbol you can get you know you can
quote them in Mathematica you don't say
quote you say hold or you say
unevaluated you know any and you know
hold form or hold and at least oriented
you know we've seen you know in
Mathematica everything is a list like
this you know this set evade is this is
this giant list and this vector angle is
you know this you know based in
functional programming you know just
like Lisp but Mathematica is not pure
functional language just like this you
know you can do loop you can assign
values and so on
so anyway Soviets so I think let's wrap
up yeah I think we've already actually
that we covered all the things you know
most of the things I want to talk about
today so um so Danielle says Lisa seems
to have too many useless names okay and
Daniel says if you don't like Caron
cutter right first and rest and said Q
is pretty nasty and harder to avoid okay
so what about con queso mathematical
code design is elegant so so but symbols
are global and there is no lexical scope
which is which does not scale that's not
true
I mean depends on what you mean the in
Mathematica for example I have encoded
Mathematica for 10 years but in
Mathematica for example you say module I
can you know I can actually still
remember the syntax because I could it's
for so much for example body so this
this is the mathematical syntax this is
equivalent to lisps let okay this is
equivalent for example XY and these two
are equivalent now now you may complain
this to I equivalent okay but however
the math math the way Mathematica
implement this lexical scope is by his
by actually rewrite it rewrites these
variable names into a global variable
name in other words it will create a
global variable name name something like
that okay and you know some random
number that's how that's how Mathematica
implemented this now in this actually
it's similar
it's similar you have you know just just
like Mathematica you have a you have the
how what's the core symbol table there's
a name yeah you know anyway and I'm not
going to go into detail there let's see
we can go to yes so go to my email list
and you can see it is symbol topic so we
cover this symbol this special form
what's a function so let's go to this
symbol and you can see we talk about
single thing we talk about
there is a thing I want to find
a beret yeah that's a word
Harper Lee hop hop array in Lisp I think
also comedies is basically a table of
symbols like every symbol you ever used
is in a beret not every technically but
vast majority so you know in a similar
way you know similar weight you know
Mathematica is that anyway so
okay yeah that's true I think that's it
for today because I've talked long
anything else what's up um if you
Internet is applied mathematics
okay yeah so my you know for me the
question I have is you know you said I
really want to ask you know the racket
to people you know these computer
scientists you know why what do they
think you know why is not any expression
a you know good solution I don't really
understand so anyway yeah that's it for
today so thank you guys for watching so
if you haven't said how yet say hi you
know if you if you like my stuff you
know go to my website and any page
there's you know I got paid wrong you
know patreon paper Hawaiians you know
put money in my box so I see you guys
have a good day