good morning good morning everyone
welcome to another episode ofan talk
show hello so today we are going to code
some emac list coding randomish okay so
ask your questions ask your questions
and we I'm going to we are going to
unbox this new camera I got this is more
coose unbox it and uh some emac L coding
and some random chat random chat okay
hello guys good morning everyone so
let's begin good morning Juan good
morning
Hank uh my keyboards glove 80 fantastic
ultimate hacking keyboard fantastic this
is newly trackable now this is my main
input mousing device fantastic and this
is Logitech Logitech uh
g502 the best thing about this is the
sping wheel okay so let my devices and
don't
forget I'm still going to cover this
this is SM board SV b o a r d good
morning Mark Jefferson Smartboard okay
so you have to wait so let's begin okay
so let's why don't we unbox this thing
okay more course let me show you what
that
is so switch camera so you can see my
screen yes yes yes yes yes so go go to
my em you see I'm switching window
without old X just by track fantastic I
talked about these two videos ago so
showing browser more coose camera so
this one so this one the purpose of this
camera is so that you can you know I can
put it up here so you can see my
keyboard clearly right now you cannot so
you see
this web lousy webcam I mean Logitech
you know it's got problem focusing and
stuff
you know so anyway so unbox let's unbox
this
okay this I think it's
$130 you know if you really want a good
camera they cost like 5 600 you know
it's hard to shop for one because I
really want you know I don't need huge
megapixels I just want a simple like I
would say
$200 camera that allows me to have clear
view shop view of my keyboard as for my
face it doesn't matter much but you know
if you you know there are thousands of
keyboard reviewers on Amazon and they
all have crispy
videos and you know so I try to look at
what camera they use they are all like
[ __ ]
600700 okay so the mco's camera is you
know what they call industrial camera so
you know it's not a kind of industrial
so you got what is this so this is a
thake
USB uh
USB code you know USB you know the the
the the the standard
connection MOS device uh uh okay MOS C
100 manual let see okay this looks like
this is a used I mean this is not you
know uh
bad
Omen
yeah you know so it looks like that so
I've been looking at Amazon reviews but
um well so Amazon reviews and you know
they have a lot fake reviews so oh it's
a bit
heavy let's
see I can twist this off so this is a
fixed focus
camera oh okay so you got you know so
this is a fixed focus camera so you plug
USB here and or HDMI you see this is a
problem with the
Logitech 920 something you know
so
uh so it doesn't you know it doesn't
have a viewfinder or any screen
there and so this thing you just twist
it on
what is this so yeah the lens so
supposedly you can I mean you can switch
the lens you know the for the
photographers photography photographers
are the most lowlevel idiots you know
you go to YouTube there are tons of them
like it's like the lowest level thing
it's like a gym workout or Diet you know
what what my diet is this meat or no
meat or eggs you know the low lowest
level uh bottom of society then you have
camera photographers you know they will
talk about oh what lens is this you know
you you need to switch lens or single
you know reflective lens or whatnot
idiots extreme there is tons of it for
like 15 years by now so anyway this is a
fixed focus camera so it's not
autofocus you see one problem with
autofocus is that they you know they
constant you know
swoosh in and out okay you cannot see it
clearly this is stupid architect oh
there it is so anyway you supposed to
twist this for you know Focus shutter
speed or whatever I have read a turn
about you know photography but if you
don't really have a good camera you
really don't get into like programming
you know if you want to do
programming uh just by reading it
doesn't do you any good or mathematic
so you actually if you want to learn
programming you really have to get hands
on so likewise so
anyway and on the other side you have
the the power plugin and a memory
card okay so I'm going to stick this
into here hopefully so next time you
know my video will have great I hope so
great um
videos comments comments comments in
questions let's
see Hello Matty hey good to see you good
to see you guys crispy Mr you are
already very crispy not
really so they got a remote
control you know so also by the way I've
been watching I discover
ChatterBait Jesus 1,000 1 million girls
beautiful girls young girls spreading
their legs so chatter bait you know so
that's one thing that's the thing most
of you guys are the first thing that's
what you guys think about but when I
look at chatbate there's lots of other
things to look into you look for example
camera you know I want to buy a camera
so what all these girls are using and
You Know You observe you know how how
they have autofocus on now they they you
know most of them are so
sharp uh anyway so
and I I suppose you know I I suppose
half of them are using good cameras like
costing 500 600
dollar um
anyway okay that's about that this
unboxing of this
mocos thing okay we'll see how it goes
so you are saying my my camera video is
all already quisp not
really because you see it's not sharp
really anyway let's get to what else so
you ask questions I answer okay
otherwise I'm going to start to code
emac
this okay so here is my co camera uh you
know I have blog on my U so here is my
like Research into
camera you know since like two years ago
you spent hours and hours you know
watching YouTube that there are 10,000
YouTube camera reviews you know hours
and hours
and uh anyway you you see if you have
money then you don't worry about it you
see but if you don't have money you you
kind of you know you don't want to
return it um
anyway so cameras what else okay so last
talk show we talked about last talk show
is the wolam
language animation generator and
geometry pling curves fantastic now I'm
here to tell you the code is now on
GitHub okay so you go to SAR GitHub just
search for let let's do it here okay SAR
GitHub and go to S GitHub the code is
right there let's turn JavaScript so
that Google knows where you are what you
do uh there it is and is W mod planker
plot uh so those are fantastic packages
okay uh repositories I just added this
yesterday in fact I you know I added two
two of them but anyway so here it is
planker
generators uh and let me show you here
fantastic okay so you can get a code
free fantastic all these animations you
see this is like the radar the sonar
radar of sub
submarine you know in order to
appreciate this you need to know polar
equations okay
mathematics you know whenever I
see you know space ship or technology or
quantum computers I consider you know
that's what I
do because you have to know all this
code you know this like millions of
people's
contribution made made all this
possible uh so anyway so this package is
now on GitHub free okay now close this
close it wol FR language W from desktop
okay what uh so imag LP
next can you understand
ebonics I know what that word means that
word is you know the black community
created that word
ionic to refer to black
people you know black people black
people in America is quite controvers
controversial you know since they've
been they talk about it forever you know
since 30 years ago so you know this
first you know for ionics for example
one of the things about the naming how
do you call black people what is the
proper way so some you
know you know the most natural is just
black black people because they their
skin is black okay there's no bad
connotation whatsoever it's just black
people and white people and yellow
people okay red red skin red skin is the
American Indians you know that's the
natural reference but then you know they
they they created the politicians you
know a lot of these involving
politics uh you know trying to G power
and uh and and and tactics you know like
the like the grifter you know grifting
scam you know uh so anyway so you know
they decided some people decided you
know we need to usually it's white
people you know because the white people
they control usually the control they
they are the power in America so they
created typically or usually beginning
in Academia okay so some Professor
created oh we should call them African
Americans African
amans uh and then then then there's
ionic I believe because what how do I
know because I look up words you
know uh I'm have interest in vocabulary
so I talked about this before so you can
go to whaty English blog and you have
English vocabulary 5,000 words of
English par parah bestowed Insidious
restive
agundiz Mis misanthropy now this this
this this one is popular today in the
past 10 years nefarious you know so i i
i l words I study words that's how I
learn English English since
1986 so then there's g words
unflappable unflappable anathema okay
let's say random
order
modelin commant
vernacular so ionic is kind of
vernacular okay you could say
technically I don't know estimate uh
estimable estimable okay so each one has
a you know example when I read it you
know that's my habit you know every time
you read whatever when you see a word
you don't know you write it down so I've
been doing this since 1986 that's how I
learned English the way I learned
English is very inefficient I I told
this story before like three or four
years AO ago when I first started to do
YouTube but let me tell it again since
it's long ago so the way I learned
English is like my mindset is like
the um Bru Force nerd you know like the
you know the Brute Force you know to
learn a language all you have to know is
just the vocabulary just know every word
so when I started to learn English
around
1986 my methodology my thinking is that
I'm just going to boot Force I'm going
to I'm going to know more words than any
English professors but simply just look
up every word in the dictionary and
memorize it that's literally how I
learned English so in the first 10 uh in
the first 20 years you know when I was
younger the first 20 years of my life
every day I look up you know at least in
the first 10 years I look up
dictionaries back then you don't have
digital you know there's no internet so
you have a thick you know I I got the
thick uh English to Chinese dictionary I
I look
up more than 100 times a day 100 words
you know so to the point that pick any
English word for example me I can I can
open the dictionary right on that that
page 95% of time you know that that's
this thick in fact I have a document
document of it uh documentary
okay how to increase your vocabulary so
there is this digital dictionary when it
first came out in 1988 I bought it
because I'm a big dictionary obsessive
dictionary fan and encyclopedia I talked
about this quite a few times in my live
stream so 1998 when this dictionary
digital dictionary came out I bought it
right away
I think it's $300 I was working in a
bakery and so here is the English
Chinese dictionary so that's about uh
about this you know basically that's the
biggest one at the time you know
1986 this one is from Taiwan Far East
English Chinese dictionary the biggest
one so I can open it like any word I I
do it once right on the page
so uh yeah that's how I learn English
Okay so yeah back to ebonics so
ebonics question do you consider
yourself American I am American
okay I am American citizen and
also all my life is you know all my
adult life uh since since when I was 16
okay when I was 16 I was in Canada but
since
1989 I live in California basically
where I am today you know so all my you
know so do I consider myself American I
am
American you know it's funny so American
you know
like like this this is about racial
issue you know because you don't you
know if when you when you are not a
white man this this even if you are
American but they but the white people
they don't treat you exact exactly
there's a difference okay anyway maybe
we shouldn't get into
that chick
Ching chist am is that Christ or chist
thank you two 20 pounds British pounds
heavy thank you eonic okay uh EB o n i
CX okay so let's look up dictionary you
know key press emac the power of emac ch
ch ch and there it is
ionics and so let's see what the the
proper definition okay
ionic now used with singular verb okay
any of the nonstandard varieties of in
English spoken by African Americans oh
okay oh that's technically what it means
but I thought it just refers to black
people uh I'm pretty sure there's also
that meaning here so um black English
okay uh Linguistics us another name for
africanamerican vernacular English okay
uh it's a silly
name okay so what uh now so what is this
the thorus okay so
anyway so let's look up uh Brave let's
see what Brave say ionic word English
put M two of words money and phonetics
is a term that was originally intended
to refer to the language of all people
descended from African descent
particularly in West Africa the
Caribbean and the North America the term
ionic was created in
1973 now it's interesting let's see the
Orient of the
word 1973 by group of black Scholars oh
who
disproved of the negative terms being
used to describe this type of
language okay since the N since the 1996
controversy over it's used by the
Oakland School Board yeah controversy
like the you know every day in USA it's
you know uh yonic has primarily been
used to refer to the social elect
African ameran English yeah a dialect
distinctively different from standard
American English
okay uh eonic well okay that's
that H says you didn't cover binary
Lambda calculus yet have you heard of
it no I haven't heard of it but I heard
I I think I saw you post a video about
it but I think it's pretty much [ __ ]
you know it's it's one of the niche like
not that important I mean it's um that's
my guess okay I I I can tell you pretty
sure that's probably what that is you
know it's kind of unimportant or Niche
subject so let's see binary Lambda
calculus what is
this let's see so binary combinatory
logic binary combinatory logic is a
computer programming language that uses
binary terms okay maybe that's not what
you're talking about so you
see okay how can use binary Lambda
calculus you know usually my reaction to
this is ignore it immediately but I'm
reading it only because you are asking
the question okay so let me tell you
what I think you know so basically just
this website this this um uh wait
basically this apparently this website
made it you know popular
online B Lambda because basically
because you see no other reference you
know it's you know like some Joe blog
you know some some some Zuma idiots
started to talk about this and
everyone's oh binary get
calculus you know like there's no
nothing you know if you like typically
if you search for some established or
important topics such as calculus or
even uh you know type theory for example
then you see lots of professors or
papers you know
esoteric then you know you can tell that
is really important meanwhile this
online you know website you know the the
the socalled you know media you know the
social network you know s you know the
Zoomers beginning with the late malan
genen [ __ ] they started this you
know clickbait you know drama you know
so so so your brain every every whatever
you see every day is just like 90% is
just [ __ ] okay binary binary you
know binary Lambda calculus do you do
you do you even know what Lambda
calculus is
so okay so but let's look at what it is
okay so
um yeah so let's open a few
websites so let's
see okay binary Lambda calculat
background binary iio delimited versus
undelimited
universality Lambda encoding complexity
correctly theorems concretely okay who
who who is this guy uh okay binary
Lambda calculus is a minimal pure
functional programming language invented
by John Trump
oh this
himself that you know that's his website
trump. GitHub iio John Trump in 2004 so
it's like new new new kit in a block
block based on binary encoding of the UN
typed Lambda calculus in the rouin index
notation okay what what the [ __ ] that is
binary encoding okay so are they
links binary encoding represent text
okay binary encoding so you know bunch
of jargons pure functional programming
language what so it's just a programming
language if it's just a programming
language is like like even more you just
completely ignore it I thought it's
maybe some
Niche computer science you know
theoretical computer science but it's
it's just a programming language
background VC is designed to provide a
very simple and elegant concrete
definition of descriptional complexity
okay uh you know so you know let me tell
you R just random you know I don't know
what this is okay but I can I can tell
you how I feel so it
says it's a you know binary Lambda
calculus is designed it's designed to
provide a very simp simple and elegant
concrete definition of okay what is it
it's it's it's
it's provide providing a concrete
definition of descriptional complexity
okay and parenthesis col Colo gr
complexity okay now what I can tell you
is that that colal gr complexity will
take you a PhD like 10 years uh at least
four years to actually know what it is
this this Colo rule of complexity okay
so anyone who want to talk about you
know the this this binary Lambda
calculus first of all you got to
understand this and to
really understand this to be able to
talk about this jargon in a meaningful
way will take you four years you know
well I mean like a PhD
okay
so so back to the let's go back so it's
trying to you know give a elegant
concrete definition of descriptional
complexity okay of that roughly speaking
the complexity of an object is a length
of its shortest
description uh you know to make this
precise we take this blah
blah basically useless okay that's my
opinion the binary Lambda calculus is a
useless [ __ ] comp relatively okay not
absolutely
relatively relatively useless thing that
is made Popular by the online idiots you
read you you know you read Hank you read
you read The Hacker News so this random
math too
much uh does that
well kind of you know so I mean you know
math is a lot math you'll take a person
you
know so many 10 years or 20 years so
there are some you know so many branch
of math and part of it is computer
science right so you want to
know if you are not a specialist okay
now if you are already a specialist then
you know what you're doing because it
takes you know 5 years 10 years to a
specialist
okay but you are average person you know
like uh like most my viewers uh yeah you
so you are average person if you are
average person you have to know you know
so if you are average you wanted to you
are interested in Sciences you know math
or you want to know what are what they
are as a you know just you know like
general
knowledge uh you know maybe you are not
a programmer you and you you are not a
you know mathematician but still you
have some interest you know a general
education right so in that case you want
to know what's important you know the
established you know what are topology
what is calculus doing exactly what is
linear algebra what's the difference
between algebra and calculus and what's
the linear algebra why is it linear
that's what you want to understand you
know the the established man you know
other words mainstream okay mainstream
science that's what you want to get a
overview you want to know so that's a
good thing you want to understand what
they are what you don't want to do that
would be waste your time is like
following this online thing like the
esoteric Niche oh new thing new this
this is going to change the world you
know quantum mechanics Quant Quantum
computation you know you know those you
know most most of the online talking are
these things you know it's random [ __ ]
and 90% of the time they just they don't
know what they're talking about it's
just
[ __ ] uh so anyway so what is is but
you know it's not it's I'm not saying
they are just
force you know you know this as far as I
you know so far I see it binary Lambda
calculus you know it's a it looks like
it's just a programming language there's
tons of esoteric useless programming
languages but does that mean they are
useless well not really you know they
are useful some you know to some people
to some researchers right so
but but for average people you know you
know this is a waste of time
okay and for me it is a waste waste of
time to for me too
because two aspects for the Practical
aspect there a lot other programming
languages I need to I want to learn more
for example
FSH okay even hascal I would want to
know more far more than this whatever
this binary Lambda calculus okay hascal
F and I also would like to know some
Julia if I have time but I don't have
time actually the time I want to know is
the proof Theory you know Co s cogg you
know that's another programming language
you know that's practice iCal aspect so
these programming languages I can learn
you
know and I'm old so my years are unlike
you young guys you know you young guys
have time to chat random and you know
you can
explore and part of the exploration is
you know online right so it's it's not a
bad thing to read about this but for me
I'm old so I I I don't have much time so
there only these things I want to learn
and that's on the Practical side on the
theoretical side computer science
there's the combinator you know you know
the
combinators um T machine and you know
proability prove Theory uh type type
theory that I really want to know okay
I've been working on I've been trying to
learn those and also machine learning
you know today's you know this chat Bots
you know today this wonderful quite
helpful chat chat bot you know that
neural networks you know so there's a
lot to
learn so this is my context you know so
you ask me what it is this is this is my
context it's not useful to me and I
don't think it's useful for most of
you okay so that's about that random
chat today I think maybe that's it I
mean what what else what else ask
questions okay post your questions um
let's see what is this uh talk let's put
the binary Lambda
calculus
here okay so let's see what
else
uh Mouse wheel with middle finger or
index
finger that depends on you okay so you
know so let's look at the mouse so the
you know Mouse whe do you use middle
finger or index finger usually I use IND
uh index finger okay so but oh Mouse
wheel uh Mouse wheel usually I use the
middle finger
exactly where here okay so for the
wheel yeah you well sometimes I do use
index finger okay that that's up to you
I don't think there's
uh you know there's one answer to that
but now I I love this track board
though uh next question next question so
is there any memorable quote you want to
uh you want on your Tom headstone yeah
that's interesting question one of my
motto I used to read when I was younger
when I was you guys age I think I'm not
too sure how old you are 20 something
chis but when I was younger I have um my
life is not not good
okay uh because parents you know bad
parents bad family is [ __ ] up so one
of my motto when I was younger is five
years will be passed sooner or later
okay five years will be passed sooner or
later and somehow that MTO has is always
uh encouraging to
me because you know it you know 5 years
will be passed sooner or later later so
whatever you your issue your problem
right now it'll be passing you know you
know back then this model was very uh
useful to me so CH Ching thank
you how many languages have you studied
you mean human languages or programming
languages and uh I need to find wife
before that yes you do
hang you you need to stop posting gay
and random [ __ ] find your wife well
actually maybe you'll find your wife in
your you know heavy metal parties you
will
yeah for Windows what program you use
for auto click yeah you uh yeah I saw
your question on Discord but I don't on
Windows I don't use any extra program to
auto click so I simply use the windows
Hoover to activate window so you know so
windows don't have auto
click okay human oh human languages so I
know Chinese of course Chinese is my
native language what's your native turn
well my native turn is body
language okay so but Chinese
okay Mark
Jefferson say so Chinese I speak and of
course English and when I was living in
Montreal and Montreal Canada in 1986 to
1989 they speak French there French and
English
so uh but I kind of I didn't learn
French but I'm kind of you know I I
somewhat familiar with the you know
French sounding and before that in parai
South America and Central America for
about a year so I also have some
Affinity with Spanish so actually I did
learn some Spanish when I was you know
back there around age 15 16 you know I I
have I start just like the way I learn
English just learn words you know write
down vocabulary every day so I know some
Spanish but it's what it's long time ago
like I haven't uh so I don't know really
know
Spanish am I on window 11 yet no I'm not
because the windows [ __ ] you know the
windows the windows scum let's talk
about Windows okay uh comp so let's go
to so wait how long have I been talking
40 minutes okay so let's random
chat Windows am I on Windows no let's
see you know just go go
toi window sucks search for
it uh window sucks and why window sucks
so you have a collection of my articles
on about 20 articles on why Windows
sucks Windows sucks in every way so by
the way for for you Linux people you
Linux idiots idiots Linux Linux sucks
more
okay I know many of the Linux idiots
they will be gleeful yes yes windows
look so bad but Linux Linux is more
extreme
[ __ ] why because because Windows is
a commercial entity it's one of the
biggest biggest commercial entity so
obviously they are incompetent because
their goal is not to be competent you
know their goal is just suck your money
you know as soon as they get all your
money they don't they don't really care
okay so you want to blame well windows I
mean it's commercial entity just like
today Google has G you know many of the
big powerful company G bad usually when
they become successful or even
successful people like one day if I
become you know I have 10 million five
million
followers my nature will probably not be
the same okay you know well I'll be
become just like one of these idiots
online you know these
YouTubers so Windows sucks obviously
because they are commerci commercial
entity well actually not just because
commercial because apple apple is truly
the best okay apple design Steve Jobs
okay apple design everything is great in
general generally speaking sometimes
Apple makes mistakes okay but Linux you
know the Linux with the Linux [ __ ]
and idiots extreme the Linux people you
see it's free and open
source so in theory you know it's great
it's great what you know all the so
including me you know I've been in open
source I've been doing open source for
30 20 plus years right so in theory so
you you don't have the you know the the
the corporate structure the incompetence
the paperwork you know you can just
create great things but it doesn't it
doesn't happen instead you have just
just you you instead you just have open-
Source fanatics while when you install
Linux this doesn't work USB doesn't work
Wireless doesn't work you go to stack
workflow you know to whatever flow you
know what where you know 1,000 Pages
that's 10 years old you you know you you
nerd oh yo oh you have to run this
command and then then then [ __ ] Linux
okay that's a situation it would be
great it would be
wonderful you know imagine how wonderful
it is free free you don't have to pay
you know download operating system and
no you know there's no like when you do
something someone check you know oh oh s
is looking at this website you know you
know getting into your pants like Google
Google and Facebook and Microsoft is
doing right so you want freedom you want
privacy right Linux it's a great but
instead what you get is is one Bunch IDI
you know nothing work you know half of
the time things don't work you have to
spend hours to get it to work and if you
ask the question then one one bunch of
Linux [ __ ] Linux and Unix [ __ ]
these people they tell you oh you should
do it that way they don't really answer
your question you know instead oh why
don't you open source why don't you
contribute you know is just like
trash Linux very sad story then then it
got run it got took over by Google and
Microsoft
you know the Linux like free software
Foundation Richard storman is kind of
dead you know the the the money the
funding for all Linux for all open
source is from Google and Microsoft and
they become so extremely corrupt you
know they they they they they they
become so corrupt that and they they
made programmers you know if you are a
programmer like me you cannot work by
yourself you cannot make money because
there are 1,000 1 million open source on
GitHub that's controlled by you by by
Google they all work for Google you know
at they make a lot money by day they
work for Google by night they sing the
songs of Open Source they you know so
whatever I do I have no I cannot compete
and they are all free so who is going to
buy you know I've been working on emac
for 20 years who does who pays me like
nobody you know that's why I you know
it's very sad
however the Linux people they got brain
they they don't know they open source
Fanatics every day they ask they still
saying oh you need to open source open
source this you know you need to open
source GitHub now is bad you need to
switch to kit laab or whatever the new
thing you know it's it comes in Cycles
until gitlab until Microsoft say hey hey
gitlab I'll give you 10 million you know
you belong to me we'll do it yeah yeah
they will do it right away then all this
[ __ ] the Linux open S [ __ ] oh okay
we going to I'm I'm switch to another
new thing you know this cycle
repeats so I've been talking you know
renting about open source in a lot of my
videos but you know it's like useless
you know like uh anyway that's a old U
thing Hank you know Hank says no I mean
it's not that it's not all bad okay you
know don't say that Hank of course L you
know
like Linux is still very useful for
example yeah someone you know who asked
me about Windows 11 you ask me right
because Windows yeah let's go back to
Windows you know Windows sucks so bad
they you know it becomes basically adwar
so they they tell me
that for
example like I'm doing something right
like can you see my screen yeah I'm
doing I'm typing something and suddenly
boom this thing popped
up a New Journey with Windows Ste we're
gonna take you to a New Journey but you
gotta pay your Windows 10 is is is going
to be dead soon so you have to pay us
you know it popped up where I'm doing
something every you know it's been
popping up like it happened just
yesterday too
yesterday or was it today you know it's
just just pop up and every time you do
something like Bing you know Microsoft
Edge please use Microsoft Edge did you
know that Microsoft Edge can also do
this we also monitor what you do but by
the way we also do this [ __ ] Microsoft
so this is when I'm going to switch to
Linux you know but even though I I
despise this Linux [ __ ] this OT
extreme
but but you know compared to Windows
this situation you know I'm going to
switch to
Linux but you know I'm it's not so easy
because I'm not like you guys like you
don't have nothing on your computer I
have I have you
know three 30 years three decades of
stuff I need to migrate I need to buy a
new computer I don't have money you know
then you have to back up then you have
to move you have to transfer files you
have to make sure they remain intact you
know so I did that like I I switched
from Mac to windows in 2009 then to
Linux in
2012 you know so now I have experience
about switching so these days I don't
use any software that creates its own
kind of format all my files all my files
photos whatever I can move to any
operating system right away without
having to worry about file name
incompatibility there's a lot issues I
have like tens of articles about it
because for example when you move
there's a lot file name issues file name
in coding for example I'm Chinese so
sometimes you have Chinese file names
and when you switch to Linux or
Microsoft boom all those you know file
names becomes giberish you know that's
one of the issue not just Chinese but
also so they have sometimes unical
characters so this a lot issues you
know um
anyway uh so Random talking yeah so
Linux so you know Windows is telling me
that my machine is not good enough to
switch to Windows 11 which is false
which is you know one of the scum
tactics uh Windows too uh let me show
you okay so you see
this uh where do we go update in
security is that there yeah yeah this PC
doesn't currently meet the minimum
system requirements to run to run
Windows 11 that's Force okay that's a
scum you know they want to you they want
you to buy a new computer that's that's
the purpose of Windows 11 anyway okay
they want you to buy a new computer they
benefit because Microsoft you know
Windows is bundled with computers so
every time you buy a computer they make
money you know then PC health check you
know so scun you know this
scun so that is why I haven't upgraded
to Windows 11 but also I know from
Reading Windows 11 is not you know it's
like crap you know it's the same same
thing same crab there's no basically
little to no improvements it's just
same you know like if you check out my
articles each one of them it's the same
it's the same on Windows 11 you know
like incredible for example let me show
you something okay I mean well anyway
there's a lot you know like in
this uh yeah you bought a new pc yeah uh
yeah
okay anything else maybe that's it for
today okay let's screw EAC this coding
then no EAC this
coding uh for
today thank you
Chris anything else anything else
you see this cup US
Army or
college by the way this is a nice
quality cup heavy very heavy and this
words are carved in you know this is
actually carved in very heavy Cup this
this cup is for my
neighbors so sooner or later I'm going
to switch to Linux on this machine I
also have a Mac but like I said you
know switching is not not that easy I
mean it may be easy for you guys because
you guys don't have anything you know
you know but I have lots of stuff so
um so you know maybe I'll switch to the
Mac or you know on this machine I switch
to Windows but that will be until
Windows 10 become
dead you can't trust them and uh
anyway uh what else let's see
so yeah so I'm going to yeah this new
camera I'm going to install then I'm
going to you know do you know maybe The
Spar board then uh I've been thinking I
really want to go into the
Odyssey you know because YouTube you
know so I I can stream on Odyssey
let's see a
SE actually so there it is a se s my
website I mean my account on Odyssey so
maybe I'll stream on Odyssey about
political
stuff because I don't want to talk
about political you know because YouTube
scum they're going to sensor you they're
going to kill your
account so that's it for today anything
else
thank you for your service thank you
Mark
uh yeah lots of happening in politics
because you know as you guys know it's
big news in the past
um four days you know three days
ago and
uh you know it's pretty sad reading you
know reading this
pretty sad uh big
corruption
so yeah I'm not going to talk about it
so you know maybe I'll start a you know
I'll do a live stream I really want to
do a live stream on Odyssey so I'll tell
you guys you'll see it on my Twitter
follow me on Twitter and also follow me
on K Discord you can find all these
links in just. info okay just go to my
website.org go
to.in and uh then you can see my YouTube
my Twitter my Discord and odyssey so
I'll be
announcing anything news there bye guys
bye
guys yeah rumo is
good uh
yeah it's I mean
yeah oh this you Lambda guy yeah you I
know I recognize you on
the git lab is on sale for sale now yeah
what what's the new one I remember like
this year there's another like a new one
after get G lab and all the F you know
all the open source Fanatics are
switching to it it's like oh we need to
switch the [ __ ] idiots
this in this mostly you know these
Fanatics are young people you know like
you you like after a few years then
they'll be bought out too they
themselves you know if Microsoft says
you know I'll give you 10,000 you know
or you know 100,000 you shut up you you
sell for Microsoft they they all these
open source Fanatics F Fanatics they'll
do it right away right away because they
they don't really understand nothing you
know they they they just think oh yeah
open source is a great ideology
until until someone pay them they be
they become the very corrupt people that
that they are opposed to or they work
for Microsoft you know they they got
hired by Microsoft or
Google Jupiter says are some of your
Twitter treats autogenerated by scripts
no everything is
manual every every my trats my post
whatever is all manual I'm a manual
guide every HTML tag the 10,000 HTML
pages I have on s.org s. info are or
manually created with love okay with
okay every tag is manually
created I don't Auto
[ __ ] okay bye for real bye uh sponsor me
you can always pay me go to my website
you'll find my links for
PayPal patreon okay that's the most
important thing