good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of exotic
show today is Sunday September September
1st 2019 good morning methylome you so
what is today's topic so Bethel um you
pick a topic so Bethel um you you don't
like JavaScript so you have to pick well
you have to pick something else then
and good morning Alan thank you for
coming by Alan so I hope you received
the the Emacs tutorial and did I send
you my son DDOT info I don't think I did
how we were saying it to you how does
Saad to word processing well I just use
Emacs I don't you know he makes is my
word processing okay so yeah Alan so
give us a topic Oh faster of me give us
a topic okay but otherwise you know
maybe I just started you know you guys
have to be fast there's a there is like
10-second delay when I I guess something
about 10-second delay when I speak and
when you type something when I see it I
think that the round-trip is 10 seconds
so so yeah so so guys give me a topic
otherwise start random you know I I this
is there's no lack of things to talk
about the thing is you know we just have
to get something interesting to start to
get it on
so Alan says how do how to schedules
clocks act change the way you think oh
how do they change what I think and what
makes a great program such as
productivity and
- okay and technical how do you get help
in emacs
ch is good or bad yeah that's very good
okay I'm gonna talk about that and those
are mundane questions well those are
questions that you know everyone wants
to know that those are pop pop short for
short for popular you know like pop
mechanics pop science pop psychology
that's what gets you audience you know
if you get you know if you do advanced
your audience is drastically reduced so
path Romeo says number 10 what
scientific programming do you like to do
that's also easy to answer I basically
just do math math visualization that's
that's essentially the only scientific
programming I do math visualization
typically for educational purposes such
as you you probably have seen sorry
plane curves sorry a visual dictionary
of special plane curves oh my god this
is a huge topic I spent I spent like
five years working on this back in the
1990's that's what got me into Wolfram
research I worked for them and this so
so this is kind of the thing I choose
the scientific programming you write
programs to to generate computer
graphics sometimes animation that
illustrate mathematical concepts or
properties and in the case of sweet
playing curves now playing curbs is a
kind of a big topic
yeah curves is actually in some
perspective you can almost you can
almost think that that math curves even
playing curves frame is you know pain
you know to just curve not suffer
so higher dimension so plain cups in a
sense you can actually say you can
studies you know so much a math with
just plain curves up to you you know
even beyond graduate level beyond PHP
for example some topics in plain curves
is for example algebraic curves elliptic
curves now those are very advanced I
don't I don't understand okay but
elliptic curves for example you can just
look it up yeah I PT I see elliptic
curves now that is you know this subject
I mean just this subject alone elliptic
curves you can study for ten years and
you you know it involves cryptography
algebraic geometry very advanced you
know graduate level and you know if you
know and you can use this you know I
don't I don't really understand the
subject for example there is you know
see wikipedia says they also find
applications in elliptic curve
cryptography so you see when you study
cryptography cryptography technically
belongs to number theory okay number
theory but when you get advancing MA in
math all these topics are kind of
intertwined so you find some deep theory
that relates to you know algebraic
geometry or relates to topology you know
relates to cryptography number theory
you know so so very advanced and you can
solve some for example Fermat's Last
Theorem I don't know if you guys know
about it but if you are in math
community you must have heard X and X to
the nth power of X to the nth power plus
purse why to the enth 1 plus y to the
nth power equals to Z to the nth power
now X Y Z are integers and n is also a
integer so the problem for example so
the problem is is are there integers
that makes this equation true
but for N greater than 2
for example if n is 2 then we know a lot
we know a lot of numbers that satisfy
this equation for example 3 squared
let's let's just do that ok I'm starting
to digress a lot but I'm going to answer
those questions so for example 3 squared
plus 4 squared equals 2 let's say 3
squared equals 2 9 4 squared equals to
16 and yeah 5 obviously right so and
they equals to 5 squared which is 25 you
see so when n is 2 this they are numbers
such that this equation is true now the
fermat's last theorem says they are no
and greater than 2 that this equation
will be true for any integer X Y Z now
that so-called fermat's last theorem you
know he didn't prove it you know he this
is very famous probably a lot of you
know that he wrote in the book margin he
says I know this is true but but but the
book margin is too small for me to write
down a proof so this problem is a open
question for hundreds hundreds of years
for several four hundred years or
something
and eventually in 1990s or was it early
so someone solved it proved it you know
Fermat's Last Theorem so
is called Fermat Last Theorem okay you
can look up on Wikipedia let's this is
just such it probably on this page
because the proof the way heap and true
Andrew well the way he proved it uses
the theories of elliptic curve let's see
if ye are MA there it is you see
so you Libby says elliptic curves are
especially important in number theory
and constitute a major area of current
research for example they were used in
the proof by Andrew Wiles of Fermat's
Last Theorem ok yeah so so you know you
can you can read on Wikipedia now these
are kind of things you know I'm talking
about math but I'm not a professional
mathematician and I'm not expert in math
you could say I'm like master degree
okay master degree in math is probably
equivalent something like that but but
but okay so but when I talk about math
it might get you interested you know
informally then you become a
mathematician you young people so anyway
so that's for my last theorem and that's
elliptic curve and I was saying you know
curves and properties by the way this
this page visual dictionary of special
plane curves these are elementary so you
can read it and you can enjoy it enjoy
it oh yeah by my website okay you go to
my website sorry dot info and you know
you go to the homepage sorry dot info
you can buy the entire website for $100
you know cheap because there are 4,000
there they are about 3.7 thousand
articles programming languages on
JavaScript in depth you know like you
know for 4,000 articles
and mathematics you know including this
visual dictionary with special pen
curves
you know I spend like five years writing
this project and actually I could start
to show you some of these very extremely
interesting properties of curves in such
a way you understand because this page
is elementary you know you don't need
you don't need calculus you don't need
any anyone can understand children many
interesting properties about these
curves and you can see them visually
okay because I have animations for
example one of the most popular are
these chocolates epic rocker it's
hypothyroid
epicycle ODEs they are for example you
can see that's how they are generated
you wrote a circle on another circle and
you generate these curves over these are
tiny Mathematica back in 1995 ok 19 1994
to 1997 basically that's that's the I
spend every day you know I work on these
these things so these are you know as
you know this d probably know the name
spirograph you know that's what they are
mathematically you are rolling a circle
on another circle and the technical name
for this spirograph is epic rocket epic
rocket or hypo truck or depending on how
you wrote a circle or or cycloid let me
show you Cyclery so this is a cycloid
and you can see that's how cycroid's are
generated you know it's like a bicycle
wheel when you have a bicycle wheel and
you put the light on a wheel
you ride the bicycle and that traces out
a curve like that and this curve so I
mean you might say so what what's the
point
I mean
okay yeah so that's interesting that
that looks fun so what's the point the
point about all these is that often
almost always they have significance in
mathematics like like applications for
example if you want to invent trend you
want to be your engines you know then
then you study you come back to all
these things you know you come back to
all these curves you need you need to
understand that the properties details
of these curves for example this curve
this this curve there's a name this this
curve is called cycloid okay this this
thing is called cycroid they are
actually the solution they are the
solution to actually if you such you
know like you can you can go to
Wikipedia these days they have they have
more rich information half at that time
you know submits a half a half of the
time the corresponding page you know
there is a corresponding page on
Wikipedia and today they have the more
information then then on my website it
used to be they all just link to my
website but you know Wikipedia they just
copy things and you know you cannot
compete with them so anyway that that's
about curves so why are we talking about
curves because that's the visual that's
the scientific programming I am doing
basically so this this one for example
this one is called witch of agnesi not
very dramatic title ok witch of agnesi
now Agnes is Maria Agnes II she is one
of the you know female mathematician you
know today people like to say Oh female
mathematician but anyway she is one of
the female mathematician and the the
name just happened to be
witch of agnesi why is it called witch
oh yeah I think yeah and the etymology I
think it's what it was because
mistranslation I think mr.
mistranslation but then it's just this
curve is just called witch of agnesi
this curve you know so anyway so that's
the scientific programming I I used to
do I didn't I'm not doing much today I
my hope is is the Audis are written in
Mathematica and in many other
interactive geometry applications such
as such as geogebra and geogebra
geometers sketchpad capri and you know
these software come and go you know they
come and go so I wrote many of them like
sixty hundreds of them in multiple
versions in each software you know when
this software died then I have to
rewrite the whole thing in another
interactive geometry software then and
you know and also I had Java 3d object
visualization so you can rotate 3d
objects then Java applet I'd you know
the browser Google killed it so all
those are dead so anyway that that's the
about scientific visualization so so
actually we digressed about all these
things let me answer the previous
questions then Alan's questions and
so what do I do if I have $1,000 a month
right now that's what I'm making $1,000
a month my rent is $2,200 and they
increase it to two hundred two thousand
three hundred this month you know I live
my with my roommates and so in and I
don't have a car and it's pretty bad
okay I'm you know whenever this subject
comes up it's like depends on what how'd
what do I want to say you know basically
you know you know you know the homeless
people on the street I'm above them okay
but not not much better you know so
anyway so let me go back to the
questions that spices show political
questions political questions about Hong
Kong you know I don't know what what
what do you have in mind but I've been
you know looking at Hong Kong it's
pretty bad anyway let me answer the
questions in a beginning okay so let me
begin to talk about that so open an open
a new buffer paste it and go to this
buffer go to diet copy the file name
close it go back to this buffer save the
file paste name it txt okay so that's
the chat and copy the file path go back
to this buffer paste the file path make
a link to make a paragraph showing
browser
okay that's today you know I I have to
do this for my videos because I try to
keep a log of whatever you know on
YouTube one day YouTube might just you
know delete erase me you know who knows
but I don't have the video saved because
each video one hour
it's you know when she got bite or
something I don't have I don't have this
space I don't have computers anyway but
at least I have a record you know what
what I talked about you know for the
past of each talk so let me answer the
question then so so if you have a like a
question you want to ask me just you
know make make my name orange like type
my email address I think yeah ed sorry
yes
text file you know because oak Ahmad I
try to use it I never just I never get a
hand of it because whenever I use oak
mod I tend to write just plain text
without you know the oak Milito
formatting things I end up just plain
text except the only thing I use is a
header you know the one asterisk header
then even that you know I don't use it
much because I prefer I prefer a lie you
know like that for example today's date
something for example let me show you my
Twitter posts so here is you know I
write everything in HTML so I try to use
oak mod then I turned out I just I just
do plain text I don't even need
I don't want those stars you know those
you know augment formatting or those you
know bold italic I don't know and I
don't you I just use plain text okay but
sometimes I want images or I want
pictures
you know images or some other or headers
then what I do is I turn it into HTML
you know so so yeah for almost today
everything you know I don't like ice for
this file is still text but usually I
just make it HTML you know I just like I
can easily turn the whole thing into
HTML for example let me show you for
example so this is the chat you know log
select everything make it
select everything make it oh I have to
switch to one second switch to HTML Mart
first now select everything make
everything to be a paragraph show in
browser oh wait oh yeah I need to rename
this to HTML so let's do that
rename this okay so we name this to HTML
like that okay open it
showing browser now it's HTML now if I
want to be proper I can add start to add
header files you know I mean the Papa
for example then you need a title tip
today's talk log for example title h1
showing browser there it is then I can
add images it's not to add images let's
see okay
oh okay so let's say this image okay
paste it here make an image showing
browser that's that's too big so what
you need to do is add the sauce CSS file
okay
copy the file path close it go to the
header above the title
paste it the CSS file path make a link
showing browser now there it is now this
is Deion's petrol station
now the DeYoung visits you know this you
know follow us often so Dean is not here
today night people watching ok so guys
comments questions okay comments
opinions questions so yeah so like you
know I just use HTML I don't you know I
don't use the anyway close this we open
it okay I know I don't really want this
to be HTML because it's just
so select the whole thing remove all
tags go to the beginning and delete
these things okay and save it go to
tired do we name it back to text only
saved open we are back here so let's
read the comments and also let me start
saw start command lot mod so you can see
all my Emacs commands on the left ok so
what so how does how do I do text
processing yeah Emacs how to schedule
how to schedules clocks change the way
you think
I don't so basically these days well
since almost 10 years ago 20 years ago
my philosophy has been as far as
scheduled in Krakow's my philosophy has
been free men I am a free man
I don't follow any schedules oh god you
know like you want to live in a hermit
in a you know sage in a wise sage you
know the ancient you know Chinese
philosophers where you you are not bound
by modern societies things real things
so you have to do schedule Oh today you
need to do this this this this that so
like this is not set in stone
ok that's some somehow somewhat that's
kind of my doing that you know so you
don't follow Cox and schedule you know
let things be natural by the way that's
not that's not it's like it's it's not
like oh that's the way I want to live my
life not really like that it's just
somewhere like that
ok what makes a great program you know
so to answer that that that is in my in
my it's also you have very
easy answers basically you just think of
things scientifically okay
so scientifically what makes a great
programmer well you work hard you study
you know what you're doing you study
computer science or not necessarily
because most programming you know in the
industry you don't actually need
computer science knowledge because you
know most of the computer science or
even algorithms they are theoretical
they are they doesn't help you actually
in daily programming you know because I
you know in industry it doesn't matter
what you do what you know today you have
front-end JavaScript or UNIX sister
being or program in Python Golan or any
any of these or programming front end
you have to know Dom you know JavaScript
where our Dom well and you know you have
to know these frameworks well back then
if you are UNIX is that mean you have to
know all the Unix commands you know that
you have to know them well yeah you know
as you know the Unix commands the Unix
commands such as I'm not this page close
let's go to the Linux Linux tutorial ok
showing browser get system info for
example how do you get system info on
the Mac you just go to the top left
corner about this Mac ok then you got
you know all the system info and how
many memories and so on and you had also
two system report click on that button
then you have full details of your
hardware the graphics card you know
whatever chips whatever burst PCI
whatever you know things like that
that's math on Windows similar on Linux
oh no you got this bunch of commands how
to find out CPU you type cat comp long
bit how to find how much RAM you have
you know cat prog ma'am info and so on
fairly complex let's
Linux okay Arnie and and also the
different Linux distributions they
differ somewhat okay not all the same so
on Ubuntu is these are clinics it's
another you know and then for example
the in shell basics yeah shell as you
know it's fundamental you you have to
you know if you are Linux user basically
you know that's what you you have to
know all of them all these you know tens
of commands you have to know them well
then you have get cat awk unique sorts
find X ox and so on and top you know
hundreds commands you have to know where
so so this has absolutely nothing with
to do with computer science whatsoever
you know first of all all the
programming you do you know like for
example let's put it scientifically you
you take let's say 1000 workers from
Google for Microsoft from Facebook or
from other companies from Oracle
you know let's say from all the top 1000
companies so you have 1 million
programmers you you do statistics like
you I mean you you look at what they do
what they need to know to do their job
computer science no not really not
almost nothing so what do you need to do
to in for industrial programming mostly
it's knowing the two as well well you
you have four you have to have some
under specific understanding of computer
science such as what does operating
system do you know what what is its role
what is the what is the relations you
know what does compilation means compile
passing you have to know you know that
basics you know passing what what what
what they do but you don't have to know
any details like nobody can anyway so
but mostly most of the time what you
have to know is so these little
non-computer science stuff like like
mastery
of those you know be familiar with all
these Unix commands and you know have to
know Python Python cooks you know you
have to know those kind of things and
you have to know terms of api's you know
for example in web dev you have to know
terms of frameworks API how they walk
how to talk to database you know you
know those kind of thing it's like they
have little or nothing to do with any
theoretical aspect no any they are not
clinging anyway you just have to it just
experience and also yeah experience is
very important so so back to the topic
about let me copy that go to the talk
page go to the what is this Twitter
close to the close that go to the talk
page Pacey here link of a so so so back
to the question what makes a great
programmer you work hard you yeah you
work hard you study you know your stuff
you know comparing languages and
memorize all the UNIX you know know them
well the Unix commands if you are
working UNIX if you are working on
Windows of course you have to know
Windows how to do things usually it's a
GUI
then you have to know master of the
field for example if you are doing
e-commerce you know transactions
ecommerce you know shopping shopping
cards on the website you have to have a
good idea of what's merchant you know
how the relation between merchant you
know how the corporation's how how the
transaction you know how your client
works you know what does your client
want what what's their problems what
what they want you know what they are
non-programmers what they do and if you
are doing you know if you work in a
financial sector of course then you have
to know something about business
transaction an shal stuff money you know
how stock works how to stock works you
know those are not programming but
you have to know them because if you
work in the financial field you have to
know that so that that's kind of the so
that's what makes a great program of
course lastly you do have to have some
talent some you know some affinity for
the things you do like some people are
good programmers they are good with math
you know some people are good with
programming some people are good with
talking to people you know if you are
good talking to people you work in sales
department you know you go you go to
management things like that so yeah so
you do have some if you are good with
you know if you are interested in
programming that makes you a good great
programmer so work hard so that's that's
basically that is my answer to this
question you know as opposed to I
suppose you know on a web you know on
the hackers Emax community you will hear
oh great programmers are such and such
those usually dramatic nonsense so that
is that question productivity cleverness
okay as far for those things
productivity you need to you need to be
you need to have I guess you need to I
mean that's part of working working hard
you know you like you don't have to push
yourself but you you work reasonably you
know you spend time working on things
and cleverness
I would totally disregard I don't care
for Clement crabbiness at all as far as
productivity goes you know you I guess
you just you know you just be reasonable
like sleep you know head get good sleep
that's it so next question
technical how do you get help in Emacs
CH is good bad
let me copy that and okay product how do
you get yeah that's it very easy okay
this question how do you get help
let's go to my Emacs blog let me just
show you okay this this is a read my
emails website because every time I see
so many questions
you know I my Emacs tutorial I try to
write them so that they are extremely
efficient and condensed you know if you
have a typical Emacs phonetic you know
you read my site you don't see fancy
jargons you know you don't see I tell
people oh you should use this Marcus Oh
Kiba Marcus Marcus oh oh Crozier you
know fancy things like that I don't you
don't I don't I don't you don't have
that but so maybe you get an impression
oh this this tutorial is not so good
well the tutorial is very you know at
least I try to do it's very condensed
and they focus on what is the most
practical and efficient and proper way
to do something for example if you want
to learn eMac this read the first you
know the first section the seven seven
pages you know you you know a lot about
you know because I this is the most
efficient tutorial in a sense you know
that's that is that's what I try to do
and similar
similarly for Emacs so as far you know
as far as how to look up documentation
like like the question where is it okay
so the question how to get help in Emacs
yeah so so here are in fact I have so
many I have quite a few you know almost
repeating articles about that question
because you know you write them nobody
read it you know and after a few years
then it becomes history like Google
don't show it you know but it's still
100% good information you know that you
know
so that's a problem with the writing
blogs or website because meanwhile there
are billions you know what they are take
100,000 people they are trying to create
tutorials just for money
and with the very bad information so as
you know for looking up dark so you
check this so the most important is just
describe function describe function
describe variable these two and also and
and you so this is about eMac this let's
go to eat practical Emacs factorial e
masks I have a article somewhere
okay so describe describe function you
want to do that all the time this five
key yeah it's a in the first Emacs first
a let's see
Emacs first day let's see
basic Emacs keys everything is a command
describe function this describe key it
is quite variable that's what you want
okay let me see
Emacs basics where to download fun with
Emacs Emacs first a let's see okay Emacs
first a Emacs basic Emacs keys okay
everything is a command yeah describe
function describe keys is mentioned here
then if you got you into if you start to
program eMac this then described
variable that's that's not actually that
much useful described function and
described keys okay then apropos apropos
anyway yeah apropos okay I it's on my
website so that that's my answer to that
another question procedure for
introspection related to yourself so how
do you so Allen say so let me read a
sellers let's see let me read the
questions quickly so I can catch up
forty minutes okay so Bethany says what
would you do when suddenly you would get
additional 1000 okay that that yeah yeah
I digressed it on that I probably do for
$1,000 a month that's not much
you know I probably do the same thing I
do yeah I'll be happier and be able to
you know yeah yeah I'll be it will be be
you know that will get rid of the my sob
stories the frequency of my sob stories
will come up this then you know yeah
that's that's important money
Alan says are you trying to make a pitch
of young gun that's a big topic you know
maybe we skip that today because that's
a big topic I do have a lot to say about
that or any other particular topic but
that's pretty big so so well basically I
like to see best okay to see Tulsi
Gabbard I think she's the best she is
truly the best but she's being
manipulated out of the presidential
election you know the the DNC Democratic
National Convention something party
thirsty Cabot okay I think she she she
she's the greatest she's got real
experience in in Wow as a government
official and as a soldier for like 10 10
plus years and she is pretty strong
she and her policies are truly the the
greatest for the people I mean no
nonsense no light no political you know
dramatic things to get to gain to gain
vote to see Gabba Gabba
okay then I mean there's more things to
talk about you know and anyway
Allen so sabatham you say I was saying
if you had 1000 additionally to what you
already get to you which you get yeah so
that's what I'm saying yeah so if you
give me 1000 more you know I know I can
I can barely pay my rent
so yeah 1,000 more that it would be make
it make it comfortable and by the way if
you're working a restaurant if you go
mop mop the toilet at McDonald's in here
where I live you get you get like three
thousand dollars minimum a month you
know I have roommates who is on welfare
you know supposedly poverty you know
take government's welfare they they they
their food is far better than food you
know they they bring food for me maybe
you will know how to do VI speedy in
Emacs VI oh oh hi program at all
that's the only thing thing I'm missing
in Mexico oh you haven't heard of soft
like keys let me show you now look at my
keystrokes okay VI speedy you know I
have done link of video on YouTube you
can search it you'll find a twin golf
with soft like keys beats being golf
okay
so right now for example I want to copy
this line okay in VI is PD okay in Sofia
keys one key okay you want to cut okay
let's try it again
so something like is one key theme two
keys PD soft like he's one key and you
can go back here you can paste it okay
oh yeah you can see my key stroke right
so cut is just Q on black you know it's
more efficient than being okay let's
so check out you know check out sapphire
cheese check out the and by the way if
you don't have to use sapphire keys you
know if you don't want to relearn the
whole Emacs keybinding I have all those
commands for example these dis commands
for example the command I just called
cut the current line the command I just
go look at the left window okay left top
window that command is called socket
line to be or region okay now if you
just search the web you'll find a source
code socket line or region okay there it
is
then you just the copper you just copy
the code put putting your Emacs in it
then you'll have it so that's an example
of let's paste that okay it's very hot
my door is closed I let me open the door
so so I've been talking like random
topic today for 40 minutes 15 minutes
it's hot
another question Alan so a lot of
questions from Alan today some procedure
for introspection related to yours to
yesterday's talk for my procedure to
introspection so introspection that I do
that a lot
so what what was yesterday's talk I
don't remember
so let's go to Alan what's yesterday's
talk let's go to Saudi that's this see
oh yeah I can actually check my website
let's see it's not Hawk show so
yesterday is nobs keyboard joystick
Mouse Linux we are hiding Windows rat
poison judging juggling video games
Oh leadership yeah I remember that so
introspection okay you know so like you
know there's a video a few days ago
about personality personality and
personality test this one okay 2019
August 22nd now this one is very popular
for some reason like nine hundred views
and this is this one I talked mostly
about personality and a lot about myself
so I'm a schizoid personal personality
that means that basically means I'm a
loner type meaning that I like to do
everything alone okay that's just a
personality type and and also if you go
to Wikipedia I mean you know check out
this video okay because there's a lot of
details if you go to Wikipedia you'll
find that one of the characteristics of
schizoid personality is that they do
introspection a lot you know like
abnormally so much you know you just
think about you know and you think you
know introspection you think about
yourself you analyze it's so so much you
know that's one of the trait of schizoid
so so through the question so how do i I
don't it's not like I have a procedure
you know like oh I need to do in strobe
interest introspection therefore I'm
going to start to follow a procedure you
know I'm trying to come up with that
first process how to do that it's not
like that you just naturally you think
about that things and you think a lot
about yourself to a degree okay to a
degree it's actually not healthy that's
the thing you know you you know
everything you know you know like you
know for example you know as an example
the Sun if you study you know science
you know the Sun is going to burn out if
you you know in ten million ten
billion years okay and you can you can
worry about that but if you worry too
much that's not good that's not healthy
you know yeah the Sun is going to burn
out it will swallow the entire solar
system including earth you know yeah we
all be wiped out that's the fact you
know that's the fact but you don't you
know every every every scientist would
know but you don't if you worry about
that and you worry about it too much
that's that becomes a problem that
becomes a disorder you know that's it so
anyway schizoid so one of the
characteristics of the skis or
personalities is interest rate
introspection now I'm a mild skin
symptom are very severe okay because
I've joined yahoogroups
you know back in the early 2000s they
are yahoo talk coops also the you know
subject just like today's reddit okay
but back then you have yahoo talk so
there's a one of schizoid where are all
the schizoid personality people make
over there so I joined that you know I
talked to people oh my god you know you
when you are in this will be you see
there are people you saw so I'm a
schizoid right I would say my you know I
can still talk to people I can go to
conferences I can meet people I can walk
you know company no problem and it's
just in general it's just in general I
don't I don't make friends I do
everything alone I don't you know it's
like but and also by the way let me
mention again this is all natural it's
not like oh I don't want you know it's
just it's just you that's you know
whatever you like you happen to be that
way so I'm on my or skis or but there
are people you know ski so it they you
know they live in a house where there is
there's no neighbors in within ten miles
they don't want to they don't want
another person and then then they are
also prostitutes I know
this you know they you know they winning
I learned the word bughouse from them so
you know they have jargons just just
like every community you have certain
words that everyone knows bug house bug
house is a slang for jail basically so
so it seems somewhat some of these
people they're being in and out of you
know bug house so kind of psychological
word or something like that you know you
know and and some of them know a lot of
things you know it also another trait of
skis or it is that you yeah you you are
loners right and also you tend to be I
think I think one of the thing is that
they tends to be intelligent okay not
not to say not saying good things about
myself but they tend to be I think that
is true ok you go you go read Wikipedia
okay they have higher IQ IQ test results
anyway so they and some of them know a
lot of things you know really and and
they are not programmers okay I'm a
programmer so I'm into science and stuff
but but some of them are not not and
they know a lot things you know the
about you know different perspective for
my but but about about food or whatever
or you know yeah
so that's skis or so so back to the
question so as a schizoid one of the
trade is introspection that you know
again it's not like you have to you know
oh let's you know because I'm ski so it
therefore you know I should you know
think about myself nothing like that it
just it just happens like you're
thinking you know you you tend to think
a lot about what is going on and about
yourself how do you maybe how do you
compare or things like that that's part
of the schizoid personality you know
it's a personality thing
okay so lots of questions actually
so Beth Lemieux says what you do try
Julia first how do you like her so we
will now get you ran on YouTube accept
changes for me okay so
yeah let's just copy the question
how do you learn that term haha
and what term
that is true probably just have livened
so it's getting hot sand and slowed down
a little bit and maybe that's it for
today maybe so anything else let me just
finish the comments then
so what what is kvass you don't allowed
by leaving while being very open to to
the perceivable yeah that is true haha
probably just have to leer near some
slavic people slavic people so Alan Alan
we are you where are you based I forgot
I don't remember sorry are you are you
in USA Australia
so Beth Lemieux says what do I want to
achieve in the next five years I like to
there's something oh oh right Alan you
are in Sacramento okay but you have a
lot of experiences studying languages
computer languages or natural languages
so so oh yeah what what do I want to
achieve next five years you know I think
I think maybe we should not talk talk
too much about myself like all the time
back because that I think another trait
about me is that minoo at ends up just
about myself because that happens in
real life too and sometimes that's not I
want you know that's like it's it just
end up you know tends to the
conversation just ends up you know my my
my own life story is ended
yeah that's actually sometimes it's a
problem I mean that's a that's what
happens often with me so I don't know
you know we and that's in you know
that's not a good thing because you
don't want everything to become just
talking about yourself
okay you don't mind yeah but I mean the
thing is you know it's not it's not it's
not how you grow actually I mean it for
example if it is for example if I want
to get more audience YouTube audience or
something is that's not how you you know
you you can just be mostly talking about
self well I can grow if I you know I can
I can grow by talking about about myself
but that that usually is what happens
with coat you know cook old leaders they
they do that and they can grow and so so
yeah so you guys are my coat this is
Sally coat you guys are my followers
so what what what do I want to do with
next five years
you know ideally I want to learn I want
to understand I want to get advanced
understanding of differential geometry
complex analysis proof proof theory
proof systems and I want to be able to
write a compiler with my own language
and improve systems including homotopy
type theory so basically these are the
four or five the major things I you know
if you ask me that's what I want
so let me summarize understand more
differential geometry okay
understand complex analysis more and
actually several more topics in math
such as understand more maybe maybe
Archer brake geometry okay this way okay
then understand the foundations of math
including in particular proof theory all
related topics about proof theory and
homotopy type theory now this is very
big topic so they include for example
first order logic second order logic
model theory how they relate you know
you need to actually you know you need
to understand all them so that's that's
that's that then I like to be able to
write a parser and compiler and create
my own language so that's that's some
that's some of the top cause here is
something I also mentioned I forgot yeah
well the other thing is I want to these
special plane curves I want to rewrite
the entire thing in JavaScript you know
all of them right now they are not
interactive I mean you know I want to
rewrite the whole project in JavaScript
so this one is actually the most
practical and this one is actually the
most critical for me because the others
when you study math math is a like black
hole it it brings you maybe some
happiness it brings you some it's very
deeply satisfactory when you study math
but but basically they have no utility
okay you cannot make money with it you
cannot there's nothing you know they are
a lot mathematicians who are great you
know who know so much math and they are
you know far more intelligent than me
you're getting anyone then but they
don't you you know they they they wash
dishes in a restaurant you know
basically yeah you know for example
there is this mathematician who solved
the one of the Millennial problem
Poincare conjecture
there is one million-dollar price and he
refused this Russian guy let's show you
some math and show you he refused and he
lives in poverty he he lives with his
mom you know kind of but he solved you
know the one of the Millennial problem
that's 1 million dollars come you know
price he turned it down
he don't you know I don't want it he
says if I can solve that problem if I
can solve this problem ok which I did
you know I proved it and then my
qualifications you know what I know of
math is it it is I don't need to say
anything about it it's proven you know
the it's you know is his yeah you know
it's that's I don't need some kind of
organization to give me a you know
certificate you know a word you know to
to to say that oh you know I did great
in math I don't need it
and also he turned it down because he
don't want you know he doesn't like the
mast
math establishments you know like the
academia for full of power you know
politics power struggle so this happens
you know this happens almost in any
field in math too
so there's I have a his name let me show
you his name okay some of these people
math fries and Nobel ignoble t you know
great this one
Gregory parallel pyramid this Russian
guy okay so he you know so so he thought
that cleaning my eyes so this guy
incredible you know
and here's he hears him taking the
ticket taking a train look at him and
you can see some videos where he go to a
local food store you know buying
groceries but you have to understand you
know what he sobbed you know he's so
he's you could say the top 10 greatest
mathematician alive or even the
number-one you you know like how you
rank is very complicated there's no you
know depending on your point of view you
know there's no absolute ranking where
every mathematicians agree but you could
say he's you know the top 10 one of the
top 10 mathematicians alive because by
sobbing you know anyone they are like
six or seven problems with one median
price he sobbed it and any once you
solve this problem
you don't yeah you don't need this petty
1 million you you know all the
universities Harvard you know they want
all research you know or even military
they want to hire you
but he he lived you know he live with
his mom it's like mom can you can you
get me can you get me another egg
and and and there's another
mathematician who is kind of very weird
he died that is this guy Alexander urban
deck you know he's also heat he died
like five years ago yeah five years ago
and you know he looks like a Jedi
obi-wan he you know he's probably is
sometimes considered the greatest
mathematician of this century the past
hundred years his many consider him to
be the number one and he he he lived he
he went and lived in a he become a
hermit he lived in this product town
nobody knows you know he does he doesn't
want to talk to anyone cut out cut off
all communications nobody like nobody
even know where he is he just moved to
into a small town nowhere in France I
think and nobody know where he is maybe
except one person you know something
like that you know I mean he could cut
off all communication including all his
friends you know best friend Dean's
things like that and yeah and and he is
a he is anti you know that establishment
ok Firefox has this bug
so that's some random chat today then
random talk maybe that's it for today so
I'm just going to answer questions
addressed to me so if there's something
I didn't answer just say it
hey good morning Louis Hendrik
so pajama pajama crystal christo.pas
Jamar crystal good Moni says would you
use Evernote no I would never use it not
having any privacy or use an encrypted
alternative well as I don't know exactly
what's Evernote I think that's one of
the application where you write notes I
think it's a commercial application I
don't think it's open-source was it
open-source I don't know but I don't use
it and I don't use any I don't use
anything that's based on cloud
except maybe Google Gmail that's yeah I
don't use anything that's based on curve
so would you use Evernote or use an
encrypted alternative of course yeah if
there's an encrypted version I would use
that your rants about privacy gave me
give me an impression you don't care and
would you say oh no no I don't track I
don't want to use anything cloud I want
to everything based on my own system and
you know when I was younger I used to be
more more in control of my stuff but
then now I become poor everything went
right you know so anyway so I was saying
I I know every file okay I have backup
of all my files in the past 30 years you
know like at least that's that's the
idea but but things went bad okay that
didn't really work out anyway so yeah so
if I if I had let's say $1,000 a month
you know then I would buy a harddrive so
I have a backup and I would you know
like you know like Stefan Wolfram you go
to I talked about him he yesterday I was
before few days ago he has a log of his
entire life almost on hard disk you know
photos everything he has you know he
tries to make a log of it so I'm kind of
similar okay so I would have and
and of course encryption I would would
do that I used to have but on and off
then it you know then then then when you
have when you have well you see when you
don't have money when you have a crisis
you you you know you're about to leave
on the street all these went away you
know you don't have it's pretty sad
story you know I don't you know like one
day you back me and so in 2002-2003
there is one one day my computer broke I
need to buy a USB stick $20 I don't have
$20 and I cannot go to buy because I
don't I don't have I don't have a car
and so and I and and basically I don't
have money I don't have $20 to buy a USB
and my computer broke I don't have a
computer I'm about to kill myself that's
that's 2003 around 2002 or 2003 so on
that note maybe that's it for today
yep so I thank you guys for coming and
that's it for today
so forbidden forbidden 303 says have you
ever thought about using OS OS coins as
an input to control Emacs Android apps
like touch OSC with customized templates
with chalk we all toggle buttons so what
is OSC so okay so I think you are saying
you know get get some input devices and
also use the phone make the phone like
customize it in some way form of chalk
wheel or things like the old joystick I
guess
you you you take those things custom -
them so they become input devices and
you can you can use them like you know
they become input devices like Mouse so
you can you can use them to control your
computer and or even in Emacs I guess
that's what you're saying
forbidden 303 sign right a server crime
for oka okay so I guess so that's that's
that's what I you ask you are saying
right but first of all for Emacs I don't
I don't think you need those you max you
all you need is a keyboard mechanic a
nice mechanical keyboard in in Mouse and
with a wheel okay so you don't need
touch you know because yeah if you want
to be efficient with in Emacs that's
enough
unless unless you can see the voice
input that's very good but usually voice
voice input you know today it's very
robust as in particular for common
conversation like let's close is close
this
for example like I am talking about
random things today so that's a common
everyday speech if I speak it then you
know voice recognition is very good for
that but usually they are not in the
integration for Emacs is pretty bad
because Emacs it doesn't play well with
with operating systems you know with Mac
or Windows because we max is is written
by itself it doesn't use the frameworks
of the operating system so it doesn't
work on the Linux you got other problems
because on Linux open so it's nobody do
a thing you know everyone is just taking
it for free there is no really robust
voice input that's a problem so anyway
so so anyways the idea about using
different input devices for first of all
for Emacs you don't need them okay but
for others yes that's that would be very
good and I would be I would very
strongly consider I like it okay however
the problem is it is almost impossible
to actually create those customizations
for example if you are thinking of using
your Android phone as a touchpad I think
it's difficult to do right I mean then
you have to look at software then
usually they are not that's a problem
that's a main problem the best thing is
actually to get these these devices you
know something for example this one I
consider a good one you got actually a
joystick on top and you got a bunch of
for example yesterday we talked about we
talked about this one with a bunch of
knobs and also if you go to the
kickstart website they have a bunch of
module you know there are so many ideas
every day so they have today they have a
bunch of module input devices like one
is a wheel
one is some drumroll wheel
and why is the joystick that you know
you can do that but again again the part
of the problem is basically this this
there is no easy way I mean if if if I
can buy it and I just plug in that way
that'd be great you know then I love it
but usually that's not the case you buy
it you know you have to spend days to
find out how exactly to program them or
make them work together things like that
so Kathy you can want in Kathy
great to see you again
so Kathy says as far as I know many
people converted to Oakmont to keep
notes for the sake of privacy I see
yeah okay so that's it for today
yeah that's not drag on because there's
infinite topics we gonna talk about oh
one hour 116 minutes okay so thank you
guys for coming by