good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show and we are live
we are live and I'm alive as opposed to
dead dead or alive so today we're gonna
talk about random things and first of
all okay let me just ease in by by
talking about this javascript javascript
is one of the worst language possible
even today to eat you know yes 2015 good
morning
Otto so Otto do you have a question any
topics any welcome you know your
suggestion question so you know let me
know a topic so we not talk about that I
don't have a specific topic today but
you know we will see what you or the
people like to mean to talk about so I'm
doing live video live video is great in
that my video you know the advantage of
life you know live streaming live
broadcast without delay you know usually
you know broadcasting they have like
five minutes delay just in case they
want to censor something you know the
Jenny Jackson incident back in 2003 or
so so but Santosh oh you know currently
it's live it's live show it's not
prepared it's not scripted I'd you know
I you know nothing wrong with those kind
of you know videos but you know excuse
me to be live streaming because I talk I
like you know a you know I read
reduction of the fake news kind of so
let's see what is that page so to avoid
distraction that's empty it so let's go
to talk about JavaScript
okay so I have these very interesting
puzzle so let's go to language tutorials
JavaScript in-depth actually go to my
web dev blog okay so I was coding these
things so let me show you in saw start
command log mod okay I'm gonna show you
live coding of the situation of the
problem first of all let me make sure
you can see my windows and stuff okay so
I need to move this window closer to the
center and this window okay so so we're
gonna talk about JavaScript first this
will be five or ten minutes but let me
know what you what topics you want okay
any questions and you know you like this
is a talk show you know you chat things
and I talked about it so first of all
let's go to the JavaScript so you have
this in very interesting JavaScript I
run into JavaScript is one of the worst
language okay so let's go to JavaScript
blog okay and let's go to so here is a
script so let's show it actually I don't
want to let me just create a new
JavaScript window okay so I'm meaning
that I'm going to show you in real time
so first of all we are going to create a
map constant map m1 okay so new map okay
so this is going to give you give us a
map then I'm I'm going to add an entry
map set okay and one and key is one
value is a so what does that means is
that you run it you you you run it and
you get this map
you know map is it's like a dictionary
of Python or hash table of Ruby in Java
it's code map in JavaScript Java - its
cause also code map so you have you know
I'm using the set method to create a new
entry with key 1 and value a and that
works ok then I'm going to yeah
so let's for example let's do this keys
okay this is going to show all the keys
in the in a map console.log okay and I'm
going to also do values ok vennett you
see so so you can see here that here's a
result so I'm going I want to show all
the keys and the all the keys is just 1
because we only have one entry 1 keys
and all the values is just that you know
just one entry a is the value and if we
show the whole thing that is that C so
map is key value pairs
that's JavaScript this function this
object is new in 2018 I mean 2015 years
2015 okay so we add you know remember
the set method is is used to add a new
entry and the order of the arguments are
key and value okay next now let's do a
for each statement okay so I'm going to
M one for each ok and for each you need
a function so function arrow function
key and value okay actually arrow
function the value comes first it takes
you know the error function takes two
arguments the value comes first then I'm
going to console log log print keys okay
so this should print every key in B map
okay let's try it there it is it works
it says one okay so there it is it says
one now let's try to train to values
okay Wow okay
and granite and it returns a which is
correct now notice that when you do a
for each method it takes one argument
required argument and this argument must
be a function and so we are using a
function here and this function takes 2
arguments value and key member must be
in this order value first
Venki how do we know because we run it
and it checked out you know one and a so
now let's do this okay now we create a
new map ok so we create a new map m2 and
we want to for each there cleanliness
the my neighbors are cleaning the street
with this giant truck with giant truck
it's very noisy your knowing so anyway
so m2 dot for each and what we are going
to do is that we are going to arrow
function again our function is value and
key ok then here we're gonna say m2 dot
set okay we're going to add the entries
to m2 and we want em to to be key value
so in essence we want to reverse the
cheese and values Sookie becomes values
value becomes keys so you know we are
creating a new map such that the keys
and values are reversed from m1 okay so
and we we run that it runs okay and now
we let's try to print it print em - lets
see what we got okay so we well hold on
a second we wanted here should be m1
here so let's run it and here is a
result here is a result you see the
result is actually the same as M 1 so
this this is very strange I was coding
you know I was coding in one of my
project in a Unicode run stuff so I want
to have a function that reverse and key
value pairs of a map so I started to
code this and what does we saw is not
right it you know it's very strange you
know if you reverse these two arguments
then it works you see then it says a 2 1
a is a key one is a value but that's not
how it is you know because the key as we
have seen here before when we use set
the first argument is actually the key
you know and we also have seen this for
each method before when we used for each
method the function is passed two values
value and key in that order
how do we know because we have tested
here you know its value key you know in
that order so when we run this code
value key and set key value it should
give give us the desired result but it's
not so so that is the puzzle of the day
JavaScript JavaScript
so javascript is a extreme pain in the
ass I mean I you know I'm I'm kind of
the master of JavaScript because I spent
two years to write this tutorial
javascript in depth I have read I have
read two versions of the JavaScript to
two you know two versions at least
completely at least one version you know
2015 the JavaScript SPECT specification
so you know I know free JavaScript
pretty well but JavaScript
every time I coded is always this got a
lot issues you know it's just it's kind
of kind of just waste your time and
today I'm running into this puzzle this
I haven't figured figured it out yet you
know I spent like 30 minutes
just an hour ago working on this I don't
know what's the answer you know I
haven't figured it out so javascript is
a major pain so okay that finishes one
topic let's see what so what what other
topics should we talk about now this is
the time for you to write your questions
or whatever so if you know you know so
let's go to so let's go to the next
topic next topic is going to be so I
want to talk about YouTube you know the
you know it's like the TV [ __ ] I'll
show you know I talked about random
things and general in general this is a
particular perspective with respect to
you typically with respect to
programming technology nerds interest
and philosophy and your humanity so but
anyway I want to go over to talk about
you know you know one of the things I
like to talk about is YouTube people you
know the people I follow maybe I can
give you a introduction
of who they are and also as a
recommendation of you know who you might
want to follow you know this is they are
lit they are like today obedience of
YouTube videos it's rather quite amazing
like you know I've said this before it's
like you know in the 1990s I used to go
to libraries every day you know I know
several libraries by heart you know I go
because I go every day I go there I know
every chord I know every cranny every
corner of the library I know which you
know position that which place in the
library holds what kind of books but you
know but then you get you get bored
because you go to the library even
though they are like you know hundred
thousands of books but sometimes you go
there because you go every every day
years after year you go there you you
you feel you feel feel like you don't
know what to do you don't know like what
book should I look you know you get
bored but until one day you have some
particular subject you are interested
like like maybe something in the news
you suddenly want to find you know
answer to that particular thing then
then the library suddenly lights up
people because then you start to find
you know the books you need to about
that topic then you realize this turns
of it and you my god and and it's like
oh how come I didn't know that you know
because it's you know because when you
are swimming in a sea of information you
kind of you forgot it you don't see it
you don't feel it sea of the information
it's almost like you are inside a
infinity you know after a while you
don't see it you know so Internet is
kind of like that you know Internet
there are billions you know Internet
there are billions of billions of
billions of things basically the entire
humanities information models on the
internet but you know as you know you
know you every day you know you get
bored you know like internet oh yeah
like until maybe someday you know like
when something comes up maybe some some
about some images about some forum about
some topics or about some particular
game it lights up then you start to find
you know hundreds of pages you are
really interested like my god how am I
ever going to have time to read them all
and you really want to read them all
because that's an interesting topic to
you you know all the personalities you
didn't know before it's like that so
that's internet well and YouTube is
actually like that as well YouTube you
know YouTube there are on a second I
mean read the comments sound talk seen
says likes I'm about to go to bed
so I watch this recording later okay I
just finished the last episode okay now
I want to learn how to do the pen
trolling okay super good night good
dreams hope hope or as well for you so
back to the YouTube so YouTube is like
is it's a sea of information you don't
know how big is a C&T of you you are
dropped into Pacific Ocean for example
you know you know you cannot die there
that's for sure you know so YouTube is
kind of seeing of information you don't
know you don't like you Eve even if you
watch YouTube every day unless you start
to research you know it's like you don't
know what what's out there
it's like topics or people you've never
seen before and you know yeah so this is
kind of amazing okay it's it's extremely
amazing so so many people are watching
so if since nobody is making any you
know other comments about topics I guess
I'll just start start to talk about
go-with-the-flow about YouTube people
then you know there are some YouTube
people so I started to follow you too
you know I start to start to actually
watch you know really pay attention to
YouTube since about a few months ago so
I've watched a lot videos you know and
some of the some of the people are
really interesting now you know on
YouTube it's it's so so it's like in
gaming okay let's say in programming now
because most of my followers are
programmers you you know if you program
in Java you know you know about Java
community you know Java web frameworks
you know they have a form each framework
has a forum you know maybe there's a
particular community about JavaScript
functional programming in Java
okay and maybe you know then you hear
about the drama of the Java Java
community you know or new versions
latest news about Java and so on so if
that's if you are a Java programmer now
however if you are Ruby programmer if
you never programmed Ruby in general you
are not familiar with what's going on in
a Ruby community you know it's like you
know because they are you know at least
there are twenty most used programming
languages typically you as a programmer
even if you have 10 years or 20 years of
the experience typically you just focus
on maybe five less than ten languages
you know so there are a lot languages
you don't know what they are you know
you never know what you know you never
studied them you don't know their new is
their community but each community is
usually like there's like hundred
thousands of people in it and there's
news and drama every day so if one day
suppose you one day you changed jobs and
you you you switch to a job that
requires Ruby so you started to learn
Ruby and suddenly you realize oh wow
Ruby community is so it's like a whole
new world and you have you know news the
people in our community you know we
which
what what the people are like you know
do different people have different
personalities you know it's usually you
know funny very different you know so so
community is kind of like that's the
whole the whole you are in you know the
community unless you know you if you are
not a mathematician then you have no
idea what's going on in the
mathematician math community but if you
start to you know if you have a
mathematician if you have a math degree
you know then then you have you you will
know you might know you know math
communities you know who is what
mathematicians are there what they are
doing you know what's news some
mathematician died you know last year or
this or today or you know you have and
also this drama you know there's some
professors something happened math
professor at UC Berkeley and because he
did this or that you know so community
you know so you if you think about the
whole world you what do you know and
what you are is really tiny it's like an
ant ant and okay really it's like the
world is vast you know so anyway so I'm
talking about so this is you know as an
example to illustrate the community they
how they if you are not in a community
you don't know so in the programming
community gaming is a same you know they
are like hundreds hundreds of different
games if you play a particular game but
then other games is a huge community
like Second Life I was in second right
so same thing with gaming community and
also if you are programmer if you are
not a gamer then you don't know what's
going on in the gamer community so in
the same way okay on YouTube
they are tremendous number of
communities almost reflect the number of
communities in real world so you have
chemical unity yes so there are a lot
people playing games you have the
teenage community you have you know
children community like you know people
lesson
ten years old you know children like you
you are the parent your child you know
they go watch YouTube
you know cartoons things like that you
know then then you have the you know you
have programmer community you are a
programmer I'm a programmer we watch you
know there are lots of programming
tutorials JavaScript discussed like my
channel you know talking about Emacs you
know stuff so on YouTube there's tons of
communities to you know like almost
infinity it's like - its understatement
to say there are tens of thousands
communities I think I don't know you
know it's also hard to give a number but
suffice it to say that there are more
communities you can possibly ever spend
your lifetime to know so it's like it's
like a you know the the saying goes the
tip of iceberg you don't see it it's
like it's like library it's like a see
you do not know what's what what videos
are there and actually veritasium this
famous YouTube you know you probably
know if you are programmer because he's
very popular and his focus is on
technology sciences physics veritasium
very famous okay
in fact he made a video just yesterday
talking about how YouTube is the tip of
the iceberg veritasium let's go there so
the truth about Everett has him you know
so anyways he made a video so how to go
viral now that's a quick quick baked
okay so you know him
it's let's go somewhere here let's see
if he is you know I
yeah let's show his face so this video
is was watching he's a good you know if
you like sciences you know you can
follow him you probably are already so
he he made this video my video went
viral he was
he that's kind of a creek bed but the
actual content is about it's it's yeah
it's not really about here's why the
real content
the is about how YouTube is they you
know he's you know the general
discussion about YouTube's algorithms
the situation about the YouTube what's
going on you know what's going on with
these billions and billions of videos he
he actually mentioned that like I'm like
I said you know what do you see you know
there are infinite number of videos you
you probably we're never seen in your
life you don't know what they are
he's talking about talking about
YouTube's algorithms okay so anyway he
mentioned that in this video but however
this more things in this video he act
you know he's a great guy
so when he talk about something when he
does a video he owes usually go in-depth
and he usually do research you know it's
not like [ __ ] okay it's like lots of
YouTube you know youtubers they are just
comedians or whatever they push it they
you know there's no woke him up really
but he is you know he does dig into
details but he so he tells you about the
YouTube how many videos kind of like
that okay okay that's one thing but it's
this kind of switched topic this another
thing I want to mention that he talked
about he talked about in this video that
he's actually he's telling us his
audiences that he is going to start to
do quick baits yes that is what he is
saying he said that he said that you
know he says that he is going to begin
to start to do creek beds for his own
videos you know like while something
something you know creek mates with
dramatic titles which does not reflect
the real content and also he
he also mentioned that he is starting to
use clickbait icons yeah you know that's
is kind of sad you know so he's starting
to use clickbait type titles and icons
so you know how it is sometimes you see
these you know their icons you know
their images never show in their video
often that guys you know as many of the
videos they're you know it's just creepy
it's you know it's not so it just makes
you click that's it
then you watch it maybe for a minute
then you say it is [ __ ] but this doesn't
matter
that's that their goal is satisfied they
just want you quick you know how it so
anyway he's talking about he's going to
do that quick wait and he you know
apparently he also realizes it's this is
sad things for him you know he's going
to because things are happening on
YouTube and also the generally in
society you know and for me I was quite
amazed you know I see this guy he's got
he's one of the most popular youtubers
since like 10 years ago okay
he's got 5 million followers but they
you know a five million follow youtubers
he's you know he's starting to do creek
bed because he failed you know because
his reason is like if you don't you get
buried
you know you get buried in these
billions of billions videos so in a
sense he's he's saying that you have to
you know he have to in order to I guess
make a living on YouTube he has to do
creek beds so that's pretty sad and also
I was you know surprised you know this
guy's got five millions follows and he
wanted to do clickbait yeah so that's
one thing
so any questions no questions no
questions so who are you guys watching
let me know so because you know if you
have comments then I can what is this
like like iced zeitgeist by the way
zeitgeist is a funny word okay zeitgeist
that's an English word that means
zeitgeist means the thought the mindset
of an era for example in today's era you
know you know let's let's say the past
five years over the past ten years 2010
era
okay 2010 to 2020 to to today 2019 the
zeitgeist of this era would be probably
social justice it's kind of the one of
the main thing you know so ziko guys is
English what that means the the mindset
the thought the you know kind of the the
trend of an era so for examples like I
guys in the past you know 1960s the
zeitgeist you know some of those I guys
will be hippies hippies free speech
freedom for you know you know drugs you
know magic wanna drugs cosmology you
know that hippies era you know so
different era you have kind of a sigh
guys and that's very interesting I'll
talk about that but let me read the
comments good morning break the roof
welcome back
yeah what have you been up to the past
few days JavaScript tutorial and
JavaScript tutorial yeah I've been
working on JavaScript a lot but let me
finish about the size I guess did you
just came on so I was talking about
YouTube so anyways like zeitgeist
zeitgeist is the
um yeah so that guys means the the the
mindset or thoughts of an era
okay now the very the existence of this
word is very interesting because that
because it means first it invites it
means that our thoughts our mindset
changes changes you know as time flows
you know it changes so today you might
think something something and next you
know next generation next ten years they
don't think like that at all in fact
they think you are wrong so that yeah so
that's what I that you know so that's
what you know the thing that strikes me
as very interesting is about as the
words I guy guys is that in particular
is because is is when applies to
concepts of morality and ethics now as
you know morality and ethics it's you
know it's like a hot-button issue
because each person you know you feel
you have certain morality you know
certain things is taboo you can never
you shall never do if you do it all the
people in society your friends including
you know you you know all the people in
society think you know whoever did you
know touch the taboo is a bad guy should
be you know put to jail or whatever
punish for example gay ok homosexuality
yeah so let's say twenty thirty years
ago it's it's it's almost universally
you know everywhere around the world in
United Nations what whatever new United
Nations [ __ ] you know USA you know
they'd they would say oh you okay
you are got cream and your [ __ ] ass
your criminal your we're gonna put you
in jail yeah that's that's morality okay
so but but today of course it's it's
almost the opposite let's not just say
not let's not say today let's say in mm
okay 2000 to 2010
okay is fine
gay gay is you know well yeah you know
[ __ ] yes but you know but well
especially today's it's like it becomes
totally the opposite you know so so that
is an illustration of change of morality
okay now another very trite example is
slavery you know slavery is one thing
that Americans are obsessed about every
American in many Europeans white white
people typically they they have
obsession about this slavery okay anyway
that slavery is another example where
you can see that the morality takes a
hundred eighty degree turn so back then
you know like I don't know when that two
hundred years ago at least or 150 years
ago something slaves is good slave is
good you know you know it's a good thing
you know it helps the economy and you
know it put people in proper place so
everyone you know do good things for the
world something like that you know they
have reasons you know each each Iraq
okay they have they have plenty of
reasons they have volume terms of
regions we reasons written about it in
stone okay maybe this is why they
believe this way this is the moral
principles you know they have like you
know the volumes writing writing about
it and everyone in the society believes
that way however maybe 10 years after 50
years after hundred years after the it
things turns around Marathi the concept
of morality and ethics
so slavery is an example gays is the
example these are two you know popular
American spread the Americans brain did
they think of this okay well what about
some other examples that's not the
typical American let's see if I can find
one
well another example is sexuality okay
you know we you know as you know but
that's that's also typical American
thing you know the changing of morality
the changing of perception the changing
of moro particular view you know in
America in u.s. history his sexuality is
another one of them you know because in
the 60s we have sexuality sexual
revolution and today is you know as you
know we have Tinder's Tindall whatever
you know it is it it also became some
kind of a extreme it's you know supposed
to 1960 so before so so that's you know
you can say this also so that's another
change of attitude about morality but
again that's that's typically a concern
of American so I'm thinking I'm trying
to think of is here some other example
that does not involve American that's
but hold on a second on that let me talk
about another American issue
well because I'm American so I lived
here you know oh my adult life so anyway
so let's talk about another issue is the
oh yeah so well I'm not sure I can
actually mention that would it's the
yeah let's not talk about that okay so
so what about an example where a change
of moral stance that is not a typical
American issue I don't know
the cleaning truck is making a lot of
noises so anyway so change your moral
stances okay so let's let's stop there
so so yeah so I'm saying you know they
are you know this this change of moral
stances and that is always to me
interesting because one thing you have
to realize is that morality morality or
ethics you know your particular culture
or region is very strong because those
who who do not abide by it you get to
you know you get to push into jail but
however it changes you know like after
mmm
it changes completely complete reversal
so the question is how is it then how is
it right when you let's say today when
you have sudden thought about moral
issues there's certain things you should
never do but if you look at history you
know you not your morality changes so
your your your strong opinion to such a
degree that you you want to put someone
in jail today may not be so you know
after you know a few generations so what
so why is that so maybe so there's a
kind of a conflict you know kind of a
conflict so maybe you shouldn't believe
such morality or strongly you know they
are think so this is the interesting
thing to me okay I kind of like rested
and then
so break the loop so I'm thinking of
going back to talk about YouTube but I
don't know so how many people are
watching eight people watching but so
any comments break break the roof
any thoughts anyone any thoughts about
YouTube I because unless you guys have
other topics and I talk about that then
I go back to YouTube so I've been coding
so in the past few days yeah you know
javascript is one thing I'm doing yeah
what's up with you what have you been
doing so let's go back to you YouTube so
YouTube so there are a lot of people I
like on YouTube you know I like people
who are honest and you know it's you
know edge three productions edge TV
productions they are good you know he's
he's kind of you know he's kind of like
it's not technical channel you know most
YouTube channels are not technical
channels and he's a guy I like he talked
about random everyday things yeah
typically related to gamers it kind of
kind of like in the gamer community or
the I would call YouTube young people
community you know they they talk about
all sort of things you they also talked
a lot about YouTube drama like what's
going on YouTube you know some big few
medium follow followers youtube start is
something to someone you know he's like
that and he's also got he's got 6
million followers and these people I
think as long as you have few million
followers you are pretty much a
millionaire
this fever make a lot money you know and
another guy I like to mention is this
spooky guy boogie
so h3h3 is run by two guys Evan and his
wife Athens so Ethan is this guy Ethan
and his wife is the this is Ethan that's
his wife his wife is usually with him in
the show his wife is from Israel and he
Ethan is from he is his pawn in us but I
think he's Jew you know I I don't know
much about those issues but anyway he he
met his wife and got married and that's
there's a video about that that's
fantastic to watch he went to Israel and
Mary you know picked up this girl and
that became his wife so he's you know
although the topics he's his channel
topics are not something I would be too
interested you know because but he said
he's a good person okay I like him
you know because these guys they talk
about truth they talk about you know not
you know you know they are not phony
phony not they are not fake
you know they talk whatever whatever
they you know whatever they are doing as
opposed to you know the big corporation
news reporters news anchor they dress
nice and and usually they they have like
this conversation like oh yeah yeah you
know this seems like they are so
friendly smiles and you know the [ __ ]
they I cannot you know I watch them and
I was fascinated you know just look at
they talk and they were smooth like me
okay doesn't talk so smoothy they they
talk so smoothly gripe and they talk
about news and they you know laugh
naturally in the the [ __ ] is from News
Corporation's like every new
stations doing that yeah you know
sometimes they have more formal more
formal is like you have a guy with the
tie or women with some you know women
cause and they report news but but more
in the past ten years it's more like you
know you have several guys or women you
sit in kind of some kind of a round
table or lounge and you you you do news
kind of you know chatty more casual
style you know I said you know this is
[ __ ] this elite is looking nice and
talking smooth kind of people you know I
I have a problem with them usually in
society like when you see a group of
people or having fun and you know you I
run away nothing
no because usually it's just you know
these these people on the surface they
are so nice they are not doing they want
to you good when you are not them okay
so so that's the you know that's the
fake kind of thing that's a fake you see
you see these kind of thing you know in
every place you would expect for example
if you go to a job with a website you
know Stack Overflow they have a job
listing you know each company posts
their jobs usually it's like you know
they have a photo right you often they
have a photo maybe of their office or
you know of the corporation's team you
know usually it's like pretty people so
everything is so nice you know that
those those are facts so so yeah but a
ten for example a lot youtubers I like
them because they are not like they are
not these from these corporations which
has like a whole department of public
relations you know the you know so these
youtubers just like me you know you just
you are just a person you do you know
whatever to try to make your live living
so Athan is one of the such people but
however let's talk about his content his
content is not is typical of the young
YouTube crowd you know the content is
not the content is rather it's kind of
you know it's fun to watch them
sometimes it's funny and you get
information about what's going on on
YouTube but on the whole it's not
something I would watch because because
it's like the you know the millennial
generation there's nothing there it's
like empty
there's no learned you know let's put it
this way like if you are a professor you
spend ten years you know graduate PhD
degree then you do postdoc then you
become a instructor then you become a
system professor then you become a
professor you know or ten ten year old
professor you know you so you typically
you take 20 years study some subject
then you become a scholar or
knowledgeable about that then you know
depending on how good you are
then you do research you know you know
then you become a accomplished expert of
some area meaning that your name will be
part of the history when it comes to
southern subject you know because you
discover maybe history maybe science is
math a new theory you know you you
contributed to the whole humanity some
thing and and those are not easy things
you know they takes 20 20 years or 30
years of your lifetime study hours on a
specific subject that's that's what I
call learned men okay all the in old
times it's it's it's called learned men
because you spend the time to learn
thing you know when you talk when you
talk to this nun I mean when they talk
they doesn't matter what they say the
way they say it they even the style
because the it conveys you know speech
is not what do you think like you know
what you actually said is the content no
but actually like more than 50% is the
is the background information that
passes along with speed
you know the intonation the style the
way you say it you know this the way you
say you talk about certain things that
pass along is information so when you
talk to learned learned men you know and
you know Jordan Pederson is an example
Camille Paglia is another example and
there are quite a few okay doesn't
matter what they what subject you learn
things you know because because of the
they are background knowledge about the
whole world and issues but not from
these kind of youtubers okay this
youtuber Fox
you know Athens so I like this Ethan guy
and you know but you watch a lot there
tons of them you watch them they have no
conceal empty content they like they
were something's funny blah blah KFC
memes memes KFC vogue success pranksters
ranking YouTube Frank star ranking you
know Instagram Rio versus fake you know
you watched him this is nothing it's
empty but that makes money you know
that's a lot of these people to these
things and that's what people watch and
and and this is part of the reason of
the millennial generation these kind of
degenerated they have no knowledge they
have no learning they have no aspiration
of things they you just talk about drama
means means drama oh oh this not that
you know so that that characterizes many
of these YouTube channels okay there is
for example shoe are head many of them
many of them are like that and they are
all they all have like millions of
followers they are millionaires in terms
of gamers you know they all they are all
like that it's like there's zero content
of their stuff so big loop says I've
been continuing to learn Java and
started reading about autonomous driving
technology oh okay there is a guy named
Lex
Friedman that works in autonomous
driving I've been listening to his
podcast Oh next Friedman okay I don't
know that guy let's look up next
Friedman oh so he's talking Joe Rogan Oh
Joe Rogan interviews Lex Friedman so
that might be an interesting thing to
watch Joe Rogan is kind of like a idiot
I cannot stand his show but however he
is he interviews a lot people you know
and those people are interesting but
every time you know Joe Rogan is like
this clown and he's just drink drinking
and drinking beer and drink and smoking
smoking his Marsha wanna you know he
slap he and he's you know so he but he
interviews many interesting people and I
watched it on quite a lot of them but
every time the interesting people have
you know he's telling an interesting
story or thought then Joe Rogan
interrupts them and start to you know
babble about his idiotic thoughts oh ho
but I think this well you know what my
one of my experience is probably diat
Joe Rogan so so this next Freedman so
who is he so okay I'm I you know I'm
probably gonna look into a little bit to
see who he is because this is you know
this so apparently he's a I you know
related researcher or something so I we
it is of interest to me so break the
loop says autonomous driving seems like
a very very difficult problem to solve
yeah it seems to so there is a median
edge cases driving in the dark rain snow
we
intersections different kind of merging
yeah I've also been watching the show
black mirror it's a great modern
trailer's own type show that has lots of
great lots of neat neat futuristic ideas
okay I have people who has been telling
me about black mirror and finally I have
watched it
I have watched like two episode you know
so I heard that you know it's like some
people told me about black mirror and
you know like like on Twitter or you
know you know you have your communities
right whoever you hang out with so I
have my community which usually are
people who follow me because my eMac
stuff programming stuff usually so
sometimes you know they are just we were
chat they'll suggest me books to read or
you know for example the the book you
suggested break the loop we by Ryan
Aaron what's her name so that's an
interesting book but what was what is
the name do you remember
I could remember but usually The
Fountainhead yes The Fountainhead by Ayn
Rand yes
so that seems interesting book but yeah
again but it's a big book like and I'm
kind of old so I looked into it so you
know it's always great to hear your your
people your friends you know telling you
about some things so so so what I was
saying so communities yeah your friends
and you know tell you yeah so I heard
about Black Mirror so I did look up you
know so usually you know when people
tell me and sometimes yeah I don't have
time because I'm kind of getting old I
need to cut you know work on my websites
you know
do my own things it's like it's like
every time you talk about something but
all your friends like oh you should
listen to that song you should read this
book you know and and or have you heard
of this philosopher you know so it's
kind of a you don't have you really
don't have time to go into because I
mean this is one of the common
phenomenon is that in a book tour you
know some author some great science
fiction writer or something you know
some novelist
you know they tool and people are asking
me oh but have you heard of this author
which is my favorite you know he asked
he he asks you know the fan asked the
the the his idol the author but usually
very often okay the author goes oh no I
haven't read anything of that by her you
know and that's very common because if
you look at all the books you know or
the even just limit to the great books
there's too many for one person to you
know go through that's kind of factor of
life not counting you know the this also
applies to songs to movies you know two
books two philosophers you know this is
just I mean if you I thought about this
at one time in you know human history
they keep going going you know the
billions of people so nobody you know
that what we can possibly know is become
exponentially smaller so anyway so back
to the back to a black mirror so a
friend suggested you know so after some
people suggest me something you know I
would look up you know try to look up a
little bit usually starting with
Wikipedia and so I found black mirrors
so this isn't very interesting you know
the story attracted me so but eventually
I went to this great friend I have a
friend
he's Vietnamese Vietnamese by or bio
engine he so he showed me we watched
together black
the show for you know so so I watched a
couple of episodes so that was great
yeah but I don't watch you know I don't
have a TV since 2000 since year 2000 so
and in particular you know I don't have
a TV since year 2000 so that means I
don't watch any TV programs but however
I do you know watch videos like you know
I went to buy DVD but however since
about 2010 even that stopped so since
about 2010 I kind of don't have accept
the accept YouTube you know I just watch
YouTube so you know I don't I don't have
well I don't have money to to to watch
TV or to watch movies or buy DVDs but
anyway so that touches another topic
okay that that did you know today
there's a game of Thrones you know I've
been hearing that you know on Twitter
for for many years I don't I don't know
what the [ __ ] that is
you know Game of Thrones you know but
but I just know you is some kind of
popular TV show which my my initial
stance is always like I you know I
didn't I don't care some pop show again
you know these people are talking about
it but then I started to look into last
year Game of Thrones that's amazing
that's an epic you know it's a huge epic
you know beginning as I begin by
typically I begin by going to Wikipedia
you know then I go to you know find
other information there's Wikia and you
know so many information and there are
YouTube you know creep sub game of
thones they are like ten thousands or
hundred thousands probably probably
hundred thousand hits more more right
creeps of Game of Thrones are you on
YouTube so I've watched I watched a lot
okay
Oh on YouTube YouTube or just reading
the wiki's you know about all the
characters it's like this is amazing
it's truly so Game of Thrones I would
consider truly amazing show not you know
for for several reasons first of all
it's well-made you know it's you know
just like a well-made movie you have
this you know you have great actors you
know actors you have to act you know
great and great you know costume cost
costumes or special effects you know
what makes a movie great the show you
know intimate entertainment a show yeah
that's one aspect game of some songs
this great show you know it's a show
entertainment you know special effect
pleasing to your eyes eye candy okay
that's one thing but the content is
fantastic it's it's you know it's epic
the story it's epic I love epic story
it's like the doom
there's a science fiction do have you
have you read that or sing it to me is
also great so so I mean you know so Game
of Thrones is just epic you know I you
know so yeah and it seems you know so
yesterday I think it last season find
finale ended and it's somewhat
disappointing so what about pirating
movies torrent well I have done some of
that in around late 2000s like 2005 to
2010 I've done some usually movies so I
watched you know some movies that way
but I haven't been doing that for the
past five years maybe once you know last
few months ago I did you know one time
you know
I kind of also distancing from that from
the tyrant in peril day because of
immunity first actually multiple reasons
one is that you know I'm kind of getting
old you know it's it's a fact you know
it's on my mind all the time I'm you
know I'm 50 so you know different life
at different stages you have different
priorities and costs and certain
interests you had you look you lost you
know like when you are team maybe you
are into coming so movies you know you
you know everything about every movie
coming up when you are 30s you know
maybe you are interesting in
relationship incre so you know something
or your career you know when you are 40s
then you know maybe you have children in
you know interest changes you don't have
the interest you had any more so right
now I don't find you know I don't watch
movies much that you know because you
know this I'm not younger anymore you
know movie Superman you know Batman
that's the kind of CD you know and so
that's one thing and then I don't have
money to watch it you know then you know
and then also I don't use Terran now
because tyrant because you know this
like the we are reaching this
information age you know AIH so tyrant
there's lots of things going on you
don't know this FBI you know this behind
it you don't know what the I haven't
actually ever tried to study the torrent
technology I'm into when it came out 20
years ago but I actually never did so so
part of the reason I don't use pepper
and he said I'm not sure what's really
going on The Pirate Bay
and you know you know I'm not I don't
want to yeah and also also there's also
this theme that they are you know they
pirated stuff they are you know they are
just pirating copyrighted stuff so you
know you you shouldn't do it if you you
know so yeah so several reasons so I
haven't been doing that so I think maybe
about it that's about it selects
Friedman I'm going to look into and some
of the so YouTube I haven't even begin
to talk about the people I want to talk
about because there's so many there's
this guy I really want to boogie yes
okay so let's find his name
so boogie boogie is another guy I really
I can trust okay this guy he says really
has a great story okay he he was
basically he's super fat like 300 400
pounds
okay he's about to die you know this is
back then five years ago so you know and
I discovered him you know like seven
years ago or something it's amazing you
gonna watch some of his old you know
it's like this is him he this was him
seven years ago so he started you know
he's about he's this desperate you know
he's about nobody loves him you know he
is about just to die because he's so fat
and he's being abused when he's a child
by his parents you know serious serious
abuse not American
you know Americanized abuse a serious
you know violence and beating you know
mayhem and then he started to post video
just you know just to ridicu
then he became popular and then he
become you know he got millions of
followers and he it became his career so
so YouTube in a sense he that changed
changed his life so he he
him a YouTube star and his video became
kind of like comedy that's what he do
and he's he's truly intelligent he's
like this boogie you know boogie guy you
know I don't know if you guys watch him
he's not for example did that compare to
that h3 you know I don't want to compare
but he boogie-woogie
this boogie guy I watched him you know
he's you know he's a smart guy he really
got talents about you know and the way
he's thinking you know he's really great
so I like him a lot but again his
content is not the type I mean okay I
mean - I mean to meThe okay I'm into
philosophy I mean - eh I am into tech
you know I want to I mean - you know
knowledge I mean I'm into in-depth
historical knowledge or economics like
like the Jordan Pederson and Camille
Paglia
these people I that's that's kind of my
kind of the you know the category that
the things I'm interested but
boogie-woogie you know because he so
he's you know he could he's very bad
situation he don't have college so you
know universities he doesn't you know he
doesn't he's not you know he doesn't
have the opportunity you know he doesn't
study this kind of thing but however
he's still great he's just great guys so
but so his content is kind of like
comedy and YouTube happenings gaming
communities this kind of thing so as far
as content goes you know and it's not
it's not for me you know I don't I don't
want to I don't watch it much but
however here's the important thing
however you see he even though he
doesn't talk about philosophy kind of
scholarly thing okay that's not he's
thing but because he's a famous YouTube
and because he is just like a human
animal just like everyone else
so he encountered things like social
issues that any of us encounters and
sometimes he comment on them and that is
great so that is a great source for me
because he has commented on you know the
the Anita's calcium this scumbag of it
is a con-artist the feminism feminist
con artist okay so he has commented on
his point of view and and also his
interactions with that that women the
woman okay and I look you know so so
when when he went boogie says something
I believe okay this is when you learn
something from someone you know there
are billions of things in the world you
cannot make sure you cannot be sure
yourself what is true what is not true
but you can trust someone you have a
certain you have your friends or someone
you have made sure that you you can
actually trust then when they when they
say something of some subject that's you
know then you can trust so so I learned
I'd really like boogie in that aspect
so because Pookie has been out being
interviewed by h3h3
that's first that's how I found out
about h3h3 in the first phase so you
know anyway there's a lot of things on
the internet you know you can you can
you know there's too many things you can
spend your whole life in but anyway
boogie
that's this boogie guy yeah and there's
so many YouTube heroes like I guess
that's it today let's see the comments
so in the 1990s I used to participate in
PBS
where's sing okay I was part of a group
that spread games in programs he called
okay okay you go through thousand so you
know I don't get so I don't get what you
know so like I'm piratebay okay and you
know I saw impair obey you have all
these movies and it seems there are
people who are dedicated to to to to how
do you call them a rip rip yeah rip the
movie to rip them like they have people
dedicated to that but they today I don't
do they make money out of that I don't
think so right
so I mean but anyway so it seems to me
you know so there are these people who
dedicated to rip this movies also they
are software it's almost like oh all
software you have a ripped version there
are people hackers okay you know I
understand for some certain hacker
things they make a lot money out of it
they can sell their you know tours or
whatever or secret information but for
pirating movies do they do they make
money I don't think so right so what is
the incentive for them to keep doing
that to rip movies I don't you know I
never get that and and it seems to me
it's not so ok no money what we're
seeing so what so why would people do
that is it because you deeply believe
that it should be free
so anyway so I think that's about it
today so yeah I'm gonna I'm gonna take a
walk and stuff so brick the rube thank
you for coming by haven't seen for a
while so maybe the loop says the
incentive is twofold one it is again
unto itself with a scoreboard oh people
recognize and respect the biggest names
oh okay the second reason is to get the
illegal games and programs for free oh
let's see but number one is the main
reason people in in yet basically it's
for not all notoriety notoriety thanks
for the stream thank you
break2 thank you guys for watching bye