welcome
to another episode of talk show today is
2021 july
5th uh welcome everyone
and we're gonna do um emacs
and i'm gonna give you some reviews of
my new toys okay
some emacs and review of new toys if you
have questions post it
i'll get to it okay so it's gonna be
kind of randomish
hello float p and bot and uh
guillo liano
okay so we yeah let's begin
let's begin at beginning okay so i want
to do
some uh let me show you okay note
so some emacs some some emacs and new
toys
uh pen tablet computing pain computing
okay
so you can see i'm gonna
i'm gonna do kind of a review of these
things
okay so you can see these uh different
tips of the pen you know and i got
a um i got a logitech
trackball okay i'm gonna talk all about
it
but first i guess uh emacs then uh emax
so uh so there's something i want to do
okay uh so emacs
format lines okay so let me show you
uh go to stop show today's talk show
paste it here show in browser and then
you can
see so there is a command start format
format format reformat lines reformat
lines
okay we are going to do e
max list coding i'm going to modify that
code but first of all let me explain
what is going on with that uh what does
that command do
okay let me show you so this command so
you see
i have a giant buffer so here's a long
line
more than 80 characters so i can press a
key
uh let's do this okay so let's put it
here
and remove that uh you can see all my
command codes on the pink window
so you can see this is a long line okay
oops
uh what talk hold on hotkey so today's
so you can see here's a long line and i
can press the button
what press the button there it is
and that command that button is this
command because i reformat
lines okay now back to emacs browser you
can see
now they are less than 80 characters per
line okay
let's turn on ruler show ruler emax has
a ruler you can see
here's 80 characters so you press again
you'll
toggle it back now some of you
emacs users might be wondering hey exa
there is already a
field command why do you have to write
your own are you trying
to be different for this for the sake of
being different
no there's a problem with the emacs
field command let me explain okay
so first of all let me show you the let
me demonstrate the emax field command
okay so you see again here's the long
line
then you call the command meta x
field uh field you know
it's got several problems first of all
field region for your paragraph okay so
let's call field region
but first of all you need to select it
that's a pen so you have to select it
otherwise it doesn't work okay uh
for example let's try without selection
field region
field region you see that is a command
you do it
did it work it didn't work still a long
line okay so you have to select it
then call field region then it's less
than 80 characters you can see
so that command is built in okay that
that command is built in field region
okay there are several versions of it
anyway i want to
you know i can give you explanation why
the default emac sucks it sucks
in multiple ways okay in uh
with technicality okay no [ __ ] it
sucks in multiple ways
now let me check let me check if i'm
uh like alive and well audio
is well video is well okay
okay so so so let me just explain okay
so let's go to let's go to the source
code of these
okay uh so
describe key then you see the
documentation
of this command there it is and
go to sunflower keys that's the source
code
then you can see here is the command
okay magnify so here's the command now
let's uh narrow to region
uh oops wait not that one this one okay
so i have several versions i i
i you know if i explain everything it's
gonna take an
hour so anyway here's the source code
then there's a corresponding uh
page on my website so let's go to it
here is the html source code
shrink the window show in browser so you
can see
there it is okay reformat lines to
source code so you can grab
you know reformat lines for source code
okay
i'm going to explain why the distinction
for source code
so this command is actually specifically
specifically designed
when you want to um compact you know
when you want to make the truncate lines
you know the
add add new line characters to
so that lines are no longer than uh 70
or 80 characters
this command is specifically designed to
work in source code
that is one of the major difference
between
my command and the emacs building
commands called field something okay so
anyway
let me explain the whole okay so emax
has field region
it has several problems for example it
will
so so for example when you think about
when you think about okay
let's copy that let's go to my emacs
blog let's
add a new entry paste the path file path
here
and make a link so that i can work on
i can go to that there later okay so
close that
now you can see yeah let me explain
what's going on with the emacs the
default emax
command problems okay
uh yeah so
so the emax so i actually i explained
in this page okay so let's go to uh
let's copy the url go to talk show
and today's talk show and go down here
and paste the link and make a make a
paste the file path and make a link so
you can see
we have uh later on you can see that's a
topic we talked about
but okay let me explain so go back to
the page
so what is the um yeah so what is the
problem
of emacs field commands okay i have full
detail on this page
several problems uh in fact
i have full detail i mean this page only
explains part of the problem
in fact there's a let's see
uh okay so let me let me explain first
of all you know
user interface wise it's no good because
like we showed you before you have to
make a selection first
that's you don't you don't have to
because when you don't have a selection
just
just tell just let emacs to work on the
current
you know the current paragraph you know
whatever the current text block
you don't have to for example i call my
command you see it actually toggles
emacs doesn't have had have this toggle
feature
several problems okay let me explain
first of all in emacs
first of all the emax field command okay
let me show you okay so
uh a propose okay so let's see a propose
search for command okay field okay let
me show you all you see
now you can see here is a list of
commands that begin that contains the
word field
okay and and let me show you okay so
let's uh make a new paragraph so you can
you can see
it's fairly complex so i'm talking about
e max problems
then you have a c a version for just c
then you have your individual paragraph
field your
uniform then you have the field
paragraph uh then you have fear region
uh you see then you have fear regions
paragraph blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah
javascript field paragraph okay
so you can see and then then you have a
list
for your paragraph so first of all what
does this feel
mean first okay problem okay let me let
me explain the e-max problem
e-max problem uh
e-max pro e-max
command
emacs problem of
commands that does
uh uh
let's say toggle new toggle new line
into multiple shorter
lines okay copy that let's go to
stock show so max problem okay so emax
problem
uh so first
okay
name problem confusing it
cause it
feel okay that's a problem fear what the
[ __ ] is it is
is that if you don't know if you haven't
dived in emacs for 10 years you don't
know what that is
what why is it called feel fear what
fear or fear
you know feel then okay that's a first
problem
then another problem
user interface problem user have
to select text first
okay so that's a user interface problem
okay
then another problem uh this problem
is um
multiple versions
multiple variations of the
command very confusing okay
so you can see you have
you have you know field paragraph you
have field region
then you have field region earth
paragraph uh i think that's a new that's
new actually let's let's look at what
that is
so when is this added did it say
it oh this is old actually so anyway
so multiple variations of the command
problem okay
then then then okay then then you have
then apparently you have
a version specific for each uh
programming language so you can see c
field paragraph
and the javascript c field paragraph
javascript c field paragraph then
javascript your
paragraph what the [ __ ] is the
difference
i don't know i don't use them and then
you have a list for your paragraph okay
confusing names very confusing so so
okay so so we we talked about uh several
of
the problems and one more one more okay
let me just
wrap one more i'm not going to cover
everything because
uh one more the uh no and feel
command okay so so what does that mean
so for example if you have a field for
example you want to toggle right
so you can see here so you can see
here's a long line
you can toggle you can cut it okay let's
let's make this long very long line okay
so you very long line if i use my
command i can press a single key you'll
just toggle it
now if you use emacs you cannot do that
you can
okay for example you select it then
then field region then and
feel there is uh there is no unfeel
command okay
so what if you want to you know make it
into a long line again
well you have to you have to first of
all
uh let me show you the the the extreme
tediousness
okay the emax idiots that not typical
emacs user idiots the emacs
elite hacker idiots they
they are the person they are the people
who you know write emacs blog
emacs wiki they tell you what to do you
know whenever you criticize something
they will tell you you are you do
you you should this or that you know
those are it is those people that
creates this kind of problem
so you know i listed problem here so for
example so i want to
you know truncate this you know if i use
my command you can see the pink window
watch the pink window you know i can
press a single key you just toggles okay
cassava reformat lines but if i on
emacs first of all i selected field
region
then if i want to make it into one line
there's no way you have this is what you
have to do
you have to call set field column okay
set field color that tells that's a
variable that tells e max how much
you know what what is the width you want
to cut okay
so set with set field column
and then you have to say 1 million okay
now you have set the field column to one
million
okay now you call the field again so now
select again
call field region do it
now that's one single long line okay so
that so
it's a user interface problem lots of
problems the emax
okay emacs is that way because of the
emacs elite
hackers you know those leaders they tell
you what to do they refuse to change
when you criticize them they'll say oh
why don't you go use notepad
[ __ ] those are [ __ ] whenever
you
you you you want to improve emacs user
interface
you know imax is 40 years old whenever
you do then then immediately you'll
become
why don't you go use notepad these emacs
[ __ ] okay
so several problems you know for you
know i have articles i have quite a you
know not just this article i have
another article you know describe all
these problems uh
but they don't you know it's impossible
to get them to change
uh then okay so problems we
we have not done finished with the
problems yet there's one more problem
okay
so far we discussed several user
interface and naming problems
now there's more serious problems for
example if you are in source code
for example this one so so so so what's
the problem
you know normally when you cut a line
for example this one
okay let's show let's show white space
so now you can see the white space okay
now when you when you want to compact
into multiple
compact into one line or or set it to
wait hold on a second
ah feel region so once you set field
region
it [ __ ] up you have to set field
column again okay
so set field column even my command is
is [ __ ] because i need to change that
because my command is relying on the
field column
you know for compatibility reasons so
let's change the
field column to 80 again okay
now my command works again you see why
does it rely on field column
because field column is a width so it
kind of allows users
to specify you know normally like
how much how how shorter you want the
lines to be that's why i rely on that
but thinking about it i probably should
modify it so that you have a separate
independent variable for the width maybe
okay
anyway so you you see what this command
basically what it does in a technical
way
of explain explanation is that it
basically adds
the new line line return character into
into appropriate places that's all it
does either add that
or remove that for example you see this
paragraph i can
i can delete that then delete that then
then it becomes
online okay essentially that's what it
does add or remove the new line
characters okay however when you call
emacs field command
that's not all it does sometimes it will
introduce
uh extraneous characters into your into
your file for example let's
look at this one okay copy
so for example i now have a long line
now this line begin with the dash
okay now i i tried the e max field
command okay
so e max field region first of all i
need to select it
then e max field region call it
okay call it then
uh then you can see that it added two
spaces
in front to make it a line okay let's
undo let's
try this so if i have multiple spaces
let's
select that call field region you see
now turn off the space you see it adds
it kind
you know it adds extraneous things to to
your string
not you know besides just adding or
removing the new line character okay
so that's one thing so there's more okay
for example this
asterisk okay let me show you this
example
so again so uh
okay let me call my command okay so
let's uh
okay let's uh let's add some more okay
paste paste paste paste paste okay so
you can see
there's a long line okay you see this is
a long line now i'm going to call
emacs command field region do it
okay so again it adds indentation so
wait
uh i want to show an example where
it actually adds asterisks at
each every line um
okay i have i have example here
uh anyway i'm not anyway you can
uh so i i believe i i've
explained it well here i'm gonna go into
duplicate yeah asterisk deleted okay so
yeah okay let me show you this then
uh so so so for example this is your
line
then you call fee or region it's not
going to change anything
yeah okay so you you see i have five
five lines here now let's narrow to
region
um
okay so you can see one two three four
five five lines
now if i call emac sphere region do it
it becomes four lines and and it removed
one of your asterisk
so essentially it [ __ ] with your text
it [ __ ] with
if you are in source code then you got a
problem
then there's more examples for example
if you have chinese
it will add extra space into it
okay so so
so that's essentially wait uh okay so
that's some of the problems let me
explain here
let me add um
it adds or remove characters in your
text
other than new line okay
so that's some of the problems of the
emacs building field command
okay then
okay so then
then okay so here are some of the emacs
feel region commands
okay so that's a problem of the emacs
field commands
now so so that's that is why i have my
version
my version doesn't have these problems
fix most of these problems okay
so that's the source code now there is
something i want to do which
which is what i'm uh going to do today
which is
to modify this code to improve it
because i want
i want some new features okay update the
blog
date so let's go to the source code okay
so we are going to begin emacs list
coding
uh let's go to the source code so
yeah there it is the source code
now okay so so here is the source code
and uh so what what
exactly is it i want to do let me
explain okay so
so um
so let's let's let's say i have let's
say i have
these uh let's say i have these long
lines okay i want it to be such
that for example let's put some paren in
it
um
yeah i want it to be so if normally if i
call this command
if i call it it will just toggle it like
that right
but sometimes in emac this code i wanted
to for example i wanted to
do it like that okay you see undo
redo undo redo you see the difference i
want just to compact
the text within parenthesis so one of
the feature i want to add is that
if the cursor is on a parenthesis then
then just do that then just do that
parenthesis
because if i don't because otherwise
you know right now if i call the command
it's gonna compact
it's essentially gonna compact the whole
thing let me show you okay so for
example i put my cursor here
or anywhere in this block call it
you see it becomes that so
so i so you make this now i have to
usually i have to select it
then call it then it works only on that
so i want it to be
uh you don't have to select you just if
the
character is under cruiser is the is a
parenthesis or any bracket
then automatically just do within that
bracket okay that's one thing i want to
add
okay let's just do that okay
okay so if we gonna do that that's gonna
take another 20 minutes
then we don't then we don't have time to
explain
uh the mouse or stuff should should we
uh because so should we talk about
should we do e-max this coding or talk
about mouse
say say it okay answer because
we've done a lot emac based coding in
the past
several videos
without any answer i'm just start to
code it okay so
first of all you want to determine if
the cursor is on a parenthesis
so what do you do so okay so
okay so let's expand let's copy that
let's make a new buffer
paste it here and let's copy the file
name
let's set it into emacly smart copy the
file name and save the file
save the file as that
and date okay so
okay so people want to see mouse so
let's talk about mouse because we've
done
we have done emacs list coding a lot in
in my past videos okay so let me just do
this offline then
yeah let's talk about mouse and random
okay
so post your questions now
okay let me clean up here then we let's
talk about mouse
uh mouse and a bunch of things okay
so i went to shopping so first of all i
got this okay so here is my
here's my keyboard blog so you have this
fantastic
uh do-it-yourself keyboard from a
japanese guy
you can see here's his twitter link so
i don't know any details about this it's
in japanese but anyway they
you know it's very uh interesting
you know it's pretty good it's cool you
know it's it's cool
so you got a trackball there so but i
want what i want to show you okay so
i got this um
so yeah so questions so so i got this uh
um
uh what what what am i going to do i got
this mouse oh yeah i'm
going to adjust my videos so you can see
okay let's see if i can do this here
like that yeah [ __ ]
so at least you have some kind of bigger
pictures okay so i got this
bad video okay you know this logitech
my video camera is sucks sucks donkey
yes
so this logitech so
so okay to prevent
to prevent my confusion let me just list
the topics i want to talk about it
okay so so
logitech
and u575
variations okay or history
then i want to say okay
mouse versus trackball okay then i want
to say
yeah so so then this trackball um
so this is actually not mouse versus
trackball uh
but actually trackball versus
programmable
10 buttons mouse
that's a big difference okay so anyway
so so this logitech
um you know they have um
several variations so logitech so
in the beginning so we want to go to
trackball trackball
so you can see these three of them so
this the one is very old this one
logitech 570 it's a classic
it's uh 10 years old and this one is
still popular this one
marble logitech trackman marble which i
have
but it's in the closet both of these are
in closet
so the marble is like 20 years old
technology but
apparently people like it so it's still
you can still buy it and this one is
basically defunct
uh and they they you know logitech
replace it with these two
so this one came out first the logitech
mx ergo
i don't have it but i have tried it from
my friends
so this one is supposed to be much
better in every way and
uh and it turns out a lot of people
don't actually
find this better they prefer they
when they use this new one they fail
something is lost
you know they they you know so
so this came out you know mx ergo came
out in 2017
and in 2021
logitech made this kind of remake of the
570.
so a lot of people say oh this is
actually the better one
but this one the ergo mx logo actually
got more buttons and more features for
example the scroll
wheel it's got tilt left and right
but this one doesn't and you know
so i got this why do i buy you know i i
have a fascination with trappos uh right
now
i don't have it set up so actually let's
see if i can
um you know the
the the mouse okay so
so actually so let me
let me turn back to my face
so actually so let me take this out
so there is the there is the
the usb thing
and i'm gonna i need to plug it in
okay then there is a little button
you can you need to press to switch
between
uh between the usb wireless dongle
versus bluetooth so what is it now
uh
yeah so there it is so you can see
as i move the mouse the cursor moves
okay so now it's working
i have a fascination with trackball i
you know
since 1990s i always believed that the
trackball
is superior than the mouse uh
but in the past you know since about
five years ago
five five years ago the
i bought this one i bought this one in
uh 10 years ago
so it this one came out in 2004 i got it
10 years ago 2009 and uh
then then then i also got this one about
five years ago something like that
uh then turns out the trackball is not
better okay so so is it better so
mouse versus trackball so i have full
detail here
uh let me just tell you okay the
trackball first of all you have to
actually clean it every every month
because if you don't you know you need
to
pop this ball out if you don't clean it
you know the truck will become slower
so it only takes like five seconds to
clean but that's still a problem with
mouse you don't have a problem you don't
have that problem okay
so that's first issue then with with the
mouse
okay i need to actually show you um
show you my hand on the mouse though
with the mouse
you see i have to you know i have to use
my fingers
uh much which may cause
you know the thumb problem you see
you know i'm using hoover to click which
may cause
uh some problem but on the other hand if
i use the mouse
if i use the mouse you see um
yeah okay so if i use the mouse usually
i don't i don't put my hands on it
you know if i want you know i just i
just move it
and i can have my mouse you know i don't
i don't
i don't you know uh move my fingers
rather i just
nudge it you know use the mouse you know
nudge it
so in terms of um
kind of hand movement or ergonomics
you know mouse trackball is not
necessarily better
because for the mouse if you if you
use the mouse you know you hold it the
way you'd uh use the mouse with the
right techniques
the mouse and also with the hoover so
you don't have to click
hoover activation of the windows
it so for me the mouse is actually more
ergonomic
even even my mouse is not the ergonomic
one
and also for the also as far as
efficiency goes for example if you want
the utmost efficiency
let me show you my articles so a lot of
people you know especially gamers they
talk about oh which one is better
mouse for gaming or you know you you
have to do it scientifically so
how do you do that this game is perfect
to test
whether mouse or trackball or the pen
or you know or the pen tablet or touch
screen this this game can tell
you know just you try different devices
on this game you'll immediately know
which one is uh most intuitive easy to
use for beginners
and which one is the utmost efficient
once you have some practice
you know this game so a lot of people
have been playing this game this
this guy is uh this guy is a trackball
genius okay he used the trackball
to play this game
fascinating then then people have
recorded you know with a pen
this is actually the most efficient for
play this game
this with this you know how you test it
you know
let's say one 1 000 people you know 1
000 people you have
you know 1 000 of them using the pen
1000 of them using a mouse
mouse 1 000 of them use the uh
trackball this the those with the pen
will
have the highest score by far okay
so this is actually the most efficient
in terms of
in terms of from going from place to
place on the screen
but not yeah i would say um
yes but not necessarily for uh first
person shooter but anyway
that's that's getting complex okay so
let me get back to the topic uh
so there are also people using the touch
screen so you can see
i have you know i searched and collected
video recordings of different people
using
and then this guy is using a touch pad
and this guy is using a you know the
gamepad joystick
which is uh very bad okay for these so
and and the last one is funny you know
you know these games are amazing
they have you know this is a bonus point
so so this game is one of the way
actually one of the best way
to to actually test scientifically which
of these devices is the most
efficient at the task at
the task of going from one precise point
to another point on the screen
and also a drag because sometimes you
need to drag
okay so so it turns out
you know for my you know i always have a
heart for a trackball because
why because mouse you know you cannot
see the technology you know it's just
it's just a piece of things that moves
but meanwhile trackball has the
attraction
you know the trackball you know it's
like the um
steampunk you can actually see the
technology
because you see the ball and you can
move it you know it that that's
that's a a huge attraction
but despite my enthusiasm for trackball
i find that you know really trackball is
not
it's not that much better mouse is
actually better trackball is better in
the sense
it's kind of it's more intuitive okay
for for beginners it's more into
intuitive uh but other than that okay
there are other
you know there are other manual
advantages uh for example if you are on
a warship
you know let's say if you are on a ship
you know checkbook who invented
trackball trackball is invented by
a navy canadian navy you know
in the beginning it's a huge bowling
ball you can see you know you go to
wikipedia
uh the article trackball you can see the
history okay
beginning it's a giant bowling ball it's
invented by the navy okay so
on in the sea you cannot have a mouse
because
the sea till so the mouse you know
you'll be moving so that's no good so
you need something stable
so track trackball and
it's intuitive and it's um
but and
for for many people trackball is also
less uh hand pin inducing
it's more ergonomic because you don't
you don't have to
hold it that's you know
yeah so in general trackball in general
okay in general trackball is more
ergonomic but for me
because i have a special technique to
hold the mouse you know i don't
i don't palm hole pump holding is the
worst technique okay that that's
that creates rsi you don't want to pump
hole you want to claw
and in fact most of the time you know
you don't put your hands on the track
uh the mouse at all that's what i do
and also i have hoover activate window
that's a fantastic feature you want to
do
you want to have that okay so you can go
here software
and i tell you uh
techniques to how to do that on on
windows or mac or
linux okay where do i show it i
see somewhere here okay
let's search for okay linux okay
mouse hoover to raise window okay so
let's copy that
okay i'm kind of rambling over i need to
uh
not coherent so there's a wind so
uh then there is okay so that's linux
then there is
mac and there is windows okay
so here's how you do it hoover to
activate window
mac and here's how you do it hoover to
windows okay so show in today's
talk show page you have links there okay
so
hoover to activate window that's a great
great
thing okay also you want to inc also you
you want to make everything single click
okay
no more double click double click is
1990's
thing okay if you can make it single
click
but however there's a complexity because
when if you are on a tablet
lots of these techniques does not apply
so on tablet
if you have if you set things to have
single click then you have a problem
with selection
you know so anyway on desktop single
click is best okay no more double click
so actually so let me also also copy
this article
uh okay so let's go back to the
trackball versus
uh mouse thing okay so i talked about
this
how to test efficiency of trackball or
mouse or pain input okay
then and then
mouse versus trackball we talked about
in general uh i'm disappointed with
uh trackball so my enthusiasm with
travel
so anyway that that's some of my take
okay so
so i got this trackball i thought you
know it's a new one you know um
i bought it but it turns out actually i
still need the mouse
i mean the mouse is just better okay
because
because i'm going to use it every day
then for me
i'm going to stick with mouse why
another important
reason is that like i talked about
yesterday
we with the mouse you have
for every trackball okay so here is
basically
almost all trackballs you can buy on the
market today
then then you also have trackball
history okay so let's look at trackball
history so
you know these are since 1990s trackball
history
and this game is fantastic i played it
when in
1984 this uh you know marble madness
this fantastic game
uh it it you know it it's uh built uh
you know the machine has two two
trackballs there
so uh so yeah i want to say so let me
show you so
trackball histories uh lots of trackball
but
for every trackball you see on the
market there are
100 more mouses choices okay
so that's an issue that's an issue
because the trackball market is very
small
and one of the consequence of that
is that even though you see lots of
trackball but actually there are not
many because all
because all the trackballs you see there
you see here on my page
they do not have the onboard memory
programmable feature
okay some of them do have for example
for example the
the do it yourself which cost like 200
dollars
you know for example property okay this
this cost something like 200
you know this is new you know just
beginning with uh do it yourself kind of
thing they are program um
okay so so here so you can actually buy
pre-made uh so for example shop
shop now
hundred hundred two hundred dollars okay
so
full kit for kids hundred forty dollars
for fully assembled two hundred to ten
dollars okay
so you see that's a problem and this is
only one of them so
so if you actually buy this one then you
have
on-board memory so that means you can
program the keys
or even the ball i think i'm not sure
but you can program the keys for sure
and the scroll wheel to do whatever you
want you can program the marker but even
you don't need that because you only
have five buttons you know on the
trackbar so
so that's a problem with the trackball
okay you don't have many choices
very limited you don't have onboard
memory
all these commercial ones for example
this one high quality
150 dollars no onboard memory
no not you know you cannot program the
buttons and also also
when if it only have five buttons
uh programmability is not important
because all those five buttons their
function
their original function is useful you
know you don't want you
so programmability probability of the
of the mouse or trackball is becomes
critical only when you have more than
five buttons
okay vast majority of these mouse this
trackball only have five
buttons so programmability doesn't even
come in with a picture
for example the one i have one two three
four five you know
but i need programmability that's the
thing because
because then because i have mouse for
example uh
when you know the reason i bought the
trackball is because you know i
because i'm using this wireless
bluetooth mouse mouse
for my tablet okay uh it only have one
usb
port so i need it to be bluetooth
not the usb dongle wireless i need to be
bluetooth
so you don't you know occupy the port
usb port
so i have this one but the problem with
the mouse is that sometimes on bed you
know on bed this
you know fabric you know it does not
track
i have to smooth out the fabric so i
thought
maybe i should get a trackball so i
don't have that problem
but turns out i need for example this
one it's got like 10 buttons 10 or 12.
i need the button to close the current
window for example i
know i do i press a single key i can do
it on the mouse too
you know for example let me show you let
me show you my mouse again
uh so you can see
yeah okay so you can see
you see now where do i put it okay here
so i can
okay here so okay so i need to
for example so you see i
press this button to close the current
window
okay i need that that that's that's a
great feature okay
because if you don't have that
then what you have to do is to then
what you have to do is you have to move
you have to move
carefully to the you know to the
to the little cross then you have to
make a click
so you have to m look m
and click you know that's no good
because you know we you know look you
know
my hand is on the mouse i can click
close close close close close
whatever current window i just closed
five
and on my keyboard macro i can reopen
them okay so let me show you
so this reopen reopen reopen
reopen you know there we have it close
reopen or i can use the mouse close
but i don't have a you know the mouse
the the current mouse
only have like nine buttons not enough
so i have to press this key to
reopen another thing i really need is
for example
now let's look at the mouse again okay
so
so you see i have so many tabs i want to
switch to a previous tab
previous tab previous tab you know so
normally my
you know i can just switch tab around
and don't like this one close you know
reopen so i need those features without
those you have to
you have to move your hand and aim and
look
okay that's a
that's a issue so i wish you know if
there's a lot of trackball
makers you know i wish i can buy a
trackball
i wish i can buy a trackball that has 10
you know 10 buttons and i can program it
but you you won't find it so there's no
such
so and plus trackball is not
really that efficient you know like you
know so
so trackball is actually and then you
have to clean it every month
you know so despite my love for
trackball so it's not that great
okay that's it that's it for today i
think anything else um
so what do you think about the one that
is only a ball
and you click with your keyboard okay so
we get it we get into complex
questions you see lots of these
trackball you know
beginning about two years ago the newer
do-it-yourself trackballs you know they
begin to have the idea where you just
have one trackball no buttons
you see for example okay the picture is
too big for example
here you know do it yourself
just one trackball no buttons okay then
you can also see the
uh okay this guy is making it then
you can also see the plupa is also doing
it
okay so i you know i don't have a
picture of you know you can see it on
their website they i showed that before
so you can see
this model this all you got is a
trackball there's no buttons at all
so how do you how do you how do you
press the button
well the thing is with do it yourself
keyboards you know
so these people so you use your keyboard
so your keyboard part of your keyboard
um for example let's look at a keyboard
guide
keyboard blog for example we show this
japanese guy
so the buttons are on your keyboard
so in my case for example i have lots of
marker pad which is actually i can show
you
which i i can show you here you can see
uh you see
you see this is actually a click okay
let me
let me see if i can show you that
yeah okay so this is
uh this is left click this is right
click
this is middle click so let me move my
mouse
to the window so you can let's uh
for example i go here i move i move the
mouse to the link here
then i click you see it goes to twitter
but i have javascript turned off so uh
let's go back okay
oh yeah close this okay so left click
middle click so middle click is useful
so i can
i can open it in a in a new page so i
just click
that and i move it to it move to the new
tab okay so that's
uh so that's the thing
about these trackballs with uh
just one just one ball no button
so you do you so you need you know
either you're doing yourself keyboard
typically yeah or programmable keyboard
so it can work it can work because
because with with do it yourself
keyboards
uh you have lots of you know
lots of variations and situations or you
know
you you know you can it can work well
so in fact you know i just showed you my
my my mouse click on the keyboard
uh you know so that even furthermore
reduces my need to click the mouse
button so
because clicking the mouse button is one
of the major
reason that the mouse causes rsi
especially drag you know it's you know
just just like the chord keys
control you know those those kind of
things and when you do drag
on the mouse you have to hold it put
pressure and keep your finger in that
stressed situation
for a while then you drag you know that
that's causing rsi
and also putting your hand always flat
on the mouse
you know most people you know palm users
especially palm palm uh grasp users you
put your hand on the mouse
all the time that's no good don't put
your hand on mars okay just
touch it when you need to
uh same thing for the trackball this way
you i don't you know you don't you don't
get the mouse hand
okay less swearing okay because google
censorship
uh g520
is not perfect for you so in what way
the g520 is not perfect for you okay i
can tell you
well basically because it doesn't have
enough buttons
okay g5 to zero so this one doesn't have
it only have besides those
standard ones on top you'd only have
okay
two thumb buttons and one more three
thumb buttons here
and two more on the on the top left okay
not enough because one is
back to previous page browser okay back
to previous the other one is closed
current
tab the other one is copy then the
top two i have them as previous tab next
tab
okay not enough i don't have i need i
need one for paste
i need one to you know not enough
to for example undo the last closed
tab uh so
not enough buttons that's a problem but
however the other one
okay so
i'm i'm with this um
mushroom kingdom idiotic shirt someone
gave it to me
i don't think this suits me um
so so this is my old one ten years old
it's not good okay so this wheel makes a
scratchy noise very annoying
very annoying this one is not much
better
okay back to the mouse so i got this one
this one's got much more
buttons like four more buttons than the
g502 so you got six
you know six on the thumb and two you
know
but however the problem with this one
actually this one is
less ergonomic okay so let me explain
so you go to uh mouse so you know so
it's this one versus that one the g502
the buttons are lighter okay uh my
photos are not so great
but anyways the buttons are lighter
than this one this one it takes much
more force to press the
side buttons and that's no good
you know ideally so i have some idea
about the ultimate mouse
uh i have not seen any other people done
it
and i wrote about it a little bit uh
last few days ago
so the ultimate mouse that's gonna take
uh some time to explain the ultimate
amount of
first of all what you want is
uh let me show you okay so first of all
what you want is
you want light buttons okay
what i mean by light you want them to be
[Music]
here okay so here is someone
you know someone using the keyboard
key switches as mouse buttons so there's
a do it yourself
and you know some of these are id ideas
and this guy actually did it so he
modified
he he he modified
he modified the mouse so that now it has
you know keyboard buttons on it
and here's a sketch you know by some
other guy
and then another guy made this one
and another guy made this one you know
the the
the idea is that you want keyboard
switches on the mouse why because
keyboard switches are much lighter
so why that's for ergonomic purposes
because you have to use this
when you use it eight hours a day you
want lighter switches like
yesterday i talked about why lighter
switches is
important uh
but for a mouse you probably want
something
clicky like blue switches so you want it
to be
45 maybe 50 grams 50 grams or 60 grams
switch
those are still lighter than the than
the
mouse button so called uh
the the mouse buttons they are called
micron or something like
microns which you know it's a company
who makes the mouse switches
so that's a summary so let me copy that
okay
so copy that go to talk show paste it
here
then we talked about then go back to the
mouse
we talked about that versus that
close uh okay close
wait undo copy that back to emacs paste
it
back to browser close it copy here
um what
yeah paste it close uh copy
here paste it okay we talked about these
three
uh these two mouses okay this one versus
that one this one is the buttons are
harder to press
but otherwise you know it's this one is
pretty good okay it's wireless also
bluetooth
this one also have wireless version but
it's very expensive hundred
hundred five dollars or something
so between these two there are pros and
cons
you know this one is more ergonomic uh
but not many buttons uh it has wireless
version
okay this one is much cheaper you know
like 40 dollars cheaper
and plus it has small buttons but
however the buttons are harder to press
and uh and the the shape
i would i prefer this one okay the
general shape
okay that's it for today so if you like
my stuff you know go to my blog
keyboard website and stuff and buy it
okay
let me paste it here go there uh if you
are in usa buy it for my amazon links
or you can paypal me you know paypal
you know go to my website you'll see my
paypal and patreon
links or you can buy my emacs tutorial
and javascript in depth
okay that's it let's see i'm gonna shut
down
in one minute so i guess we talked about
yeah
we talked over an hour so i'm going to
shut down
now i'm just going to
shut down so we talked about that i'm
going to clean up
my
my talk show page and
shutting down so if you have last words
posted there okay
14 people watching
right uh you know i i think i had a bird
brain moment
i mean well not not a moment but the
fourth for the past 30
minutes i've been rambling in a
incoherent way
richard stowman you know he don't type
he don't he no longer types much you
know he got isi you know
if we want to talk about richard stowman
he got isi
in the 1980s okay
and 1980s back then
you know throughout 1990s i read
every article richard strowman stoleman
ever wrote on the free software
foundation website
you know free software foundation in the
1990s i was a fan
of richard stowman and i was a fan of i
was a
proponent i was advocate of the free
software foundation
you know their ideology
what do you know i'm young just like you
guys
so i was a fan you know i support
richard stroman so i
i have read every article
on the free software foundation or gpr
you know the gnu
you know website in the 1990s everyone
or basically essentially every one of
them
uh whatever you know they have there
i've read everything
then of course i uh i started to use
emacs and i read
a lot so so so richard storman got
rsi so i have article you can see
okay search for famous programmers with
rsi okay so
there it is famous programmers with
repetitive strain injury
so first you know the biggest example is
richard stowman this is in the 1990s
so he got you know he's got he has an
article
by the time i you know so this article i
wrote is in 2010
so by 2010 i cannot find the original
article
about richard snowman rsi uh
which i have read you know back then but
instead
you you know i got the second hand from
by the michael tn man guy who is
uh founder of the cygnus sigwin okay
so you are what you are looking at
history now you know
today even sick win is dead you know
nobody is using sick wins now but
in the 1990s it's a big thing it's a big
thing if you want to use unix
on windows okay but today you know
you know there's microsoft has linux on
windows
anyway so that so i got a second hand
information
i mean this guy michael tn man the
founder of sigwin
he wrote about richard stoneman rsi but
however richard solomon himself
has an article i forgot where i cannot
find it
you know by 2010. anyway so richard
snowman so anyway
but since 1990s since since
about the year 2000 richard stowman
basically stopped coding
you know he become the guru the you know
the gospel the guru like the you know
like those new age gurus he can fly you
know he can fly
he just sit there and he just talk and
you
you give him money that's what he has
become he just
sit there do nothing and money comes to
him
the gospel of communism which
you know free software foundation uh
yeah then another biggest example is
jamie
zoensky uh you know i was
kind of a admirer of jamie zorensky jwz
he's more known as jwz
i have like 10 articles about jwz okay
throughout the past 20 years
and i've emailed him we exchanged email
maybe maybe three times five times
so jwz saudi jwz
you know where do we um
okay i guess you you don't even find the
uh
oh how do you spell his name
jimmy z-a-w-i-n-s-k-i okay
so anyway i have about like five five
articles
about this guy jwz he he become
very famous of course so here you can
see some of my articles
so he is also a biggest biggest example
of isi you know
you read his story written like in 1999
before there's a word blog you know he's
also he's a giant
he's one of the guy very dramatic
dramatic okay
like you know in this open source
software community
or free software community there are few
people who are very dramatic for example
the most famous
are richard simon of course although
he's not
he's not drama for drama purposes he's
not
you know intentionally creating drama
but he's one of the
uh dramatic guy because of his behavior
and so so
you know eating food richard showman
jamie zawinski is one of the dramatic
you know
flamboyant okay he he's a he's
like actually he's also an [ __ ] in
his behavior he
i think he's a okay guy okay ethically
he's a
not bad person but he's one of the very
dramatic
person and he write a turn like me blog
you know before there's a word blog you
know
he write a ton okay then when he talk he
you attack
people you attack things you know he
talked dramatically
jamie zorensky of course he he's out of
programming industry
professionally for 20 years by now you
know he started he
opened the bar and uh today he's he i
i don't think he's still a code that
much here but
you know he started his own bar but
unlike richard snowman he's still cold
jamie zoensky still called when he began
about you know he became very rich
after netscape so he started by and or
club or whatever then he he's keep
talking about things about
you know then the problem with him is
that you know
anyway i like i liked him okay but
but back about three years ago four
years ago when
when the trump okay the trump issue the
social justice
gang versus trump you know trump you
know u.s election
i had an exchange there's a there's an
incident between me and him
and he this this guy jamie zorensky when
it comes to
kind of personal opinions you know he's
he's an [ __ ] okay so he just
basically he
you know i talked you know i should um i
anyway i wrote about it you have to
he i i think you still can find it i
wrote about it
anyway he's an [ __ ] uh
so
so anyway so he's he's one of the most
famous
uh people who got rsi very bad okay
to the degree basically your your
your programming career is done for
then there is uh you still use c green
okay
uh then there is ben wing who is the x e
max coda the lead x e max
coder when it comes to xd max most
people think of jwz
because he's the most dramatic you know
stealing staining the spotlight
but ben wing is the other leader
of uh after jwz okay after 1990s
bing wing okay he's got even worse isi
you know he to the degree that basically
that ended his programming career
okay then then then there's this guy
john
osternaut who is the creator of the you
know
uh tcr programming language he doesn't
talk much
you know he doesn't he's not a dramatic
guy you know
so back then when when tcr was famous
over
you know in around year 2000 he became
famous too and he wrote an
article or two but but he basically
he doesn't talk he's not a dramatic guy
okay he's a professor
and he's a vi user okay
so anyway so that's about that so that's
it
uh that's it but you know so
i wanted to talk about actually so every
time i start a video
i have actually quite a lot to talk
about so
we haven't get into the the issues and
intricacies of pain computing okay so
the question is which
which pen are better you know for for
example you have this type of tip
you have this type of tip then you have
this type of rubber tip
you probably have seen that then you
have this active pen
which takes the battery you can turn it
on you can see a light
there you see so what's the differences
uh you know which one is better what's
you know i i
i have to talk about that i didn't know
about them until
you know two years ago i started to use
them uh
and pain computing is fantastic okay i
also have a tablet
i also have a tablet so that i can you
know
okay that's it for today uh donate
don't forget