good morning guys welcome to another
episode of accent our show today is 2019
October 23rd Wednesday 11:30 in the
morning San Francisco time good morning
Freddie
and good morning Bart I don't know if
party if you are still here high school
I screwed up my timing the YouTube
schedule yesterday because that is
problematic because that's the way my
life because yesterday I slept late so I
thought you know I couldn't make it to
his 11:00 because it's going to break my
back sometimes that happens like you
know so I plan to make it three o'clock
in the afternoon but I made a mistake in
the YouTube time so it becames 3:30 in
the morning and apparently I was not
aware of it
therefore it went so therefore it's back
now now we are live so let's check if
I'm alive yes indeed live yellow orange
for people watching ok let's begin
talking about today stuff today stuff I
have random topics and the random topics
let's just begin
good morning part c'mon in Danielle's
sierpinski now sierpinski is a term in
mathematics because there is a science
key triangle it is it is named after the
mathematician now I don't remember
sierpinski who which mathematician is
that where he from that is let us see so
Hinske triangle lithography
something-something Polish mathematician
okay so you are polish Warsaw sub
ski oh that's that's a guy
what salsa Pinsky oh okay so that that's
a Polish name oh I never I never saw his
photo so he looks like that Polish
mathematician so I never read what he
did okay so what so Waclaw you know
polish names you know polish has special
pronounciation I don't know how it's
done but anyway he was a mathematician
Polish mathematician from 1882 to 1969
he died one year after I was born he was
known for contributions to set theory
research on axiom of choice oh and the
Continuum Hypothesis and number theory
theory of functions in topology he
published over 700 papers and 50 books I
see interesting not like me do you know
okay so let's take good money so you are
you from are you in Poland Poland okay
we gonna talk about some random topics
and that's a show so I'm going to show
you I'm gonna show you my ultimate
hacking keybo keyboard okay I have a new
layout for the for my ultimate hacking
keyboard now remember to turn the video
back so this is my new setup change from
the Kinesis advantage to keyboard you
know just for a change I might use this
for a month or two or something
you know then I'll switch again
something like that yeah because I have
not you know it's actually if you have
repetitive strain injury
it is good to change your keyboard now
in there because it changes the muscle
memory and add some variation to how you
use your muscles moaning green tech
green tag to Russia
and ultimate hacking keyboard yeah so
let's let me show you that and I have a
new layout folks off like he's okay so
yesterday I started watching Chuck again
and I think CSV looks like your evil
twin brother who is that CS Lee Chuck
yeah I have no idea who is that so post
post link let's see if you can do it I
have a live chat Oh No
try try it let's see if we can click on
that
so ultimate hacking keyboard okay you
guys spy it actually if you buy this
keyboard for my website I don't get any
money because they don't have Amazon
link and you know I want to get them to
get affiliate you know I that I don't
think they are doing that I'm not sure
anyway that is awesome layout for Emacs
Emacs seen good morning Cathy
good morning Cathy to London so the
ultimate hacking keyboard is a fantastic
keyboard because you know actually I
don't like compact keyboards okay so
this is a compact keyboard so you know
it only has it only has 64 keys not
enough not enough for anything so that
that is why I have this programmable I
mean I have this keypad I used to
program you know things previous tab
next tab previous browser page Nick next
browser you know back forward backward
the page and zoom in zoom out actually
so let me show you what what are the
keys I talked about this a few times so
so that sifu head okay so so actually so
you can see then I need to see this and
you can see these here okay hold on so I
can demonstrate you can see both okay so
this is the next previous tab okay
previous
stab you know this is research on honk
loud speaker the shape you know why is
this important this is fascinating
because this shape has to be based on
mathematical principles and that curve
is called track tricks ok this is
tremendously fascinating mathematics
geometry topic track tricks and one
application of this is the loud horn
speaker design ok so anyway let's go
back to these so this is previous
previous tab next time next time you
know I can fly through my tabs and this
is the this is backward page previous
page so it's for example backward page
previous backward previous and this is
zoom out zoom out zoom out zoom backing
zoom back in zoom zoom in and out and
this is select all copy paste fantastic
okay this is new tab new tab and this is
closed tab you see and close tab and
this is an open class close open last
close close open eyes close so you are
switching around you close it whoops
miss egg open reopen fantastic and this
is reload why do I need to reload
because I'm working on my website I
makes change change I press this key
just reload okay and those are arrow
keys okay arrow and this is zoom you
know fullscreen toggle fantastic and
that's just that I don't use this is
just back to deed and this is now this
this is a feature of this keypad anyway
I don't use that so you see I programmed
the macro using the carabiner using the
the Mac software because I'm a Mac I'm
using the carabiner software and all
this information is on my website if you
go to my keyboard section so I was going
to say
show so I was going to say keyboards you
go to keyboard you got economic
keyboards then you go to ultimate
hacking keyboard now this is the
keyboard first of all it's very compact
okay so for those of you who prefer you
know 60 60% 50% 40% idiotic thing you
know you might like this okay and this
is far far far better than the happy
hacking keyboard happy hacking kibo is
one of the worst keyboard in the
universe and it is the elite keyboard
among the hackers you know the UNIX
philosophy that those people okay now
I'm I'm going to try to do this video
somewhat in a professional manner so I'm
not going to swear for a change you know
let's do that once in a while so this is
hacking hacking keyboard is well known
everyone loves it you know people talk
about it all the time it's the one of
the dramatic things like Emacs and vim
oh are you using Emacs are you using
Emacs and when it comes to keyboards
happy hacking oh look I got happy
hacking $300 $250 scrapped and and so if
you like you know so this is this is one
of the earliest compact keyboard it's
got 60 keys something like that 60 keys
okay no arrow keys you see the important
thing to note is that it does not have
arrow keys my friends if you want to
arrow arrow if you want to play pac-man
you have to hold down function key FN
you have to hold like a lot of a disease
you have to hold on function key then
you can play might you might be able
might want be able maybe to pac-man okay
pac-man and actually we can go there
play and there is another version this
is the this one is called happy hacking
light it does have arrow keys but
however the key switch
is not the tapas which what people want
okay this one the happy hacking keyboard
is famous for the tapas which one is
what it's it's one of the bad switch
okay
tapas which I have pictures here tapas
which no good okay I tried it no good I
don't like it
happy hacking and you have cute girls
from Japan lovely okay and you have this
magic wand fantastic the boyfriend to
all the girls in modern society almost
almost like every girl owns one now and
then you have some of these Japanese
comics okay
this comic is actually we shall not say
it here so hello hello hello guys Daniel
Simmons green deck and won't see you we
don't see your desktop okay you do now
I think yes so now so what we what we're
gonna do is oh yeah so I was talking
about happy hacking keyboard no good
okay it's 250 to 300 dollars its worst
okay
I've I've seen all the mountains and and
rivers happy hacking keyboard is the
worst of them all okay but but you know
it's like you know you got this elite
status everyone keeps talking about it
every day day and night happy hacking
have you hacking you know why part of
the reason you know bees besides the top
bug tapas key switch is because you know
it doesn't have a window key oh my god
UNIX lovers you love it this does not
have a window key okay and it does not
have arrow key so it's it's it's
difficult so it's a real man's keyboard
you know you know things like that
that's why it's famous and no function
keys crap so happy hacking no good but
however it's compact you know so if you
like this compact keyboard you know no
number pad and some
them doesn't have these and you know
among these nerds these keyboard nerds
they have jargons like the keyboard
without number cat No
without number pad is cord you see
here's a number pad numerical keypad
that's a fully qualified correct name no
Mariko keypad okay what a mouthful and
but you know you just go at number pad
but however among these elite keyboard
nerds this is called when you have a
keyboard that without the numerical
number keypad numerical keypad they call
it ten keyless 10 key less with this
from these idiots this this collection
of idiots 10 keyless okay tkl so if you
go to Amazon you you know you shop for
keyboard use nice see you might see you
know something something feel code tkl
10 keyless okay that just means no
numerical keypad you know they they want
to use that jargon so you know why
jargons because part of the reason
jargon the purpose of the jargon in in
communities is because they they
indicate that you are a insider you are
a member of the group you are not an
outsider you know that's important
because when you have a community
community Emacs meme Python programmers
you know the Haskell programmers or UNIX
philosophy you know Linux users or
gangsters so you know even gangsters and
politicians in social justice cat you
know you use jargon zone or prisoners
for example you have jargons why they
become popular because part of the
reason for the existence of jargon is
that they indicate you are the insider
you are not outsider you see so among
the keyboard nerds you know this week or
they could think tank idiot 10 key less
and they would they would
you know and then there's also they code
60% 70% for example this one it will be
you code like 70% keyboard and some of
them such as the happy hacking without
even the number keys you call it 60% 60%
keyboard you know it's like they are
thinking you know because it's like 60%
of a 60% of a full keyboard you know six
sixty percent idiot okay idiot but
however you know to be practical let me
tell you a trick when you see 60 percent
keyboard basically it means it's it's
got 60 keys 60 or 65 something like that
so and and today you have some people
you know who get excited about 40%
keyboard you know these keyboard nuts
these keyboard idiots they like 40%
keyboard okay you got less and less keys
to the degree for example some of these
this one is got 70 keys okay and this
isn't not bad this is we you know 70% 7
70% keyboard but now you have less and
less you know the verge to 46 Keys okay
46 so this is 40 percent keyboard you
know among the keyboard notes you go to
you go through keyboard hack there's a
website you go to test thority test
Authority you know it's a combination of
desk authority they combined the words
test test authority without a I think so
that's another website for keyboard
phonetics keyboard hack is another site
and the reddit are mechanical keyboards
that's another site dedicated to
keyboard fans
so for example this is a prominent
example of say my organ arm ik 40%
keyboard on this keyboard
atreus very popular you don't have you
don't have numbers even you don't have
arrow keys you don't have function keys
you know I have page up and page down
you don't have home and keys and you
don't have arrow keys and you don't have
number keys what what do you do when you
want to type a number key you have to
press a modifier ok the extreme idiocy
and also you don't even have brackets
and parentheses you oh you know if you
want to type that you have to press a
thumb key you know modifier key and this
keyboard is rather idiotic you know in
my pure opinion you know he's a guy I
respect actually so he's a guy and he's
a very you know he program enclosure he
programming Lua his expert in those
languages and he also program you know
he created this keyboard and he also
programming Emacs Lisp he has created
several non-trivial eMac miss packages
so he is a big shot among programmers
he's a kind of well-known his name is
Theo hackleburg he's American and and he
has a nickname called new room Neko
[Music]
necromancer no not not Nico what is of
about fire okay
necromancy or something wait not Nico
but pyro
no but he's got I forgot what's his
nickname but you go to his website you
SEL okay let's go to his website techno
manseok a cat techno techno man see now
that word has that word is a word he
created kind of okay but however that
word techno man see you see here
techno man see has a etymology has roots
man see now the part man see means magic
so you have you have pyromancy okay
means fire fire magic okay so he's got a
nickname techno Mansi you know so
apparently he do magic by technology but
he's qualified he's a great programmer
okay but so he created this keyboard
okay okay yeah I don't like I don't like
this 40% that's anything less than six I
don't even like 60% so but however if
you like 60% keyboard a remedy you know
you you have to think different like
Apple so the remedy is that you know if
you like a if you like 60% keyboard
let's say let's say you know let's say
let's say this one so this one we are
talking about wait let's go back here
and you see this one is 60% keyboard 64
keys so if you like this sick you know
if you like if you saw a 60% keyboard
you like what can you do to remedy the
situation of too few keys what you can
do is go to my website and go to keypads
buy a programmable keypad okay
programmable these are fantastic so you
use them in combination you consider
them as a set you know not just the 60%
keyboard with a keypad as I said so this
is actually better because now you got a
keypad that's flexible you can put it in
on the right side or the left side so
this is great okay so you go to my
website and buy it okay bye from Kesari
support Sally's walk ok copy it and go
here and paste it paste
enter by now for for those of you
Americans who do amazon so let's answer
some questions
oh we haven't get to our topic yet I was
going to talk about ultimate hacking
keyboard but I was going to talk about
ultimate new layout for for sawfly keys
this layout okay it's fantastic play up
for over here way over here over here so
this is my new layout Forks off like
he's okay so this is about Emacs and so
we might be starting to talk about that
that's about Emacs so you're gonna start
to talk about why this is this layout is
designed that way but you know Emacs as
a different topic we might get into but
let me take a pause and read the
comments and see people's reactions and
feedback okay so and let me get a drink
so today's drink is raspberry and
raspberry and cranberries and apple
juice this is the fuel for the body of
human animals you know like you drive
you drive and you go to gas station and
you pump gas in the same way you have to
do this because God said God say so
otherwise you die
okay so but gave us a link to a movie
let's look at the movie
I am pipi okay and paste the ID let's
see if we can find that see Ashley I am
DB biography okay let's look at
seriously who who is this guy
okay I don't know this guy seriously I
don't know his movies okay
Stepford Wives now that is a fascinating
that's a fascinating story
have you one have you seen that part but
anyway so he's not a big star I don't
know I don't know who is he so let's see
so seriously got got the acting bug is
his junior year of high school while
playing football film became his passion
he attended barababa but what what the
[ __ ] he then spent eight years in New
York City
acting with various theatre okay long
okay I don't know who is that guy and so
far says he is watching his movies Chuck
okay I don't know but is he American
that's the thing usually you see that's
usually the interesting question because
Chinese America those who were born in
USA or who came to USA when they are
very young like five years old these
people Americans I mean yeah we are or
I'm American as well but I mean what I'm
saying is that these people who were
born USA these Chinese are very
different like the entire different
people from Chinese people in China or
elsewhere you see because it's not about
your skin color but rather it's about
your
of your environment you see so America
Chinese Americans that you know typical
Chinese Americans they they were pong
you know America though they are
everything they do they are thinking is
just like white American okay yeah
typically and they talk the American
talk they think the American think you
know it's it's different so it you see
America is a interesting country
interesting from interesting from a
historical perspective well it's
interesting because America is basically
the only country in a world that it's a
country of mixed race race you know tip
you know by by nature each country is
basically one race you know on different
regions you have Japan Japanese you know
they have you do have different local
ethnicities but but basically you know
you know the whole Japan is one race
close related race okay China
you got Chinese one race Korea you got
Koreans one race Germany you got John
German people one race kind of basically
okay England Scotland okay United
Kingdom actually you I didn't know
before but as you grow older you learn
more about things far away so UK is
United Kingdom and they have a flag of
the Union Jack you know like Union Jack
and that is actually composed of three
different flags you have the England
cross a red cross on a white background
England okay for the Queen then you have
Scotland Scotland is got this cross okay
that's there's a name for it okay
history you know you got names for these
courses and courses are heavily related
to God believe in the
the Christian allottee different
different branches you know they have
yeah okay let's go let's go to Saudi
Unicode and let's go to crosses let's
look at the different causes of the of
the world and basically they came from
that the cross is a symbol of
Christianity and they have historically
you have quite a variety of them and
let's remember where we are so I can
backtrack to my topics we were talking
about costs we were talking about
England we were talking about that okay
it's I so I forgot our different race
why America is interesting okay so hold
on a second let's continue with the
cross so you can see this is the Greek
cross okay now this thick one is used
for red cross
you know this is a well-known click this
is quick style cause then you have cross
on a shield you know this is this is
mostly known as far as I know is its I
when I see this course I think of the
crusade okay the Army Crusade the
Knights Knights are horses with this
shield that's what I think of guys
comments okay comments keep the comments
going let me know how am i doing
so you see this cross is a you know to
me I see this I just think of the
crusade you know I don't know much about
that but I'd you know you see pictures
you know the they fighting with Islam
crusade Crusaders you know there's a war
history so this open course okay so then
you have this Latin course okay so these
are Latin cross
then you have these Celtic cross okay
celtic celtic is that is the scandinavia
celtic the where the Thor the god Thor
came from then you have Saltire Saltire
cross did I pronounce it correctly I
probably did not satire cost so I think
that's yeah satire cause I think that's
the that's the Scotland Cross you know
it may not be because actually there's
intricate intricate histories then you
have this the most famous in modern
society every every white man wants to
talk about it non-stop this course we
shall not mention the name but actually
you know did you know this is actually a
Chinese character you know most westerns
don't know Western us Westerners these
white people are talking about this
thing every day day and night making
they need they needs to talk about this
that they need to talk about this day
and night they don't know what it is
this is this this is say what you are
seeing here is a Chinese character okay
and it's pronounced what okay it's
because I looked up when I was younger
when I was like good 12 years old 10
years ago oh you know I'm fascinated am
fascinated I have a strong interest
predilection towards these symbology
symbols you know how they are used for
you know since I was you know 10 years
old also
so I actually so this is actually a
Chinese character but most Chinese
people they would not know this is
actually a Chinese character we are
talking about you know writing a
character this is also ancient Buddhism
symbol okay that's orange and you see
this one oh this okay these are Asian
Buddhism symbol in fact I can show you a
picture of it
in some way okay he takes time to find
it but anyway this is a Buddhism symbol
Asian you know since 2000 2000 years ago
originates from India and they still use
it every every day I mean in Buddhism
you go to temples you go to China you
don't see that as much in China mostly
used well you see you do see it actually
but you can see it in India so let's see
sorry
reclining Buddha ah okay no comments
guys am i doing okay okay I'm doing I'm
doing I'm I'm alive okay check my status
remind me wait this OBS got a problem
now so discord discord and let's see I
got 10 people watching 10 10 is a crowd
three is a crowd so I got three times of
a crowd great so this symbol oh yeah we
are searching for reclining Buddha
okay so sorry we crying Buddha okay so I
want to go to my reclining Buddha page
Mori had okay maybe here clean deck
clean deck says yes you look like you
are like great still alright the
question is am I still alive yes I'm
still alright okay so you see you see
right there right there it is and this
reclining Buddha is at China China China
China China China China dafu temple then
zone yay can sue can sue okay China
dated year one year 1100 okay so this is
one thousand years old Buddha with this
symbol swastika okay
oh my god the Western white people their
ignorance yeah yeah you know you can you
can start to call me a racist now that's
what the obsession with the white
people's obsession you are racist racist
you are not raising racism is racism
everyday [ __ ] the day Oh brain don't
have nothing else to think about
that's the only thing well if in
particular the the in particular in the
past four years with the social justice
scan why why do American do that I mean
how did it become this such such a
obsession well I can tell you in my
opinion is because they you know you
have the slavery thing you know the
white people are obsessed about that
because then then there's this guilt and
there you have the American Indians
wiped out by the you know Europeans so
you have this deep deep seeded thing
about this so you know this racism and
thank you this is just forget about it
[ __ ] idiots so anyway so this symbol is
actually so it's Asian Buddhism symbol
but however you you see these two they
are actually Chinese characters in you
know in Asian Chinese dictionary you
obviously so when I was a child I was
fascinated you know that's why I'm still
doing Unicode you know I'm fascinated by
all these Unicode thing some of these
you know Egyptian hieroglyph Linear B
Cooney form okay wait for them to load
because they are sewing they are going
to slow down my video I'm going to see
lags so
so digressions in digressions la casa
Kathy look of intersectionality I'm an
expert of that topic actually I'm not
x-ray of that topic but I know full well
about that topic so Kathy says I'm
surprised that you've never been to many
mainland China so I yeah so that's true
I haven't been I would like to but today
I cannot you know you need money to go
actually my roommate is going back to
China this next year in January or so
January or February he's going back so
he's asking me you know he's asking me
to go with him for a month but that
requires two thousand US dollars I
cannot do it I don't have money so
anyway so you have Egyptian you know so
I am interested in symbols you see this
linear be symbology you know linear be
is very old 1450 1450 BC before Christ
okay so before Christ so this is this is
3,000 3,500 years old symbols we human
animals created using easy fascinating
so I'm interested in symbols since I was
child you know this voice is not showing
imp wave okay it's when you have
Phoenician Phoenicians is the oldest
Phoenician is considered the oldest
alphabet okay so you know so for example
we have Latin alphabet with today we
have Greek alphabet they all came from
Phoenician so this Phoenician evolution
of English alphabet and anyway so that's
Phoenician okay anyway back to this
swastika
Simba okay so it's a Buddhism symbol and
by the way Buddhism has this reclined in
Buddha okay it's a thing it's so today
you would call it a meme okay it's quite
interesting you have reclining Buddha
for example you never see me crying God
or reclining Jesus but we can in Buddha
is a thing because I read you know
Wikipedia you can this article reclining
Buddha the reason is because well in
Buddhism you know the Buddha got sick
you know or about to die so he's you
know lying on his bed so you got this
thing reclining budda okay and anyway so
let's go back to the crosses so this
character so so I'm saying I was saying
this character is actually a Chinese
character and since you know I looked up
since I was 10 like how is it you know
how is it pronounced you don't see it
much often it's pronounced one okay like
the character 10,000 in Chinese one so
that's about that cause you know you
call swastika swastika of course of
course in 1950 in 1940s it has
alternative meaning but by white people
okay the meaning of that symbol and ever
since that's that's a that's that became
obsession so anyway then you have all
the other crosses the Maltese Cross
okay this symbol Maltese Cross is very
much related to that okay you know why I
don't need to say then you are you also
have west Syriac west see be a cross
okay I don't know what that is about
then you have the cost of Jerusalem okay
this since it mentions name tourism I
think my friend Israel know about that
the story of course of Jerusalem I don't
know anything about that so is that is
this cost related to Jewish Judaism is
that is also so guys tell me okay Tibet
is this course of Jerusalem related to
Judaism so anyway so then you have also
duck also talks cross then you have
course of Lauren okay I don't know what
that it's about then you have cheer oh
you have taunted course you have ank
okay this egg is also ancient this tank
is as asian as the swastika okay some of
them you know mo asian than many of
these others this egg is from egyptian
okay
from egypt from this you can see
actually i think you see you see that
she this this this this creature
whereas that this creature is holding an
egg
I don't know how do you pronounce that
so
so this hieroglyph you you have these
animals you have these you know cows
sacred sacred cows you know lots of
stories related to these you know when
you when I see for example a sea cow I
mean poor I think of you know it reminds
me of Christian ality in Bible because
in there you know I don't know the Bible
well so Daniel says Jerusalem is the
gods is the god city in the final book
of Jan okay
Queen deck says I think the cause of
Jerusalem is about Christian ality in
Jerusalem
okay okay okay so anyway when I see the
pool you know I think of Bible story
where where there's
commend commandment thou shalt not
idolized other gods so like apparently
there is he you know at some point
people idolized pool and that's you know
that's not allowed in Amano feast
religions such as Islam Christian arity
and and Judaism I think you know they do
not allow it you cannot but meanwhile in
Buddhism Buddhism Buddhism is totally
different
ok it's not it's not God and it's not
about gods although you do have some
kind of gods anyway so so why they
worship pool I I can I can I can kind of
tell because pour pour pour is a sacred
and more in some countries for example
India you know you cannot you are not
allowed to eat cows because they are
sacred why because they give you milk
and they give you meat you eat them
something like oh wait in India you
don't eat them but they are you know
they help the crops things like that so
poor you know that's idolized by some
you know many I think several regions
poor typically typically you idolize you
know different regions you idolize the
animal that helps you for example poo is
an example elephant it's another example
in India
for example you have this card with
elephant head you can kind of think I
don't really know the history of that or
the religion of that but but basically
when you read a lot about these things
basically they you know the animal that
helped helped you the region becomes the
God that's kind of true for many many
regions so so we were talking about this
act thing so let's shrink shrink shrink
shrink again okay shrink this act
symbol in Egypt Asian Egypt now I try to
look up the meaning of that it's it's
not too clear anyway you can go to
Wikipedia they have a article about that
okay that's about cross okay now back to
our topic I was talking about England I
didn't know before but I learned you
know UK United Kingdom United is because
you know it's Scotland England and and
was it Wales way also something I I
Ireland you you have actually four of
them so anyway so you know I don't know
much about Europe you know but that's
the thing you pick up and England so
apparently you know the you apparently
the Scottish people and English English
people they are they were fighting all
over the past years did you know they
don't always agree and they are talking
about you know like two years ago they
are talking about separation you know
the you I don't want to be part of you
anymore so that's a Scottish and England
people so so so that's about yeah so we
were talking about that we were talking
about the Union Jack you know the United
in you know United Kingdom it's let's
see units let me show you sorry
Union Jack I have a collection of photos
of girls wearing
flag bikinis okay because I'm fascinated
by by this thing okay so hold on a
second let me go back to so this is this
is the Spice Girls which was popular
like 20 years 20 years ago
Spice Girls so hold on a second let me
go to open all of them
okay so these are actually photos of
girls wearing flag bikinis so I'm not
sure I want to show them you know but
anyway they are well they are covered so
that I think that's okay
so let's look oh [ __ ] okay so god that's
gonna be a problem that means I'm gonna
spend three hours to edit that second
out and the comments will be all deleted
because I realized once you edit the
video the comments will be gone that's a
problem anyway so I did this long ago
like 20 years ago in 2002 okay so that's
I've you know I don't remember what you
know some page you are whiskey so you
know but anyways the my what I want you
know the reason I'm interested you see
Union Jack is that you see some
countries in particular Britain and the
United States they have a thing about
waving flag things that you know you
have Union Jack on purse on cars on you
know a swimsuit on women's dress on
shoes you know this unit in Union Jack
shoes you see Union Union Jack boots
Union Jack dress Union Jack dress it's a
thing you know with with this it's a
thing and and in the same way in the
same way the USA you know is it's it's
the same okay let's see if we can okay I
have other photos I'm not sure I want to
go into okay so maybe not it mean it's
not that
so here USA you have the you you know
you it's a it's a thing it's a me okay
you wear bikinis or dress or whatever /
so you know or car so your computer
tech tech oh you know deca you can put a
you know or trucks you have you know
these lots of them tons of them every
day you go out I'll see it right away
almost you know thing with flag fasted
over but however you have to you know
one thing interesting is that this is
unique uniquely American and Britain
thing okay you know in many I think most
of the countries you do that you go to
jail okay you go to jail you know you is
considered sacrilege you cannot you know
you're not you know you are not supposed
to do that
actually people have done that and they
go - they went to jail you know for it
it is true I have articles about that
but I'm not going to navigate around
this page because Google censorship so
so actually is it on YouTube is it is it
allowed to show kids because you know
the I don't think it's allowed right
okay so but maybe just make this video
age restricted yeah but the question is
I mean even age restricted today allow
like showing tits without cover i think
it's allowed to show tits but make it
edge age mystic age restricted okay so
tit heck says tits are not allowed yeah
that's what I think I mean even age
restricted I don't think you allow
showing in oppose that's the thing you
know this you know you cannot have
pictures showing the nipple so anyway so
I'm talking about so it's a thing with
the American and Union Jack you know
American flag you have you have an
English take interest you you code stars
stars
or stars and stripes you know that's a
that's a name and for the UK flag
it's a Union Jack okay now I don't
remember why is it called Jack I think I
did look up before but I don't remember
what why is it called Jack so so let's
go back to the topic of so yeah I was
you know I was mentioning United Kingdom
because yeah so I was talking about USA
so I you know I was saying USA is kind
of unique in that it's a country where
where you don't have one ethnicity okay
but meanwhile the natural state of
things is that every country every
region you it's composed of basically
one ethnicity or one race you know China
Japan German German UK you know and in
Africa you know South Africa you know
things like that so white way so
actually I just thought about so why
white does USA became you know began to
have this kind of mixed thing well
because imperialism oh my god now I went
into this controversial topic I didn't
mean to but well you know I'm just
thinking about it when I'm talking about
actually that's true why did you create
it like a natural this is unnatural how
come how come you have a country where
it's actually mixed about different
people well if you want to trace the
history it's because imperialism began
with the United Kingdom you know the
British Empire that's how it began you
know were the white people shipping
around exploring the world exploring the
world then they do call Colin ISM you
know you occupy a place there becomes
your land
then so you see originally it's you know
it's other people you know people living
there won one race okay but you can't
you go over then it becomes your face
okay then you have a lot white people
then you import you do whatever you know
you you you you might imported you know
for example in USA that's how black
people from Africa came to USA then okay
then after hystyried and you know
something other happens okay then you
know imperialism tie-dyed color : ISM is
considered now considered bad okay also
by the white people okay for reasons so
then you UE massive MS occasion you know
you use supposedly the white people oh
they started to think oh you know they
are there anyway
it's you know ugly history so USA became
this country that is mixed of all you
like given you know people yeah that is
why so it's it's it's kind of a unique
place now the next question is is that
you're especially American my American
friends you might ask the next natural
question is that yeah so okay
he's historically you know things
happened but is the u.s. a currency you
know the mixed-race is it good or bad if
you ask me my answer is that okay it's
not it's it's not good or bad it's just
the way things are okay just that's okay
yeah I don't have you know it's not it's
not good or bad it's just the way things
are so you know live and let live so USA
Today which I'm a member of is a country
where it's a mixed race okay so you have
you have white people black people
[ __ ] people Mexicans you know
everywhere you have Russia and people
everywhere Japan and that's
you know so we you know we can we can go
on from there
but however today you have the social
justice can and you know so in my
opinion the US ways you know is it is
you got a lot of problems and it's
creating a lot of problems so not you
know the social justice can American
extreme left they created they become
very bad you know a beginning about four
years ago 2016 but it's but that's just
part of it but because USA is also doing
lots of other things even before the
social justice can doing a lot of bad
things in different ways that's my
opinion
and also like I mentioned in my opinion
the obsession about justice the
obsession about racism about all these
about you know it's no good just move on
you know forget about that move on
that's what I think okay so what do you
think about the climate change okay I
kind of we kind of talked about that
yeah actually so there is a video where
I I think you can find it where I talked
about my position on that
so YouTube Saudi crime it let's see if
we can find that meanwhile let's go to
saw talk show and such for climate okay
climate change change actually such for
global warming okay so there it is this
video let's show in browser this is 2019
September 29th open source Richard
Stallman recycling global warming
democracy dies in darkness so we talked
about I talked about my position on
global warming so it's kind of long so
that's we skip that
check check that out check that out
League of noobs so I think Google didn't
see that so I would be fine I think I
think you allowed me to so Freeman says
I think a lot of show Tate's will make
restricted
okay so Freddie says are you sure I saw
some artistic YouTube video with the
naked women it depends but the question
you see Freddie I think the the critical
thing is whether he shows nipples you
see that's the thing
you know if you show tits that's fine
make it H restricted with age restricted
but you cannot show the nipples that you
have to have some kind of cover I think
okay I think something fell don't know
what do you think about Crimean change
Daniel says show tits okay
tree tree boo they simon says how to
make a patio her blue keyboard app for
android oh are you the guy asking me
that on twitter and so my answer
actually actually I don't know the
answer because I have never coded
Android or or iPhone apps so actually I
do not know how to do that if you want
me to do that
pay me you know because then I have a
goat study electron and I can do it in
one week so so if you are the guy on
Twitter or if you are not email me okay
email me or private chat to me so let's
talk about that you have to pay me
though because I'm not going to do it
for free about how to make a keyboard
app for Android okay Freddie says I'm
also interested in Danielle's question
above with Emacs
okay Daniels question from above with
Emacs so where is the newest question
Daniel says
okay but I don't know so I don't think
so in fantasy you talk about real dates
okay what's question can you guys type
again then your question so can you type
the question again daniel says I've
heard you like Ruby and eMac this can
use sometimes show your Emacs and Ruby
config okay or how did you manage to
organize your workflow okay let's do a
max session again sometime soon
so how long have I been talking today so
let's check I think one hour so I think
let's stop now
I mean I'm yeah I'm gonna stop in five
minutes
let's make you know I'm trying to get
away from the 90 minutes long talk one
hour is good enough so let's do Emacs in
the future and in fact if you go to my
youtube channel of a new tab sorry
YouTube okay go to sorry YouTube
youtube.com sorry okay you go to my
youtube channel I'm going to start to
announce each day we are going to have a
specific topic for each day so you go to
my YouTube channel you go to communities
and I will post here about my schedule
my time and what topic for each day so
I'm going to do more Emacs stuff you
know I am thinking for each week it's
gonna be one day for Emacs one day for
JavaScript one day for : one day for
random you know random commentary you
know thoughts about politics and
whatever things like that so I'm going
to post here as well as my discord
channel now if you guys are not on
discord joining okay
very much would like that subscribe my
channels share my videos thump of and
let's see how do I invite people text
channels create invite permanent
permanent link copy curls go back here
join discord
sorry okay so if this is sort of a Sally
fan club or anything you guys are
interested you might you meet
interesting people in my YouTube talk
you can talk on this code and every time
I mentioned this code I think of bad so
[ __ ]
father you still here so this custom so
what okay so I'm going yeah so each day
I'm going to announce what we're gonna
talk about it's better okay I'll try I'm
gonna post here and I think there might
be some time change as well because my
schedule is just bad we've been doing 10
10 a.m. for for for quite long for two
months now so what so what is the next
thing I'm talking about so actually so
we backtrack so we were talking about
how USA is a country of different laces
yeah W yeah okay so we were talking
about how USA is a country of different
races and and we were so we did not
cover actually what we wanted to talk
about today
it's open that cuz that Cosette opens a
talk show so today we were planning to
talk about the Salahi's for Emacs for
the ultimate hacking keyboard actually
there's quite a few things okay here is
a website that's alternative to Google
Talk if you want to video an audio chat
to your friends or text chat or to a
group of people this is a fantastic
website okay meet dot chit dot SI this
website Israel there's a friend Israel
introduced to me okay yeah jitsi is nice
okay so this is a great website for that
you can talk to it's easy to use and you
know I don't think you even need to
register a account yeah seems super
simple to use so just go to website you
can you can get a URL and post to your
friend and they can join you and start
to talk without having need to open
account and other topic okay poor
granham created a new list lisp language
code Bell which is idiotic okay so
actually that's another topic so but I
think that's it for today we so guys any
questions and comments in opinions
post like posts now any Excel talk show
page okay so close copy paste
Egyptian hieroglyph closed único linear
be okay that's very interesting
curse unicode for Nisshin alphabet very
interesting place here close movie head
one night in Bangkok this is a fantastic
song you guys gonna go you gotta go
bear head and listen to it it's a
classic very fun song one night in
Bangkok
and the reason we are showing that video
is because we cranium put ha
[Music]
okay the reason we are talking about we
are having this one night in Bangkok
page is because we have the reclining
Buddha this is a meme it's a meme my
friend go to 4chan and post this okay
Kassar says reclining buddha rules
everything so close that Thank You Kathy
and Union Jack okay and then we have the
Union Jack which is we don't want to
post that because Google is gonna ban
the social justice scans they are
sensitivity about the word is going to
do harm to you
Union Jack it's a thing you know it's a
fascinating thing it's a culture it's
actually this is a about culture why
American and British they have a thing
about wearing flags and by the way by
law by US law this is not allowed okay
as far as I know I I kind of looked a
bit so by US law you are not allowed to
you are not supposed to wear a dress you
know bikini
you know stars stars stars and spangled
bikini but you know but actually that's
law you know but but then you have
American cultures which is pervasive you
have you have a flag you know you you
know if you go to my website you have
hundreds of pictures I collected about
flag things you have you see in cars you
see motorcycles you see in you know race
you know like race cars you see in
airplanes you see in US Navy US Air
Force jet fighters you have flag you
know u.s. star-spangled flag painted you
know over the jet fighter they fight
back
this is US government you know military
they also do that then you you have in
bikini underwear women's lingerie you
have everywhere shoes
yeah shoes and and and in toenails
you know women you know you can paint
your toenails into a American flag you
see all that everywhere so so it's a
thing it's a it so this is cultural
thing but meanwhile you you know Indian
there's a girl Indian actress who put on
a Indian flag dress she and people get
angry you have a mob you know you have a
it's reporting on the news you have a
map crying and anger mob you know who
wants her shutdown who wants first
canceled canceled culture and you know
there are quite a few other stories but
but it's a thing it's a mean for
American flags for example it's also
popular in China even you see I have
photos okay you see Chinese girls
wearing bikini or some you know girls
dress you know hot dress with American
you know star-spangled theme on it you
know so in China Chinese girls Chinese
people who grew up in China also wear
that Oh in Japan use sometimes you will
see that because it has become you know
it's a thing it's a meme and when I was
young before I came to USA you know this
way in fact the girls you know we're in
flag we always a flag rope or whatever
you know rope or bath towel whatever you
know that he that is my that's what I
see the old one my god this is America
in America you know the freedom it's
very open but that's that's the
impression I got you know you got yeah I
mean though other people in Taiwan you
know the before I came to when I was you
know when I was 13 years old
oh my god that's America you can you
know you have these kind of things when
you come to America it's something else
I mean okay it's not exactly what you
imagined because when it comes to
sexuality you know American culture is
kind of nervous because because because
of the it's almost like a you know
because they're Christian arity I forgot
what's the word
they are prudish you know they they are
sensitive about sex what's the word it's
a Christian from a Christian background
there's a particular branch of Christian
arity anyone remember a particular
branch of Christian ality I forgot the
words anyway so anyway so America in
general I mean they are kind of
sensitive about sex topics even though
they you know Asia in particular in
Japan so it's very different so anyway
that Catholic no not Catholics they the
Americans that so so what I'm thinking
is that American are sensitive about
sexual sexualities because you know for
example he you know we are talking about
before mm okay now today with social
justice things changed entirely to
something else but I'm talking about
let's say before year 2000 so he before
year 2000 in Europe when it comes to sex
it's very open so you will see for
example sculptures of of gods or
goddesses with tits showing everywhere
in public you know Europe your of your
even see that in ads in public ads you
know public billboards ads with
sometimes tits showing you know the food
tits uncensored with nipples showing you
can see that in Europe
now different country are different I
guess but as far as I know I've seen it
you know in Europe you see that
but in America you will never ever never
see that if even in smoke sculptures for
example for example you have personal
person personal vocation of the freedom
goddess justice goddess you know that
from Greek or ancient
sometimes they wear a rope with one tits
showing you know that's common you know
Greek from the Greek origin you have
many of Greek goddess goddesses but
however in America typically you don't
show that that's not allowed so you will
not well it exists some sculptures you
know goddesses with tits showing but
generally they they don't show it they
cover it then you know you know for
example if news if news media are
reporting about some news about some
building some court justice building
they don't take photo of that they try
to take an angle so that you don't show
a sculpture with you know the god the
justice goddess or whatever with that
it's showing yes because that's the u.s.
culture what's the name of the
background religion not Catholic
because Catholic is not us a thing usa's
is most Protestants but there is a
branch that describes this let's let's
try to look that Jewish is a world ok
prudish that describe a prude okay that
describe the kind of personality or
attitude who is you know not open about
nudity or sexuality so so wikipedia says
a prude meaning honorable woman of ok
from French okay etymology from French
meaning honorable woman
is a person who is described as a would
be described themselves as being
concerned with decorum or propriety
significantly in excess of normal
prevailing standards he or she may be
perceived as being more uncomfortable
than most with sexuality or nudity yes
now American culture told sex is kind of
like that okay Morris it has that but
however I'm trying to find the arrangin
because Puritan there it is
Puritan that's the word I'm looking for
not moments I mean well maybe but you
know I don't know about the actual
history of this much but anyway that's a
word Puritan that's what I'm thinking so
let's see Puritan were English
Protestants okay in a sixteenth in
seventeenth centuries who thought who
sought to purify the Church of England
of Roman Catholic practices maintaining
that the Church of England has not been
fully reformed and need to become more
protests and okay
messy history of Christianity
so period Puritanism played a
significant role in English history
especially doing protector rates okay I
don't know what that is some kind of
historical event then you have okay then
it gets complex reformed theology peyote
cover nests okay another branch charges
separatists and so on and so anyway
that's that's I don't know much about
this topic but that's what I I think you
know the American true to attitude
towards nudity's because Puritans that's
my opinion that's what I think
so thank you guys for watching we end up
on the note of Puritans hope so have a
good day bye guys donate ok PayPal me
patreon
go to my website pay me and last thing
my last thing to mention I have I'm
offering tutorials one on what video
tutorials teaching Emacs or Emacs Lisp
entire whole course or JavaScript
ok I'm offering that and I can also do
colon and Python but actually I don't I
haven't been coded colon daily for a
year and Python I'm only you know I
don't know Python I mean I don't know
goal and that well so anyway but but I
do offer a Mac this entire course you
know I am a Mac B's expert so if you
like that contact me privately so I
offer three hours one hour a day for
three days basically three days one hour
a day in a week we spread our in a week
I offer that for $100 so if you are
interested talk to me okay
email prime it for email private talk to
me thank you guys bye guys