good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is July
8th 2019 9 o clock a.m. in California
and today we are going to do a
JavaScript live coding session Tran Chet
tires let me show you what that is so
let's go to my Emacs of my math blog so
let me put this here so you can see and
let's move here
Tran cheat tiles so good let's go
through here and that's just such for
you know I've been wanting to do this a
few months since few months ago so this
so let me show you what is the transit
time transit how is this basically it's
a decorative pattern it's actually a
technique to create a decorative pattern
it's called Tran trijet tortured tiles
you can see you can find it on Wikipedia
so it's a technique to generate
interesting patterns what you do is you
create a square and you mark
you know the edges of the square you
connect them by circles or you know arc
of a circle or other patterns then you
have a bunch of these squares in
different orientation then you have you
know the final result is this
interesting pattern so transit has so
what we are going to do is we are this
is a gif animation from somewhere online
and what we are going to do is to use
JavaScript to create this today so
you're gonna you know hopefully you
gonna learn some
script coding in JavaScript
now let's pop this out this will take
like 30 minutes
you know I hopefully we can do it in 30
minutes but probably 40 minutes or more
I hope not
so 28 hours so let's let's begin shall
we let's let's see how we wanted to how
we want to do this 28 tiles so so let's
go to math block okay so we gonna so
this is my math block and I'm just
creating a new file here let's say
transit tiles
okay and and I'm using Emacs and music
supply keys so start start command log
mod so I'm going to turn on command log
mod so you can see all my Emacs commands
I call I'm using sapphire keys so
Trenchard house that's its to a new page
okay that basically just generates a
link and it creates a new page so we can
see here the source code okay transient
house now
let's when people watching good morning
say hi here trendy house so we're gonna
start to write a Java Script ranchitos
okay so first of all create a create a
new file link link it link if I open it
it's empty
okay and this is the empty violets for
the date then we start to code
so view these in browser actually let's
view this in Chrome because in Chrome I
have JavaScript on we cannot do this so
we're gonna code let me put some
comments here live coding Java sweet
chunky tiles and Trenchard tiles is this
okay so let's start coding so what what
we want to do first of all we need to
have a display area that is this is the
area where the JavaScript is going to
insert the graphics so ID okay so we
have a ID and show in browser and this
right now it's empty you can see that's
put there you see T it's empty
and we go to the top we add a style we
add a style so we say this ID style will
be lets say border border solid thing
red okay show in browser we got a you
know that thing okay so this is the file
and now we're gonna gonna do you know
let's let's remove this redundant thing
here this these are Google ads and
Google Ads stuff so that the whole file
will be Creole simpler so ads ad autumn
and we move that we move that we move
that remove that showing browser yeah so
it's now it's cream we want to yeah so
let's start to ko JavaScript
and hey good morning rose Koda you are
you are Jack are you the jack the
Haskell code or the node with which Jack
the Jack in China so so anyway so that's
it's not to code the trench a tile so
what so how do you do this we we are
going to use the SVG technology now if
you don't know SVG let's go to SVG
tutorial now if you go to my website you
know that I still search my name sorry
SVG then you'll find my SVG tutorial now
SVG is a scalable vector graphics
meaning it's that you know it's a it's
not bitmap its lines and figures you
know it's suitable for what we need to
do today you know you see like start you
know charts pie charts bar charts stock
charts you know all those are done in
SVG you can see them every everywhere
today
like on github you know statistics
charts and you know so on SVG is very
good for that
so SVG so so yeah so SVG so SVG is based
on XML technology basically it's just
like a HTML so now let me show you then
all you have to do is you know for
example let me let me show you a quick
little example so I create a new file I
create a new file paste this content in
save it let's say X X dot HTML just a
random name okay now so you can see this
is the file or HTML file oh I have you
know I have is this SVG tag SVG tag with
this this line tag you know a line says
x1 equals to you know
and should we show in this browser you
can see there's a line so that is what
SVG is is it's very it's pretty simple
it's just like HTML it's really simple
so you just add this thing and it
creates a line and if you want a
rectangle for example let's say I copy
that let's put the rectangle here and
copy that put inside the SVG tag and
show in browser you see we got a
rectangle in the line so that that is
what we are going to do we are going to
use JavaScript to create to generate
this SVG string tag
you know the basically strings then
insert it into HTML page so so that
eventually we gonna get this tranche
entire source code it's me Jack who is
100 yeah hi good morning jack I don't
have a phone yet you know I was thinking
you know I was thinking you you create
the you know we you know I wanted to
create a YouTube not you a video account
on the China's video platform peedee
peedee which is extremely popular so you
know it's it's in China because China
cannot watch YouTube unless they have to
do some you know as you know SVN you
know basically so I want to create a
video account you know talk show in
China in Chinese you know for Chinese
audience but I don't have a phone like
usually you know I don't have a cell
phone or any phone usually these
services now they require you to have a
phone in order to ever come so I'm
thinking Jack need me me niebaum work I
got what you need watch in Judea the
yes you see my way but my worries so I
you know jack is helping me you know
create account for BD BD in China so but
I'm my way why is that in China you know
you know if if my video becomes
extremely popular later I can make money
so if if Jack you know you it's if it's
your account then it can be some you
know it have a problem I have to trust
you but I trust you
so Jack what's up need were shunned upon
knowing that our young leaders only from
being about what your young need now in
a wash on what can I eat - Lou its Lou
in in ele onions onion though it's Lou
so he host of Denis me much dad your
second and from being what is for the
zoo zoo zoo cuckoo Lubow known as
Antartica Kate san-chan Doha segi above
ambient so it doesn't was something in
Washington is a uniquely super me from
being on knowing that someone else is
young this is what day watch I'm just
sayin I'm just Jim is the chansonia
check hotel humble también you any
youtube need Twitter's song Idol fan
John from beer so it Nagar Skype sound
under maybe down it's a question woman
Josie young she know you know you know
what you handle so change inputs order
it's a toy stop if another harder the
MENA hi mayor Hayes Mayo has young oh
it's a channel that's male CEO John just
as you'd say yeah zucchini yeah come on
hot idea so let's talk offline something
yeah we should yeah let's talk about it
you know we find a time when you have
time let's talk on skype or something
so anyway that's about my ambition you
know so you know I I was trying to do a
YouTube for Chinese audience because in
China you know they have like 1 billion
two billion you know
people you know this is it's a huge
market well you know I'm not here to
make money so it's not a market for me
but but you know you do have a lot
Chinese people they want to learn Emacs
yeah you know they they like they can
learn Emacs from you know my Emacs
expertise so anyway let's go back to
let's stop go back to the coding of the
the SVG okay so let's we don't need this
file anymore so we are coding this yeah
great so we are coding this tranche
eight tiles in JavaScript so as we
mentioned before we our JavaScript needs
to create this this sgml these tags so
yeah okay let's begin you know I was
afraid this is gonna take a long time
it's already 14 minutes so you know I I
hope I can we can finish in 30 minutes
so okay so what do you need to do first
so we need to create this so first of
all we need to create one square one
single square with a arc pattern on the
side so you know let's just walk it out
you know workflow is part of the fun
yeah like you know you see me you know I
haven't done this before so but we can
do this in like 40 minutes I'm pretty
sure
so okay let me get I need to get focus
on this so yeah so we're gonna create
trencher tiles so what what is a fan so
we need to create one square SVG so
we're gonna create one SVG square so
let's write it down
but great one is VG's square okay then
we need to create a OCH patterns on the
square okay create rock pattern create
two SVG ox on the square then okay
here's a plan so then we generate array
of such squares okay then
each with random orientation okay
okay goodnight jack
yes good night so yeah so generate array
of such squares and each with random
orientation that is the plan
so let's create one SVG square so let's
yeah so let's create one SVG square so
so what is the syntax for SVG squares so
SVG square is like that there is no
primitives for rec for square but you
have rectangle so so basically we need
to generate something something like
this okay Rex something is something X Y
width and hate which will be 100 ok hate
it 100
okay let's say 10 so start at now the x
and y are what is the x and y XY are the
upper left corner of the
tango so we want it to be zero zero so
we're gonna generate this stream so
let's create a function constant error
function gen square okay
f change square okay so so this is the
string we want and let's just say return
that okay and actually we need x and y
coordinate so Y so it will generate an x
and y position okay so that is a
function to generate a SVG square okay
we generate SVG square which is this
line but we also need to generate this
SVG tag so how do you generate a SVG tag
you know the way you do it is by so you
go to my SVG tutorial at the bottom your
C scripting SVG okay and here is the
code to generate a SVG tag yeah so
everything is like you know just copy
and paste this is the code to generate
an SVG tag then let's go back here
anchor so let's say this is anchor
and okay so so anka is a position we
want to insert the SVG into so so first
of all get get element by ID okay
document.getelementbyid d okay then we
want to do that so we won't say constant
that that okay so this this gets us this
this gets us that dive tag which is a
position we want to insert the SVG okay
then we create a SVG element oops
yeah we create a SVG element then we
have a function to generate a square
then we want to append the SVG element
into the into the dive tag right so how
do you do that so we have we can do is
that that dot append child okay a pinch
out then SVG one okay that should be it
so now we go back to the file and we
refresh looks like it's a success we
inspect
success we got an SVG tag here you see
in the file so now let's try to add a
square so SVG square so let's say F
change square okay
generate square and let's say at zero
zero okay my square okay
let's say constant my square equals
through that okay then we again append
the child to SVG okay so you see we
generate a square and we attach the
square to the SVG tag so let's see what
happens in browser see if we got a
square no let's see what is the problem
let's expand that okay so it's okay
uncut type error fail to execute a paint
child Arnaud parameter one is not of
type not oh that's that's right because
you see when we have a string rectangle
that's a string that that is not element
so you cannot append a string to a child
so what we can do is actually we say SVG
one inner HTML equals to my square so
this will actually work its trial in
browser you see it works we got a little
square but black square okay so we are
using in image HTML but using in HTML is
not a proper solution rather you should
generate a element that is the better
solution so let's modify this
this function if let's rename it f sv g
square
okay let's a that's a function and
then it should the function will
generate a square by calling these so
this line generates a element of the rec
element generate basically generate this
element then as commander nod then
square set attribute okay then set
attribute x equals to x y equals through
y and with and hate okay so so with
equals to 10 let's put width and head
here so okay and this function generate
we turn a SVG element SVG rect element
top corner at XY with head of wh okay
that's what this function does so with
and hate we need to hate here okay and
okay then we return okay
so this function generates a SVG square
element and return the element that is
right so so now we have the function we
call it here width and hate 10 then we
append a child to the SVG element okay
that seems to be it let's refresh
excellent
you see we got a rectangle element here
0 0 10 10 that's success
okay next so of you guys are watching
post your opinions questions anything ok
you know let me know how am i doing
I love to see your comments so okay so
far we got a we got a we got the element
we got D we got a square going on now
you see the square is black that's you
know that's not good
and it's first first of all it's too
small let's change it to hundred within
hate let's say so there are two things
we need to fix one is that it's black we
don't want it filled we want just a
border so what we have to do so let's go
back to the history G let's fix that
let's look at the SVG tutorial SVG
tutorial you you need to control the
weather it's filled or not that is so
you are controlling a style so you want
to say stroke
stroke stroke with and feel so feel
should be none okay so what we need to
do is we need to say create another
attribute style and feel none okay then
stroke stroke read okay let's see what
is a stroke stroke is a color right
let's say stroke read and stroke width
so let's add another one stroke with
stroke width let's say two pixels okay
now let's try it again
excellent we got you know this we are
making progress
okay so we got a style and there's
another problem because you see so so
what is the entire SVG's with and hate
we need to put a little control on that
so we can so the so basically you see
when you create a SVG let's go back to
SVG tutorial so SVG basics when you
create an SVG you see you have a width
and hate you can specify if you do not
specify the browser is just gonna
automatically usually 100% that you know
fear what it whatever it's available and
generate some automatic hate that's not
we want we want a square we want a nice
big square canvas so let's add a width
and hate element so so basically here
set attribute okay with let's say 500
okay
then hate 500
Vanja okay go back to the browser
refresh excellent that's what we want so
so the square is hundred with hate so
you know it looks like right right five
of them feels it that's right so right
now we are going to have 5x5 array so
now next next we want to do we want to
put an arc into the square remember we
are doing you know this trench church
Church eight tiles so you need these
little quarter arcs in yet you know so
to get these beautiful images so how do
you how do you do that how do you create
an arc now to create an arc in SVG is
not easy it's actually turns out it's
actually difficult but we have a
solution here so let me show this in
chrome so you can see let's go to SVG
and you can see there's a section a
chapter on circle arc so I created this
interactive application that lets you
interactively change you know create the
circle arc with a code over here you can
see you know you can you can create or
sort of arcs you know I mean your
different shapes of Lisp so if you wanna
arc just put minor axis in major axis to
be equal so for example let's say 100
you know 100 so we kind of get a
circular arc you know so that's how we
create a rock okay so yeah we want a arc
but we also we only want a quarter of it
so you can do it by and see a quarter of
an arc to 95 and rotation
okay so what we gonna do is that we we
are going to put a little arc over here
like like right here let's see so the
radius of the arc will be let's say 45
you know the the width of the square is
hundred so the arc will be let's say 45
radius of the arc is 45 so so let's see
41 44
something like that that's what we want
so the code is these the code to
generate these are cases but actually I
have a function this is written in
JavaScript so let's just use that copy
it this function this F SVG list Park
will create an arc for you an arc
element basically this element this path
something-something so we copy the code
let's put the code here now this is
starting to get calm complex let's put
the code here paste so so now we're
starting to get become complex so this
is the function this function returns a
SVG element of an arc so so let's call
this function so we're gonna call this
function over here let's see how we do
not do it let me show you so we call the
function the first argument will be XY
that's the center center of the arc so
the center will be at 0 0 over over here
so Center is 0 0 and the x and y RX and
ry are the radius of the release so we
want it to be 45 okay then the next
parameter is T 1 and Delta so what is T
1 and Delta T 1 is a start angle in
Radian so like where does the arcs start
to sweep we wanted to be 0 that's right
so let's go back here
start start sweep at 0 and n sweep at 95
degrees
well except we need radians not degrees
so to convert with the degree to radians
we divided by 180 and multiplied by PI
okay so we can use the symbol pi because
we defined PI over here you can see so
okay so start sweep and end sweep and
what is the last parameter the last
parameter is rotation of the hole okay
so we don't need any rotation so it will
be zero so this creates an arc for us
let's say arc one okay so that creates
an arc for us then we need to append the
arc to the square okay so right now fan
child up in the up to the to the wait
not not to the square but to the SVG
that's right so let's try in browser
refresh excellent it's incorrect but at
least we got something now why is it
incorrect because it's it's it's trying
to feel it tries to feel the style you
know feel the inside we don't want it to
feel so we go back to the SVG style
shape style and say feel equals to none
so actually we have code already here
here so we
so we say Ocwen dot set attribute okay
set attribute style equals to feel okay
so here is a style you can actually just
copy it so we so we said Ocwen say the
style attribute and feel none stroke
read okay
stroke with to okay let's see how it
looks
refresh excellent
we are making progress so so far so good
okay one people still watching okay so
we got the feel we got arc one feel
that's correct now we need to put
another arc so let's say arc to how to
will be how to we'll be starting from
here kind of like that
so is it begins so the center will be
one hundred hundred so the center will
be one hundred one hundred the the art
radius will be 45 45 the same the sweep
will begin at 180 degrees which is PI
okay then the endpoint will be two pi
divided by three
- 2 pi divided by 2 pi times 3 over 4
so basically basically we have a we have
a circle we want to start you know we
have a giant circle and here's the
center we want to start from here to
here so it's it's like from naio clock
to 12 o clock so now your crowd will be
PI degree Radian in radians so 12
o'clock will be wait where does the
degree begin in SVG I forgot let's just
see let's see how it looks now we need
to append arc to okay switch back to the
browser refresh okay that's something so
yeah so that's incorrect so we the sweep
angle is incorrect so we start here we
want to end ad
so where is zero okay so we actually
don't know let's let's try where is zero
let's say start at zero okay refresh I
don't know
so let's say 1 ok
refresh ok so let's say to refresh ok so
0 is like at 3 o clock 0 degrees for
yoga and it goes clockwise because in
SVG things go clockwise so 0 is that so
we want to start ad over here so we want
to start at 2 pi times 3 over 4 okay
that's incorrect
we want to start at pi that's right so
actually hi that's correct
now we want it to end at right so we
want to end at 2 pi times 3 over 4
yes still wrong so to five times three
over four what is wrong with that does
anyone know okay one people watching
this is discouraging okay so we can we
so let's see let's let's make it let's
change the style so Oh sweep oh that's
right it's how much you want to sweep
not the end position so oh we want to
sweep sweep is half a pie that is all
that is right
excellent excellent we got it working my
friends so that's what we want now the
next thing we want is we want to let's
just continue you know actually we have
a lot of things to fix right now because
we also need to control the orientation
of the whole square you know we we could
it would be useful if we abstract the
whole thing so we create a function we
create one single function that that
give us this whole square with arcs and
we can say orientation you know
orientation one or zero
you know one is like that zero will be
like you know this rotated you know
where the Ox goes from here and here so
you know basically two orientations so
we we would like to have a one function
one single function that creates this
whole group of things instead of you
know little functions right you know but
let's that let's do that later on later
because let's press on let's continue
- you know now let's just try to feel
fear the whole canvas with these squares
so okay so we got once we got one square
we got one arc arc 1 we got our two now
we want to feel the whole thing with
these squares actually how do we do that
okay so we we need to feel the whole
thing with the squares with this pattern
so
so we need to fear the whole thing with
a pattern so we need to actually it
would be simpler if we right now create
one function yes it would be nice it's a
good time that we create one single
function that create that generates the
whole thing let's let's do that then
yeah let's do that
so create a new function error function
let's say name let's name it pattern one
okay and the function will take
arguments X and Y which is the position
of the the upper left corner of the
square here and you will just generate a
whole SVG element so let's let me let me
just do it quickly because you know we
are taking a lot of time right now I've
been talking for 45 minutes so it's it
let me just code it quickly so okay so
first of all we gonna create in SVG
there's an element called G this this
element is a grouping element you know
it just it just like a empty container
you know it's like a dive element so we
have this grouping element then we then
we generate a square let's copy the code
here so we copy here and put in this
inner element so we create a square
XY with hate with hate
okay we create a square with width and
hate then we create a hog hog hog radius
equals to equals to width divided by
width divided by 2 times 0.9 okay so hog
radius that's what we want okay and here
will be X&Y
the sweep is like that that's fine so
awk 102 will be similar
okay except the center wheel will be ad
you see the the second arc Center for
the second hole should be at the lower
right corner of the square so here it
will be X plus W and y plus hate okay
so hold on a second let me in let me in
tenth the whole code so that so it looks
pretty okay there it is
so there is a function so we create a
wrapper we declare our radius we create
a square we don't want that we create a
square we create a lisp and we want to
append child so Gigi dot append child
append child square and append child hot
one and a pinch out of two and also for
arc one also we gg the whole thing we
say the attribute style for the whole
group GG okay so let's let's make it
pretty
so there we have it so this function
this function we create a square pattern
with ox inside okay and so that is the
function
so this function will basically give us
this whole thing and we need let's let's
use another parameter well it's not
let's just see if this works so create a
square pattern with arcs inside then it
needs to return return return the thing
return the thing so so now we write so
you save it so let's let's move it here
so so we create a square here and then
we append it we don't need that those
anymore
because we can let's call pattern okay
let's we call pattern let's say at zero
zero then the the width will be 100
hundred okay that creates the SVG SVG
element for the whole square pattern
then we then we
here's what will you do so we let me
show you
so we comment all these out we don't
need it anymore
so all this code is now replaced by this
single code we create a pattern let's
see if that works
okay refresh excellent
this is the excitement of coding success
so we actually so you know you see it
works so now we can easily create
another one let's say another one at 100
100 okay
refresh excellent oh we missing the
square huh
okay so simple a bug did we why are we
missing the square so we don't need
those anymore but why are we missing the
square so if we remove that it's me
fresh okay it's trying the square
position is wrong oh we yeah obviously
we must have missed something here
Square yeah so this should be x + y X Y
excellent excellent you see we are
making progress so now the next one will
be for you let's just try that okay you
see excellent we got a you know we got
almost a prototype now the next thing to
do is that for the pattern function we
want to be able to say orientation you
know like either like that or rotated 90
degrees so let's create a parameter for
orientation now the orientation will be
you will be like either true or false so
so let's do this
okay so let's so orientation if okay
orientation if orientation is true then
let's say that okay
else else similar okay so let me
okay so else the orientation will be
wrong different so else we so else let's
see we want to draw a circle from here
to here so that's a quarter yeah so a
quarter start form so it will be start
from PI over two okay then the next
circle we want to draw is from here to
here so it will be starting from 3/4 of
a circle
two pi times 3 over 4
okay so
oops what's going on okay English okay
so here is I believe that's correct
okay error pattern one hawk one is not
defined
okay so
och one is not defined if orientation
what why is aqua not defined and caught
reference arrow hawk one is not defined
at 975 975 Hawk one is not defined
let's make sure our parameters are
correct
[Music]
okay and I don't know what's going on
but I I think there's an easier way so
let's copy that
so let's just do that there is a easier
way if expression if expression okay if
orientation then 0z then 90 degrees PI
over 2 else 0 okay so let's put that
there
okay that's I think that's what a what
work
oh yeah it's not defined because we
forgot to give parameters here so stupid
so we need parameter here so let's say
true true false true okay let's just try
that okay we are getting somewhere
okay the arcs the arcs are still wrong
okay yeah the rotation is wrong that's
right so so the arcs are wrong it's made
me so that people can see hey oh so we
got new people here so great thank you
guys for coming you need to set constant
Ocwen outside the if statement then
define yeah yeah well it turns out is
that that's a common error but that's
not in this case no so yeah so decree
Ocwen yeah to try catch block by
capturing air oh yeah try catch is nice
to do but we can like skip it right now
so I mean looks looks like our code is
actually working so this code is working
except yeah this code should walk let's
let's try it again
ha ha Kuan is not defined
he should walk right I mean there's no
reason you need to there's no reason to
move the arc variable outside but anyway
let's let's try just get this you know
let's try to finish this because this is
already taking a long time so let's just
fix whatever let me let me let me do it
this way so it's easier to see so
orientation so let's change the
orientation to rotate you know so it
means just rotated or not
so if rotate is true then then we rotate
because because this function SVG Elyse
arc has a parameter at the end this fee
this fee says rotation of the whole oh
as I see that's incorrect because well
it's incorrect because we cannot use
that because you know because no because
because it's trying to rotate with
respect to center not with respect to
the corner of a square which is our case
so we can use that but anyway what what
is wrong here
let's refresh so reference arrow Hawk
one is not defined line 80 Hawk one is
not defined
it's defined here in okay let's
try to move it out let's say variable
okay
let Hawk one hop to okay this maybe
maybe maybe that is the problem okay
refresh
oh that is a problem why is that
happening
because the scope of or maybe if you
have constant the scope is inside F I
don't think that's okay so anyway let's
forget that that's so now it looks it
doesn't look good this is incorrect
something is wrong here something is
wrong with our yeah the angle the angle
of the rotation so let's let us let's
just do the true case let's see what
happens if they okay so the problem lies
in this part when it's false so when
it's false
what we want is let's see true force
let's see what happens when it is false
okay so yeah it's it's trying to what
the heck
it's just draw 100k so here we see the
problem okay so when so first of all
this will be the center oh yeah the
center of the circle is wrong you see we
are still drawing at this upper left and
the lower right corner it should be
upper right and lower left so the center
will be first of all over here so
Express with okay so Center will be
expressed with Y okay then the next one
will be express hate and y plus hate I
think let's hope that is the case let's
run it okay now the the next one okay so
the second one is wrong great fantastic
now let's let's let's let's do some of
these correct it's to that excellent now
we have like one final step we just feel
the whole thing with these patterns with
the random true or false at the bar at
the end so we're gonna create a so how
do we do that
yeah the declaration inside if should be
fine but for some reason it's not
working but it's yeah I'm let's skip
over that because it's gonna take more
time to figure out then you know let's
just try to get this finished so now we
need to map all these you know to
different positions you see the only
thing that changes
is the the center you see you can see
here you see everything parameter is the
same almost almost the same except the
center and you know whether the
orientation changed to force so we need
you know the easiest way to do is to do
a nested for loop
yeah let's then we can either easiest
ways to do a nested for loop you know we
can you again you know a more advanced
is to generate the nested array like a
matrix then map to the whole matrix
actually that's the right thing to do
but let's just let's just use nested for
loop okay you know let's get this
finished so for I equals to 0 to I equal
to I less than 500 each time we want to
increment I by I equals through I plus
100 okay we increment by 100 so
so we have that I hi yeah that looks
like that's okay let's try it
refresh
okay yeah that's correct that's correct
then we need another for loop inside
okay so let's do that inside here you
know for loop inside so this this will
be J J again J goes to 1 to 500
increment of 100 so so
so what should be inside the P IJ o is
it JJ wait wait
so I think the decoration okay so so
anyway let's see
I say okay let's see Oh fantastic
okay fine look this is trial and error
the success the power of trial and error
like I didn't you know we haven't
logically thought what it should be but
you know it's just run it and it worked
so now now all we have to do is to
generate a random true or false that's
it that is very easy so we can do if
expression if expression okay
then we want a random number math.random
now in Java in JavaScript I believe the
math and when we returns from zero to
one I think we can you know I have a
tutorial let's look up my tutorial math
math.random where is it method sealing
power makes financial trick okay random
there so value properties methods random
so return a real number from zero to one
that's right so random
returns from zero to one so if this is
greater than 0.5 then we return true
otherwise return false so actually this
is all we need okay so that I think
that's it let's let's try it
excellent wait something is wrong the
you see those those curves are not
connected
why he said yeah okay so yeah so that's
that's right so they the radius of the
circle should be 15 not 45 so let's just
change 45 to 50 right the radius of the
circle should be radius okay so the
radius should be half of the square
length okay excellent so so I think
that's it for I mean that's that's
that's it for today basically yeah so
you know let's try again like each time
we refresh we get a different pattern
this is fantastic so we we did it you
know in oh it's over an hour so okay so
now the next thing we can do or you know
is to clean up our code you know they
are you know usually after you have a
prototype you can you know because we
did this quickly you know track just
just to you know do a prototype then we
can bring up the code for example
comment you know we don't need those
anymore and this double for loop we can
change it to you know like array map
into array maybe that's more cream
things like that you know but but
basically on a whole we you know this is
what we want but there are more features
to add for example you you look at this
one you know they have this automatic
you know random random noise Asia you
know it's it's nice to see you know so
we could add a feature where when when
user clicks on this thing it rotates it
so you know that would be a nice thing
to add so we will have to add an event
handler yeah so when unclick then we
basically delete that element and we
generate a new SVG element the whole you
know pattern with with it rotate it so
yeah that's that's a feature to add then
there's also little things we can remove
the you know if you remove the square
grid the pattern will look different
let's try that you know you know let's
try some of the fun things so for the
square let's see where is the function
okay here here is a function and let's
remove the square SVG square actually
yeah let's so here basically we remove
this element this thing refresh you see
that's great and also let's decrease the
width of the square so we got lots of it
so let's do that degree T let's decrease
the width width of the square so okay so
the square which will be 10 10 okay and
this will be increment of 10 let's hope
that works
oops something wrong oh hey it works
fantastic okay that's too small let's
say 20 okay
excellent somehow it's slow you see this
is this is not proper it's it's slower
than I expected no it's not so we need
to figure out which part is actually
slow I shouldn't do that so anyway we
got what we want so so that's it that
good morning
messy butchered butchered toe is that's
a Polish name so so actually we are done
so you guys have any questions any
comments questions opinions just posted
okay and and we are done for today we
did this and you know so that is great
that's a demonstration of Java
JavaScript coding and JavaScript in SVG
now let me put a plug so if you like my
things go to such sorry JavaScript
tutorial just such sorry JavaScript okay
then you can find bike sorry JavaScript
tutorial you can buy it okay if you like
my stuff you know you can buy it here
but basically here is my try it's all
you need you know concise you know and
accurate example based tutorials so that
that's it for today so thank thank you
guys for watching hope to see you next
time bye