good morning guys welcome to another
episode of sound talk show so today we
are going to code emac lisp uh tutorial
and live coding uh and uh I got my new
keyboard so you are looking at con you
are looking at Expose okay
uh uh video check audio check so you are
looking in my keyboard This is export
expose
this is actually my third one okay
um
I'm not going to do a review today but
um but you can see but I have review
written up okay so let's let me show you
go to my keyboard blog and show in
browser and you can see uh this one
Kinesis I mean expose X expose nice
night keyboard expose night keyboard you
know they have several versions you know
from 100 to 300 so they have like four
versions okay and this is actually my
third one because in the very beginning
in 2017 they sent me one the very good
the very first one okay and I have a
review here and that is fantastic you
know I have so many keywords so many
Batman keywords that's the point I have
I have by now over 10 Batman keyboards
and this is one of my favorite okay
uh this is because every time I get back
to use it it's just a joy uh I mean even
though it's flat it's not split it's not
tended but it's just a joy okay so this
is my uh the very first one is the
expose okay and right now this one is
selling uh as the it's named
exposed light or expose
uh nature okay the nature version has
qmk fantastic programmability okay but
but right now the one I have is a fancy
one expose night
okay so let's go to expose night this is
the one I have you are looking at
fantastic and this color show ever I'm
not gonna show it so
I recommend if you never use ergonomic
keyboard before and you have hand paint
you know pinky or your arms you know
your arms or your arms for me it's arms
right right here you know in the in the
past year also but sometimes it's Pinky
sometimes for some people it's index
fingers or Knuckles you know painful so
if you are thinking of getting an
ergonomic keyboard I recommend this one
go run and buy it okay
uh uh I would you know like there is a
differences differences in matters of
taste okay so if I were to choose one
the price doesn't matter I would pick
this one expose nature 150 okay it's got
qmk programmable but best of all it's
got this uh
um
I'm gonna show it another day okay I'm
gonna go do emac this coding today so
depending on uh what you guys saying are
you guys there immortality hello I got
my first Ergo keyboard through a few
weeks ago the perix very board that's
not good is that is is that mechanical
key switches
I don't think that that is right you
want mechanical key switches okay that
is more important than the shape of the
layout okay
you know I used to think 14 years I used
to think the key switches doesn't really
matter it's more important is the key
layout you know the split or you know
split for each hand separated and uh you
know
a great layout you can see this vertical
lines are straight
I thought these are more important but
actually it turns out you know I changed
my mind the the most if you have to pick
one of these two the most important is
the mechanical key switches and the
lighter the better okay so I for me I
have to have red switches linear okay
linear light switches which such as
Cherry MX red or gate around red
uh but not the other red the other red
is like five grams more heavier but
anyways
um called
um
I forgot what's the name but anyway so
yeah so my new keyboard okay and so um
so I would recommend you know if you
if money doesn't matter I would actually
pick this one expose nature because it's
lighter you know this is fairly heavy
the one I have is exposed night which is
the highest basically their highest
um you know model you know the the the
the other one the exposed Knight plus is
basically with
with a number pad you can attach to the
right or to the left Okay so
yeah but
so I have exposed Knight which is high
grade 230 dollars and it's one kilogram
very pretty heavy but you know a lot of
people like heavy but I don't really you
know care for heavy and aluminum body
you know uh well it's good
so anyway expose okay so let's go to
programming emacs this I got myself a
Logitech
g604 based on your recommendation okay
now Logitech g604 let's let's see what
that what uh which one that is
uh there's so many so many I don't
uh let's see Logitech
g604 isn't that the mouse
that's a mouse right
let's see Mouse
that's the one I'm using this one
so
oh yeah okay yeah so the that's the
wireless one yeah it's good okay so
let's let's do emacs because I need to
code Emax
um
so close that uh reopen it copy the link
close that uh keyboard actually forget
about it so let's talk about let's do
emac basic coding okay so I'm going to
show you what I'm going to
right we are going to write a emac this
command to do something
so I'm going to show you what am I going
to do
okay so uh hold on a second so let's so
on a pink window you can see all my key
strokes and command codes such as select
the whole paragraph delete it
highlight current match highlight con
line so you can see all my command cores
and keystrokes I'm using Vol rag layout
of course this is fantastically
programmable
so I set it to boraclia so uh okay so
now delete those lists and the link via
all these and make a list again show in
browser so I'm going to show you what is
the goal of my of this command okay so
I'm going to show you because it's it's
it's
um it's not fairly simple okay so you
can see I have these four pages emacs
ini file tutorial emac sample you need
file okay uh okay hold on a second let
me um
oat
t
s let me magnify the font okay so you
can see
okay 20.
okay
okay so let's see if I'm covering up
yeah that's good okay so you can you can
see I have several files let me show you
okay so one two three four uh
one two three four now these four files
are related let me show you okay so you
have emacs init file tutorial then you
have the sample unit file and then you
have starting emacs without loading init
file or starting emacs with a different
unit file now this means you don't need
chem kmax you know there's a package
called kmax that allows you to have two
running two emacs instances with
different init files different setups
you don't need it actually you know it's
just one simple line you know you just
you have one single line you don't have
you don't need a package for that I
believe that's called chem emacs or
something
okay and so anyway so I have this then
there is this file emacs command line
options there's quite a lot actually so
but these are the most useful so this
four articles are related so I want uh
to have a link that groups them so
people can go from one of the page to
the other easily you know on the left on
the left side you can see the panel you
know uh navigation panel full of links
uh for example this section is emac init
file you need file sample you need file
standard copy code paste Keys how do you
uh config them font setup uh type
override selection all these are init
file you need you know uh configurations
how to so on the left panel is the
general navigation panel but for each of
this file
you know it's not good if you put all of
them to the panel navigation panel
because if you do that then your
navigation panel is going to be hundreds
of items you know
so I try to limit limit the navigation
panel items to be kind of the key Point
entry points but you need a way to for
people to navigate between related items
so that is why I want a link let me show
you where I have an example here so you
can see this page is starting emacs
without loading init file or with
different unifier okay this article is
focused on that topic now at the bottom
you can jump to what is init file you
can jump to sample unit file you can and
here's a current one then you can jump
to emacs command line options it's
related because when you are reading
this page you see this option you might
know you might be want to know you know
what are the other options so you need
this topic box that or related articles
box that makes it convenient for people
reading tutorials to jump to the
appropriate page now this section you
know this bunch of articles are not
necessarily in the same category for
example if you are doing programming
I can show you JavaScript so let's go to
JavaScript tutorial
who who is that Kyle okay
now I haven't been uh talking to you
guys much in my live stream because
usually I you know I've been doing video
for two years two or three years now uh
like I usually other people don't like
it because it's always you know they
they come here they want to see the full
content not chit chat so anyway so for
example when you code JavaScript when
you code uh for example let's see string
okay so string so you have template
string so when you're looking at
template string you might want to know
several other things you might want to
know regular expression you know like
when you are doing a real coding uh in a
company or something usually that's the
case when you do when you do something
with a string you might want to look up
documentation about characters what's
the character how do you get a character
or how do you turn the character to
Unicode you know how do you do Unicode
in JavaScript or how do you do regular
expression now these characters regular
Expressions Unicode JavaScript they are
not necessarily they are not in the same
character they are not strings okay they
are not strings so
so for Strings you have these several
topics for example uh you know the
stream functions stream methods but
sometimes you need to go jump into other
topics
so that is that is why this sub
navigation bar is useful okay so anyway
let's let's get back to writing the
emacs this code okay so close that
showing browser so I want to so so so so
let's let's um
okay so first thing you want to do is
you want to get a list of files okay
let's let's say let's let's go there
okay emacs you need file tutorial okay
now you page down page down you see you
want to add a navigation box at the
bottom okay so you go to the button
show the pink window you go to the
button you can just search for main okay
so there so let's say
I I need to write this quickly so anyway
so here are then you need to gather a
bunch of files that you want them to be
cross-linked so for every page of these
four files they all should be have this
set of links okay so you now you
of them make a list then you want to say
for me I have a topic box okay I type
let me show you okay I type top pick
T and I press space and it will expand
okay that's the power of emacs a brief
okay now so this is a template okay so
this this
uh what what
yeah this this is a template okay now
showing browser go to all the way to the
bottom you can see we have this
navigation box and these four links
needs to go there okay so I'm gonna show
you what it
should look like okay
uh
so the title should be emacs init files
okay simply read topics emacs init file
so now we got this uh
you know I'm still getting used to this
keyboard I've been using the Kinesis
Advantage 2 for three years in the past
um well on and off I've been using this
keyboard for a while but the point is
that once you stop using a specific
keyboard
then after a month or two
your muscle memory kind of starting to
go away so anyway so showing browser all
the way back to the bottom you can see
this is what I want and when I go to the
next page like we use a click here and
all the way to the bottom
you want the same thing okay
Crosslink cross reference think very
convenient super convenient so
so what I want to do is I want to write
a command to automate this process so
what right now what I do is that I copy
cut I mean I copy and cut the whole
um
this whole block okay I already did it
did it you see paste paste you see undo
undo
so I copy the whole block uh okay undo
copy this whole block then let's do it
again okay then go to each of the page
so I go here this is the current page
then go to the next page okay go to the
bottom
okay uh oh that's not it here go to the
button paste it okay save it close then
go here open it go to the bottom paste
it I already did before okay close then
go to this page open it then go to the
bottom
then paste it okay
um okay so let me show you so now
showing browser you see emacs command
line option
option so you can click on that uh go to
a different page then click on that you
see
that's what we want to do we want to
write a command that automate automate
this process okay
so let so for now let's delete them okay
close
but
close Okay go here delete that save
close go here
select that delete that save
close okay okay now it's just this file
this file that has this
block okay now I want to write a command
that let's
um
let's start to write it okay so go to
today's talk show let's go here let's
start a emacs lisp code block and start
it here Define okay now we need the dark
string okay so what is the dot string
going to be let me let me let me show
you okay so the dark string is going to
be let's split okay so we want to
extract the
this is gonna be uh quite a few quite a
lot e-max this coding
so extract the current
extract
all links in current block
context block
then go then open each file
extract or local links okay in context
block then open each file
uh
then insert the same text block into it
at the button okay that is what this
command
will do that's that's the plan
okay so yeah we need we need to do a lot
of things so how do you extract all
links
I have already written a command to do
that
let's close that let's go back to my
pages let's see okay so the command is
this okay so HTML extract URL
so you can jump to the code it's part of
the HTML mod besideshtml extract URL
okay so let's see beginning and optional
uh
uh not full path okay so I want the okay
so we can call this command to extract
it
no I'm not so this code is about
50 lines okay I'm not going to go
through we already I mean it's already
there so let's just use it close it okay
so let's go back to our this code close
that
okay go back to all this code now
yeah so now we can call that command
um
okay so first of all let's write a
let's write a function I mean let's
write code to select the current
block of code okay separated by empty
lines okay so first of all you need a
uh let's see 0.1
.2 that's two Cruiser positions okay
yeah such okay let's write this quickly
search backward
Stitch backward okay such backward
by two
ways the key
by two empty lines
okay
uh optional bound
no Hero count we don't care okay move
the cursor backwards
by two empty lines and uh set
position one
to be
match
end
okay so that will
if the cruiser is here it will search
back two empty lines so the cruiser will
end up there then the position we want
is actually here so that is the match
end that's the end position of the match
zero means the whole match okay so then
go to char
then search forward actually so in the
beginning let's do
so point zero is the current put closer
position Point okay so let's go to go
back to point zero then
search for word
copy search forward twice so again we
want to set the
beginning position of the block and end
position that's what we are doing so
okay so do that that that that then set
0.2
match
beginning
zero that's good
okay that's that's our position
okay so let's put a
comment there okay purify the code okay
so now P1 and P2 are the beginning and
end position of a current text block
defined by two empty lines okay now so
we got a position then now we want to
extract the links in it so that is
that's what this one is for okay so what
does it return though let's look at the
documentation uh
for encoding this code beginning in on
the region beginning and positions
return a list of strings that's what we
want
yeah okay close that so uh
okay so let's double check
no full path
okay we want the full path okay so that
returns a list of file paths okay
so so now let's declare a new variable
Okay so
set
that okay so now we got a list of file
Pathways final path that we want to
go through open each one of them go to
the bottom of that page paste this text
block
then close it okay
so this is the final path okay now we
also need let me show you okay
uh
we also need the block okay so so we
need
we need to copy this
text text block
in order to paste so how do you how do
you do that uh easy okay
uh let's say meat okay for now uh
let's say text block
let's just say text okay
so set Q text so we want to grab we we
are given two positions we want to get
the text between them so the command is
uh get buffer
uh what what is the command get buffer
God I'm distracted
what
uh
gap of
that's right Caper for substring get
buffer substream no properties
oh okay so actually it's perfect
substring no properties Okay so
there so that's how you
uh
get
a string from buffer
giving it two positions okay all the
strings you know the text between those
two positions okay that's our text now
next
map car
map car is a takes a function and we'll
apply that function to a bunch of lists
okay so the list here sequence is gonna
be F path
and what's the yeah okay and what is the
function the function is going to open
each file
Lambda okay open each file
um
fine file okay let's just do a simple
find file
uh
okay fine file is one way okay so let's
just do it fine fine
um find file X
then
actually we don't want to I don't want
to use from fire but
okay fine file
so we open the file and go to Cha
point mean that means go to the above
the beginning then
search for word okay and
that's what we want to search men
then
let's let's add another Point P3 okay
set
actually we don't need to set okay so
let's
search for what man then just paste it
okay
insert
text
then also insert
two empty lines okay in fact I think
that's it that's that's our code
okay
now let's come compact this
now let's name our function okay HTML
copy
topic box okay
so
I think that's it
now let's review the code then we're
gonna
um
test it okay
so search backward search backward to
empty lines then
then
set 0.1 to the beginning of text block
then go to chart go to the original
because the position P0 then search
forward for two empty lines then set P2
to the end of the text block
then set
text to be the string inside these two
positions the text block then
extract the URL in this text block
and set it to a list of path that's what
it returns F paths
then just map a function map this Lambda
function to each one of the file paths
so for each one you open it find file
then you go to the
because the beginning
then you
I mean the perfect beginning then you
search forward for the slash main which
is the end of the article which is in my
HTML I have that tag
then insert it okay that's it and don't
save you know insert it then we can
optionally also save it and close the
buffer if you want to save it you say
save buffer uh
okay that's
um if you want to save it and if you
want to close it you say cure buffer
okay so if you want to do that but let's
you know I want to leave it open
so okay so eval the buffer now we have
the code now let's try it okay let's go
back to
this
okay so showing browser so emacs in a
tutorial go to the bottom
you click on that go to the bottom
there's nothing there okay click on that
go to the bottom
nothing okay back go there
nothing okay now we're gonna call this
command
you'll you'll add those okay
so what's what is the command name
SA
Copy Text uh
topic box okay such tml copy topic box
do it
done
hey I think that's it so now let's
um list buffer so you can see we
actually open those files and you see
those asterisks that means that file has
not been saved you know so it's opening
in browser
and let's
oh okay so we add you know that happened
because
we added to the wrong you see we added
you see this is the block
of interest but we added after the main
we want to add it before the mean okay
that's a mistake so let's fix it
so let's copy this and find and replace
fine replace this
and actually let's just do it manually
and it's
yeah okay
delete it save it show in browser okay
back okay so let me just do this quickly
and now you need
uh so TV save close
sample you need save close
okay
so yeah emacs you need file so let's do
again but this time we need to modify
our code
so yeah so
search forward
and uh
and uh go to move closer go to char
match beginning
yeah we missed that
buffer
back to the fire let's do it again okay
showing browser
okay now let's list both of us okay same
thing
showing browser
effect
undo
close
undo close save and do
cross save
and do
now why is it
go to Cha match beginning
oh did we forgot to eval the buffer
did we forgot to evolve the buffer
so go to search forward that then go to
char match beginning okay that should
work give out the buffer let's try it
again
uh wait
okay so this text block
do it
okay show in browser
emacs you need file tutorial
yeah it appears twice that's expected
you know we need to fix the code
that's a current file so let's go to the
next one
go to the bottom
correct let's go to the next one go to
the bottom
correct let's go to this one
correct okay
okay that's done now there's a issue
about the duplication of the init
initial okay so yeah we can fix that too
so what you do is you
when you
copy the text
then
so first of all you extract the links
let's put it here
then you copy the text once you're done
remove it okay
once you are done delete it so delete
region there it is
okay
eval buffer that's it so now let's put
this this code back to the Emax
today's talk show okay showing browser
that's our code now
um
syntax cover the code
back to the browser refresh that's it
that's our today's code so how long does
it take how long did it take 40 minutes
my girlfriend is uh
Vega bound what crap question
okay so that's it for today anything
else
uh that's it okay so
that's what we need to do and we did it
uh everything is nice now except you
know well we did not explain how does
the extract URL works
um but
that should be it today maybe we can do
some explanation so
uh I think let's see
let's see if I already have a page
written about that function PSI HTML
extract URL that extract all URL in a
text block okay
so describe function go to that page
then uh there it is there is a URL so
you click on that
so
the code is already here emac this
command to extract URL
English region okay so here's
explanation why you need it and here is
a solution in the code okay so that's it
for today thank you guys for watching if
you like my stuff bye
xiaomax tutorial fantastic okay as a
donation you know because everything is
already open source so if you like my
stuff donate
okay that's it bye guys