Hello, good morning. Welcome to another
episode of talk show. We are going to
code emacisp. Today uh I'm going to to
show you how to use
emacisp as a scripting language to do
some text processing tasks. So for edge
for so the task so what is the task? The
task is about for each HTML file in a
directory there are like 10 thousands of
them. So for each one of them check uh
HTML
markup and uh for so for each one of
that find a corresponding one. So these
two markup must always come in pairs. So
if it if they do not then report it you
know. So this is over 10,000 files, HTML
files. So we're going to write that. Um,
and let's begin. Okay. So, so today's
talk show page. Uh, let's
begin. Remove that. So, let me double
check. Audio check, video check, audio
check, video check. If you are watching
offline, watch at 1.5 speed or higher
because I ramble.
Uh if you are watching live say hi cho
man. Hi hi hang. Okay so let's write the
let's start. So the pink window shows
all my command calls and uh um and the
keystrokes on the left keystrokes
command name on the right. Usually you
search the web for the command name
you'll find the source code you know uh
for those of you Emacs users. Okay,
let's begin. So, let's write a script.
Let's start uh emacisp. I'm using kasa
eaglist mod and kasa html mod. So,
defend. Uh so, what we want to do? So,
let's see. Let's copy uh get some
documentation
going. So, this is what we want to do.
Okay.
So, and uh we don't need a function now.
So, so what we need to do is
traverse
the open each HTML
file. Uh then so you're going to learn
how to do that. Then we going to uh find
all the
markup put them in a hasht association
list.
Find all the target
markup.
Put put them in hash table or
association
list. Then pair them up. Check if any is
missing. Okay.
If so report like
printed. Okay.
So, so why? Let me show you. So, what?
Let me show you the markup. So, there is
this page
uh the fisherman and the genie. Okay,
this is a very popular story of Arabian
Knights. I recommend you read this at
your leisure because it's very
interesting. It's very different from
what Disney told you about Arabian
Nights. Uh so for example, Arabian
Knights, let me show you a few. Uh you
know, so what is Arabian Knights about?
Look at these pictures. Then you
understand what Arabian Knights, the
tale of 1,1 nights is about. Okay. It's
about these things filled with it. You
see? So, uh, and you got monsters, you
got prince, you got, you know, the Arab
countries is, uh, heavily Islam and you
got magicians. It's fascinating. And you
got girl slaz like
uh so you know uh totally different you
know the what the Disney's Disney um
Arabian nights tell you is like that's
entirely different thing. Okay. So if
you want to read Arabian Knights I
recommend this um Arabian Knights
translation by Sir Richard Burton. A
very uh interesting character. He is
so-called polygod you know he knows many
languages and is a
scholar of Arabian uh you know Islamic
practices. So anyway so let me show you
a page. So the fishial man and the genie
you see these annotations those are
annotations done by me around 2006 or
so. So you can see each of these
highlighted words you got the dagger
sign you hover over it then you'll see
the annotation. So with means in
addition there with so it's here. So you
move here so held what does it mean?
Pool okay archaic uh there at what does
it mean? So you reading and you know
there at so that means at that event on
account of
that extempo. So what does that mean?
That's my favorite word. You know this
live stream is done
extempolo. So extempo means without
preparation. Okay. So this you got this
markup and annotation done by
JavaScript. So search for JS. You can
see this is JavaScript and uh go to the
top you see uh let's go here you see
this
with so let's go to that word
okay so highlight the word with so you
can see it occurs here in the main text
so you got this span tag
um you know so this xn marker uh marks
the location where that word occurs.
Then you got the matching pair which is
this xn target. Okay. So they must
always come in pairs. If not that's a
problem. So you know I did this like
over you know over over the years I got
some inconsistencies. For example look
at this page.
Gulivas travels. Okay. I also annotated
this this
um this satire very famous satire in
English by this guy Gulivas Travels
Jonathan Swift supposedly the
best satire writer in English. uh I
didn't like this work much so I also did
annotation of
it but uh but you can see for example
this chapter Gulovas travels part four
uh voyage to the country of the
hams okay so there's also annotation
prince of orange you see you see but the
markup doesn't work I mean the hoover
you see prince of range. So let's search
for it.
Prince of Okay.
So you see so it occurs here and there
you got the marker but you don't have
the
target you see but because the target is
just a Wikipedia link you know Prince
prince of orange here. So open that
Wikipedia. So that explains what Prince
of Orange means. So anyway, so so that
needs to be fixed. So in this case, you
need um you know, you need a target
markup of that. So I can I can do that.
So for example,
um what what is the target markup name?
Uh let's
see. Close
that. Open Guliverus. Then uh then this
should be that cut prince of orange. So
it should be that. Delete that.
Then open it in browser. So now you see
I move hoover prints of range. You see
that matches. Okay. So we're going to do
this report. Okay. So let's begin. Okay.
So let me just copy that. Close. um
showing browser. So that's today's talk
show. And uh let's
see. Okay. So go to Emac Bisp. We're
going to code it. So Oh yeah, it's
already here.
Okay. Okay.
So Okay. So let's start to code traverse
directory uh open. So let's try open
each file first. So uh the file will be
uh okay. So let's open this
file. Okay. So let's try that file. Uh
different
process file. Okay, this is just
temporary uh kind
of program name. So, open a
file. Okay, so you want to open a file.
How to do that?
uh you want to you know normally
typically you use fine file but that's
no good because when you call fine file
so for example let's uh for
example you know you open that you see
it open you I mean you evaluate this
line it will open that file but that's
no good because then uh Emacs is going
to kick up syntax coloring and all sort
of hooks to check if this file is is in
a git repository. If so, you see it
shows git master and so it's going to do
lots of things behind. So, so usually
that's 10 times slower. So, you don't
want to use that. Okay. So, how do you
open a file for reading um
you so search for Emacs tutorial? Emac
this tutorial. this basics that that's
about programming emac disp then you I
mean disp okay that's about lisp the
language like strings and stuff then you
want to go to uh eac disp then we want
to find open a file okay so cursor
position move cursor get user input
buffer read file okay open read file so
this is how you This is efficient way to
open file for scripting. You can run
this just like Python, you know, without
interactivity. So, so we want to uh this
is how we do it. Okay, my process file.
Let's just speed that. Okay, so uh so
let's
just process file at at that path. Okay.
So, okay.
So, yeah. So, you what you do is with
temp buffer it will create a temporary
buffer and insert the file into that
buffer then you can do something. So,
this is like 10 times faster than find
file. Okay. So once we open the file uh
what we to what we want to do we want to
find this uh this target marker.
find
or put in a hash
table. Now should I put them in a hash
table data structure or association
list? Let me think. You should you see
they needs to be unique. So each of
these marker the inner text is a
key key. So this this is kind of the ID.
Okay.
Um, and they should be unique. If they
are not unique, you should report it.
So, what do we do
here? Okay.
Put ID in a hash table with file path.
Okay.
If already exist report as
error because ID should be unique. So
each one of these occurrence should be
unique. Okay. So that's
that. Okay. Let's do this. Let's call
this
part. Am I
good? Some looped
invitation. Uh hi gamma sim loop
invitation. What does that
mean?
So okay create a hash table. So um
should it be hasht? Yes. Yeah. So how do
you create a hasht? So let's go to so
read file. That's what you need.
So, emac lisp how to read a file. Now,
let's go to hasht. hasht is part of the
basic lisp in any lisp programming
language such as common list scheme lisp
closure. So that's in this section lisp
basics. So then you go to number boolean
variable conditional loop data
structure. There you go hash table.
Okay. So we want to make a hash
table. Okay. Create a hash table. Uh so
but so before uh that we need a um we
need a local variable. So let's do
let let's just say table. Okay. move the
whole thing
inside. Uh then X table
uh this will be table of the markup.
Table of the marker.
Okay. Let's say marker
table. So make mash hash table test
equal. Okay. Let's let's speed
that. Okay.
So, so uh wait.
So, we do that there. Then we open the
file. We insert file path. Then go
to point main. Go to the beginning of
the buffer.
Uh then we search for
word. Okay. Actually we want regular
expression rearch for word.
Okay. And we want to search for
something like
that regular expression. Okay. You need
um escape the quotes. Okay. So you want
to search for that regular expression
and this ID part you want to capture. So
in EMAC this you got
the toothpick syndrome. So this is how
you capture. So capture
anything not equals to uh less than
sign. Okay. and one or more. Okay. So
you find all this span class
then anything not less than sign then
span. Okay. Then close it. So you search
for what that bound neo no error true.
Okay. Now you need if it's found. So
if search for word if it's found it
returns true. So if it's found then what
you do
um push to hash hash table. Okay. So
um so if it's found you push to the hash
table. So how do you push to hash table?
I think it's uh put hash. Okay. So,
let's do that. Let's do that. Let's just
copy paste coding. Okay. You got the
hasht put
hash. Um now hasht what is our key? Our
key is going to be string. Okay. So, we
want a
string. Yeah. So, we want a string. So,
this part is
ID and
So this part is match
string the capture. So this is our
capture the ID. So match string the
first capture optional string. Not we
don't care about that. So you put that
there. And what is the value? So and
what is the table name? The table name
is going to
be that. Uh but what is the value? So
the value is going to be
uh so keys ID. So let me let's make it
uh let's make it more um easier to read.
Okay. So let's let's say X ID. Okay. So
X ID
set X id is going to be the match
string. Okay.
[Music]
Then clarify the code pify. So the ID is
the match match string. Then put
hash ID. Okay. And what is the value?
The value is going to be
um we don't really care for the
value. The value is going to be
um you know let's see let's just say
true. Okay we don't care for the value
really.
Okay. So, but before we put hash, we
want to check if that already exist. So,
let's do that because if already the ID
already exist, it's a it's a issue. It's
a error. It shouldn't. So, we need to
report it. So, how do you check
existence get hash? Okay.
So there is id
if get
hash
[Music]
key
table. If that key in this
table already exist then error. Okay
then you need to print it.
Print uh what do you want to print? X
[Music]
ID marker
that already
exist. Let's say duplicate marker.
Okay, then that is id
um yeah print. So predify the code. So
if it already exist then
say that okay
otherwise otherwise push
it. So far so good. Is it Am I doing
good? How long did it take you to master
using that keyboard? Uh a month. Okay.
This keyboard glove 80 fantastic a
month. You know, watch my tutorials. I
have like two or three videos talking
about this and many other keyboards in
the past two
years. Okay, this is going slow. Uh well
I mean so this is a task that
uh well it's warranted that's how you
know that's how long it
takes. So find all the marker get their
[Music]
ID. If it already exists, report
it. Uh and we also need to report the
file path.
Okay.
Okay. Okay. Print the ID. Print the
final path.
If not exist just push it. Okay. So we
got so we are making populating the hash
table for the markers. Okay. So that's
one thing. Now what if it doesn't
exist? Uh what if it doesn't I mean if
none are found if none are found then do
nothing. Okay. Like we can just say Neil
or just leave it like that.
Okay. So that
populates populates
the Okay, that is one thing.
Now, now let's populate the target
table.
Okay. So, we need another
table, target table. Okay. So, we set it
just like before.
Good. Color
it. Yeah. So now we got the target
table.
And so here it's a little trick. You can
actually put them inside. So remove
that. Remove that and just put it there.
And uh remove that and
just put here.
remove that. Pretty fine. So you got
these two tables set up in the let
variable local variable.
Okay. Okay. So and you don't need that
comment create hash table. Okay. So this
is
uh open file for read.
Okay. So now populate that. Then the
next thing is populate the other table.
Okay, so this is going to be target
table. So let's just uh kind of do
template coding. Okay, so now we search
the target table. Okay, so we need to go
[Music]
to Okay, there's one more thing before
we populate the target table. You see
for this one is search for word for that
marker. But only once you need to repeat
this. So you need to do a while. So
while you need to do a while loop. So
while
loop such that while you know searching
that is true then what you do? Then you
do uh kind of that. Okay. So let me just
do
that. Okay. Now it's Now it's proper. So
while you found this marker, get the ID.
If the ID, check the if it already
exist. If so, report it. Otherwise, put
in the hash table.
Okay. So now we populate the other
table. Okay. And what is the markup for
that target? Okay. So this is the target
uh so we need the regular expression. So
here is a regular
expression. Okay. So find this target
and this is the target ID. So we don't
need that
part. Okay. So, so far so good. Is it
good? Greetings from Unix master race.
Neckbeard. Who are you neck beard? I
kind of remember you. Uh neck
beard. So, ENS says, "How long did it
take?" Okay, I already answered
that. So, search forward. Uh, now let's
[Music]
see. Okay, before you do anything, you
need to go to point main. Okay.
So, go to point mean the beginning of
the buffer.
search
forward
um search forward this
target and let local
ID let's say target ID
uh
wait let's just say ID you
know. So find the target ID which is
this
part.
[Music]
Then then extract
it.
Then check if it's in the target table.
If so, report duplicate
target in file. Okay. then
otherwise add to the target table. Okay,
now we kind of populated both table.
Actually we can run this
code. Uh so let's shrink a little bit. I
guess that the font is kind of too big
too big. Okay. So this is the whole
thing. Okay. We are just writing this
process in one file. Okay, let's try
it. Make a
backup by compile. Yes, there's a
warning. Okay, good. Okay. File has no
lexical binding directive on the first
line. Okay, that's true. Let's add it.
X. Okay, that's how you add it. Coding
UTF8 lexical binding true. That will
that's a kind of new feature added 10
years ago in Emacs. That makes all the
functions to be closure so use using
lexical scope instead of uh dynamic
scope. It's kind of hack to fix it.
because back because before that Emacs
is using dynamic scope. So what's the
difference? The difference does not
really matter if you always code in a
functional
way. But if you don't code like function
like all like all variables like all
functions has no side effect. So I
always do that. So so the effect doesn't
happen to me. But if you do not do that
you do like the way C style like
variables outside variable of a function
instead of function you have procedures
you know which access you know global
variables or variables in different
places and change them then you got a
problem then the issue of dynamic scope
versus lexi lexical scope becomes very
apparent okay but I don't do that so
anyway so Now make a backup. Go to
directory by compile again. No
error. So you know jump to the list
buffers. Compile log. No arrow. Close
it. Close it. Close it. Okay. So we got
this is my tempter. We got lots of other
backup. That's F. You know I'm like
doing F. So delete them. Yes. Close.
Okay. So back we to this is is this font
big or small? Is it good? Should I
should it be
bigger? Hello Kim
Posome. Long time long time no see on
YouTube. Kim Pawome been watching me
well at least in the beginning like
three or four years ago and Kim Poram he
quotes Nim he's a fan of Nim he also
called this Emac this he also writes his
own kind of trying to uh write his
create his own language and he does live
coding sometimes on Twitter or some
other okay bigger phone, okay, on Twitch
or you know there's some new video
platform he he
uses King Herring. So if you have not
already joined Kasar Discord because
here that here that's him that's King
Posome. So here you can ask him where is
his live stream uh link and stuff. Kasar
Discord you can find um you can find
the the invitation link on kasali.info
my homepage. Okay. So okay. So back to
this
um so we got this function to process
one file by compile. Good. And let's try
to test run it. Okay. So test run. Uh
let's go to a file. So that one copy
uh this file open it let's run it okay
now evaluate that function now evaluate
that fantastic no error now we can
actually
print so let's go um for example message
print all the hash table let's
say print up So we're going to print out
this. This
is all marker found. Okay. Marker ID. So
let's do
that. Evaluate that. Then evaluate this.
Fantastic. Let's go to the messages
buffer and uh copy it. New buffer. Paste
it. Make it one word per
line. Okay. T we don't care we don't we
just care about the key.
So so this is all marker ID found. So
it's a hash table test equals so
starting here with so you got with held
there at extle. Fantastic. So this means
it's
working. Close that. Close that. So we
got these two hash table done. Next, we
want to check check if they
um each ID match. Okay, so for each so
let's go uh let's go uh let's start to
check if the two hash table have the
same keys. Fantastic.
Oh, that's easy. That should be Let's
see.
Um, okay. So,
first need
to loop through hasht.
Okay. Now, we need to loop through
hasht. How do you do that? Go to kasa
emac this tutorial. Hasht. Hasht. How do
you loop through it? Pretty print. hasht
to list sort hasht test hasht
equality you know what so what we can do
there are many ways so one way is just
to iterate through the marker hash table
then for each item you check the other
table but then that's not so good
because then you have to do
reverse because the other hash table may
have more
keys which is not good you know then but
the other way is turn the hash table
into just keys. So you got one hasht a
list of keys then you got the other
hasht list of keys then you sort both of
them then you simply compare the list
are
equal can you do that yes you know let's
let's
test
equal a
b
c so uh
Let's see uh you know the let's try to
run that to see if that works. It says
true. So you can Yeah. So this is kind
of tricky in different languages because
some
languages you know you cannot compare
the content. They only compare the
reference of a list. So anyway, so I
think so. Okay. So what you do is turn
the hash table to key to a list. Okay,
let's
see. Get all values, get all
keys. Okay, it's building in since like
10 years ago. Okay,
so hasht keys. Okay,
so hasht keys.
Uh okay. So look up the documentation
hasht
keys return a list of keys in hasht.
Okay. So it's actually um in this
special you know this is very annoying
because that
means it's not loaded by default this
function.
Yeah, you know because you
know you know this subx kind of means
like
experimental uh very annoying you know
imagine in all other languages today or
10 years ago they have a hasht to list
function by default you don't have to
load library because it's so basic but
emac this like they
It's not good you know they don't put
they don't like anyway so so this
function you know you know I used to
write this myself you know so anyway you
know they it should be like
default loaded okay so it's in this
library close that so let's just declare
let's just declare
we require require
uh no
require require this okay then that
loads then hasht
keys so returns a list okay so
yeah
yep okay and we then we need to sort it
now sort is another complex
King. Let's see. A B C A C
Reet Neo. Okay. AC
E Neo. Okay. So that test out. So you
need to sort
it. So um
sort uh very annoying because the sort
function by default is
destructive. Yeah. We don't care. Okay.
Uh destructive, you know, it says um
sort sequence uh pre uh key less reserve
in
place. Did they uh did they actually
change it so it's not destructive
anymore? destructive meaning that if you
have a v variable that holds a list then
you call sort then that variable list is
going to be changed kind of
destroyed so you need to uh get the
sorts return value
uh so sort return sorted sequence search
for
destructive I think they change
it interesting
So let's check my tutorial to make sure
I got
that you know. So go to list open it.
What is a list? Empty list
length. Uh so list create list get
elements modify
iteration check element exist remove
element sequence
[Music]
join okay that's not
good I find sort here that means a user
interface issue of my
[Music]
tutorial. Time. What are you talking
about right now? It's
1:45 p.m. California
time. Okay, I got the issue here. Why
don't I have sort you know this is about
my tutorial writing. Why is my tutorial
you cannot easily find sorting a list?
Because it should be here. List
iteration check element exist remove
element sequence join convert.
I have it for sure but you know let's
just search for sort sort hasht sort
lines sequence uh sequence
sort okay it's in the sequence
section yeah so original is destroyed
but
however it doesn't say so in this
documentation because I think they
changed
it. D E S T, you know. So, search for
destroy. Not here. Search for
um Yeah, I think they changed it
sometimes in the past three or four
years, you know. Let's check.
Let's Let's Should we digress? So let's
go to
uh control
hn. That gets you the emac news meaning
emac release
information. So right now I'm on emac
version 30. Okay. So you see so meta x
version message show message buffer. You
see I'm on emac 30. And now search for
list matching line
sort.
Okay. So can does it mention that sort
uh it looks looks like they did change.
Look here new sort arguments and
features. Okay let's open that. Jump
that. Jump to
that. Oh. So there's new yeah so major
change in emac 30 of the sort
function. Okay.
So, so does they say do they mention
destruction
de
T nondestructive
operation
dstr okay so only happens here
warning about mutation of constant
values. Now the compiler now warns about
code that modifies program constants.
Okay. Okay. It's not about
sort. So did they not
mention that sort is no longer
destructive? So maybe they change it
even in earlier versions. So you need to
go to Emacs 29, search for
sort. There it is. You see sorting
commands no longer necessarily change
modification status.
Wait, no, that's not that's about sort
lines. So do it
again. Anyway, that's it for that
digression. But the point is swords is
no longer destructive. So I need
to change my
um Yeah, I kind of need to change my uh
my tutorial. Okay, copy it. Close it.
Close it. Go back to the talk show.
Paste about the sort and paste about the
hash
table showing
browser. There we have
it. Okay. Now go back to the code. Let's
just say sort uh and okay. I also need
to update my emac this
template. Yeah, ne never mind. So
anyway, so sort you want to sort this
hash table and what is the default
function? Uh it's optional. Uh let's say
sequence and and key we don't care.
Okay. Yeah, there's a major change now.
They support extraction of
keys. Yeah, major change in this sort
function and it's written in C.
So okay so we sort
um sort the hash
table and that's one thing then we also
sort the other hash table target table
then
compare
equal equal these two
things.
If
equal
message, very
good.
Fantastic.
Otherwise, you got a problem.
Okay, let's just be that. And
now evaluate the code. You can see eval
last six. Fantastic. We don't need that.
And process this one. Okay. Run it.
Fantastic. You It says fantastic. Oh,
thank you. Fantastic. Now, let's try to
make a arrow
intentionally. So, this target, let's
double the target. Let's just add extra
here. Okay. Save it. No, wait. Undo.
Make a backup. Now add it. Okay. Save
it. Now go Now go back to the code. Run
this again.
Run. It says fantastic.
[ __ ] Something is not
right. Wait. Did Wait. So we got this
target ext. Yeah, that happened twice.
You see? You see happened twice in the
file. So this is the target. Go back
here. So why is the target table
not [ __ ] finding the
duplicate? It's so this is
debugging. So you search for that for
the target
markup then let ID okay then get hash if
it's already
found duplicate target. So go to the
message buffer does it say
duplicate? Oh it did say here.
Okay. Okay. Instead of message, let's do
warn. Instead of print, let's warn so
that we are like jump in your face.
Okay. So warn, what you going to warn
about? You're going to warn. So this is
just war. Okay.
So
there. Okay. So you need to W instead of
just print and also
here
W. Okay, remove that print. Okay,
now evaluate that function. Now let's
try this again. Okay, run it. There you
go. Duplicate target
ext. So
fantastic. Close the warning. Okay. Now
open that file. Remove this target
marker. Now let's duplicate this marker.
Okay. Put the marker. Save back to the
this. Run it. Warning. Duplicate.
Duplicate marker there at found.
Fantastic. Okay. Reopen that. Remove
that. Save. Go. Good. Okay. Now we have
demonstrated the duplicate works. Now
another thing to check is that what if
we
have a marker. Let's add a random word.
Okay, that doesn't have a margin target.
Okay, save it. Go back
here. Run it.
You got a problem
indeed. Okay.
So, so let's update this. You got a
problem. So, this will be one. You got a
problem in
file.
Um that Okay. So
the there.
Okay.
Fantastic. Uh but it doesn't tell you.
So you see it doesn't tell you what
key it needs to because a file may has
tens of these markers in target. So if
it doesn't tell you
then the
um then it's hard to find it.
So but in order to report exactly which
one is missing, we cannot just compare
them. you need then you need to um
yeah you can
just anyway let let that be for now.
Okay, evaluate it. Run this. Okay, you
got a problem in file. Okay, so far so
good. Okay, so we finished this part and
essentially that is the heart of this
program.
Now all we have to do is to write
another to traverse a directory then for
each file you just call this then you
got you know report we can do that in
five minutes but that's the gist of
today's program okay the spec is here
now put it back
syntax show in browser so that's today's
talk show this is how you do it and how
do to traverse the directory. All you
have to do is just go to
um go to eac bisp, open it and
uh text
processing writing a
command user input get user
input file and buffer and walker
directory. So that's how you do it. So
copy it uh and paste it here. So those
of you interested, you
can, you know, work it out. I think
that's it because we already talked for
like 1
hour. So actually, let me do the
traverse because I want to see my
thousands of files. Okay, I want to
actually
see. Okay, so let's see. So this is this
directory. No
recursion uh no sub se subd. So this one
this directory and all subd. Okay, let's
just skip the reading and just copy the
code. Close. Okay, make a backup. Pop
out the this code and uh let's just rec
uh now let's recurse. Okay, put a
comment there. Put a comment there.
[Music]
Um okay so what is the home directory
let's
say okay the home directory is going to
be let's copy that I mean the root
directory we want to do this
recurs okay let's let's just say that so
in this directory for all HTML files and
uh and skip.
Okay. Okay. So, so this will this will
give you a list of the Okay.
Uh okay. file
list. Okay, that's a file list to
check. Then you just
map map a function to it to the file
list. You see? So I don't I don't
actually want a uh let's leave let's
create a variable. So file list. And
what do you want to do for each file?
Well, you're going to call my process
file on the file. That's it. Okay, let's
run this. Run it. Fantastic. Now,
describe variable that variable. So, you
can see you got all these files, you
know. So, how many files? 700.
Okay. All these file these are novels.
Time machine, you know, time machine.
Great
tales time
machine fantastic tales okay uh about
future of humanity like today we have AI
you know in robotics that's quite scary
so what will the future of humanity be
like that's told by this time machine
and featuring pretty girls white girls
the center of
humanity. Fantastic story. Okay. I I
also have annotations. For example,
tramos. What is a traml?
Fundy controvert. You know those
highlighted words are interesting ones.
English the study of lexicons
vocabulary. Okay. So spamastic uh
spasmodic
accession. So for those of you young
zoomers, you need to study transitory
manner. Okay, that's time machine
anacronism.
uh battle of hastings, you know, that's
one of the big thing for English
speakers, you know, because it's one of
the big battles
in in kind of the
Europeids
history, but you wouldn't know anything
about Chinese battles, but anyway. So,
time machine is great. Okay, so close
that. Then you got um E Common Cummings
uh poet you got Russell lecture you know
Russell lecture what desires are
politically important so you got
annotation Korean war what is it Korean
war UN what is
UN so all annotations I did so you got
700 files so so let's run it
okay let's run
This run it. Oh, you got
goggles of
arrows. Okay, let's check. Duplicate
target found Arabian Knights. Okay, so
you
got not many actually 30. Okay. And I
know most of them occur in this gulivas
travel. Let's say open it. You see
gulivas travel. So you got mismatched
annotations. Okay. So that's it for
today.
Fantastic. So my job is going to go each
one of them and fix it. And that's
another task because for example you
open a file Gulovas travel part three a
voyage voyage to
lauta and Japan you know very
interesting Amster Amsterdam is
mentioned and then they mentioned an
island uh let's see where uh this one
is Amba
Ambboina Island is a name for the Ambo
Island, Indonesia, where Ambo massacre
happened in
1623. Ambo massacre in Leen a city in
Netherlands about 37 kilometers
souththeast of Amsterden. Oh okay. So
this is Gulovas travels. He mentioned
these things.
cave of good hope that's near the
southern tip of Africa uh Gina you know
so you know it's interesting read
um by guys don't forget to donate to me
okay just go to top go to the top go to
the top homepage kasari
info PayPal me Amazon gift card me
Patreon
That's
[Music]
it. God speed in your endeavors.