good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show so today we
gonna talk about I don't know
so type a topic type a topic guys just
type of go to this page and type a topic
there and okay so I'm going to start to
talk random on random stuff so Joe
Armstrong died he he died today so he
was born in 1950 so that makes him 70
years old yeah
Oh 69 so he died today and you know Joe
Joe Armstrong he is the creator of the
airline language I actually never
learned online language but you know
Olin is you know one of the language
that has the feature being kind of like
distributed computing actually I don't
know much about it
you know because well I you know a line
is one of the functional language
actually is one of the earliest most
successful functional language you know
he used in the industry yeah that's a
key it's a most successful functional
it's a first successful functional
language used to in a computing in this
industry you know and so that also means
it's very practical unlike for example
Haskell so al and you know and it's it
has the kind of some kind of a hot plug
feature and distributed but you know I
want to I want to learn it but I just
never did so we have one guy watching
hey hey guy hey say something so Olin
so yeah Joe Armstrong died but you know
it's interesting because well I have a
kind of a story to tell
let's go to web design okay so I have
this page on web design and one of the
problem of the stupidity of the web
design crowd fashion is that you have
these let's see gray text gray text on
white background usually you can see
let's see if you can see it gray text on
white background yeah here okay so let's
move this over here so you can you see
this is one of the problem of the web
design you see it began around 2010 and
people the web designers you know
website started to use grey text on
white background it's one of the extreme
idiocy and it also inflicted the skin
racket Lisp languages web site you see
these text can you read them I cannot
read them you know it's great
why do they use grey because supposedly
you know you you have actually I don't
know I I think there is like one or two
guys who began this grey on white trend
you know typically these are kind of
like gurus you know this guru
they you know they are like they so they
post to hacker news and their posts
becomes widely popular or spread by
something like at least you know there's
a web design website code at least
something it's all no good and also
there's a CSS garden it's also kind of a
fad so this these gurus you know
supposed to be web design guru speak a
net so and then over sudden Oh websites
almost most websites began to have gray
text in white background
so I have collected on this page some
some some of the egregious examples you
can see so there's a racket skin website
racket skin racket Lisp and then you
find this page this one this okay hold
on a second okay oh these are gray and
white and look at this one this one is
from ARS technica now us Technica is one
of the technical you know it's one of
the website for programmers and their
articles are typically above average I
mean to you know III their article has
higher quality than most but however
they are also inflicted by the gray on
white design thing look at this orange
text like can you can you actually read
them I mean if you think about this it's
like impossible it's like this you know
this idiocy spread you know any any
person if you look at this you we all
know that this is you know really hard
to read however it's just like that you
know on their website so that's another
example so let's show you some more
examples okay here are small examples
then then it is also inflicted Google
you know from website there you know
Chrome's related website dev tools and
stuff
gray on white and he you know it's got
worse and worse examples you can see and
lo and behold look at this one look at
this one okay this one is from Joe
Armstrong the guy who created all Olin
now look at his code example here it's
impossible to read now this is his blog
on 2015 on github github
io dot io so anyway that's the case you
know he's it's on his website you know
it's not it's not exactly that he
created this color scheme to use for his
website this the spreading of this web
design guru problems is that usually you
know when guru proclaims something is
good then is spread so basically is
spread to the all the frameworks and
templates you know like CSA this a bunch
of CSS templates I don't think they are
good you know basically you know cut and
paste that that's the situation with the
industry so you got this whole bunch of
frameworks and templates so so and they
are using grey on white so that is how I
believe that is how you know Joe
Armstrong also his black also become
this grey on white thing impossible to
read but however so this is 2015 but
however the website changed you know
afterwards I suppose okay so actually
this is 2013 so this article oh my god
he also did he also delete all his
blocks see right now it's four four four
now let's see if he show Armstrong he
did it his Prague okay let's see
huh
tea tree wiki Wow it's possible so Joe
Armstrong's website is gone so what is
this
titli wiki so who is watching say hi so
today wiki's the best software found for
organizing ideas since it's where we're
spending also vision so what is this ttv
wiki now it's possible someone stole his
account I mean you know he passed away
he died and maybe sometimes maybe he
abandoned his blog and someone just you
know used it used his name it's possible
oh and something like that I'm not sure
what's going on but anyway that's his
website so what I'm saying is that so
his website on 2015 it has this great X
on white background then then after you
know I noticed you know I checked no and
then then it's fixed
I suppose recently was you know gray on
white because he was using using you
know one of these fashionable
templates you know people get old so you
know in 2015 he is already 65 or
something you know there's a video on
YouTube where Joe Armstrong talks about
Ireland and you can see that the video
is like from 30 years ago 40 years ago
you know see the way he talks you know
the programmers oh he's so different
they are still using telephones you know
so our line is designed you know it's
one of the you know first functional
language designed in using using a phone
networking industry
so anyway so that's the land so that's
Joe Armstrong and this is this is about
gray on white it's one of the most
idiotic thing in a programming industry
you know there are so many idiotic
things in programming industry however
they just spread you know and the reason
for that is I mean you know you
then you know you know obviously yes
that's untrue what well in a sense
that's scientifically not verifiable you
know it's it's it's said to be a faith
now on the other on the other hand if
you are religious let's let's see let's
say you are protesting or you know you
are Catholic or your moment or you are
you know Islamic you know there are
there are many branches many sects okay
now let's say if you're American
protests and some Protestant yeah yeah I
mean I don't I don't quite understand
some of the branches and you know there
is there's also puritanical you know oh
I know it's basically on top there's a
two divisions like protests and and
Catholic okay and so both of these are
Christianity okay
of course there are also moments which
doesn't belong you know to either
protest or you know or the Catholic but
anyway so so all these are Christianity
but also Islam actually they they Islam
in Christianity they have the same
parent kind of you know the is called
Abrahamic religions now now if you you
know if you are you know God believer
you don't like to hear this probably you
don't think it's that's valid but anyway
that's how how it is classified in some
kind of scientific sense because of
these religions also called monotheistic
meaning that they believe one God
well actually they are kind of the same
parent same branch because they have the
their Bible you know the Bible and also
Judaism you know the also belongs to
part of the Christianity you know the
Bibles and the Islam's the book you know
they're they kind of they kind of all
share the same story you know
he says Sameera on the other hand it's
Buddhism is entirely different thing and
Buddhism you know there is no well it's
an entire different you know region it
it has its branches as well so anyway so
what I'm saying is that back to the
topic so I'm saying is that yeah well if
you do not believe in religion then
obviously to you you know the concept of
God and things like that is just absurd
I mean from a scientific point of view
because it's just a faith you know it's
what you believe you know you cannot go
all the way scientifically because if
you push scientifically all the way then
basically you don't know why you are
here what's your purpose you know
there's none there's none you can say
you cannot like you can now say okay
scientifically therefore I'm here
because this or that there's no such you
know so anyway so if you are not you
know religious person then you you you
know obviously those scars in stuff are
absurd now if you are religious but you
can also see you know the non-believers
or other regions are absurd because you
know for many of these religions you can
only believe one card if you believe
other cards as heresy you know you know
you believe in Jesus Christ for example
for example okay but you know some other
religions Buddhism doesn't believe you
know there's a Jesus Christ you know or
maybe there is but it doesn't believe
you know it's not the Buddhists
Buddhism's thing so it's so to a
Buddhist for example it's kind of an
absurd you have this this Christian God
you know but to the to the Christians is
kind of you know it's it's it's a heresy
to have this put Buddha or whatever you
know this or in India
have this God with elephant you know
like elephant God you know a God with
elephant trunk and stuff like that so so
you you know outside the programming I
said outside of science you know physics
science engineering you have all these
different beliefs you know and they are
not scientific beliefs but but actually
I think it's it works in the same way
for programmers and engineers engineers
because as they say you know for example
your Emacs user then you believe in
Church of Emacs to you eMac this is one
of the great language it's fun it's you
know it's so powerful eMac is the
greatest editor you know that and the
you sight about Emacs versus see me
versus women you know all day day and
night and you say talk about how Emacs
is the greatest editor how it really you
know kicks out all the others like no
comparison you know that and how Emacs
is a beast machine you know as a only
not it's actually in fact from a
scientific view it's actually patently
untrue
like what you believing about Emacs is
just patently false for example you know
a few weeks ago you know this people are
clamoring about eMac this how great it
is a language so I did a video you know
I I did a video about emag Lisp in the
language it's actually one of the worst
possible you know even from a reserved
scientific point of view like very like
you want to buy us you want to buy us in
favor of Emacs and Emacs Lisp for
example for example I'm you know I'm
Emma America's programmer so even if you
want to really want to believe you know
there's just no way to justify and yeah
I mean the fact is I emag Lisp is one of
the worst possible is language on
you used today one of the like the worst
there's no question about it is there's
no maybe oh maybe it's just you know an
opinion it's not a pinion eMac this is
the worst language possible in today's
world let's say what's in the top 10
most popular languages well worse than
PHP okay what's the in JavaScript no
doubt about it no there's no question no
argument about that but how it was you
know in in the Emacs community we it
seriously believe he magnets this great
and all that okay that's that's about so
so what I'm saying about all this is
that you know programmers they for
example this gray on white this web
design thing and lots of other web
design issues so many things programmers
believe we believe okay we believe so
strongly
like for example formatting which is
another topic we I talked about it in
another video a few weeks ago about you
know code formatting coding style kind
of thing you know so lots of things
people programmers we believe but
actually that is patently force so so
the question is why is that and I think
it's really it's because it's really
because you know programmers are not
very different from non-programmers on
things that's not related to programming
such as religion you know as an example
so so yeah so that's so in programming
community there are lots of beliefs as
well you know the lots of beliefs codes
and you know and they could and some of
them come and go you know for example
this ad Joe in this patterns and hi
patterns there's object or
programming is functional programming
you know some of the some of the things
we see are just enthusiasm which is okay
but what I'm saying is that often it's
beyond the enthusiasm some people for
example there are people who believe in
Haskell for example functional
programming to such a degree that less
that they say things that are just not
true I don't have much example about
functional programming but I have
examples about Opie object-oriented
programming and you know agile and
patterns stuff and lots of things and
the Emacs of course okay so what so
that's about that so I'm talking about
something okay so that's about that so
programmers programmers actually farmers
believe are actually not reliable not to
be trusted
much of it is force ok what else
so web design so Joe so Joe Armstrong
that is the creator of Berlin died today
let's let's talk about something else so
I've been working on my JavaScript I've
been working on my JavaScript stuff
javascript in depth a lot in the past
two weeks you know I'm getting back to
JavaScript
[Music]
so anyway so let's see who is watching
two people watching okay okay this let's
talk about some other things so okay so
if you have a comment or opinion or
questions just type it type it okay
otherwise I'm just going to talk about
random so I've been working on
JavaScript in the past two weeks to
continuously refine my project which is
this tutorial javascript him in depth so
close that
global variable yeah JavaScript
so web design that's lots of topics
there
so these I'm not sure what's going on
this Joe Armstrong Joe Armstrong page
becomes this ttv wiki sucks our talk
show okay
so let's go to Twitter let's go to
Twitter or let's go to
vim golf we did wink off yesterday
and see how comparator looks Coulomb and
treat her so what's new empty sign
so we can talk about JavaScript I can
give you a introduction to you know I
have a lot of topics like like you know
huge amount of topics and then start and
the thing the thing is that the thing is
that you know in a conversation you know
you know how it is like when you have
maybe with friends you know sometimes
you don't have any topic to talk about
that's a situation
so javascript function arguments default
value so yeah javascript javascript is
one of the worst language now I need to
say that with some clarification because
because if you first of all JavaScript
is a very advanced language okay since
2015 it is it has features comparable to
Python or Ruby okay no less in fact it's
even it's even faster than Python and
faster than Ruby okay that is the nature
of JavaScript JavaScript 2015 for
example if you go to my website
JavaScript 2015 features it has a lot
features in fact javascript is in some
sense it's more advanced than will be
then Python then email is okay
since 2015 you know you have and you can
you know you have arrow functions you
can you have this structuring you know
the destructuring assignment you don't
even have that I'm not sure you have
that in Python and I'm not sure you have
that in Inc in Ruby neither
and this structuring assignment is
actually fairly complex it can get quite
complex and then you have also you have
spread operators okay finally someone is
talking good morning Finch a Joe is the
cancer of the programming world yes it
is
so Finch what you up to well it would
matter where were you from again
as they could now agile with a small a
what do you mean agile with a small a so
you know there is something very
interesting
okay okay finally we got questions
good morning sound toxin thus JavaScript
have any use outside of browser yeah of
course
heavy seriously heavily used for example
you know atom editor and you know the vs
editor for Microsoft vs code code you
know the is the name of the editor is
code so github
you know they decided they want to
create an editor about eight years ago
something like that so they created one
written in JavaScript and actually the
way it works is that it is it it is
basically just the Google Chrome browser
you know that's a basic that's a
foundation then you know so the atom
editor is is basically a Google Chrome
browser so it's written in JavaScript
then so that's Adam so they then Adam
you know the kid hubs at an atom editor
then then they split out the core part
they end a code electron framework so
electron is a framework for JavaScript
to create applications any application
not you know not web page not website or
not phone apps you know any application
for you know your desktop for operating
systems so you have the atom editor
which used the call of it is the
electron framework then I believe
Microsoft used the electron framework
and created their own version of editor
called Microsoft code and in fact I
think electron frame
is used by lots of applications now and
those are not just web pages and in fact
I think Microsoft also made their net
dotnet you know the whole dotnet
structure to support JavaScript meaning
that you can use JavaScript to write any
you know any software for Microsoft
Windows so yeah the use you know
javascript is you know is so heavily
used everywhere today yeah so let me
talk about JavaScript a little bit let
me clarify okay so JavaScript today is
one of the most used language let's say
top five most popular so am on top five
you have see actually sees not that
popular today okay so anyway C C++ Java
JavaScript Python and you know PHP Ruby
these are about the top five and maybe
c-sharp so these these are the top five
languages okay
okay don't trust much what you read on
the web okay about your electron
actually I don't I don't have any
experience using electron but yeah yeah
I couldn't say it's I think I also heard
negative things but anyway that's what
atom editor is written at am editor so M
is cold editor let's just look up some
of the web pages okay so let's look up
some of the web pages atom editor and so
we have the atom editor okay
it looks pretty you see this animation
is from github hackable text editor for
the 21st century my ass all these
marketing phrases I really despise them
hackable you see No okay so this is a
marketing face you know obviously
because you know on the first page it
tries to say something to entice to
attract you know the users so it's for
marketing phrases you can see you can
see a lot of things you know between the
lines first of all you can see that you
know what's their goal you know you can
see what's the audience the audience is
obviously programmers because you know
the editor is for Paramus so they want
to attract programmers so they attack
line or the marketing phrase is hackable
takes editor for the 21st century so
what does that mean you know it in price
okay it's for the 21st century meaning
that it's like modern you know so it's
like new essentially it means like new
better than old things like Emacs you
know then note the word hackable so it's
like okay a hacker
taxi so the hacker boat you know the
hack ability is right so it means it's a
it's a positive you know it implies that
programmers like that you know they like
something that's hackable they like the
word hack you know which is I despise
the word hack anything you know that's
associated with the word hack I despise
hack to you okay common common
programmers oh the elite hacker typer
programmers to them okay it means you
know it's it's it's a privilege like
it's an elite it's like a higher status
it's somehow you know hack you know it
came from you know the Richard storm and
basically that generation you know
hacker you know Oh hacker news for
example the program you know it's hack
means like it's um it's it's kind of
like a positive tag to them okay to this
programmer Fox to me hack means the
worst you know you don't know how
to design you don't know mathematics you
don't have time you don't you know you
don't think about things you hack you
know like you try random things you try
clever you know clever things like the C
and UNIX you know that that's to
me what what hack means I don't want to
be a hacker okay alright if whatever I
do is good I want to be considered like
great mathematician great engineer great
programmer okay not hack so anyway
that's about the atom editor okay so so
okay they got Wikipedia page atom editor
so Adam editor is a free and open source
takes at text in source code editor for
Mac OS we for Mac OS and Linux and
windows
Haddam is based on electron formerly
known as atom share a framework that
enables cross-platform desktop
applications using comeon in not jeaious
yeah so basically it's you know it's
just Chrome web browser
you know chrome web browser you know web
browser has become so powerful in so
monstrous you know so they they you know
so it functions like you know the core
you know the framework for text editors
so you know imagine in the atom text
editor when you have a new window it
actually just a new browser window you
know a new tab is just actually a broad
new browser tab and and where did where
did the URL field go well it's just like
removed you know so the whole you know
window is just a just like a window is
just a text box you know you know so
it's it's like a you know Chrome browser
but anyway so let's look at visual code
studio okay let's look at that then
visual studio code because that okay so
this is Microsoft's version you know
code editing redefined okay now let's
look at this this is what Microsoft okay
we visual called studio visual studio
code now they also have a marketing
phrase the marketing the primary
marketing phrase is code editing video
find and free open source runs
everywhere so there is another marketing
what you know code editing redefined so
what what does it mean we define you
know so the way they want you to think
is that that you know like the atom you
know let's compare
marketing phrases compare these to
marketing facts
so this one Adam is the hackable text
editor of all 21st century now the
Microsoft version is code editing
redefined oh Jesus they redefined it
what so what does does it mean so so it
means they it's not just new ok and if
in fact they redefined the thing I guess
you know it implies they changed the
nature of code editing you know so it's
it's it's brand new of the new it's like
redefined and compared to the github a
hackable text editor for the 21st
century now in comparison the github
marketing phrase seems to be lackluster
you know it's just a hack bow text
editor for a 21st century Jesus 21st
century we are year 2019 we are already
19 years into 21st century so this is
this 21st century is kind of old already
now on the other hand the Microsoft
Visual Studio code is code editing
redefine oh god this is really fun and
it's free or free is a keyword you know
when anything it's free free food free
pizza you know things fire fly and
open-source and runs anywhere oh yeah
just like Java ok so yeah so that you
got these things and electron
not funny electron or whatever that is
electron hole let's look at that
do you think a college education is
important now if you are going to be a
programmer if you envision programming
is your career goal then a college
education is not important and I would
also say if if you have a strong
interest in math if you want to be a
mathematician not just want to be but
you are you know you are so much
interested in math like like you read it
every day you eat math for food if
that's the case okay then college
education is also not important as you
know provided that you know folk
programming and mathematicians you do if
you know you really have strong interest
in them you don't need college education
but high above it for some other things
for example if you want to become a
dentist you know oh you know a doctor
then it is you know important and if you
but if you want to be a let's say
historian no it's not important if you
want to be a writer a greatest writer
for example you know college education
is also not important in fact
connotation education the value of
college education has been rotted you
know let's say hundred years ago or two
hundred years ago a college education is
rather prestige you know if you have a
degree but it helped has become for kind
of two reasons one is that it has become
commonplace you know it's like every you
know almost everywhere it's become so
very common in fact you know it's almost
like free education in many places like
in Germany or whatever you know it
become required even whenever things are
free okay the quality
goes away goes you know become lower so
that's one reason college age education
has become not much value you know you
have like thousands of thousands of PhDs
every year you have ten thousand hundred
thousand ph ph d--'s even in math mad
mathematics okay and in computer science
computer science okay they know nothing
really they know they know nothing first
of all a lot of these people with a
degree they don't have interest in the
subject
they are the in college because their
parents told them to because they think
they'll get a good job you know have
good money but you know they do homework
very higher somewhere else suggest me to
do homework for them so college
education ya know so so let me read
electrons so this there's electron
framework let's look a little bit what
is all this looks fancy electron field
cross-platform desktop apps with
javascript HTML and CSS you know there's
one thing interesting about CSS you know
because CSS you know is used to define
appearances right I myself never had the
experience of programming or desktop
application you know I never actually
have the experience I read a little bit
but I never actually coded desktop
application doesn't matter in Linux or
Windows or Mac I never did I only have
experience of building websites you know
all website apps so cool you know you
could say that so I know CSS you know
very well but but it appears but I don't
know I don't know how to
kote GUI you know let's say right this
top application
you know GUI app in any OS you know I
never done that but it appears to me CSS
the way CSS is used CSS and HTML is used
to define the looks of a window and you
know buttons it seems they are replacing
the traditional widget frameworks you
know in desktops I'm wondering is that a
good thing or bad you know I I don't
know because I don't really have
experience of how do you actually the
GUI frameworks to create windows buttons
menus and things like that but however
it seems to me today CSS is kind of
replacing a lot of that but I don't know
how is that good or bad
okay so let's read comments a bit
Finch yeah so javascript has huge uses
today for some reason
I think he's mostly fashioned it's not
because you know JavaScript is really
good therefore you know all these big
companies started to create frameworks
to let you use JavaScript to write apps
no actually I think he's rather the
movement of the industry and part of the
the way the industry moves is because
you know where there is money and where
the program programmer interest goes and
programmer interest interest not
necessarily because you know they have
good knowledge you know they have good
decisions but rather because you know a
lot of us we programmers they don't know
nothing you know but they you have a lot
JavaScript programmers therefore you
want to create a situation where you
know people can use JavaScript to write
apps because then you can hire them
cheaply you know so I think that's the
reason
have you heard of the Pony language a
reference capability secure programming
language no I don't know what is the
Pony language let's see
hmm pony Isle pony pony
that's interesting
so welcome this is the website for the
pony programming language Pony is a open
source object-oriented
actor/model o capabilities secure oh
what the is that
high-performance foreign language I
don't think I'm much interested I'm
first of all turned off by
object-oriented and turned off by actor
model well but you know I'm biased
biased of course I don't even know the
language but just from the marketing
phrase I don't think it's for me
so Pony okay so let's see so do you like
pony or what do you ask
Finch so you think it's good so some
toxins says I have mostly heard bad
things about electron yeah Finch says
okay make sense to use JavaScript
so Finch says it makes no sense to use
JavaScript for a desktop application in
my humble opinion yeah I agree yeah so
Finch says I don't mind JavaScript
itself it's just that it has way too
many silent behaviors which can cause
problems in corner cases yes it has tons
of it you know I cannot begin to
describe es6 is quite good to actually
use yeah you have some form of
destructuring in Ruby oh okay argument
destructuring good morning I'm a digital
Nomad from Australia oh yes from
Australia no wait
is a US is is that Australia or Austria
it's kind of confusing to Austria in
Australia so Finch says agile with a
small a is aids layered on top of cancer
that is yeah
so sometimes seeing uneven good morning
green deck so green deck says what is
your advice
okay green deck green deck says what is
your advice in choosing key bindings for
new commands if I use sawfly keys
okay that's a good topic to talk about
I'm kind of you know I'm probably not
talking well today because sometimes you
just don't feel like it you know and and
I don't you know so like sometimes I
feel you know I should make this show
like a real show so it's more
professional and you know none of my
anyway so so what is your advice on in
choosing key bindings for new commands
if I use stuff like he's okay I can
answer that one okay so here here is
advice for that okay you if if you have
further questions green deck just
comment okay
I'll see it in an answer that right away
so if you are a Mac user using some fly
keys and you want to you have some
commands you use often you want to give
them a key give them a key so what key
do you how do you pick a new key so
here's a general rule okay one is your
command repeatable meaning that for some
commands okay I call them fast
repeatable meaning that you you want to
repeat a command several times within a
second for example move cursor to the
right or to the left for example yeah
move kusa you know to the right or left
up or down you know like the arrow keys
or move by word okay
this are what I call fast repeat to ball
commands it's such the word sorry
fast beep eatable
come and you'll find an article I
discuss the situation so this is the
article keybinding design fast repeat
commands okay so so those are commands
that that you often code them more than
once within one second you know so
usually that means you hold the key down
so for example page European page down
you know that's one of the example you
know page down for example you have a
loan if you have a loan page you know
you can hold it and you just just you
know keep calling a command tens of
times within a second for example so
those commands are fast repeatable
commands now some other commands are not
for example if you are in Emacs let's
say let's say you want to open a file
right I want to open a file so then I
caught a command then I have to choose a
file you know it's not something that
you just call it you know many times
within a second okay so they are
repeatable fast repeatable commands and
they are those commands that are not
vast majority of commands are not okay
now for the repeater for commands you
want to give them a key such that you
can hold it down for example any of the
function keys like f10 f11 f12 for
example you know you want to be able to
hold it down or you can give them keys
like ctrl T for example you can hold
down control and hold down T and that
command will just repeat so you want the
keys to be repeatable
now what keys are not repeatable so for
example you cannot have keys like you
know control X then to you know
obviously that doesn't work because you
have to hold control press X release X
release control
impress - you know that's that cause
your command but if you want to repeat
it you cannot do it you know you cannot
hold a key so anyway so fast repeatable
commands you you want to have fast
repeatable Keys such as control T or a
single key you know the keys like that
so focus you know for Emacs so I would
recommend bind them to control something
okay finally some controls something key
you don't use then bind it oh you can
burn it to MIT has something or add
something okay like old tea or you know
do that
now if the command is not repeatable you
just then you just bind it to a leader
key like space something for examples
you know and you know and find a spot in
fact there's an empty spot you can use
let's say let's see if space wait
yes space space dot you wait space dot
space star on Borak okay on QWERTY it's
space II I think I think that's empty
you know just find an empty leader key
space and and bind all your commands
non-repeatable commands to to that okay
that that's one question answered I'm
not doing good
I'm not doing where I'm talking today so
let's see next question green deck so
green deck I hope that this I'll answer
the question so next headless browsers
in a manner of speaking with the custom
UI yeah that's about Adam
help heavys browsing amana speaking with
a curse on UI
huh Aaron dot says hikes are speaking of
math do you have any tips advice on
self-study math yeah but like but what
do you mean specifically like do you
have any context
so speaking of math math do you have any
tips advice on self studying math that's
you know actually actually if you want
to depends on what you like what's your
situation are you a young guy who you
know like a team okay let's say you know
20 or below 20 who wants to be a
mathematician and also yeah it depends
on lots of things or did or maybe you
are 30 you know you already have a
programming job and you want to study
math so the path no the tips will be
very different for example if you are a
young person okay if you are under 20
you you like math a lot and you want to
be a mathematician you have to be
careful because you don't you you can
study math by yourself but it is also
very important to have a guide like you
really you you have to you know like
some some professor you know like a
friend or some your dad is a professor
for example um you know if you have that
context then that's good because from
them you you have you have even implicit
guidance about you know what you want to
study you know you you you are on the
right track but if you don't have
friends who are you know Malcolm
attrition so you know thesis or whatever
you don't want you may not want to take
my advice of just studying math by
yourself because you get you
you have guidance and this you know huge
amount of math you know you you can use
easily go astray you know you like
you're going nowhere you actually
so the despite even though you are
extremely interested you know you could
have you know you you you want to have
some kind of guidance you know yeah so
so that's that but some yeah about okay
so about some tips about learning math
and see okay so what about tips and
advice for self studying math yeah
that's very broad question like do you
mean what text what topics to read like
what branch of math to study or do you
mean what's the techniques of you know
doing proves you know like let me know
Erin so here on dot let me know and
what's your current level yeah that's
also a good question I mean yeah good
tip so some Thaksin says I was
constraint considering college but
haven't gone yet I'm not sure what I
want to study yeah so that question
actually that depends a lot on you
because each person are actually very
different you cannot imagine what's
other people's situation including you
know your family background are you and
how much money your family are making
you know it really actually depends all
that or that and also which country are
you from
so you really have very different
answers so yeah so about going to
college you want to you know if you give
me more
detail I might help a little bit but
actually I think this is you know
whether to go to college is a kind of
very broad general question you know but
if you ask me it's it's overrated for
sure you know as especially for
programming if you want to be a
programmer you don't really you don't
you know you don't want to go to college
Chantry also actually go to college to
learn something is actually extremely
inefficient because you have to you know
drive or take the bus or whatever to go
there every day you have to do the admin
stuff you know like registering a class
then you have to meet you know go to the
class you know take the time to go to
class you know you have to meet people
you have to do homework you know
extremely you in efficient like like
eight seventy or percent of the time you
spent of you know so-called going to
college is like not about studying
actually less than 20% is are actually
reading you know the books or stuff you
know listening to lectures but however
the advantage of college is that it
gives you a context it gives you a like
a community you know you know you with
other students you know like you have to
do this every day it's kind of like a
routine of your life you know if you
don't go to college then you are like me
for example sitting at home all day what
you're gonna do today you don't know
what you're gonna do tomorrow you don't
know you can easy you know if if you are
not a puta you know like me you easily
get distracted you easily become
something else you went to do drugs or
whatever you know you because he on the
other hand if you are going to college
you know every day is your college life
you know you you go to this class today
you go to party tomorrow
but then after tomorrow you have to go
to another class you know you kind of
you know that this way you know
it sets schedule for you but in terms of
actually not learning you know you are
learning like only 20% of your time is
spent actually learning something and
and also this a lot of things can go
wrong you know you most people go to
college you are not you know you don't
learn anything you don't know learning
history you don't know you don't learn
nothing you learn you just go to college
to party you know that's a good thing
actually you you meet other young girls
and you party you know young guys are
actually stupid you know young boy is
not until you are like 30-something you
became it's actually true you know for
females for girls okay they they mature
naturally very early young when they
were young you know because I suppose
it's because by our biology you know
because women you have to you have to
have baby early young because after a
certain age you cannot on the other hand
men you you know this you know
essentially there is no limit you know
until you you can still have baby at
eight age 50 you know so and remember
just 200 years ago
people died at age 30 you know so girls
they get married when they are you know
13 14 you know then they have children
at you know 13 14 and people die you
know 30 you are gone for new you turn
your done year 30 you know 40 you are
lucky so that's that's just even 200
years ago so you know but so anyway I
was saying so females naturally they
they kind of mature early while guys you
know you know as a girl say stupid boys
that's true
you know so we so but when you are older
you kind of get for some reason okay for
males guys when you are older you you
you know what you want you know about
you you become more mature which is a
case for me as well you know I when I
was younger yeah was especially with
respect to girls like I don't know what
I want you know and even I do I don't
know you know what to do
so girls like you know guys who are
mature know what they want and can get
it you know like you have to all these
came from experience anyway so so let's
read some more comments so Aaron says
so Aaron is studying calculus yeah so
Aaron but that also depends on your age
like are you like kind of under 20 20
something or are you you know 30
something you know so you know yeah so
the advice about learning math would be
different you know for example why are
you learning calculus in in linear
algebra so Finch says
okay Finch says I like pony the language
it is extremely powerful but with a
steeper learning curve then even rust oh
my god
type self-type safety and data rays free
Karen peace at compile-time
are very interesting to me oh that's
interesting
so I suppose pony is kind of a low-level
language yeah I don't know much about
low-level programming so and so aut
Zoe's Austria Oh
aus is Australia OSE Austria what
language today is speaking Austria
okay so Erin says I do software Deb
already but I like to get into more math
heavy areas like kamdev okay now we have
context okay so your D you are videos
you know software programmer but now you
want to get more math now that's now we
have context because now there's a
question of what math to study you know
you could study calculus and linear
algebra you know like the other day I
talked about the branches of math you
know there are many branches is you know
yeah I think you know we you know it it
really depends on what what's your goal
now if you have some specific goal for
example if you are game dev and you want
to get into more linear algebra okay if
you want to understand more math related
to programming so you can maybe do
better game programming or something
then you want to study practical linear
algebra you know you know like linear
algebra related to computer graphics
you know which is actually quite
different from linear algebra you know
kind of that really linear algebra
mathematicians are interested about you
know like for programmers when you when
we think of linear algebra we think of
Oh it's useful for computer graphics you
know 3d actually that's not that's not
that's not the nature of linear algebra
and when you're talking about linear
algebra you know we're talking about
computer graphics you know matrices oh
court onions you know programmers always
like these fancy words you know they
know nothing about you know they well
they maybe know some quota they don't
know the whole background you know where
were these come from like they have no
idea they just know linear algebra oh
all matrices all quaternions you know
that's what programmers
I despise I despise the programmers when
but why but what's the alternative the
alternative the normal the proper way to
understand things it's not just you know
you heard it something on hacker news
every day then you talk about that all
the time that's that's what happens with
you know quaternions rather you
want to have no more development you
know so you understand like you have the
broad of you know whole things you know
you learn things naturally then maybe
you find this interest you know called
quaternions interesting you know then
you talk about quaternions but you know
but when you talk about that you already
know the background you know how you
know all the other things you already
know you know unlike the programmers
concept anyway so
so when program let's talk about linear
algebra you know what they are thinking
is you know the matrix multiplication
you know computational you know to find
out you know how how do you rotate for
example you have a point in 3d space you
want to rotate it in certain degrees and
what's the you know what's the
coordinate for the new point that's what
you do you know that's what that's the
use of linear algebra or actually main
matrix multiplication for computer
graphics okay but that's not math okay
that's not that's one application you
know application of linear algebra
theories linear algebra is actually
about linear is a qualifier okay it's an
algebra algebra abstract a structure
okay so for example if you go to
Wikipedia okay you see nothing about you
know the code and it's points you know
he's you know linear algebra it's you
know for example yeah the so it says you
know Wikipedia linear algebra is a
branch of math concerning linear
equations such as
you know a 1 X 1 plus a 2 X 2 plus a 3 X
3 equals to be ok and and so on that
that is the origin of linear algebra ok
that's that's a history that's a
historical origin of linear algebra but
linear algebra is a proper math subject
is not about linear equations ok
for example the Wikipedia alko gives you
history you see the history the
procedure for solving same similar
simultaneous linear equations now called
Gaussian elimination appears in Asian
Chinese bah-bah-bah anyway that's the
arrangement of linear algebra to solve
multiple linear equations ok
that's the whole engine of linear
algebra but it's not it's not really
linear algebra is about today ok what so
what what is linear algebra math you
know real math you know for today's
mathematicians it is this ok it is this
one vector spaces you are dealing with
vector space so what is vector space
well it's okay so a vector space over a
field F is a set we equipped with two
binary operations satisfying the
following axioms okay then you have
these axioms so it's a it's all abstract
there's no equations it's just this it's
just a set of things it's a field so
what is the field theory say another of
strengthening our Chopra so anyway so my
what I'm talking about what I'm saying
is that linear algebra the real linear
algebra of math okay it's not about
computer programmers thinking about all
matrices so you know get the coordinate
of a point it's nothing like that
it's about this
you know then you have linear maps the
subspace spanned basis okay that these
are critical concepts okay then you have
matrices matrices is not actually
matrices is actually just a
computational tool and the morphisms and
square matrices determine okay
icon values and eigenvectors those are
also critical stuff
duo map okay anyway so so yeah linear
algebra so so back to the topics topics
so if you are a programmer depends on
what you're interested in math now if
you want to just you know a little more
math so that you can be a better game
programmer for computer graphics then
then okay learned in your java okay but
then if you have general curiosity about
math then there's lots of things I
talked about this topic the other day
and a few videos back you might check
you might check it out because I gave
you know C okay okay thank you green
deck
okay I think we talked about for long
okay we are about to shut down so any
more questions so Aaron says for context
I mean you might meet 20th with software
job that's great yeah so what exactly is
your goal in math are you just curious
you want to like you know want to be no
no more math it like because there are
so many things you can go to go into
very interesting to programmers for
example there's graph theory okay that's
very interesting there is okay abstract
algebra like I mentioned linear algebra
is part of algebra again this of
abstract much algebra okay where you
have fields being groups those are very
interesting
you know graph theory okay you know
abstract algebra also those are
fundamental on the other hand you know
when you are saying you are studying
calculus that's also very important but
but in that direction really have very
little to do with programming because
then you need you you study calculus in
there multivariable calculus then you
study analysis so called analysis which
is actual real mathematicians calculus
okay then you have topology then then
you may get into differential equations
in differential geometry but anyway
those are not much with to do with
programming yeah but the point is there
are so many topics then there's also
computational geometry you know then
there's also a branch of logic where for
example if you are interested in improve
theory you know lambda calculus that
type of thing or theoretical computer
science you know what is computable what
is not compute
you know then you you you know that's
another topic so so there are many ways
to go into math depends on what's your
interest does that make sense
I mean let me know
okay for me having the math lesson yes
yeah this is crazy
indie dev I you know I actually I like
to know how to do game programming I
never had you know I never actually
learned you know it's I think it's very
time-consuming is there anyone who wants
to teach me okay we can do okay now if
you if there's some of you okay Aaron or
Finch or some of you now well you have
to be a you have to be a game dev for
like two years let's say then we can set
up you know we teach other Pro it teach
each other program you know you teach me
some game dev okay from the ground up
then I can teach you you know maybe some
math or where to go about math or
something like that I can teach you eMac
this for example for example okay so if
you want to do that you know let me know
you know can't contact me in private
okay so sound toxin says you are in the
US and family is not very wealthy being
out of school so are you country working
as a programmer so you are considering
your options yeah that would be hard to
say so
[Music]
so wait sound taxing what's the context
oh yeah so you are wondering if you want
to go to college
wait am i still broadcasting you know
okay I think I hear okay anyway my talk
went you know kind of bad I guess so
guys any more questions let's say
goodbye for today alright see you guys
tomorrow hope you join me tomorrow thank
you for coming bye bye