another episode of sound talk show today
the topic no topic random so you ask
questions and I will answer
meanwhile I'm going to work on my uh
work on my emac website I mean not just
emac but on my
website so you know what I need to do
there's tons of things to do so let's do
uh one of the things I want to do is
write the emac
program uh
that that will move a
HTML block of text to another page with
all the relative links fixed okay so
let's uh Define the name move
html text block let's just say that okay
on the pink window is all my command
course and the keystrokes aside type
aside for example delete paste copy
paste undo you can see all the command
names and the key strokes on the left
I'm using Sly keys of course this
fantastic sofly Keys you can get it on
GitHub and the most efficient key
binding for emac and I'm using a v
keyboard layout so for example go to to
keyboard blog and go to
layout design keyboard special keys
layout so you can see there is the VAC
layout
fantastic okay so remember random topic
okay so you ask questions and uh
meanwhile I work on my website good
afternoon hello step flat step flat
where where you from and have I asked
you that question
before and hello
Dave so by the way this is red wine
let's see so this is red wine red wine
with paple juice
fantastic and my keyboard This is
Ultimate hacking keyboard fantastic I
use it for as a keyboard marker so I got
60 keyboard maros or something 62 or
something this is Ultimate I mean
ultimate hacking keyboard This is glove
80 keyboard my main drive now fantastic
and this is
newa
m501 I believe I talked about three
videos ago and this is Logitech
50502 I think
g502 so that's my keyboard and I want to
mention this again I'm still working on
it so this is SW board s v a l b o a r d
this is the most
fancy uh extreme
keyboard search for it you'll see my
review and other people's uh information
about
it so yeah let's go back to emac this
coding again ask questions okay so let's
uh right now I want to write this
command uh
what okay so
documentation can buffer
to to next with all relative link fixed
now this is a very useful command
date why is it useful for example you
see
I have a you know so let's go to sound
talk show you know I work on
HTML there are 10,000 HTML files so for
example I want to let's say go
to
uh my blog programming blog let's say I
want to move uh you know so there's
article about rip grab which I did a
live stream about issues of rib grab and
this is a creator of rib grab so I want
to move this you know this block of text
into let's say ex talk
show so let's see today's uh let's go to
ex talk show and today's talk show
showing browser so I want to move this
or this block of text into here now if I
just copy it it won't work for example I
go here you see this this this I press a
key to copy and delete it undo so you
can see the command in the Ping window
that is sart delete let me try that
again you see my CER is here press one
key e on B and that whole
HTML element is removed and copied okay
undo now I move the CER to this s talk
show panel paste it you
see
fantastic the most Supreme efficiency in
emac showing browser you see you see the
rip grab link is there but if you click
it file not found why is that the reason
is because you know in HTML you have
relative links so this rib grab is in
this directory which is s info comp
while the c talk show dire jump go to
the top is in C info talk show directory
so the talk show directory do not have a
file of rib grab so to properly link
this rib grab file what you have to do
is you so I want to make link of this
file you press a key to copy the URL
full path so you can see the command is
s HTML extract
URL so now I move the cruiser back here
to the S talk show you can see the name
is right here enter paste okay so you
got the full path now you can link it
link and uh make it a list showing
browser there it is so now you click it
the it is a correct
link so instead of doing all these steps
manually I would like just to
you know like press a key and we will
move the current text block to the other
pen and with all the uh relative link F
links fixed okay so let's show okay so
delete that delete that showing browser
okay now go back to the so we are
starting uh we are going to code
hello so again as ask your questions
okay ask your questions and I'll answer
meanwhile I'm just going to work on my
um stuff okay so you know as my emac
blog lots of updates you know turns
every day so let's work on this command
some move html text
block okay now let's go back here ping
block close close close close showing
browser yeah today talk show so now I
already have a command that we
move that will
turn all links in a text block so that
all the local links the related file
links will become full
path okay so let me show you so for
example let's uh copy that let's paste
it here so you see this is a text block
containing a link now
I press this key Bam Bam ban you see the
file path now
becomes full path absolute path uh but
actually this this is uh this is
actually uh the format for local URL so
you have file colon SL
slash so now if you show in browser you
know that link still works
you know this is the complexity of
URL so I mean what why do you use this
URL local format local URL format
instead of just let's say uh wait
instead of just you know you know the uh
file full path well if you use file full
path it does not work you see click a
click it doesn't work so in HTML if you
have a local file and if you want the
absolute path you need to add this file
colon slash slash that's the URL format
okay showing browser again click it
works go back go back okay so I have a
command so let's undo undo undo undo
undo undo Undo You See originally looks
like that now I press key all links
become full path links in the current
text block okay that's fantastic now I
can copy cut this and move to some other
HTML and paste it then I call another
command then all the full path URL will
become relative links so let me do that
press press press you see fantastic and
you can see the command is there HTML
local links to Rel relative path and
then then you also havea HTML local
links to full path okay all those arear
HTML uh mod major mod okay so you have
to pay to get it
because after 15 years working in open
source you don't get money you die of
hunger and you become the you know the
worst part is you become Tech
support like every day people will just
like how do you do this oh this one is
this this command is wrong you need to
you know can you fix it yeah and you
know they they act as compatriots you
know it's like they are helping you or
something so for 15 years about 15 years
you know I've been doing like you know
tech support and some of them will start
to argue you know this part is actually
you should write it this way because
it's better you don't know you don't
know how to code you know the full of
arguments um so
anyway so let's write so yeah so now we
have the two commands so let's uh split
the buffer let me just work work this so
all I really have want to do is want I
want to call these two commands so one
of them is that okay here is the
documentation here here is a uh command
name the other one is describe key
press press press okay the other one is
this one copy and so these two commands
that's essentially what I
need okay uh sitea local links to full
path okay so let's look at the
documentation again so you can actually
jump to the source code
uh local links to full path the path
okay change your local rela links to
full paths in current block or selection
okay so you see we are writing this new
command and will be it will be using
this
two commands Okay
but one thing you need to do
is you see this this Command right now
we are trying to call this command to
change or local file path to full path
but this command does not specify a
beginning position and end position
which we do
need so so I think the first step is to
modify this command let's
see so this command just assume the
current block of text or selection okay
uh
yeah okay we'll change it
cheers okay we're going to so first job
is to modify this command so it takes a
POS beginning and end
position describe command describe
function show the documentation press
tab to it jump to the source code so
here is the code we need to modify this
so that okay new buer paste it save as a
temp file XX today State and the command
name eel okay we're going to work on
this so we're going to
add uh HTML local link to full
path Okay so
so you need an
optional optional argument that is
begin end okay that's a emac convention
you have a beginning and end position
just work you know if those arguments
are given just work on those uh
region so when so we just added that and
so when you are coding this command
interactively that is meta X then you
add this argument yourself okay so let's
do
that so now you need uh begin here end
you need a value for those okay so we
going to do
that okay so so
actually uh okay so actually interactive
let's make it a let's create a let block
okay then put it here okay so let have
so therefore you can have local
variables then let's copy that we want
local variables xp1 xp2 for beginning
for position one and
two hello light on Twitter on
x.com again you have a questions random
questions ask me otherwise I'm coding
this
okay so we you got two positions local
variable and uh in fact I got this super
convenient code let me just copy that
let's
[Music]
see uh get position of block or so yeah
so
set so in so the interactive block means
that if you are coding this function
via meta X like
interactively then it
will it will call this part of code
interactive to
fill to fill out the arguments this part
automatically okay so that's what we
doing that's what we are doing here so
so sequence set Q that's a new command
in the past five years also so we got
SAR get position of block or selection
that's what this command do it's
in uh it's not in wam language mod okay
so it's in s utilities okay so you can
find it on my
website uh but uh let's see
yeah so here's a source
code pretty short but the
actual UT actually you can find it in
this in this um iMac
dis uh no actually not there you
it's actually in this file sarget things
okay so you can show in browser you can
actually download it so the code is
here so this saret things will allow you
to get the boundary of the current word
the current line the current you know
region block or if there's a already a
selection then get the grab the
selection if not then the current world
whatever so these are the functions
provided and uh the code is here
okay hello Hank why is emac self
documentation not sold as AI uh well
emac claims emac proclaims that it is a
self document self-documenting editor
okay so you see the extensible
self-documenting text
editor now this makes sense in the
context of
1970s and
1980s because back then there's nothing
like emac in fact emx is the first
editor where when you type you see what
you are typing you know like something
you know this is called we see wig what
you see is called we
what you what you see is what you
get okay it's a new buffer let's magnify
to see the full Glory of this thing wey
week you know you can look up it's on
Wikipedia so it means what you see is
what you get so back in the 197 you know
in late 1970s and and 80s there's no
editor like that so you have instead you
have like the vi where do I have VI
installed I don't I'm not sure so let's
check uh get command Vim do I have VI
GCM Neo
Vim okay I don't I don't think I have uh
VI installed but back then what you do
is
you you you type a key to call a command
then you type the text you want to
insert then you then you type another
command that tells the screen okay do it
then the screen updates you have you
know like basically just like VI
so it's very cumbersome so emac is the
first editor in
1978 76 you know 1980 that has this you
know
type and see it as you go you know on
the
fly so you know this is a bit history
so so that so you know that's a context
then but besides that you see it also
call itself self documentate self
document self-documenting editor why is
that because back then again you know
emac it created lots of new Concepts
that today we take for granted such as
copy and paste you know that's one of
them emac begin
it uh more or less okay so copy and
paste you know emac begin it and type as
you go you know see what you typed and
one of the one of them is called self
document self documenting what does that
mean that means every function every
command has a documentation like as part
of the function
like like for example I want to paste
right okay let's see um well anyway the
point is that every function you have a
documentation that come with the
function you know as you code so you can
look up you know for example I want to
look up this command I call describe
function type the command name and enter
Then here is the documentation for that
command so basically every command in
emac by default you have you know uh
1,200 commands also they all have
documentation that tells you what this
command do so this is also new the first
you know emac is the first to do
this you see today it's very common for
example let's go to
uh python okay okay you know today it's
very common to
see function with documentation for
example do we have
a uh
What uh not
here py uh for example let's say this
here this is a python code and you can
see here we Define a function and here's
the documentation doc string for this
function you see and this is in every
language
today and emx begin
it so emac made a lot
Innovations so anyway so back to emac so
that's why uh let's see let's go back to
uh uh go let's go back to the emac
documentation control
h so tab tab go to emac documentation so
that's why emac say it's self docu
documenting editor you know that's a
very Advanced idea also also
customizable extensible you know so it's
advanced advanced in the sense of
1980 okay so that's emac tradition to
this day it still says this but every
editor you know every editor today is
basically extensible customizable
self-documenting okay like you know vs
code you know and so on but anyway the
emac is the first you know you know emac
1985 but actually begin earlier so that
is why it says self docu
documenting okay so it is not really
AI I mean it's Advanced but it's not
really AI okay that's what it
um
means okay let's go back
to huh I'm feeling a bit the effect of
the
drink let's go back to what we want to
do do I make sense any anyone comments
questions
okay so we need to code this uh code
this interactive to give argument
so the beginning Position will be xp1
and end Position will be
xp2 okay because we call this function
this function will return the beginning
and end
position
if there is a selection like right now
there's a selection then you know it
returns this point and this point if
there's no selection it will return the
current text block
which is defined
by which which is defined by basically
empty lines
so so for example if we add empty lines
here and we add empty lines here and
this is the current text block okay so
if you make a selection it'll return the
selection boundary if not if there's no
selection you'll return the text block
okay very convenient so the value is xp1
xp2
position and then all you have to do and
you know let's reformat and then you
just return this so This default
directory is a current directory xp1 xp2
so that is the argument feed to this
function when you call this function
um what
when you code this function by meta X
okay okay so we added that let's see
what else so change the version date
okay to
today I think that's it I don't even
need to um test it because the code is
very simple I know what I'm
doing so that's
it okay now I want to cut this go back
to where that file came
from
so describe function that function so
it's in here so this is the original
code now cut
swap back here paste then cut the new
one back to there paste so there we have
updated
this this function okay save it uh make
a backup okay go to
diet bu
compile yes oh okay unus lexical I'll
given oh [ __ ] oh yeah we forgot there's
something else we need to do so one of
the advantage of bite compile emac this
file is that you know it can catch
errors okay like like right now okay so
we go back to it there's something else
we need to do so we yeah because right
now this beginning and end is not
used so we need to make use of
it okay so let's see we have to say
if if not begin if begin is
new okay so if begin is near
and and is new
then then
[Music]
we set them
okay
otherwise otherwise we just set
otherwise we just
said okay so you see let xp1
xp2 now if the beginning and end
position is not
given then you set them otherwise you
just set them to beginning and end when
it's given so now the xp1 XP P2 is our
beginning and
end okay so far so good okay sounds good
now make a backup drop to dire directory
di jump and compile bite compile the
code yes no error fantastic open the
bite bite compile file delete it because
usually I don't I don't I don't need
you know usually B compiled emac list
file is about six times faster when you
uh when you load it or when when you run
it so it's a slightly faster
but but you know usually it's not
noticeable unless your code is really
large you know usually it's recommended
recommended you buy compile your emac
this files so
anyway uh so we have updated this
function to allow the option begin end
fantastic okay so let's see let's see do
we need to modify the documentation
change your local relative
links
okay okay I think that's
good fantastic
eval the buffer close it now this is you
know the original we don't need close it
saret thing close it close it okay now
back here so now we can call this
command and we can give it xp1 begin you
know we can give it two positions but
actually first of all you need a
directory uh
so anyway we are coding this command so
let's
um so we need two variables so these two
variable is the like the beginning and
end position we want our command to work
on so let's document it move a html text
block
uh from current buffer
to to next buffer
with all relative link fixed
okay uh text block or
selection okay Inc buer okay that's what
we
want it's a bit long for the first
sentence by convention the documentation
the first sentence should be within
76 count of characters but okay we'll
fix it later
l so anyway
so let's see so we need let's see let's
again let's add options okay
um okay I'm like I feel slightly
drunk local links to full path
okay so loc let's see let's just get it
to work then we'll do some fix or
whatever later
then then you
call uh then you call Window okay
so other window moves your closer to the
next pen okay so other window other
window count so okay you move to the
other window then you
paste okay then you okay then
you save Excursion uh narrow to
region point
point if you have questions ask it okay
otherwise I'm just going to code it
because this takes you know a few
minutes to
explain so save restrictions now this is
in a new buffer I mean in the new pen
you move the cruiser to there then you
narrow to region of the current point
then you want to paste Okay so
oh okay so you actually need to grab it
first so we do need position
one position two two positions local
variable and
uh okay so
Mo find mod that's not what we
want let's look
up let's get a code it's kind of like
that
so that's right so you do that and then
so that sets xp1 and
xp2 then you call this okay
so then you call this
command okay but before you do that you
need to narrow to region because every
time you change some text in a region
the end point boundary also changes
so God I'm a slightly drunk now okay
so let's see save
restriction then do that uh then you
do point
mean Point
Max okay then you
do then what you do is you want to grab
the whole
thing so let's uh make a new variable X
text okay uh
block okay so let's just say text okay
so X so then
you
uh buffer string okay
so you set X text equals to basically
this whole thing something like that
okay so you instead of so you want
buffer string let's look up the
documentation buffer string return the
contents of the buffer as a
string yeah so that that's what you
want okay so so this will change all the
local
links and uh return the
text not really
something uh
okay so we want
to delete and kill
region
this Chris says in one of your 2002 blog
posts you mention wanting to teach your
grandchildren something do you still
plan to have grandchildren
I don't remember what that post 2002 and
grandchildren yeah I don't remember
what PO is
that do I still wish to have
grandchildren well I don't have children
at all so I wish to have children do I
wish to have children
yes but right now my wife is old you
know so I happens my wife is like my age
50 something so she cannot have children
so it's a problem you know I need to get
a blonde I need to [ __ ] a
blonde
so right now I'm not sure how is that
going to
happen but you know I keep my hopes
up you know I need to talk to wife she
says you you can't afford to survive for
yourself so if if I win the lottery then
I'll get a CH uh I'll get you know I'll
[ __ ] a BL and get children
from yeah I I would like to have
children uh you see time is getting
tight you know a few more years I
probably won't be able to but I can Ste
right now so let's go to emac this
there's something I need to look up
uh [ __ ] I'm a bit dizzy so but I'm going
to finish this yes
yes uh what am I doing so I need to get
um oh yeah delete region and copy so you
go to emac
disp uh emac dis move cursor search text
text editing Mark and region copy paste
and work with L
what move go the text editing okay
insert no delete text yes delete region
yes that's what we want but we want this
delete and extract region okay so it's
proper name is delete and extract region
there it is
fantastic okay so delete and extract
region what we want
uh yeah
so point mean and point Max okay I think
that's so we don't need both of string
let's
see uh let's Sy make sure you know this
is one shot coding no trial and error
because I know you know I've been coding
this for 15 or 20 years 20 years by now
18 years so I don't I so I know what I'm
doing
so so you change that then
you you just Del the whole thing yeah
but actually you don't need it oh yeah
you need you need to yeah you need to
delete it not just get it yeah okay
so delete and extract region fantastic
beautiful quote from you okay so it says
I want to be able to show my rents to my
grandkids when I'm 100 perhaps winning
their smiles okay and that rings a bell
but I don't remember exactly what's the
context you know because I have been you
know blogging for 25
years but I can find that quote right
away now I hope that's
not you know I hope that's a let's
see okay not here
uh
org uh not not there
what where did you find that wait it
should be here
so not there
neither bottom of page
what oh okay so there it
is oh it's
uh ah I see it's one of the rent I've
written in you know in those news groups
so there it
is so if you show the page that Unix
plan text email fetish yeah okay so it's
from one of the rent it's
not you know it's a rent again it's the
Unix fuckets written in year
2002 so I can tell you what you know I
can tell you about this rent you know
basically the you see the Unix
people
they they have a plain text Obsession
you know because the Unix philosophy or
whatever that is you know it's not
really a philosophy but the Unix code
you know it's it's essentially a code
they think that everything should be
text
only that's what this Rand is about you
know today you may not know this much as
much but you know Unix is basically
became Linux right but today this notion
uh you don't see it much because today
you know it's like [ __ ] ridiculous
you know it's idiotic extreme if someone
says everything should be text because
everything should if everything should
be text we don't have live streams we
don't have videos you know but
understand back then in year even
2002 a lot of you you know it's almost
like the most of the programmers the
Unix you know the elite type of
programmers you know they will they they
Harbor this thought you know for example
if you send an email if you contain an
image in an email they get annoyed you
know they think you are an
idiot you know if if you if you are
Grandma you know if you are Mom and Pop
you know maybe they don't complain but
if you are programmer you send an email
with a image in it they get annoyed they
said you know this this idiot [ __ ]
idiot you know because in their mind
everything should be just plan text
that's what Unix is about I mean that's
that's how incredible extreme you know
[ __ ] cat they don't even know you
know they they have no idea so you know
you can read this rent so you know
because I have a lot of detail about you
know the technology you know 200 you
know 240 you know
2400 Bard rate modem you know modem and
you know all the you know you get to see
what the internet or the web is like
back in year 2002 what are people
thinking okay so but anyway the the the
the the hard of is that the you know in
year 2000 a lot of programers still
think that everything should be text and
they don't like decoration you know for
they don't like Microsoft Word they
don't like bold you know if you make
something bold they they hate
it unless unless it's marked up like a
text you know let's let me uh you know
let me
actually uh you see so this this
formatting all in one line is the
formatting I
use but now I there's another thing I do
is I make them you know each line is a
sentence okay so I just just press a key
and each line become a sentence
okay so
anyway so yeah that's what this article
is about now as far as
that that sentence is concerned you know
I said I want to be able able to show my
RS to my grand grandkids when I'm 100
perhaps winning their smiles that's just
that's just troll okay that's just
taunting this Unix fuckets okay the the
lines here at the bottom it doesn't
really actually mean much I mean it's
it's it's just a part of the creative
writing okay you know today's Zoomers
they have no idea they don't know how to
write they can't even write one two
you know formal well contained you know
meaningful sentences that's today's Zuma
[ __ ] you know it has become so bad
like today's people like you can see in
Discord they don't even know how to
write you know two or three coherent
sentence sentences together a lot of
them you
know all they do is just meme you know
Meme and whatever you know like
they they don't know how to
express you know so is that really true
actually that's actually kind of true so
it's kind of
really
uh it it is actually true though
although people do I
mean don't think of any conspiracy
theory about this okay it's not you know
it's it's not like oh everything is this
way or whatever people today today
people Zoomers they are actually smarter
because you have you know Wikipedia you
can know a lots of things but they also
are
lazier and uh you know so this good and
bad but one of the thing is it is true
that today's Zuma let me be specific
let's say
today's people young people among let's
say age 16 to 25
in USA okay
they they are writing abilities and they
reading comprehension abilities is much
worse than 20 years ago okay when for
example when this article is
written so anyway so so what was I
saying so
they you know they they can write okay
so yeah oh yeah so the reason I mention
because you know this sentence you know
the last the punch line in a in a in a
sense I want to be able to show my RS to
my grand grandkids when I'm 100 perhaps
winning their smiles that's like a
punchline to a creative writing okay so
I was saying today's today's rumors they
don't even know writing less creative
writing like what the [ __ ] that is is
that and they don't they don't care
that's the thing about them you know
they they just go to Twitter and you
know you know how it is you know like I
can show you right away you know you go
to almost random Twitter like this one
who who posted this you know like you
know this is just like this
[ __ ] trash the [ __ ] you know zumas
idiots and okay this is this is a new
post so you don't have to rep
yet okay but you just go to like you can
click it like click you know click you
know like it's is all drama and trash
and look at let's see some okay this
account don't have much
replies but you know what I'm talking
about you know you go to TW not just
Twitter Twitter Instagram YouTube any
any almost just any so-called social
media you look at repes it's like all
one bunch of trash
one sentence they can't make one even
coherent sentence and often times it
doesn't mean it you know it's hard to
find what to tell what they means and
all mem and Jons you know they they
can't write English
properly so anyway
that's yeah I guess that's the about
that um
Passage about the Unix you know the Unix
fuckets with their PL text imagine you
know truly imagine in year 2002 you know
these people they don't they don't want
images in email
or or you know is really that's their
mindset you know so this here you have a
collection of articles about this Unix
people today they become Linux okay they
they become Linux people but
you know is still pretty much the same
but some of the extreme idiocy is is
like is less perceived by the uh Linux
people for example today's the Linux
people they would say uh they would go
for you know the cess you know ces.com
you know those Unix tradition extreme
idiocies okay so anyway that's about
that
copy that close close go to um Talk Show
and let's paste the link back to talk
show so let's paste the link here delete
that showing browser there it is and now
let's we can go back to whatever we were
coding okay that's a big digression but
uh so I already forgot where we were so
we were writing this okay it this can be
done in five more minutes so let's
continue so we got that uh then go to
other window then uh
then then do that and uh actually you
don't even need actually uh oh you need
okay you need then just paste okay so
let's
see okay okay then you just yank yank
okay yank means paste okay so let's go
see y y or Y P I don't know so go TOA
HTML I mean
emac uh go TOA emx
tutorial and go to emac this tutorial
and there is a section on copy and cut
and uh so in order to paste what you
have the command name to call
is yank okay yeah y just y okay so you
paste you know the um wait no not y okay
so you actually because we have this x
text here so we do insert okay so we
insert that text
then then we need to select all that
text and change the relative links back
to relative okay so so we need to call
this command but however like before
this command doesn't take
a it doesn't take a region beginning and
region end so we need to add that okay
let's add that let's add that
quickly options begin end okay so so we
got options so let
um okay let so let me just code quickly
okay
so so code quick quickly
okay that and uh that and uh okay so
then
then okay
so then that that that that that that
that okay then we need to yeah so we
need to add the same thing like
here this block of text we need to put
it here
yeah so instead of that you do that okay
so
actually what you can do let's be
creative okay set
them let me show you okay so that that
that
okay so you see let me show you so set Q
set these two variables now if if
there's no beginning and end they are
not given not defined then you call this
command which will return the beginning
and end positions of a selection if
there's a selection otherwise just the
text block beginning and end okay
but if beginning end is given then just
return a vector so that will become the
value of xp1 xp2 okay so I think that's
it and change the version date eval the
buffer go to make a backup go to the
diet byy compile it okay compile no
problem delete it okay now clod set so
now this function can take a begin and
end position let's do it so first of all
is a directory then begin and POS end
Position will be okay
point point minimum and point maximum
okay yep that I think that's it that's
our Command uh the fruit of our Command
okay is this any any questions
okay I think that's it for our Command
let's double check one last time and we
can run it one shot it will work
okay
so move html text block from one panel
to the other and change all relative
links in the text block
if there's no selection otherwise do the
selection okay so we grab the selection
of the text block okay we get the
beginning and uh positions then we set
the text to be narrow to region we call
this the default directory the current
directory point mean Point Max yeah and
uh Delete and extract and we delete them
okay
that's right okay then that is saved to
X text okay then we switch to the other
panel then we narrow to region at the
current curer position then we insert
the text then we call
this you know from the beginning and end
position so that all full file path
becomes relative links fantastic okay
let's eval the buffer okay let's so now
emac knows this command let's put it
back syntax Cate showing HTML fantastic
that's our talk show today that's our
code but now let's try
it okay so let's try it so we want
to uh let's say let's
say uh
okay so actually we have a link here
yeah the Unix resource you see we got a
link there let's split the pen split the
panel and let's go to comp let's go to
emac
block okay so showing browser this is so
this panel is emx block so
now I'm just going to call the command
so this block will be moved here will be
moved here with the correct URL but
actually in this case it doesn't work
because I mean in this case the same URL
will work for example I paste it there
uh oh okay so we can actually it doesn't
work so we can try it here okay so
now let's call the command so let's
what's the command
HTML move uh
um was it the
block what was our
name cam move HTML okay so let's do it
again cam move
HTML do
it okay run type argument integer marker
begin okay something wrong okay so
let's pop it out something is
wrong now where does that came from I
don't know
so okay now so let's call this
command toggle debug on error okay and
let's do it again so
we so we
um so this is emx block and uh let's
yeah so let's go Ahad move html text do
it okay so now we
know so the last command code is nrow to
region save restriction okay where is
this okay so local links to full path
okay that is where the error came
from so HTML local links to full
path oh okay I think we forgot to set
this that's why okay so let's go back to
our
code uh this one describe function jump
to the source
code and what
what let's try and call this command Eva
region Eva region I mean Eva so evx
knows let's just try
okay so yeah is that command is
wrong save
restriction then Nar to region okay
something is wrong there let's look at
the command
oh this this is incorrect this needs
true because if you use a vector the
values are not evaluated okay so instead
of that you need to say
Vector okay like
that
yeah okay and uh so there and
actually and actually let's transform
this so let me show you let's transform
this block
[Music]
to to this form okay set
yeah so we transform that block to this
one this is statistically better because
it in because in the outset we know we
you know we are setting a variable so we
want to set the variable XP X xp1
xp2 by either that or that okay yeah
okay delete
this okay and uh eval the buffer now of
course there's also here you need to do
here so yeah this beginning end uh wait
this beginning end needs to be a vector
okay so that it will actually evaluate
the arguments okay eval the buffer now
go back here
what is this this is emac block okay now
go back to the talk
show there okay so here is a talk show
now we call the command it should move
this block to
here with the proper relative link okay
do
it do it fantastic you see now you got
two dot dot there you see we can
actually call it a again and you'll move
back here let's try may I X I'll move
html text block do it fantastic do it
again fantastic perfect perfect for the
day that concludes
today's aures workout so how long I been
talking oh 70
minutes I suppose nobody's watching
n people wow pretty this quiet night
people okay but however we did work out
this so now let's clean up here's a code
pop it back show the pink window go
back uh syntax col hello go no showing
browser today's fruit is this code took
us one 1
hour you know usually I can code this in
about 20 minutes but you know but when
you are talking and doing live stream so
it takes
longer uh so that's good that's what I
need so because I write everything in
HTML manually so constantly I need to
move one you know one paragraph of text
to from one page to
another and uh you need to get all the
links inside fixed so now I can easily
do that you know
fantastic you know before today I would
have to manually call this to change all
the links to full path first then cut
then move then paste then change them
back to relative link but now it's one
shot plus we improved both of these
commands let's see
you know we improve the command so that
you can call them in list and give a
beginning end position now if you are
calling it manually like meta X then
this interactive section takes care of
it fantastic okay I think I I think
that's it for
today
uh that's good thank you guys bye
guys uh
of course you can buy my emac tutorial
just go
to. code.
info and uh you can buy my emac tutorial
the best tutorial let's
see where where is the link There It Is
by emx
tutorial okay and actually I need to
increase the price uh by the way not
many people buy it because everything I
have is free online why do you have to
pay because you are beautiful but but
most people don't you know and uh uh so
you can buy my emac tutorial and also
this JavaScript in depth is great so you
can down you know you buy it then uh the
link is here by JavaScript in depth so
you get the whole thing about 600 pages
so you have all JavaScript
references uh you know to support me if
you like my stuff okay that's it for
today thank you guys for
watching we shut down in 1
minute yeah
so we got this code yes okay I need to
get commit okay then we got what is this
emx blog close close this
errow our talk show that's today okay
then yeah okay bye