The power of Emacs begins now.
So, I'm going to write a Emacs Lisp code
that will add section tag.
Such as that.
To every headers, okay? So, let's begin.
So, delete those, create a Emacs Lisp
code block, and let's find a page where
there is a lot section tags. I'm going
to show you what am I going to do. The
goal.
Okay? So, let's go to Emacs. Uh okay,
Emacs block.
Showing browser.
Let's Okay, so you see there is Lisp
basics. So, let's go to Emacs tutorial.
Uh start to download.
So, let's
search find and replace find count,
okay? Meta X uh
find count. So, I want to count the
number of H2 headers, okay?
And uh
I want to I want it to be
greater than
let's say four.
Okay?
And in this directory, yes, indeed. All
HTML files. Okay, so many results. So,
do you see 7 9 14? So, let's pick one.
So, let's pick Let's uh okay, Emacs Lisp
hash table. So, there is one. So, let's
go to it. Showing browser.
Okay, so this page, there is a lot
headers, indeed. I'm going to
So, let's let's work on this page, okay?
Copy the text. Go to Xah Talk Show
today.
Go here and paste the link here.
Linkify it. This is the page we are
going to work on. Turn on highlight
current lines, okay? So, this is page we
are going to work on. Show in browser.
There is There are a lot headers, H2.
I'm going to add sections to each one of
them, okay? So, first of all, make a
backup.
Then, go to the directory. This is the
backup. Let's rename it.
Original original, okay?
Save it. Now, open that. Show in
browser. This is the original page. So,
we can do comparison. Now, let's close
this page and work on the the thing we
want to change. So, I want to change it
to
Let me show you. So, you see, this page
currently look like that.
Header, header, header. There are 17 of
them. So many.
So many.
Hash. This is Emacs Lisp hash table or
dictionary, okay? So, what I want to do
is Normally, to do this manually, I
would select this this this this
this this this, okay? Until you see,
starting from H2 until the next H2. Stop
there and add a section. Wait.
Yeah, I did. So, you see, this is the
section tag we added.
Let's jump to
um
Yeah, so you see, we can jump around. If
we shrink,
you can see
we added this section there and there.
There and there, okay? So, magnify.
So, now show in browser,
you can see with CSS, section adds this
box. So, that's what I want to do. I
want add sections to all these
uh H2 headers, okay?
So, now
of course, I can do it manually, which
is like this. Do it Go go here, go here,
add it. You know, once you add it, you
also want to remove the date. So, remove
the date.
And also there's another occurrence,
remove it, show in browser.
So that's how I want it to look like,
you know, add adding these uh boxes. So
it creates visual clarity.
More so.
Okay? Okay, but we have we we want to
write a Emacs Lisp com- command to do
it, okay? So let's do it. Let's begin.
Defun
uh
defun xah-html-add-section
tags, okay?
To all headers, okay? Documentation, all
important documentation, version,
today's date.
Add um HTML
section tags to enclose all
H3
headers.
Okay?
That's
that's the documentation, okay? Let's
begin to write it. Now for the whole
buffer, of course. So
what we're going to do is we
So um
Let's say it's uh okay, so hold so
So this is going to be about text
processing, more specifically find and
replace. So we are going to find
any H3 tags,
then before that add a section, and also
after. Okay, so find
is the main thing.
The description of the this code, what
what it's going to do.
Okay, so uh
He- hello, hello Dion.
Let's pop this out.
Uh what happened to
Okay, so we want to add a header. So
what what we going to Let's let's do
this fast, okay?
So add a
So first of all
while
search forward, we want to search for
H3. Okay, optional bound, we don't care.
We don't want to have a boundary. We
want to search until the end of a
buffer. And no error true, we don't want
it to stop error out when it cannot be
found, okay? So this returns true when
it's found. Then you want to replace it
by
Oh god, this is um
Okay, so let's go back. Let's
We want to replace it by
for example
something. So we want to replace H3 by
H3 section, okay?
So here
There it is. That's what we wanted to
replace.
And also before that, we want a end
section, okay? Let me just do it so it
makes
it makes sense later.
So for each H3, we want add a section
end and section begin.
Then
optional fixed case, yes, we don't care.
Uh what Actually we we care.
Fixed case true. Literal true.
String nil, substring nil. Okay? You can
describe function and find the details
about those parameters.
Okay? So, this is essentially what we
want.
Uh, and what else?
Okay, so we want this to be starting
with the region. Okay? So, let's just
code code it. Okay? Start with the
region. And let's evaluate it.
We want to um
add the section boxes, but where does it
begin? It begins at
the first occurrence.
Right. It begins in the first occurrence
of H3, then it ends at the last
occurrence of H3.
Well, the H3 ends here, but we actually
want the end section pack over here. So,
so is there a mechanics is there a
criteria we can determine where does the
H3 section header ends?
In general, no. Therefore, our command
needs the user to specify where it begin
and end. Okay? So, let's let's do that.
Start end, that's our parameter. Okay?
So, that that's going to going to be
region beginning and region end. Okay?
So, let's define some
parameters XP1, XP2, that's position.
Cursor positions, two cursor positions.
And
um
and
set
XP1 equals to
uh region beginning, okay?
Uh actually, that then we don't need um
Okay, let's not give a parameter. Let's
just do this, okay? XP1 set XP2
cursor position
to region end, okay?
Fantastic. Then, we narrow to region
XP1
XP2
and we then we do the while then we
inside this region
we search for that.
First of all, we need to go
to
go to char
uh point minimum. That's the beginning
of the region.
Okay, we narrow to region, so Emax
thinks that the buffer is just this
part, okay? Then, we go to uh go to char
point minimum.
Move the cursor to the beginning of the
region. Then, we start to do the search
and replace.
Now, after we done that
we need to go to um
Well, there's a you see after we do
that, we need to go to char
beginning of the buffer again.
Then
search forward for
this end section. We need to remove it
because it's redundant.
Okay, option bound
nil no error.
We actually care because it should be
there. So, if you cannot find it,
there's error.
So, we search forward. Then we uh
replace match
by empty string.
Okay?
Then we
go to char
2. max end of the buffer.
Then we
insert we want to insert
this thing. Okay? So, we insert
that. Okay? Now, prettify the code.
Prettify the code. That should be it.
That should
uh be it. Okay, so
go to char.
Okay, let's eval the buffer. Go back to
the test page.
Remove that.
Let's go to go to this Emacs hash table
showing browser. So, it looks like that.
Let's remove this uh section for now
because
remove that section. Showing browser.
Okay, there's one more.
Okay, now there is no section.
Now,
those H2 we need to change it to H3
first. Okay? And yesterday we did a live
stream writing a command to do that. So,
so for example, list matching lines H2.
You see? So, there are 17 H2 headers.
Now, we want to replace them all by H3.
So, we wrote a command yesterday. So,
let's call it cos-html
demote headers buffer. Do it.
Okay? Now, now you can see those are H3.
Now, let's this matching lines H2 zero.
Okay. Now, this matching lines
H3
we got it. So, now we refresh the
browser, you can see they become
smaller. Now, let's call the command to
add the section. So, we just wrote it.
So, insert HTML
add section tags. Do it.
Search failed section.
Okay. So, this matching lines section
did it do anything? It didn't. So,
search failed. What what What is the
problem?
Close that. Let's go to our this code.
So, search failed.
Search failed for
end of the section. So,
Why is it search failed?
Oh, because we set a region beginning
and region end.
That's That's right. Our code needs the
region beginning and region end, meaning
selection. But, we didn't do any
selection.
So, we need to do a selection.
Because without manual selection, human
aid, the computer would not know
Well, it would know when to begin, but
it would not know when the
the section end, you know, it should end
here, but the computer doesn't know it
should end here. So, that is why you
need a
uh
selection.
So, yeah, so our code still correct. We
just made a We just have a human error
where we need to begin.
Okay, so where we want to begin? So, we
want to begin
here. Market.
Okay.
Uh and then go all the way to the
bottom.
We want to stop here, okay? So, now
let's call the command.
Add section text to it.
Seems it works, okay? Fantastic. Now,
add the line break.
Now, there is some
Well, it should work. So, now refresh.
Fantastic. You can see
all the sections now have a this uh
round box around it.
That is what what I want. So, it makes
the headers somewhat more clear. And
also, it adds a syntactical unit. You
know, in the source code, you can for
example, let's search for a section. You
You can see I can press a key and we'll
highlight, you know,
this section syntax by syntax alone.
You know, without this nesting, you
wouldn't know. You know, it's very
similar to how this code is all nested.
And one of the advantage of the such
nesting syntax regularity is that you
can
you can you can you can
delete any
syntactical unit that corresponds to the
semantic unit. So, you know, in C or
JavaScript or Java
or Haskell, you cannot do it. They'll
fail.
You know, so this one of the advantage
of the nested syntax, which applies to
Emacs Lisp, any Lisp in general, and
Wolfram Language, and uh HTML, and uh
XML.
Regularity of the nested syntax, that's
one of the advantage. So, okay. So, I I
that's it. So, how does replace match
work? Okay, so that is the
you know, so in Emacs Lisp
every time you call search forward
and or
so that you know, I'm going to I'm
explaining so so every time you call
search forward or or
research forward
those commands will you know, basically
take a text or regular expression okay,
and it will save the data of the found
position, you know
and the end position
and whatever capture if you are using
regular expression into a
you know, it will save them internally
and you can access them by match data.
Okay, that that is the
match data, you know, describe function
you can see match data is a function
that retrieves all these internal data
about the last command that did any sort
of search, you know, where is the
beginning position position and a
position and so on and capture if any
and then
so any so basically every time you call
search forward you can then you can call
replace match and give a string that
will use the last match data and to
replace them. So, that's essentially
that's how it works.
Fantastic, I'm doing great. Okay, I
think that's it for today, you know,
that's 20 minutes.
Okay, so
let me think about it if there's
anything else we want to do here. So,
yeah, say let's pretty by the code, you
know, that's
um
I think that's it. So, let's pop this
back
to HTML buffer syntax color it show in
browser.
Yeah, so I think that's it. So, let's
compare, you know, let's compare
the original. So, this is the original
page. Let's shrink it a bit.
Go here, shrink twice, okay? Magnify.
So, you can see
this is the original page. This is with
the um
with the section mark. You know,
um
but, you know, you see, in this case,
there might be too many lines, but
usually it's better.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
Bye.
Yeah, that's it.
That's what I want to do, and
I need this function for my for writing
my own pages.
Okay.