hello guys good morning
well good afternoon welcome to another
episode of sock talk show okay I am
Alive so today today's topic is going to
be why emag list sucks and wait I'm
waiting for people to come out so you
might take a well yeah I'm waiting for
people to come on so let's look at my
Emacs blood
so I listed well at least I listed some
topics and some articles so I'm going to
talk about I might use to talk but
basically the topic is going to be the
main topic is going to be exact to be
why eMac this sucks and why because of
this reddit Arco okay no one is here yet
today's Saturday ok Saturday people are
doing vacations
you know the yuppies in society the
yuppies in which society you know you
work from Monday to Friday and Friday
night you go to watch movie so have
dinner you know go to bars and Saturday
and Sunday you you vacation it's a
typical
[Music]
white man's life in you know in in rich
countries in cities so do we have people
here yet hey guys so today's topic the
main topic is going to be ye Michael is
said how emag list sucks so high break
the loop
do you like Emacs list overall even
though you find quality sucking sake
okay yeah so that's what I'm that's why
I'm talking about that topic because
it's not just you know there's many
aspect for example you know if I ask you
let me see let's say if I ask you a
question
okay forget about the question but but
you see do you like so the question is
do you like eMac this overall even
though you find quality fine qualities
sake so yeah well in general I like this
I like the Lisp languages of this family
of languages because primarily because
it's functional you do functional
programming in these languages even
though it's not pure you know but in
general functional function of foreign
languages means you know you use the
function you use the language and your
coding style is primarily function and
there's nobody to stop you so in general
I like this but however the limit is
this quality sucks so bad in in many
ways in many aspects you know compared
to okay anyways yeah that's today's
topic so let's let me begin talking
about that so so anyway so today well
few days ago there is a reddit topic so
someone posted a lisp sucks and
immediately it's being voted down
however seventy-eight comments and vote
it down and you see the you know it's
somewhat censored you know you don't you
cannot see that you cannot even see the
topic unless you expand it so he says it
is Lisp which is great and it ties into
an amazing platform but as a modern
programming language it is such glaring
Watts indeed and seemingly no roadmap
yes exactly photos to be changed
exactly well said am i delusional I can
be the only one who feel feels this way
to make this post a little more
constructive what would you change it is
if you could now remember this topic
this kind of immigration sucks
they come they happens every every every
every few months though every half a
year okay but it's just that people's
you know it's been happy this kind of
post it's been happening for like 20
years at least you know okay I started
to code eMac B's you know I started to
use Emacs in 1998 and I used it I live
in Emacs every day in 1998 or 1999 98
for sure you know but I started to
called eMac miss in 2006 so since I
started to type into you Magnus you know
actually I know even though I know
before so it's for at least 20 years
people have been complaining about Emacs
list and it's it's the criticisms are
very valid
I mean it's valid back then it's a and
but however you see when you say eMac
this sucks so language X sucks you have
to
in general you its comparative
comparative to other languages you know
out there that's happening you know you
know because when you say a language X
sucks or how language X is great it
doesn't make sense to say in some
absolute sense you know because language
you know they evolved very fast you know
computer science very technology that
changes every every every year and new
languages come and go so anyway so II
maybe sucks that is true 20 years ago
and it's still true today and it in fact
it's much worse if you look at all the
other languages let me give you an
example for example PHP
okay PHP you know the language everyone
hates and it became the most popular
language in the 2000s and also
javascript also a language everyone
despises it was especially the hacker
types you know they despised PHP and
JavaScript JavaScript also became the
number one the most popular language
Deveny
how you count okay number one or number
top-five okay
if for example JavaScript which language
has the most number of libraries today
that would that is JavaScript and and
you know JavaScript hell has developed
so much you know even Microsoft you know
before you you use you know languages to
write a blog you know JavaScript is just
for web web web browsers oh you know
phone applications but but now like when
you write desktop application you also
use JavaScript because Mike it's so
popular that Microsoft created the whole
framework you know so you use you use
JavaScript to develop desktops software
[Music]
yeah and so PHP so so okay so backs back
in 2005 scheme Lisp the language also
that does not have a namespace okay
scheme lists do not have a namespace PHP
do not have a namespace eMac based on I
have a namespace of course she does not
have a namespace Nina you know when you
have a language that does not have a
namespace it's really it's as sucks
donkey ass you know language with our
namespace that's like from 1970s like C
but anyway when you know by late-2000s
PHP has namespace and scheme this has
nice namespace Emacs this still doesn't
have it so so I'm saying
comparatively eMac this really sucks so
bad in many ways like like I'm I can
start to give details you know like lots
of concrete examples it's it's just
incredible to me like that these people
you know okay so you know people
especially the hacker types they they
they disagree they anytime they see
these kind of opinions they disagree
they suppress it they Pam people
you know they been people yes if you say
you know I posted I posted one reply and
you know why I'm not ready I'm you know
I joined our Emacs you added typical you
know dreaded began in 2003 or something
2005 or something like that I never use
any of these forums I don't want to
touch it because you know when you you
want you go there it's a you know geek
fight you you you type whatever you know
they pan you you cannot you know freely
say your opinions and today the social
justice you know Rose you know so that's
the the the the the the environment
changed changed so that today it's like
a different set of things you cannot say
and still you cannot you know say too
much so I've been careful you know you
know what I'm saying okay anyway so eMac
this sucks
so I let's see okay so let me just talk
about it so someone posted this message
and I agree very much and here is what I
said you know I agree very much and it's
very hopeless and it is due to Emacs
code so
so I don't you know eMac this is not
just bad it's like a magnitude was
magnitude was
and the Richard Stallman Richard
Stallman it's he's a very problematic
today he's like he's become completely
irrelevant totally irrelevant and and
becomes a dictatorship and even becomes
a bad person in some way
so anyway I'm a little bit lost like you
know I'm I'm a little bit lost um you
know I was going to say I have like a
tons of things to say about this topic
you know but usually I have to you know
sometimes like my mind is lost like I
don't know even know where to start like
we have to focus on something but anyway
so yeah let me just you know fitness
just keep reading this one eMac this
this this thread let's start from there
so this one is posted by prominent
cocktail
you know if reddit is funny that a lot
of people just go there and create
account and post my message and delete
it and I don't know who is this Pro and
cocktail but anyway let's go back to the
thread so I got a few replies yeah so
let me just let's go through the reprise
then you know the nail have you know
I'll start to ramble about lots of
things and I have you know I in fact
over the 20 years I have written lots of
articles each one addressing a specific
detail why emag disp sucks for example
like you know I just come to my mind is
this is like too many examples you know
it's very it's also very interesting
that I almost never agree with this
these kind of people on the you know
hacker news slash dot you know such
studies like
you know today we have hacker news and
read it you know so hacker news is you
know the the forum where most
programmers you know the elite geek
hackers go to write but slash dot is
before before hacking use by the way you
are in San Jose right break the loop how
old are you like roughly 20 is 30s 40s I
mean if you are in the you know 40s or
50s then you know slash dot you see my
my followers up my followers are kind of
diverse you know they some are around my
age which is I'm 50 and some but I also
have like younger people like
20-somethings and usually they are also
spread over the world you know like this
many from this from from Japan from
Germany from China from India and you
know and some in South South Africa so
anyway yeah let's get back so let's
let's let's read this reply so this guy
says I both love your content and
appreciate that you've contributed to
the community but can't agree with this
a code project is nearly always a social
endeavor 50 however in this instance
anyone can [ __ ] this project and fix the
issues you claim so in my mind the issue
are aren't as big as used you say to
just fight for what complete idiocy I
mean this this is typically I'm like
ninety 90 percent of the reddit people
or hacker news even on Hacker News
usually it's like 90% of people are like
just complete idiot like they have no
idea what they are talking about and in
and in fact I was you know watching the
other video by that Lopez guy ty Lopez
I got this Lamborghini mimic garage you
know I bought it as a reminder not happy
I don't know if you guys are familiar
you know that guy
the Lamborghini guy ty Lopez okay so you
know Slashdot yeah okay
yeah I'm sorry my alarm clock
sorry about that my alarm clock every 30
minutes so I'm kind of like Rambo I'm
kind of lost track but let's get back so
it seems that there aren't any
not many people coming oh there's four
people now okay we are well that's good
i ramble because you know that's what
talk show is for you know I don't like
to yeah let me just go ahead and ramble
because that way actually I I can I can
get more things to say and eventually
we'll come back to the topic about eMac
B's you know I don't like to you know
when you do a video some people some
people do scripted you know you know you
write things down you prepare I don't
like that you know a video format is
it's like a conversation like when you
talk to your friends you know you you go
to a coffee shop or whatever you talk to
friends and you know topics you know
come and go you know you you talk to
people and that's that's a fun part you
know what whatever it comes to your mind
and you can learn things like you if you
go to you know meet Emacs you know Emacs
Meetup
you meet people and you talk about
things you ain't and you learn things
and so that's free conversation that's
good on the other hand of course you can
do a scripted way or on the extreme you
know there's lectures and that kind of
boring you know if you really want to be
focused you know you read a book you
know you you use someone someone you
know take a year or years to write a
book and you read the book or on the
other hand great thanks on the other
hand you know people yeah so the reading
the book is the most focused you know
you you someone you know for the author
usually takes you know several years
sometimes 10 years to write a book or a
novel and you as a reader you know you
enjoy it you read it they on the other
hand they are you know today we have
like my blogs my Emacs tutorials either
you know there are a few hundred pages
you know if you want to learn Emacs
really focused you want to be efficient
you don't want to waste time
you know things like that then you read
my new max tutorial but the thing is you
know reading you you don't you don't see
the facial expressions you don't I mean
it it's great if you really want to
concentrate like for example math
suppose you want to learn calculus first
you want to learn differential geometry
you know some advanced math you know
suppose you want to learn you know
manifold out algebraic geometry and so
on then then you read a book or you have
someone teach you a professor then you
take a course right you know you go to
see a you know professor anyway so but
that's not fun you know because well
most people when you don't watch YouTube
like right now you you know you are not
really you know I want to you know
trying to study some topic anyway of
course there are some some some are like
that but vast majority of youtube's are
not like that people just want to talk
about things okay I kind of lost where
I'm going you need Unicode Braille yeah
I just added this page okay I was going
to talk about emag leastwise sucks yeah
let's get back to that then okay let's
address these guys by the way if you are
this guy maybe you know sometimes they
they will watch my video and think I'm
insulting them not really the other
problem is is that most people they are
anonymous for this question for example
of this guy Nessa old who you know like
okay okay Nessa orb and this guy t-33 3d
this guy
Emax so mesa it's kind of getting you
know it annoys me like sometimes for
example let's say today I I replied to
this guy so I take you know 30 minutes
so me being our to write a good reply
and tomorrow pan he's gone like you know
you know he did it it's rated account so
these people you know you know that's
part of the reason I don't like this
reddit you know this old anonymous Fox
you know I what I like is you know use
if you have a pinion you say it you you
if you want to argue with someone you
said you know you are serious about it
oh you don't have to be serious but you
know you you are responsible you know
you so so with this anonymous you know I
you know this I've done before you know
I take some time to reply and next week
pan they are counted you know the
account is gone like they did it they
account DVD the account sometimes they
also wiped out whatever they posted so
it's like you just see messages replying
to ghost so you know this is really a
bad thing you know these people this
mentality of doing these kind of things
so anyway so let's let me address this I
love your content and appreciate what
you contribute okay blah blah blah but
the co projects is nearly always a
social indeed Eva so what did what what
does what does I mean a code project is
nearly always a social project what
things are not a social project and if
it is a social endeavor what are you
getting at you know what's your point
so in commercial you know software or
the Google or the Apple stuff or the
Microsoft proprietary are they not
social endeavor then he says however in
this instance anyone can focus project
where did I say I you know you have to
focus I didn't say that you have to
focus I don't know where did they get
the idea so he says however in this
instance
anyone can focus project and fix the
issues you claim anyone can why don't
you you know is you know it's like oh
yeah [ __ ] the project you know it takes
money you know how you get money to
focus so in my mind the issues are as
big as you say you know what is this guy
saying so in my mind the issue aren't as
big as you say to justify a fork first
of all I don't mean that we have to
focus I mean I never mentioned folk and
what would mean I mean so so the problem
you see the problem here we see is that
his mind said you know and my mind said
I in different faces like he's talking
about something over there I don't know
what he's talking about you know I don't
cannot see how he is addressing anything
I said and I didn't say too much because
I cannot because if I start to actually
say you know the problem about this you
know soon soon I'll get banned you know
I know because I have been in emacs
community for 20 years
I know basically the majority of the you
know Emacs developers I know them and
they know me and also the moderators I
know who are the moderators in the
beginning there is one moderator that is
basically my enemy you know I don't I
don't go through any of these online
[ __ ] you know including reddit you know
even in the beginning you know you know
it's like can stress you from groups so
you know whoever started this group you
ruin it and any opinions that you don't
like you can ban that's the beginning
it's it's the case for Emacs are are
slash Emacs on reddit its
the case on IRC Emax you know but anyway
the politics changed so that's before
you know anyway it's against a bunch of
gangsters yeah again typically white gay
white people okay I'm I'm mentioning why
people I never used that word but I
mention it today because it's
fashionable is it became fashionable by
the social justice Gann okay so yeah the
white people so in the beginning you
know so this is so this is the scan of
good people and similar for Python in
Python grooves and in probe per groups
but now it's social justice can so it's
the the context the the rules the
mentality changed slightly but anyway I
was saying you know the so the
moderators in a beginning is the guy who
was my enemy okay
he will basically any like to just like
enemy by that I mean that anything I
post even even like completely you know
mile just saying some opinions or
something you know he or just in just
Spaniard you just kick me out or
something like that and few years ago I
noticed that he is not on the moderator
list anymore however there is another
matter
moderator there which is a young guy I
do know well I do recognize the name who
is also this dislike me very much okay
at one time I saw okay you know it was a
mass this this guy it's this guy was a
massa he by the way
Sasha did a video interview of him you
can watch on Sasha's channel so you know
one day this is almost like maybe ten
years ago you know I can still find it
IRC let's not do it but anyway he you
know he's one day posted in IRC which I
found out that says you know he says he
is like make making
a cream that he's complaining that every
time he typed Emacs or some you know
Emacs questions my website always come
out first so a bunch of people on Emacs
IRC are talking about it and they based
basically say this they basically say
I'm a [ __ ] you know that's how they
did we got me and the and this guy what
Samara says he made it he says that I'm
using a like underhand tactic SEO like
you know basically he's you know they
said something to that effect you know
like claiming that I'm you I am abusing
Google's policies or something like that
that is a malicious lie okay that's a
lie poll that's a legally valid lie okay
but anyway it's on IRC so I just found
it so he made that claim but I noticed
that but but anyway a year later you
know when Sasha I interviewed him I
didn't make the connection I didn't know
that's that guy but I made a connection
later on so so I wrote a blog about Oh
sasha is interviewing this guy and this
guy is doing something and it looks
pretty good you know he also have a blog
about Emacs he has like two blocks one
block is about basically criticisms of
Emacs which he kind of he trying he
doesn't market it as much you know he
trying to tries tries to be quiet on on
but he also have another block that's
anyway that this is so few years ago I'm
not sure what's the state of his blog so
what I'm saying is that so since I wrote
that blog which is you know positive
about him so I guess now he is also
positive you know he doesn't I guess now
he doesn't look at me as bad as before
but still this I you know I regard these
all these people are [ __ ] you know
honest okay well actually that's too
strong a too strong a word
okay nuts I take that back but what I'm
saying is that you know most of these
people these hacker types I don't I
don't like them and their opinions it's
this is this is very interesting you
know I have you know their opinions all
these people you know this matter it's
in Python or Perl the opinion
I always almost always despise what kind
of opinion basically this opinion we're
in a community maybe it's a Python
community or Emax community or emag base
or parole or maybe others okay when you
are in this community let's say Python
usually they have you know certain ideas
about about you know Python programming
you know for example coding style the
idioms you know how you should format
your your code things like that things
things like that you know and those
ideas typically usually are just wrong
yeah I mean by that by that I mean they
did is just stupid ideas okay and I was
thinking you know why why is that the
case you know what why is that these
people's opinions you know you know I
just don't I don't always agree I think
you know I'll just get straight to the
you know bottom of line I think the
reason is that the true I mean that
really the reason it's just that their
opinion is just wrong simp simply put
you know vast majorities people like
ninety percent you know people online
either opinion just fury bad you know
doesn't matter
also let me mention also usually the
people who created those opinions they
are the like the elite hackers like they
are the leader of they created some
project or something okay so it's not
just it's not just a random you know
nameless people it's usually the you
know some of the hack hacker types to
create things in a community
these created these opinions for example
Kaido yeah that's a good example to use
sky dough van rossum he's like you know
he created Python so so why is that you
know so okay here's why you can see how
my opinion forms you can see why why it
is valid okay possibility I mean you are
the you know it's it's up to you to
judge okay judge for yourself
so anyway I'm giving you opinions of
guide or van rossum so he has lots of
opinions of course he he created Python
and usually typically most of the Python
opinions are from him because he created
and he as followers you know so he
created this pep thing stupid pep thing
so let's yeah so let's take him for
example so in Python community you have
these rules or what what is supposed
supposed to be the right way to do
things
so I despise them but but but why is I
am I wrong I mean he said am i
scientifically you know my opinions just
bad oh you know what's okay so he's you
know so I mean but look at this way okay
Python is just one programming language
but they are other programming languages
such as Haskell or functional
programmers okay
many functional programmers now Kaito
doesn't like functional programming so
in Python the language well you can say
it's does support function of
programming but overall the general
design it just if you if you like
functional programming just doesn't work
well in Python so in this perspective
you can see that whatever his opinions
is actually you know if you look at the
whole you know in if you look at from
the top in the whole history of computer
science you know the history of
programming industry the history of
computers I you look at the things from
the top then you try to read resolve the
situation try to answer questions so
so that what happens here is that
pythons you know guy dose opinion or
pythons ways is simply just one of the
ways of doing things okay so in sharp
contrast you know as a concrete example
the shop contract is like functional
programming where there has cow or this
okay you have another group who's
thinking whose ideas are very different
from Python so when it comes down to
many programming details like idioms
like coding style or variable name style
of formatting and trivial things I mean
but also idioms like more important
things like you know idioms they don't
they disagree so it's simply two
different you know they don't disagree
and it's not necessarily one is wrong
because many programming practices they
are not exact science
okay it's it's not like mathematics I
mean as far as approaches you know
idioms
I mean styles there is no actual one
right answer so from this point of view
you can see that you know the Python way
or whatever Python people say when
you're programming in Python is actually
not necessarily you know like this must
be this is the only way so okay so so
when I see Python okay with my own
opinions I don't agree with them you
know liking Emacs I don't I think they
are totally stupid so that's you see so
that's the conflict you you know it's
not it's not like I am incorrect Coelho
I'm stupid
no is it true that they are wrong okay
but I like to say that you know okay so
anyway that's that's how you can see
this situation happens yeah but anyway
so I kind of I'm kind of getting lost
you know I was trying to focus you know
I was you know I was I meant to talk
about why eMac this sucks but so far I'm
just like going around
and not you know addressing anything in
particular but am i doing okay Oh am i
okay so anyway okay so well let me go
through the reply then so okay this guy
says you you the prefer configuring
Emacs in JavaScript and or PHP no
absolutely not
okay so let me answer the question so by
the way back back back the loop you as
you you asked me that before as well so
do I prefer you know configuring Emacs
in JavaScript or PHP no absolutely not
I prefer a Mac B's but what then why do
I say you know that's a different
question you know why do I say Emacs
Lisp sucks that doesn't have nothing to
do with whether you if I you know do I
actually prefer to swap out the Emacs
Lisp you know like you know for Emacs
like when you create criticize a
language eMac please this sucks
okay I'm gonna talk about in which way
it sucks you know so many concrete
examples you know I have written lots of
essays about it so anyway so I think
eMac B's sucks then this person is
asking me to you would I rather prefer
JavaScript or PHP no but why do you ask
that question I mean how is that has
anything to do with anything I mean okay
II may at least I think eMac this sucks
however however I would not like Emacs
to be to use the PHP language I think
that I mean like depending what you mean
by Q I mean if you imagine today all of
a sudden by a snap of a finger we have a
system where PHP is
you know you know Emacs is is the Emacs
scripting system is PHP well I don't
know I wouldn't like it I don't like it
you know I don't want jumpin Emacs in
JavaScript or PHP because but there are
a lot of details you know what how is it
done I mean how is it done
do I do I get all for example let me ask
you this question if you know if we have
Emacs with PHP as a language do we have
all the PHP library in Emacs and in the
PHP system that you know you can also
install from external sources but anyway
PHP integrated into Emacs in a
consistent way and consistent and well
well done if that is the case yeah I
well compared to what compared the
current Emacs Lisp like like right now
Emacs version 26.1 compared to that then
maybe I would prefer PHP because you
have like hundred times more libraries
building and you have much more powerful
language even though I don't like the
PHP syntax I don't like the PHP syntax
yeah so you know similarly for
JavaScript now JavaScript syntax is kind
of was because JavaScript even though
it's it's functional in some ways it's
actually more functional language than
email is because you can define a
function you can pass the function as a
you know a function has a value you can
pass it as an argument or a function can
return our argument that's JavaScript
however JavaScript syntax is such a mess
that you anyone you know someone writes
JavaScript you cannot and you cannot
read it because the syntax is very messy
in the language semantics is also
very bad so so but if you have
JavaScript emag B's I mean it's hard to
say so exactly so the question is would
you prefer a Emacs with javascript is a
scripting language or Emacs with Emacs
Lisp that depends I mean exactly how
depend depends for example in the Emacs
site let's say what we have is Emacs
26.1 the current you know version of
eMac Emacs
so with the eMac this but on the other
side the Emacs with JavaScript okay what
you know since it doesn't exist we have
to imagine you know some some we have to
imagine it so so let's imagine then you
know so obviously if the first of all
let's imagine it's it's JavaScript
es2015 you know the the new version of
JavaScript script syntax so I let's
imagine that and let's also assume that
the the whole entire Emacs
this you know all the thinner structures
thinner structures you need for Emacs is
also there for example you have point
you know the crucial point you have
buffer you know Emacs buffer data type
you also have what about rejects you
know to wit we have we're using Emacs
this regular expression or are we using
a JavaScript regular expression in in
this case I would prefer the JavaScript
regular expression so we suppose that
and and what about libraries know for
example in email is you don't have
namespace it's it's a [ __ ] mess you
know imagine today you have a language
with our namespace so every every
library everything every library you
load the entire thing is is in one
global namespace it's everything is
global variable that is the case in
Emacs that okay that aspect by itself is
the most [ __ ] idiocy in you know you
know
anyone who would say is eMac Bisbee is a
great language language you slap them
like right away you slap me across the
face because they are talking they are
it's the pure [ __ ] just only because
eMac list does not have name space just
by that reason alone okay it's a
sufficient to to slap them so I don't
know what what these [ __ ] heads are
thinking okay so so that's just one
reason I haven't yet mentioned many
other reasons yet so I mean let's get
back to talking about the the Java
scripting eMac this case in Emacs so
JavaScript then also do we okay so
namespace so JavaScript Emacs Emacs with
JavaScript so do we assume we have a
namespace let's assume that wait let me
think about - ok JavaScript the
namespace in JavaScript is also a heavy
mess it's an entire messed up but for
this case you know for our current
situation we can assume that JavaScript
in Emacs is using the namespace
mechanism introduced in Ahmed script
2015 okay then that's good
so we have namespace okay so anyway so
all these issues and also then so if we
have this Emacs in in JavaScript then
compared to Emacs 26 - I which one would
I prefer you know that's still hard to
answer though you know because I don't I
do not really you know the JavaScript
syntax really sucks it sucks so bad
because it's it's it's a new dough it's
a syntax OOP you know in this you know
everything is like structured I mean I
don't I don't necessarily need that okay
you can have for example C C or Java sin
well Python syntax that even those are
better than JavaScript syntax so so
right now you know it comes to a point
where I have to talk about JavaScript
syntax which is which is another one our
talk you know I have to explain why it's
so bad you know it's it cannot be
explained simply but if we just want to
put it in one sentence the the problem
with JavaScript syntax is that it's too
flexible
you know actually that's not the word I
want to use because mathematically for
example mathematical syntax with the you
know fully nested bracket expression and
in matrix expression is far more
flexible than Perl in any language like
far more flexible yet it's it's you
press one button everything becomes the
nested expression like sex like this sex
okay so that's Mathematica so that's
very good email it's supreme that's
supreme so it's do you want flexible
flexibility in syntax yes we do want
that you have Mathematica okay yet it's
hundred one hundred percent regular
unlike this okay this piece like 99
percent regular the mathematical
synopsis is more flexible it's more
flexible than them perl yet is hundred
percent regular but the the JavaScript
syntax is like it's it's just a extreme
syntax OOP you know different
programming different programmers
different styles create a you know write
code that you cannot read let's suppose
everything is the same but they can you
know given let's say please let's put it
this way given a javascript source code
let's say 1,000 lines I can't you know
you give it to me I can change it to my
way of style without changing algorithm
so the program does exactly the same but
but the syntax I can change it to the my
way the way I prefer we are not even
talking about the format
King issues now formatting is you know
where you put a new line where you put
you know indentation we're not talking
about that you know we're talking about
changing syntax so so javascript is a
language the syntax is that each person
can create things in so many different
syntax you know different ways of syntax
so it's it's really bad so anyway back
to the previous topic so given that
JavaScript in Emacs versus Emacs 26 I am
still not sure I would you know switch
to JavaScript you know so that's so
that's the situation so if you are
asking you know this person is asking
you know you to you I preferred you know
so that's my answer
you know you have to you know you have
to go a bit deeper to you know see
things man get people you know think but
let me mention another thing so so Emacs
least you know so you don't have name
space right it's that's just by itself
extremely bad also you don't have
libraries you know in okay let me
mention okay so let me let me start to
beast what up the problems of eMac beast
first of all you don't have namespace
that's bad okay because what we are
doing now today like basically
everything is global variable everything
is a global variable so you can be you
can overwrite anything by mistake easily
trivially there's no okay also eMac this
doesn't have structure you know you know
that well it's related to namespace you
know in other languages you have
namespace then you have AP eyes okay
application programming interface you
know when you want to do something you
use that API if you are basically
meaning that you have a set of functions
you just call and you don't care how the
function is implemented it's a you know
suppose for your black box so I mean you
just use API for example you have API
for
dealing with money manipulating files
you have API for URL you know to fetch a
website you have API to deal with HTTP
stuff you know you have there's so many
API is but you Mac base beats there's no
API okay first of all there's no
namespace then there is no API
everything is like a mess it's it's a
mud it's a mud boy and there's no API
for URL for for example manipulating URL
you know processing URL there's no API
for processing for parsing HTML there is
no API there's no such thing you have to
dig you have to dig you have to go to
stack overflow you have to go to Emacs
quickly to see oh how to help people do
it you know in which directory it is you
know you have that library or whether
you know you have to that's that's a
situation that is not a situation in PHP
not in Java
well not okay in PHP and not in here
okay let me he said so in PHP or Python
or Perl or Ruby you don't have these
worries you know everything you know you
want HTML parser you you you you go to
the you know the repository that some
well sometimes building HTML HTML parser
is mostly building you know there's just
one library building then you use that
that library and you use the API you
know in JavaScript case it's a little
bit more complicated because you have
yeah JavaScript is the community the
ecosystem is pretty bad you know it's
pretty bad because you have NPM there's
you know 1 billion libraries out there
in some libraries are just 5 lines so 10
lines is one library when you download
one library that library downloads one
100 other libraries JavaScript let's say
ecosystem so I don't want to be you know
that's pretty bad but anyway in most
other languages PHP will be Python you
know goal and Java even Java you know
you have libraries you have namespace
then you have libraries you know many of
which the important ones are building
then you have AP is when you load a
library usually you just use the API and
it's also documented in eMac base that's
not the case you don't have the name you
don't have namespace you don't have
libraries well what you have libraries
but it's just a file it's a source code
one source code is one library that's
see that's what Emacs this concept of
library there's no namespace there's no
structure there's no API you know if you
wanted pass HTML you you know you go
search the web how people do it where
you know which which which something's
something that ER to to load you know
it's a complete mess complete [ __ ]
mess you know I can you know when you
talk about this subject you could so
back to the question you know I cannot
possibly fathom why are these idiots you
know have such an opinion that you know
it's such totally wrong 100% wrong
patency wrong no computer science
scientists okay no let me say there's no
computer scientists or anyone we can
contradict what I say ok you know I am
known as a troll in online especially in
mm but actually there's no computer beep
you double well known computer science
scientist you know contradicts me no no
okay this zero you you do not find it
you know you go online sometimes you see
you know people troll you know they did
random talk they say bad things about me
but they they are yeah almost from they
are you know always just from this bag
of idiots
there's no they asked some famous
programmers i i've known for example i
have talked to the neon wine rep you
know i have meaning the famous
max programmers or common these
programmers I fight with yeah why don't
you know the let me mention a few names
then Daniel one read the many many okay
so well should I
well since I'm doing a video actually
it's better if I just actually do
mention the names so it makes my talk
more concrete so there is also
well-known common whispered Kent Kent
Pittman okay there's also Eric he died
by the way Ken Pittman is he's got
cancer I'm not sure how he's doing now
he's pretty old he's been quiet for you
know I haven't seen him talking online
for 10 years now but anyway yeah let's
look up the by the way if you guys have
questions keep typing okay I you know it
looks like you know you know you look at
me it seems like I'm angry but that's
you know I'm just ranting I'm not like
I'm not like you know emotionally hit or
something so keep the questions coming
you know if you have questions so
comment just post it type it so I want
to get back to why eMac this sucks
you know I want to really okay so that's
that's why Emacs Marco sucks but okay
how commonly so so many people here
famous common dispersed okay guys still
I never talked to
Rodney Brook I never talked to Peter
Gabriel Richard P Gabriel I have talked
to of you know I mean I've by talked to
I mean we had had emails of several
times so he never you know said anything
bad
attacked my opinion never never even
though I'm attacking I am attacking many
of the problems of common lisp but in
those conversations mostly this is in
new scoops you know in complan lisp come
that come that land that whisp new
scoops okay look up look it up if you
don't know it's called new scoops it's
still around though that anyway I'm not
going to go look into it but anyway so
Richard Gabriel his famous program
I never exchanged email with program
Daniel Wang Reb we did exchange email a
few times
oh yeah the other guy is eric nagging
let's see
eric nagging died he is the famous the
most famous troll supposedly in the lisp
community where is my article why not
where are they not
okay the arocs nagging
it's not okay this one so this guy this
is how he looks so Eric nagging you know
yeah some people say you know he he
criticized he framed me many times and
actually that's not true he began to
frame me when in 2000 year 2000 or 2001
when when I posted my first this related
stuff you know question actually on
complan scheme I think and actually I
showed the link here you know and yeah
this one yes this one so you know he so
my point is you know he's he's a he's
very famous for a troll
you know people come in Joe troll
because he he had fights with a lot
lispers and very extreme I mean he is
actually like he he say things like you
know he wish other people dead you know
more serious than that I mean that's not
something I would say but anyway anyway
I'm just going to my ponies I'm saying
what I want to say is that he never
actually say that my opinions are bad
and except in the beginning he kind of
you know wanted to say that until but
after we exchanged several messages then
he sees my point and so he started to
withdraw you know he he doesn't you know
he never never one time you know
attacked my opinions when I criticize
beast so anyway let's let's get back to
so I was saying oh my god
I am completely lost so yeah let's get
back to so I'm back to so I was saying I
was saying oh my god I've been talking
for how long
one hour already so I was saying you
know eMac this is extremely extremely
bad no namespace no libraries
no API and also you have to okay let me
get okay let me get the point so I'm
starting to get the points so all the
way all these three are major points
concrete in major points also eMac this
is slow it's something it's I would
claim I would claim it's four times as
well five times as slow as Python and
the Python is five times as slow as
Golan okay so five times also and also
also look at all the other languages you
know you look at PHP you look at Python
you look at JavaScript and then you you
know many of these languages you know
over the past ten years
they have several generations of
compilers meaning that they are
compilers this rewritten completely
rewritten you know more than once
you know so they have a new compiler
then that compiler after a few years is
completely rewritten so you got a new
compiler you know faster and more
improved more features you know also the
language yeah especially PHP PHP
JavaScript you know an including Python
you know from Python to to Python 3
their language also had almost
completely new versions like with lots
of new features you know lots of
foundational fixes you know Emacs
doesn't email Emacs we are stuck with a
compare compare that's written almost
like 30 years ago you know with without
much change
in the language is this it's stuck so
even so from that perspective how can
anyone possibly [ __ ] say that Emacs
is alright or even you know good that
you know that's what these people are
thinking you know this these people you
know you know they are about to ban
people you know you know things like
that and also threats like this they
happen every every half a month you know
by tomorrow you know have a cookie you
you won't remember a thing you know
like next month someone with this way
the whole this this episode you know how
Emacs suck so how eMac this sucks we
will just repeat yeah that's how things
are it's it's been like that for 20
years so ok let me ask let me answer one
more question and the me so yeah so you
see other languages say improved vastly
you know the imagine you know it's not
easy to rewrite a entire compiler but
over the past 20 years that's not a
short time that's a long time
you know PHP has rewritten compilers
more than once more than one time
JavaScript has rewritten compilers more
than once besides every browser they
spend millions of dollars PD ins you
know having the programmers you know ten
thousand a month twenty twenty-five
thousand dollars a month to to to get
their JavaScript engine fast because the
browser market is highly competitive you
know they are trying to each one tries
to control you have Google Chrome you
have Firefox you have Microsoft eight
edge you know for example
so anyway JavaScript engines today you
know there are several and they are
competing fiercely but these days you
know a lot you know anyway this is not
good get into details so so they have
simpler version of compilers and in
those comparators are not easier easy to
write in fact those compared to a
JavaScript compiler
it's much more it's much more difficult
to write than the Emacs is a [ __ ]
trivial petty emag B's compiler okay so
so did you have those so we look PHP PHP
compilers has gotten written written
several times also added namespace added
a object system you know check PHP
doesn't have object open you know
object-oriented programming before you
know in the early days of year 2k and so
they added they have that now and it's
very good because I have been doing PHP
project I have studied it you know and
so you have PHP you have JavaScript you
know seven compilers and you know an
entire whole entire new language you
know yes to 0 15 you know and they are
coming out with a new version every year
now so you have es2016 you have es 2017
you have es 2018 and this year you are
going to have years 2019 you know each
each year you have new features in
Python you know as you know there are
several competitors of Python Python
moved from Python to to Python 3 you
know so that's a situation you know how
could someone possibly [ __ ] say that
emag business is doing great or is still
great I cannot understand I mean besides
you know when you say something X
language is good or bad you compare to
the whole thing others right industry
are these are these people living in a
hall or what ok let me know also mention
email is you know this I can use endless
problems I can continue on and on you
know concrete I give you concrete
problems for example I've already said
name space no API no libraries yeah in
fact not just know if he are no
structure of libraries in fact you don't
have libraries itself [ __ ] email is
if all for example if you want to pass
HTML
weightless for first of all there's no
structure so you have to find it okay
but are you going to find it it's likely
not you know you know I actually I don't
know if there's a possible HTML in eMac
B's well actually there is but because
they are browsers returning Americas for
example there's a you browser and 20
years ago you have II III W I think I
was actually I used it in year 2000 year
1999 so anyway so so suppose you want to
pass HTML okay no namespace no if he I
know libraries okay but there is code to
do that so you you just have to dig like
you you you start to you know look at
you Emacs wiki to see maybe it's as
people maybe you ask people you go to I
ah see oh you dig the you source code
you know I mean let me show you
ewww so for example like Oh
e w w describe function I'm using and
smacks by the way so so there's you you
go into let me let me magnify so you you
go into the source code magnify you go
to the bottom so it's 2,000 lines so
apparently it's gotta be more because
this is this is a browser so you so you
start to look into the structures so
okay so this is the in the directory
Lisp net okay so suppose this directory
is networking related so let's go back
to you well actually so networking I'd
remember I've looked at into the
directory before then you're not going
to find HTML parser in this directory
because even if it exists it's not in
the dotnet I think his zero HTML
so anyway so you get a you get my point
its father I mean this is just for
passing HTML what if you want to you
know I mean when you know programming if
you look at Python library there's lots
of things you know you don't
for every anything you want to do eMac
base there's no structure it's it's hard
okay so they also speed is a problem
okay I have script I'm not gonna show
you but you know I have script that
process you know five thousand you know
for example let's go to my comp lens so
my computer blog go to tired actually go
to eMac to go to each l1 directory up
now let's type find wait find em so I'm
gonna list or HTML files let's see how
many so I do find any we placed on
thousands of files every day for the
past over ten years more than ten years
so I have written script that does find
script find and replace in a Mac based
in Perl in in Python so because I do
this every day I need to do it and they
are like five times faster than you make
this you know Python and Perl they are
all five and gold and they all five
times faster so you see in this domain
sorry that info I have four thousand
files you know okay so let me show you
some so if you want to do fine
finding replacing a Mac please use use
this package this is this is my package
so find and this one and if you go to
top you can see this is my URL let's
look at in a browser you know it's on
alpha you can use it you know you can
try to you can use it so and of all
possible ways to do
and replace in emacs this is the best
way okay because I wrote it
well actually I've tried always you know
big I do find we place almost every day
on few thousand files every day for the
past 10 years I've so I've tried always
to do that in eMac in Emacs and
eventually I find this way the best well
but why with respect to what and why I'm
not going to go into details that's
another day so anyway so late let me
show you another one so Golan replace so
here's a program this is a Golan script
this is in returning goal and it's just
200 lines
184 lines and it does find envy face and
it makes a report and if you go here you
can see by the way this is on github if
you just search sorry git hub and such
folks are fine replaced so you are see a
go line version for find a go line a
python 3 version for finally paste this
one and you'll find a python a : version
full find and replace and a python
version full find and replace this one
and also a python version for find we
face rejects anyway so yeah so you know
I have written find repairs in several
languages I use them all the time so why
am i mentioning that because you know
back to back to back to the reddit so
yeah so I'm talking about yeah finally
I'm talking about the eMac list problems
so okay so this is jump to the next
okay you guys have quired any any
comments actually uh actually today I
rambled too much I kind of remember too
much you know we well anyways I mean get
get done so this guy you know he's
posting about guile Emacs and you know
he thinks that will solve the problem
you know people need he's probably a
young guy or newbie he doesn't know
about Gaia Emacs so for those of you
don't know Caillou Max is a guy Oh
the name Gaia is a name for a scheme
based implementation of it's it's
basically an implementation of scheme
okay but slightly different
so it's called Gaia now back in two
thousand twenty years ago Kyle you know
is supposed to be the scripting language
for the new operating system oh my god
it's a whole history but anyway so
Richard Stallman knows he has a vision
you know he want to create a free
software you know foundation so but you
to in order to do that you need an
operating system you need editor you
need compilers in your applications and
so on so he started to do that so one of
his first project is Emacs then the GNU
Compiler you know the GCC and a bunch of
new utilities like you know bash bomb
again shell bash you know yeah yeah can
you know UNIX tools so in his vision so
he wants to create the whole one you
know one complete operating system
people can use and it's all free free
meaning you know free software meaning
that you can you know you and share the
source code but not necessarily free
like some you have to pay like he's you
know that's the idea of free software
you have to pay you it may be free but
he was you know
he charged people for Emax like you have
to pay him he send you a copy of Emacs
so that's his vision but however he
doesn't have the operating system than
the kernel which is called guna and
heard hu Rd heard operating system okay
you know I don't think I'm doing great
here because you know usually the talk
show is supposed to be fun for people
you know fun for everyone but for today
I'm kind of you know it's just like me
rambling angrily angrily rambling angry
that's not fun for people because not
just to you guys but there are also
other people that's going to watch
because this is going you know when when
the streaming is done usually if you
wait for half an hour it's going to show
up show up on beat on YouTube as a you
know my video but anyway heard if you
don't know heard is the project that is
supposed to be like Lin ups ok Linux is
a kernel
you know the operating system so heard
is good news you know he's Richard
Stallman's you know average system but
you know this is like 30 years ago you
know when I was young in back in 1999 I
was a fan of Richard Stallman and I was
like I was really really hoping for hurt
you know with you know I you know like I
tell people like infused like a phonetic
you know like today you know many you
guys you know you tell people oh are you
using Linux which mimics are you using
you know you should be used Linux you
know so so I was a fan of Regis storm
and heard and that just never come up
you know that's a vapor where for 30
years it didn't come up in Linux came up
then richard stallman tells people you
are you shouldn't you code you should
say you know new linux you shouldn't
just go a linux because
because because because he's because
today today ok it's reasonably to say
that he is just not good you know assume
some sort of ass Richard Stallman anyway
knee how are you Chinese
I do so yeah so I was talking about eMac
lease problems and you know this you
know this lots of problem there's also
directory yeah let's mention that one
don't you know okay so in Perl let's go
to sorry pearl okay I have 1000
tutorials on 1,000 languages okay so
this is Perl and you have let's see
directory Traverse directory so in Perl
in each of the language Perl Python Ruby
or : when you know sometimes you need to
traverse or walk a directory like you
want to process files you want to visit
every file in a directory you know you
want to you know for example Find and
Replace
so you have a use your library or
function that lets you do that for
example in Perl it's this module in Pro
you call it a module find file module
you know and you use it like that okay
so that's Perl example now let's go to
Python so it's got to complain tutorials
and let's go let's open up : let's open
up Python
let's open up Ruby okay then let's go to
:
so Golan you can also walk a directory
and that is done by
this way and what you need is this you
need the library OS and echo okay the
you need the library pads file path it's
building you know it's all building in
these all these languages you know so
this is how you do it so the you know
that's it just these lines and you can
visit every file you can also filter out
files you don't want you know for
example you if you just want
HTML files or you do oh if you want a
subdirectory so you don't want
subdirectories you only want the top
level you know you can you can do it by
using you know parameters in stuff so
that's Golan and Python - lets see
Python - so here is how you do it in
Python
- and here is how you do it in Python 3
so python 2 and pattern 3 you have
different functions they are they are
slightly different why because in
pythons - python version 2 you have one
way but however it turns out it's it's
not very good so Python 3 improved it
you know so they introduced OS dot walk
in Python to its OS start path dot walk
their syntax their semantics is slightly
different the Python 3 one is better so
you see there's an improvement in Ruby
you can also do it actually I don't know
how to do it in Ruby it should be easy
but I forgot I don't have one for Ruby
so you know you have Python 3 Python 2
goal and and you have Perl you can go do
it but he email is it's it's it's it's
[ __ ] painful you know suppose I want
to go into a directory I want to walk or
directly let's go to let's go to Emacs
let's go to
so socks REE max practical Emax tutorial
then you go to practical it is then you
go down here so Elise writing scripts
then you have worked here so so here is
how you walk a directory just like the
others however there is a major problem
suppose you want to go into a directory
you want visit all files however some
subdirectories you don't want okay you
cannot do that in eMac this okay
basically you know I'm not going going
to go into details but basically you
cannot so that's another major problem I
mean this you know
so yeah that's so that's a major problem
okay so I think that's it for today so
any questions break the loop break the
loop and diarrheal helps hi Dario I
haven't seen you before I do okay so
anyway so that's pretty I think you know
I feel this is pretty bad today's Emacs
talk show so and let me show you a image
lisbug this is interesting so let me
show you the Braille VIII yeah so if you
look at this page you see this is
Braille Unicode well let's look in
Safari you see it's very interesting you
know if the Braille is for blind as you
know however there's a eMac leesburg you
see this is HTML file you can see if I
magnify magnify you see every character
is 6.66 dots can you see that oh wait a
minute
I was wrong so this is interesting so I
was mistaken you see it's just they they
do it they are using different fonts
okay so what we can do so let's do this
so let's copy that copy go to here a new
buffer paste and magnify
yeah so okay so that's interesting this
font it just it just it includes the
white dots so this is what font is is
this is sparrow pattern dots font
oh so this is actually Apple Braille so
this font is is Apple Braille but what
fun is this by the way does anyone know
how to find out what font is using in
Safari for example in brave browser I
mean in Chrome browser and right now in
brave browser which is using a Chrome
Google Chrome browser engine you can
find out what font is actually used by
going to inspect and
and here there
oh it says Apple Braille that is strange
but but so why is it in Emacs you don't
you see the white dots but you see what
I mean that's strange
okay that's it for today so is any any
questions so about the topic of email is
ye Maglis sucks I think I covered it all
the you know hold on a second let me go
back to those who actually I didn't even
you know cover much I still asked I have
lots of so the main topic so so I have
these articles you know I put it here I
was planning to maybe talk about them
because I have written about this
subject a few times and they are mean
there are many great Emacs Lisp
programmers for example all these people
I respect and all these people they have
written eMac they have written compilers
using images in Emacs so for example
this guy marriage in have a Beck he's
the author of eloquent JavaScript and
creator of ton dot J's turn Dodgers is a
JavaScript parser compiler and and he he
also wrote a JavaScript parser in Javas
in JavaScript I mean he's a emag best
coder as well but as far as I know he
has not written a compiler in him a
crisp and he is Christopher
Whalen's you know he's you know he's his
blog no program he's a very advanced
America Lisp programmer so of all the
people I know he is the number one who
who knows email is in depth of them all
that you know if I if I
you know if you force me if you force me
to name one person he is one person who
knows the emag bees the language in
depth and the most of course there are
other people who actually know a lot but
you know me you know a lot of people
they don't blog much you know they are
quiet so maybe you don't hear about them
you don't know but of all the people I
know
you know he's Christopher valence is you
know he knows him at least in depth the
the Emax fry check author you know he
also done things fear haggis bug no
Aztec no man see he is also a great
programmer you know he has written
things in closure and also he created
cider
you know cider is the Emacs IDE to
closure basically and in the recent few
years he has also being a program of the
language I forgot what's the name but
it's like a scripting language used in
by gamers Stef ammonia you know so all
these people they they many of them well
yeah all the people are listed here they
have written compilers and they are all
eMac these programmers as well so you
know if America is improved
you know then we really benefit a lot so
what so what so what is the problem the
problem is the Emacs code you know that
that is a problem because every time you
know you mentioned you know Emacs flaws
you know the Emacs code creates a
mentality this mentality that just
prevent it it's it hurts the community
it damaged the community that's why you
don't see progress you know there are so
many problems in a numerix community
the the richest stone and he is actually
a problem he's a guy who has done the
most damage to Emax community you know
we want Emacs to improve and you know of
course most of you are open-source fans
right not even what was open-source but
you are the free software foundation
fans right that's okay you know so we
okay you want that that's good I I can
accept you know I agree so we want free
software foundation we want GPL license
that's okay we can have those and we can
improve Emacs you know we can make Emacs
a lot better if we don't have the code
you know if we keep you know we fix
problems that needs to be fixed you know
if you know there's a problem about a
Mac base we fix it but why Cannot we fix
it because there's many obstacles then
we identify what other obstacles
you know then we fix that you know so if
there's a community problem we fix that
you know you you have to do that but
this this is not happening because is
one of the problem is you know I
generalize it's just a code problem
because every every people have the you
know the vision the open-source vision
done anyway it's a big problem it's a
big problem is I'm not sure I'm gonna
talk about so anyway let's go back to I
think I'm done so here is a Richard
Stallman let me just show you a few of
the things that Richard Stallman is
saying so here's a for example this is
an email from 2014 and Richard Stallman
says what is magic why is it preferable
to using VC and why is it not in Emacs
okay and here's a graph that showing the
number of lab
in email / versus the number of
libraries in emacs in GUI Maxis ALPA
summer party basically fries off you
know Melba and so this all-male public
you know they yeah they are increasing
but the flat line is alpha which is
Emacs growing Emacs library
you know nobody puts this stuff they are
big why because you know you have to
sign papers and the whole experience is
very frustrating
ok here's another email from Richard
Stallman this is shocking statement is
it really so someone says you know this
is from 2014
ok thinking of Emacs as an entire
ecosystem most of Emacs is already
maintained in the independence fee from
either Emacs Co Co alpha okay so he's
point out milpa you know the male part
you know there are thousands of
libraries you know like ten ten times
hundred times more than then whatever
the l-pod the Emacs the free software is
trying to maintain so Richard Stallman
says this is a shocking statement is it
true you know I kiss he's like you know
out of touch
and here's another 2014 and this here's
another email from 2015 and there are
more that's more recent for example
anyway so ok that's it for today thank
you guys for coming bye-bye