good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh today is August 7
2019 8 o clock p.m. San Francisco time
and today we are going to talk about
homotopy type theory the foundation of
mathematics logic proof theory and the
foundation of math now let me check if
I'm alive
good I'm alive and ok let's modify this
so people know random chat on mass
foundation true theory th e o ry & a
good morning the Neal Lang law is
haven't seen you for the past few days
so today we are going to random chat our
math foundation proof systems proof
theory and homotopy type theory ok
that's that's fantastic esoteric hey
good morning not J nsz ok not J so we're
gonna do random chat on this serious
topic math foundation proof systems
formalism lattice ISM into it into
intuition is a construct constructivism
or these isms now these are about math
foundation basically or you know or
philosophy of mathematics basically they
are foundation of math ok how do you
explain that basically it's like you
know 1 plus 1 equals 2 2 right but how
do you know you know
we have you know addition multiplication
and so on you know three divided by you
know four divided by two is two and so
on but how do you know for sure I mean
is it possible maybe you know
mathematicians two proofs right you know
they prove something they prove prove
four color theorems and so on but how
can you be sure you know maybe someday a
mathematician proved something that
shows one plus one equals two three you
know you have a you have a conflict so
is it just one plus one equals two or
three you know I mean so I mean so you
know you might think oh that's silly you
know that will never happen that you
know you cannot be sure because in a
history of math you know every you know
there are several crises you know
because just like we are talking you
know like you know all the
mathematicians believes in one thing
then some mathematician or something you
know some mathematician discovers some
other thing that totally you know
surprised shocked all the mathematicians
and you should typically often for like
hundred years or or you know two hundred
years that these mathematicians they
argued you know this is ridiculous you
are idiot you know this is this you are
pseudoscience you know they argue for
hundred years 200 years until they find
finally understand oh so you know it's
actually that is true oh you know
something like why is that true so this
happened you know in a history of math
basically throughout the history of math
so that is why we have this question
about the foundation of math or you know
philosophers they say a philosophy of
math or two mathematicians it's the
foundation basically so can we actually
you know so you have these crises in the
history of math you know for example two
thousand years ago the discovery of
irrational numbers like square root of 2
or square root of 3
and you know that's those are irrational
numbers meaning that those numbers
cannot be expressed as a fraction you
know you have you know two over three
that's a fraction one point five you
know so they describe mathematicians
discovered irrational numbers so you
have this number that cannot be
represented by a fraction but you see
today we don't think it much of it
because we understand oh yeah obviously
you know obviously some number cannot be
written as fractions but not so in you
know back in the days you know back in
the day so all the mathematicians think
you know fractions but then you know so
it's shocking so this is like 2,000
years ago
like discovered you know Pythagorean
school you know they have a philosophy
they have school and and you know so you
have this program by the way guys
comments okay post opinions just post it
I'm good I'm just going to do random
chat on and on you know foundation of
math related stuff like largest ism
formalism prove the proof theory and you
know the different schools of thought
different logics and also I want to
mention you know I'm I'm not a expert in
these subjects but you know every time I
do a video I have you know like I feel
like reserve doc this a conflict like
like I don't know the stuff you know so
do you people so why should we talk you
know why should people watch my stuff
you know but then I look at you know the
YouTube or the millions followers they
talk about drama the skimmers you know
it's tough so this is just you know
there's this so I'm just going to chat
about this subject you know math
foundation stuff I've been reading about
it but anyway so I'm learning so anyway
so you know history of math they are
several great crisis you know serious
crisis because all the mathematician
believes in one thing but it turns out
you know someone amended some other
thing that's shocking and then they try
to resolve it you know usually takes a
long time sometimes you know thousands
years sometimes a few hundred years
sometimes you know tens of years to
finally resolve or understand things so
anyway back in 2000 years ago there's a
discovery of irrational numbers okay
then for example then there is I guess
negative numbers also count you know I'm
not too sure there's a great shark of
that but anyway but then for example
then you have complex numbers you know
you have a number whose square and you
have a number how do you say that you
know complex numbers the imaginary
numbers let's see let's see again how do
i okay so so basically square root
negative 1 okay so square root of
negative 1 let me explain
yeah in case you don't know you know I
guess a lot of people know but for
example a square root of 4 so what does
it mean it means a number multiplied by
itself twice you know
n times N equals to 4 so the answer is 2
here so because 2 times 2 equals to 4 so
therefore the square root of 4 equals to
2 and for example square root of 9
equals to 3 because 3 times 3 equals to
however mask mathematicians discovered
that you know when you when you try to
manipulate solve equations you know you
you you it this this thing comes up you
know these things who love you square
root of negative 1 comes up
and that's strange because no number any
number times itself will be positive
it's impossible to have a number that
times itself equals to negative one so
this is the birth the birth of complex
numbers so you know the mathematicians
try to solve the problem and they you
know they run into this it's a great
person until until we realized okay
there's you know we we realized
basically we extended the number system
so you know for example you have
positive integers 1 2 3 4 and so on
everyone understand that's you know
that's natural from millions years ago
then you have started mathematicians
started to invent you know zero zero can
be in two places evil just means nothing
okay okay then negative numbers come
into play because when you solve
equations like you know something plus
three you know plus one equals to five
you know X plus y equals to five so egg
what is X okay how do you say this X X
first let's say X minus one does that
work X minus one equals to five no that
doesn't work
so X minus okay X minus six equals to
five you know like when you go you call
your daily life sobbing you know simple
equations then then you then you
encounter this equation X minus six
equals to five you know obviously we
know that so x equals two what wait like
I get this wrong now this is X minus six
equals to 5 so plus yeah so x equals 2
no this is wrong I cannot get the
equation right okay let me read the
comments
so Daniel Wrangler says since homotopy
is a very loose notion of equality
between maps to mathematician to
mathematical objects are said to be
homotopic if one can be continuously
deformed into the other right mapping
mapping and transformation tend to be
used interchangeably and Daniel says the
mathematical notion of mapping is an
abstraction of the process of making a
geographic map yeah yeah you getting
ahead of me but anyway so so what is
okay I'm I'm trying to some I'm trying
to give us explain the the the
historical crisis in math so one of them
is complex is well negative numbers but
I'm trying to give a equation about
negative numbers okay the easiest way to
because I'm also talking so I don't do
good so let's say negative 3 plus 2 plus
4 equals to 1 okay so in this case yeah
so we can say X plus 4 equals to 1 okay
that that is an example so when you
doing some equations you run into this X
plus 4 equals 1 so the obvious solution
is X x equals 2 negative 3 so that
notion the negative number comes into
play you know come became came to us and
you can and this is still pretty
intuitive because if you do you know if
I borrow money from you I owe you five
dollars you know that's kind of the
sense of negative numbers you know so
you have negative you know so negative
numbers then then you started complex
numbers you begin to have this square
root of negative 1 then we understand
it's complex numbers but the important
thing to note is that at the time you
know each of these crises okay let me
write it out
math crisis in history okay let's just
read like like we are going to write a
blog in real time so mass crisis in
history for example okay this okay
example discovery of irrational number
irrational numbers that is numbers that
cannot be represented by a fraction such
as square root of two and that is like
two thousand years ago then make
negative numbers when you solve equation
like such as X plus four equals to 1 you
get the notion of notion of negative
numbers
okay that's example showing browser so
example discovery of irrational numbers
then negative numbers then we have
example complex numbers discovery of
complex numbers okay
the birth of complex numbers okay and
this the square root negative one came
up because mathematicians are trying to
solve polynomial of degree three
okay and and degree four in degree 3
degree 4 degree five you know they are
trying to solve polynomial of degree
fees for examples such as X X cube cube
x you know there's third power of X
first person one equals to zero
something like that so so that is how
the complex numbers came up so remember
you know at the time people don't
understand it you know and and often
mathematicians like attack you know they
form schools they attack each other you
know they think you are a you are a
troll hectic what square root of
negative 1 you are a job then eventually
that if people understand so all these
are crises and for example another
crisis example example crisis in Ukraine
and geometry
okay the crisis in Ukraine geometry is
that you know in Euclidean geometry like
you know the triangles circles you
basically what happens that is that
there is this book code that you cried
elements ignoring Matthew a Sousa
oh I think I got the stream early today
cool
so I'm we are going through the crisis
of math but anyway the the Euclidean
geometry is that you know there is this
book elements written by you cried which
is a perfection of logic you know back
you know for like over a thousand years
and in this book basically the the the
okay let's let's you know instead of me
just like talking randomly let's look at
Wikipedia because it gives you a very
precise you cry its elements okay now
this is a book this is the kind of a
perfection of math for for over a
thousand years this is this is written
in 300 BC and up to like 1500s everyone
studied this book you cry its elements
so what's the deal about this book well
they teach theories of geometry you know
triangles how many angles are there you
know um you know the angle sums to 180
degrees and things like that and but
however it uses a strict logic you know
you know strictly based on logic you
know it began with some five axioms you
know like there exist you know things
like that
axioms for example first of all it
defines a point
which you know is just a point okay they
defines like one line can be connected
you know to two points and things like
that
let's see what what so so anyway it
start with you know some axioms which is
not proven you know it just gives you
you know these are the things we are
going to work with you know you got
point I think you got lines and you got
a few axioms then you build up entire
giant geometry you know for example what
you know when you have triangles such in
such and such then this angle must be
certain value this angle is the value of
you know the sum of the other two angles
things like that so so this is the okay
so this is actually the you cry its
elements I haven't seen this what year
is this printed version of you cried
elements oh so this is that was 1482
okay so that was 1482 printed so the
thing about this book is it's like it's
the perfection of logic you know it
tries to cover the whole geometry by
logical deductive steps you know so in
so given axioms then it proves every
theory then new theory my based on the
theorem before you know so everything is
like very solid so that's you cry its
elements that's you Qaeda and geometry
but so what what is the crisis the
crisis is that okay the crisis that in
this in this in this book there are five
axioms okay five postulates okay now
four of them are pretty obvious but
there's a fifth one that's not too
obvious okay like if you are a
mathematician you read it you know the
fifth fifth one is not too obvious so it
would be
better now it's you know you might think
okay so the axiom number five is not
necessary because maybe we can prove
axiom you know postulate number five by
using the you know axiom one two three
four so we eliminate you know one one
axiom because that would be better you
know we want a small number of axioms to
begin with you know so there's this
postulate postulant number five let me
show the wikipedia so you can read it
okay influence contents you cry met
methods criticism additions okay they
don't talk about that we can actually
just search it you cried postulate right
okay we can just find it you cry it's
postulates okay fifth postulate then
there are many website about is because
this is a huge topic in math because
it's a crisis parallel postulate that's
it let's let's go show Wikipedia so in
geometry the parallel postulate also
called Euclides fifth postulate because
it is the fifth postulate in Euclid's
elements is a okay is a distinctive
axiom in Euclidean geometry it states
that in two-dimensional geometry okay
this is what it says if a line segment
intersects two straight lines forming
two interior angles on the same side
anyway basically what what he is trying
to say is that if you have two lines
basically what he's trying to say is if
you have if you have two lines then then
three possibilities will happen two
possibilities will happen one is that
they will intersect you know when you
have two lines you know there are two
possibilities one they will intersect
two they will never never intersect when
they are parallel that's that's the
essence of the parallel postulate you
know the fifth postulate okay then you
know so so this is given like it's it
doesn't have any proof it just says it
is so you know then you prove all all
your theorems like in entire 2d geometry
theorems and 3d geometry from from these
given so this this postulate is
questionable you know you know okay so
two lines there are two possibilities
they cross each other or they don't but
so mathematicians tried to prove this
from the previous four axioms you know
with hundreds of years greatest
mathematicians they realize you know
nobody can do it you know it's just it's
just they cannot do it so eventually we
understand we realize that this
postulate is is is independent of
Ukrainian geometry that is you cannot
you cannot prove this is the case no you
know can you disprove it is the case
rather it's like you begin with a set of
axioms it's independent you in other
work in other words mathematicians
discovered that you can have a geometry
like entire geometry system such that
given two lines you know one of the
axiom is that given to that lines they
we are always intersect always okay in
other words there is no parallel lines
and in
you can order have other another
geometry such that given two lines that
we are never intersect so you see this
is like very strange you know in a
normal world we think of you know of
course two lines they will either
intersect once or they will never
intersect when they are parallel this is
you know the world we live in you know
no more no more intuition but you see
the ucae daeun elements you creates
elements it's a based on logic you know
it's not about what you think you know
what you feel it's about you have to
prove everything by logic you have to
you know go step by step then pick you
know so you know this this is part of
the you know this is kind of the oh you
can almost say the quick geometries or
engine of study of logic okay which we
in turn what we have is foundation of
math proof proof theory and latest
homotopy type theory okay type theories
and you know and category theory so
anyway so you can elements you know it's
based on logic and you got this parallel
postulate which is very strange and
mathematicians try to prove it all you
know eventually we realize that this is
actually independent I mean you you so
we realize you could have aged entire
system of geometry you know where the
fifth postulate is you know alternative
so when when when given two lines they
oh if they always cause each other that
geometry is called sweep elliptical
geometry and on the other hand if two
lines never cross each other that is
that is called hyperbolic geometry I
don't know you know I I don't know them
you know like like I said I'm no expert
in these things but you know I studied
them so I'm you know this is just talk
about them and and maybe you you know
find an interesting and study math
you know it's so anyway so you so that
is when you see when we say you cry D
and geometry today you know like you
might have heard it what what like what
you might think you you see your ID EA
and geometry
okay that's such it you might think okay
why is there you know geometry is just
geometry geometry why do you call it you
cry D and geometry it is because we
realized that there are different
geometries you know you could have a
geometry that's not you know two lines
never cross each other so that that is
why in this Euclid's elements this
system this system that that is most
intuitive to most of us you know
this geometry system we call you cry D
and geometry you know but then you have
others let's see you know so if you read
this you will see the history you know
that we Wikipedia gives you details you
know much more precise but then we can
see we found that then we have non
Euclidean geometry you know so we have
hyperbolic geometry then you have
elliptic geometry so those are
geometries that's entirely different
system so anyway so so this is a major
crisis the discovery of non-euclidean
geometry is the major crisis in
mathematics non Euclidean geometry a
major crisis in math and this happened
around 1700 so I think 1700
around 1700 and by the way the complex
number the discovery of complex numbers
that also happen around the same time so
you see the mathematicians they they
they got into this crisis because nobody
you know nobody in their same mind would
think oh two lines they will always
intersect you know nobody will think you
know things like that but
but if you go by logic you know if you
follow strictly logic you know you
realize that that is actually valid you
know you can't you cannot say it's
invalid maybe you don't see it in this
word in this video would but it is
actually logically consistent you know
it so it's an entire ward you know non
non Euclidean geometry you discovered
like nobody knew this before you know
before 1700 yeah let's see what year I
forgot what year but they say somewhere
here 1400 to 1700 no I guess no wait yes
severac oh geometry give gives us the
simplest model of elliptic geometry I
cannot watch that for sure because I
don't you know I don't really know these
subjects so well so you know because
when you actually talk about these
things you gotta be I mean the you know
if you ask you know mathematician you're
gonna be very specific you know very
specific you know you cannot just say
you know every time like in math you
almost always every term they have very
especially today they have very precise
definitions based on you know say theory
and logic very precise like you can just
like you you crys elements you know they
this is this is all foundations of math
is about everything is you know
precisely defined supposed to like
programmers you know Haskell Oh type
type theory type typed languages space
you know Oh object-oriented is the best
because this is that you know so so math
is a different world so anyway you you
know you crazy and geometry it's like a
entire new world okay you know this is a
so so very deep because it means you see
it means our universe you know for
example today when we talk about black
holes or wormholes or oh you know things
like that
or you know ten dimensions things like
that but it okay you could say all came
from math because with non Euclidean
geometry you begin to see that maybe our
universe is like just one of them they
are there other universes let's that's
very different and in fact also I don't
think we know yeah you know I think you
know mathematicians you know the Astro
cosmologists we do not know actually
exactly you know what is the shape of
our space like is it hyperbolic or
Euclidean or elliptic I think we don't
know that actually I think okay I don't
know for sure
because this is based on from what I
read there's this great book shape of
space I this is a great book I recommend
to check it out because this book talks
about the shape of space you know like
not just Euclidian anyway it's a great
book and it's written such that it's
written for non mathematicians so it's
an introduction so anyone can read it so
go buy it okay go buy from my website I
make a few bucks so anyway so this non
Euclidean geometry is the major crisis
in math okay so this is so so so so this
is why you know when we talk about the
philosophy of math or foundation of math
you know like we were talking about
before you know we were I was saying you
know one plus one equals to two but
maybe you know how do you know for sure
you know maybe one plus one equals two
three maybe some mathematician will
prove that you know then we have a
situation you know like so but you know
you might think oh that's silly
you know but actually that's not City
because all these things you know you
you see mathematicians the history of
math it happened you know it happens
then you have other I mean that's not
all then you have set theory okay
set theory is also was a shocking thing
to mathematicians then you have good oh
good O's theorem ok in company
incompleteness theorem now this so this
is like shocking you know like it
changed this they are like revolutions
in math they change the entire thought
about the entire math you know these
things happened so that is why you want
to study I mean that that is why the
foundations of math prove you know such
as logic proof systems proof theory and
homotopy type theory they become
important now homotopy type theory they
have a different kind of different
background when it's gonna let's talk
about that in a bit but anyway so this
is why the foundation of math is the
issue it's a major critical research
area you know because we want to know
just just you know just when is the
theory you know is it possible for some
theory to become invalid you know you
know someday so that's the foundation of
math that it that is why it is important
ok this so this let me take so how many
how much okay I've been talking for 35
minutes so let's read the comments so
the new says one point is that spherical
geometry give us a give us up gives us
perhaps the simplest model of he did the
elliptic geometry and it always existed
yet so no major crisis yes
no wait well then then Geneo se is not
nobody in their same mind says that well
you know that no that's a different
that's that's let me try to explain that
yeah so you are saying you know
spherical geometry basically you know
geometry on a sphere for example if you
draw a triangle on a sphere they are not
you know they are angle to not some two
hundred eighty degrees that's different
from Euclidean geometry where the sum of
triangle always sum to 180 degrees
but however however spherical geometry
is still you crazy and geometry you see
because you know it's just sweet you
know it's still cheap well you see
because back then you don't have the
idea of of 9q you cry d and geometry so
how do you know so how do i you don't
have the crisis situation you know
because like so what I'm saying is that
in retrospect okay in retrospect you can
look at vehicle geometry and you say oh
that's a model of elliptical geometry
you know that's a well the model of the
know you cry D an elliptical geometry
you can say that in retrospect but
remember that's a model that's that's
what we are talking about we are using
models you know for example hyperbolic
geometry can be modelled on let me show
you some examples hyperbolic geometry
okay so yeah so let's code here and it's
go to the hyperbolic geometry so that's
going to be here pseudo sphere now this
surface is called pseudo sphere so it's
like sphere but not you know see the
sphere very interesting this you know
you can look up on Wikipedia so you'll
get a lot of information now pseudo
sphere is a model of the hyperbolic
geometry so I remember hyperbolic job
geometry means any two lines they will
never intersect each other okay remember
we have non Euclidean geometry we have
these three types never intersect each
other so so on this surface pseudo
sphere it gives it gives a model you
know remember this is critical it's just
a model it's not this is not hyperbolic
geometry okay this this pseudo sphere
this this surface call we call pseudo
sphere which is a surface in
three-dimensional Euclidean space okay
it's not hyperbolic space it's seen you
know you cried in space that we can
model you know it gives us say like a
you know like example of visual you know
tangible model to represent hyperbolic
geometry two-dimensional hyperbolic
geometry you see that's what it is in
other in another sitting in another way
the sphere which is a which is a
three-dimensional object in Euclidian
space you know it gives us a model you
know the surface of a sphere it gives us
a model of a the non Euclidean
elliptical geometry I think okay I'm not
too sure about whether this qualify you
know yeah it's you know like it's is
just random chat okay either I'm not
expert on this subject okay Daniel they
may always have a lot of things to say
so Daniel says all raindrops begin with
roughly spherical yeah why so daniel
says why are longer - no it's not
parallel to each other who's what
geographic coordinate system okay
well I anyway yeah so you know Daniel is
talking about you know latitude and
longitude and stuff but let me continue
along with the you know the the
foundations of math stuff so so yeah so
you see there are a lot of crisis that's
why mathematicians begin to you know
really want to understand you know the
logic systems and foundations that's
very interesting okay one there are two
more crises I could kind of like explain
like the crisis you know the beginning
of set theory which is this is very
interesting okay this is also one of the
shocking thing and and Cantor the guy
who invented set theories Cantor because
this is shocking this okay so say theory
this is the beginning of comparing the
size of infinities okay now this is one
way to put it that's you know to make it
interesting I mean it is interesting by
itself you know you see when we have in
infinite you know like what we have like
infinite number of oranges over here
then we have infinite number of apples
over there and intuitively we think oh
they are just infinite you know both are
infinite so they are like the same
number of infinite maybe but not not
really because he discovered you know
you can compare they are different sizes
of infinity for example let me see let's
let's give an example let's let's say
the example okay so let me let me type
it which one is larger
a the the set of all positive integers
for example one two three one two three
and so on okay a the which one is larger
a the set of all positive integers P the
set of let's type it here the set of all
even positive integers so we so that
means two four six okay let's show in
browser so which one is larger a the set
of all positive integers integers 1 2 3
4 5 and so be the set of all even
positive integers 2 4 6 and so on
so 2 normally we would think you know
obviously this is so obvious that the
the set of all positive integers is
larger because you know because the even
positive integers you are skipping you
know you are skipping one so in a sense
the set of all positive integers is
larger than you know it has more stuff
in fact precisely like half half times
you know 2 times more number of elements
then the set of positive integers
integers I mean then the set of even
positive integers and that is wrong that
is a wrong answer
in fact we understand today you know
they they actually they are equal number
of elements right like they are their
size are the same you see but this is
tremendously shocking you know because
this is not how can you possibly how can
that possibly be true because everyone
you know every child can see that you
got more numbers in the set of all
positive integers then compare as
compared to the even positive integers
which you actually take out one element
at every step so but so Cantor he
created he created the set theory which
is which begin with like kind of like
answer to this question he gives so he
you know when I learned this like I
learned this in 1991 okay it was you
know he was really shocking you know it
was like you feel the power of the
universe
you know the mystery if you I felt you
know like it's like if you're really
into you know math and truth you you
feel something
you know shocking going on so the way he
did it is you know he you know explained
that logically you know by pure logic
logic you know he asked you okay so so
okay you have infinite things you have
lots of infinite things you want to
compare them to see which one has more
elements so one way to do it you know he
give out his reasons basically it's like
this okay so you have one set you have
another set and you want to see which
one has more number of elements so he
says one way to do it okay is that if
you can match every elements with the
element in the other set you know it's
like you have a bunch of curves here
okay you have a set of cups you know
cups like coffee cups
you know then on the other hand you have
a set of spoons
you know like spoons you know so one way
to see which said has more elements is
by if you can match one Emin with the
other pair by pair like you you put one
spoon in a cup you know you put one
scoop you know in a in a cup so this is
a pair you know it so it's match you if
you can do that for every elements in a
set the
you know these two sets have exactly the
same number of elements okay then you
know for sure even though both of them
are infinite but you know they have the
exactly the same element and in this
argument you see a every child can see
this is you know valid very valid logic
you know logical argument so so meaning
so if you can have a function that maps
one said to the other for L or elements
in the set then you must follow the
conclusion that these two sets are have
the equal number of elements so all you
have to do now is to find a function
that map's you know the positive
integers to the to the even positive
integers so can actually do that can I
do that not sure I can do that on this
I've I don't remember you know I forgot
but actually if you read yeah you know
if I'm gonna do it you know it's gonna
take ten minutes try out an arrow you
know so let's just read I'm gonna show
you a you know you can read about it's a
theory okay so let's let's find let's
try to find an article where where that
discuss this this particular issue
because I Wikipedia if you just read set
theory okay so let's go to actually
let's actually search for counterpose
count countable set okay there it is so
if you read this article you you will
see you will find a function you can
actually you know think of this as the
homework you know find a function that
maps for every element positive integers
married to every element of the even
positive
as positive integers so you can you know
if you read the counterpose set in
Wikipedia you you all know how to do
that so anyway so Cantor you know he so
this was shocking so you know and in
turn he discovered that real numbers are
not comfortable real numbers so meaning
that you know so basically he came up
with I you know the idea that infinite
sets they have kind of ordered they it's
called the ordinal of you know basically
the size like you know the I give you a
size for this Internet infinite set you
can now actually kind of compare you
know you we you know we it shows a light
that it shows us that we they are you
know different order like different
sizes of infinite infinities so anyway
that's that's that's that's the set
theory that's that's what set theory is
about so this so this was you know this
was you know it's it's a shocking you
know back then you know mathematicians
they fight each other you know some some
Cole Cantor at raw you know get him
fired you know things like that it's a
big chapter of history of math so you
can see all these are crisis in math
then then there is this guy hubert
german mathematician David Hilbert a
good morning's panel champ so guys any
comments Matthews sources anyone
comments comments so actually I dragged
down about oh my god you know I was
talking about foundation of math but it
ends up I spend 15 minutes talking about
you know the historical crisis of
mathematics
which you know justifies the the valid
you know why the foundation study of the
foundation of math is critical is
important I mean why you know it's not
just oh it's just philosophy you know
philosophy you know thinking about
useless things it's not that because all
these crises but we haven't got into you
know what what I wanted to talk
originally was formalism narcissism and
into intuition ISM which is kind of also
became constructivism okay so so again
anyway yeah so we are going we are
getting onto that so david hilbert you
know he's one of the great greatest
mathematician you know maybe top ten or
something in history so he he started a
school of thought you know back you know
he's he was born in 1862 so you can see
this is the era where all these crisis
happened now he's a contemporary
contemporary of Cantor Georg Cantor
Georg Cantor okay let's let's look up
his name yeah Georg Cantor he is also
German mathematician sure German are
usually great at math German Russia and
anyways you know this is about great
mathematicians so anyway he's also a
German guy so he's he was born 1845 okay
David Hilbert was from 1862 yeah so they
are contemporaries you know they didn't
know each other but so David Hilbert so
with all these crises
you know David Hilbert started to have
a program you know he you know that they
you know basically they want to codify
all math so they you know mathematicians
Begins wants to desire you know they
desire like a system or you can think of
it like a programming language you know
they want a system so that so that
mathematicians can prove that this
system is consistent and then then every
mathematics will be based on this system
so you know we want a solid foundation
so you know we can start to grow math
without all these crises you know every
once in a while with a major crisis you
know comes in you know the crisis are
critical because they they they seems to
collapse your entire math because what
you think is true is no longer true that
that is the thing because you think oh
this is why this is black then some
mathematicians discover something then
you're white and black is no longer you
you know your entire lives you know
experience is shattered you know you is
that is what you know why crises are
quick you know become that crisis so
they so David Hilbert you know began he
well basically he began a school of
formalism then Bertrand Russell began
the school of largest ISM they are
different schools of thought different
kind of school of thought they all want
to have a solid foundation of math but
Ron Rosso is kind of my favorite author
you know in the 1990s I read most of his
books you know he's he's a logician and
you know I I I follow him a lot I read
like almost all his stuff his
biographies and stuff so Bertrand
Russell
you know he you know he's a he's a
leader or proponent of the logic school
so largely systems
of thought is that okay so the logic
school is that they think that math the
entirety of math can be reduced to logic
you know like if this is so and that is
so therefore you know you know reduce to
logic the formalist school formalism
they are belief you know the David
Hilbert his belief is that the math math
is nothing but just symbol manipulation
you know like you know when you do high
school algebra you have X plus you know
x squared equals to five you know you
can add you know a quantity to both side
you can minus something both side or
divide both side by anything not zero
you know then then you can solve the
equation you know that's manipulation of
symbols so so David Hilbert he his idea
of math he believes in formalism formal
formality that's the same word the same
route of word okay formal formality form
you know you know we have the phrase for
main function
so David help but he believes in form
from formal formalism form formality
meaning that he believed math is is is
simply manipulation of symbols nothing
else it does not necessarily have a
meaning so you are given a bunch of
strings like formal language okay so
much of computer science today formal
language is a foundation of computers
theoretical computer science you know
forget about tuning machines lambda
calculus actually member calculus is is
a branch of formal language theory not
not tuning machine sided neuron not not
not exactly but anyway formal language
which which is a subject I love which is
you know last week I did a video on
what's the meaning of symbols in your
programming language like Lisp and
Mathematica
check that out because that is symbolic
math algebra and and that you have
pattern matching you have symbolic
pattern matching and and which ties to
regular expressions and grammar and
context-free grammar you know passing
compilers and stuff so the theory aspect
of them are all formal languages formal
language so this is critical ok so read
it up formal language ok this is one of
the foundation of theoretical computer
science formal language this this is the
school I like ok this is my school of
thought everything else is garbage
so anyway formal languages so yeah so
these are related formalism for more
reason you know formal formality for
formal languages the essence of their
meaning is that it's just like pure
symbols you just have seen sequence of
symbols like string you know everything
is just a string then you have a bunch
of rules to manipulate it so it's just
like it's just the form you know so
that's that's David Hilbert's idea you
know his philosophy he believes math oh
math is can be reduced to formalism it's
just you just you know begin with a
string then you have some rules how to
transform the stream and that is a
system then you can give interpretation
you know then oh this means you know you
know particular theory you know some
some fearing math oh this is some theory
in differential equations in fundamental
theorem of calculus you know that that's
that's just interpretation you know but
he believes everything came you know the
whole math is just the symbols in
manipulation and on the other hand
Bertrand Russell believes if you know
math is just logic you know you can
reduce it the whole thing to logic
there's another school I don't like very
much back then okay into us into your
intuition ISM okay that's started by
this JW poor guy very strange you know
into it into a nism intuition ISM okay
and today a branch of it is called
constructivism okay so this is started
by into it intuition
nissim is started by let's find the
guy's name where is it
infinity history okay so the several
guys you know usually they are not
started by one single guy usually it's
like several influences influences okay
this guy l ej prove prove awesome you
know so he was born in 1881 and touch
okay he's Dutch anyway so he is kind of
like the founder of intuition ISM which
is very strange and you know I didn't
like it I didn't like it back then but
this at rest
I like it now because this is why so
math is so interesting okay okay so am I
making sense guys type something except
Daniels Daniel kept typing well yeah
about you know that anyway so it's about
something anyway I want to finish the
you know I want to finish the talk about
you know so many interesting things
about foundational math okay you know
philosophy of math so anyway poopoo
Bruford
he created into asian ism you can
about what it is exactly but basically
it's like they refuse
it's very strange okay you know if you
encounter it for the first time they
they refuse the thought that any
everything is either or not okay for
example for example one plus one equals
to two okay
is that true Yemi that's a proposition
let's say 1 plus 1 equals 2 equals to 2
okay you can say whether it's true or
whether it's false you know it's either
true or false it's very simple true or
false
but intuition ISM doesn't believe that
they it's not just true or false there's
something else ok you know this is a
dramatic way to put it it's called
excluded middle ok let's look up
Wikipedia I'm pretty sure this article
yes law of excluded middle so in logic
the law of excluded middle states that
for any proposition either that
proposition is true or its negation is
true okay yeah so the law of excluded
excluded middle so if I say something
either it's true or its false you know
there's no like I mean what else could
it be you know it's so simple this is
called law of excluded middle now the
problem is you see if you are a into
intuitionist
you don't believe this law of excluded
middle ok you see so there is a section
largest is largest versus intuitionists
so let's read it ok so in late 1800s
through the 1930s
Peter persistent debate raged between
Hubert
his followers versus him and whale and
Ellijay brewer Brewers philosophy called
intuition ISM started in earnest with
Leopold Kronecker in late 18-hundreds
ok anyway that's some details about
their fight you know it's a war it's a
it's a big war between mathematicians
but anyway it's a largest you know
largest you know largest school of
thought versus the into intuitionist and
one of the big point is the the law of
excluded middle because in intuitionists
they don't believe that they don't
believe you know if you prove it's not
true then it's false if you prove it's
false then therefore it must be true it
don't believe such a thing and to me
that's just like why I learnt this why
when I read about this in 1990s you know
in from books they don't have Wikipedia
back then I think it's stupid you know
but now I see much point in that this so
this is why you know I'm doing this talk
show because these many interesting
things a good morning just just in hey
say hi to Canada hi to Vancouver okay
I'm actually I've been talking for like
one hour and six minutes I'm about to
and we should because I've been talking
too long so I've been talking about so
let's do a quick summary so we've been
talking about for the past one hour
about the various crisis in in a history
of math then we talked about that
because we want to justify why are we
studying the foundation of math I mean
why do mathematicians find this critical
so this is a critical because all these
crises and then we begin to talk about
the three major school of thought of the
foundation of math so the three schools
of
formulism david hilbert yeah formalism
of david hilbert and largest ism led by
bertrand russell and the intuition is
i'm led by the by the brewer guy you
know by in the pour le by this Ellijay
brewer guy and we kind of gave kind of
some kind of you know summary of what
they are about formalism is about
everything is just symbol manipulation
lattice ism is the belief that the whole
math can be reduced to logic you know
and the intuition ism they believed they
believed kind of they actually you know
they believed the law of exclude the
middle is force you know it's not cannot
be used to prove math basically they
believed construction nativism
constructive i think that's the word
okay constructivism now that word has
much meanings in outside of math but but
that's not what we are interested we you
know because in philosophy you have all
these many of them questionable things
but okay so let's try to find a
constructivism math okay here
so intuition ism i mean by the way i
want also to add you know let me repeat
again i'm not i'm not a expert in these
subjects so if you are interested you
know go with wikipedia if you are a
mathematician you know professor
professional mathematician logician feel
feel free to you know come and correct
but only if you know not programmers you
know if you are just like me you know
programmers you have opinions
they may not be correct okay because so
I want to also to mention these ideas
formalism logic system they are
I mean I'm simplifying them also but
also they are very precise and very
detailed you know they are they are not
like something you can just pick up and
in one hour they you have to to
understand all these in full detail you
have to basically like equivalent to a
PhD degree okay so anyway so you know
yaakov go read Wikipedia which is
actually you trustworthy on these
subjects
now constructivist I mean now one one
the main part of in intuition ISM the
school of thought is that they believe
in constructive mathematics simply put
that means they if you want to prove for
example of something exists or something
doesn't exist you know for example some
number with certain properties exist or
doesn't exist
the constructivism you know the school
of thought is believes that you you
actually have to build it I mean like
show the number something you know kind
of like that like programming okay this
is why the into a in intuition ISM and
constructivism are so much relevant
today because you know today especially
you know a man has car camp programmers
they they like to talk about you know
category theory and you know many math
dragons and how they relate to prove you
know the there's something something I
so means I saw morphism you know
Justine probably knows that you know a
lot more than me because I think Justin
is a Haskell code right so so there is
this you know popular Hart phrase you
know Howard Curie I
so movies and you know bantered around
by Haskell coders often how would curvy
Howard isomorphism okay so let's sit
let's look at that up now curry Howard
correspondence okay essentially it means
that it's a theory such that any
computer program you know algorithm step
by step instruction is can be translated
to a a proof and any proof can math you
know any math proof can be also
translated to a two computer programs
that's kind of the gist and you know
kind of of this is about so it's very
popular among you know Haskell
communities okay so just in says I'm a
scholar scholar in Haskell code learning
about category theory okay so yeah so
I'm yeah I mean learning about these
things too so so what are we saying so
yeah the intuition you know they believe
in constructive math that is they
believe in you cannot prove something
exists or doesn't exist by any way they
believe one of the big thing is that
they believe in E in actual building
something then you can say it exists
okay they don't like to talk about this
usually okay something like that the
intuition ISM does these people they
don't they don't believing anything
dealing with infinity okay when you deal
with something infinity they don't you
know they don't like it they don't
believe it they believe you know if you
want to talk about something like in in
a realm of infinity okay you have to
actually build it like like show me show
me you know okay I found this number
with
such a property then you say it exists
you cannot say you cannot arrive at
something exists so does doesn't exist
by the argument of contradiction you
know which is a conventional proof you
know method of proof in math they they
can prove something by contradiction
meaning that we begin with this
assumption then we use logic step by
step we show we arrive at a at a
conclusion that is absurd
you know conflict with itself then you
say then you know the traditional
mathematicians say okay then the
assumption is wrong okay that you know
something exists is wrong therefore
something does not exist you know this
is the proof by contradiction okay yeah
let's look up proved by contradict
contradiction we want such we don't want
dictionary okay yeah so there's a
Wikipedia article on that prove by
contradiction now this this is accepted
by majority of mathematicians but
however if you are a intuitionist you
know if you are the constructing
constructivism school of people you
don't you don't believe in that when
when when a mathematician shows the
proof you know and using the method the
method of proof by contradiction you you
as far as you are concerned you don't
believe it you know that's not proof
that's not you know that's improvement
so that's the school of the intuition
ISM people's that's very interesting
because today so you see so I find this
very interesting because today you know
we have been trying to because since the
computer age you know since 1940s we
have computers then we have you know
digital computers CPU you know we
started to and we research into
artificial intelligence
and we started to research into
automated proof systems you know imagine
how fantastic it is you know like we can
write programs write you know programs
you know so you know programs are so
logical because computer that doesn't
make errors you know so why don't we
write a program so that it can just
prove everything you know we can and let
it run by itself you know it just prove
everything you know proof it will
automatically find a theory of
relativity you know and you
automatically find whatever you know
theories we don't know yet that's that
would be fantastic
so this score is called automated prove
the automate automated prove did I spell
wrong PRF okay yeah this this field is
called automated theorem proving you
know this this is like a great fantastic
goal if we can actually find a way to do
that you know we you know we have
computers just let it run
you know you'll prove everything so this
is part of the research into the
foundation of math you know including
all these different schools and today we
know that you know I've been looking
into this because I'm so interested you
know as a programmer you think oh yeah
this is great you know automated prove
theorems we have you know Google
tetrapod of data we just you know chunk
you know the run run them in parallel
then we will find everything it's not
like that first of all there are so many
issues organist that this fantasy
because first of all you have you have
things like you have things like
theories in or cellular automata you
know how do you say that you know
meaning that if you know like
monistic I mean even if the whole entire
world is deterministic by by a rule by a
simple rule however you can still not
predict the future you know even though
everything is deterministic like you
know philosophers talk about freewheel
like how do you how do you know you have
freewheel you know and then some argue
you actually don't have freewheel
because if you know the universe physics
atoms they they work according to
certain rules you know physics therefore
free wheel is impossible because you are
actually just some mechanisms you know
you are just you think of this way or
that way because the wheels you know the
wheels in your brain big you know
they rotate this way that way therefore
you are therefore I am talking about
this right now you know like everything
is determined you know there's you but
it turns out you know the if even if the
universe is deterministic you cannot
predict predict what will happen in the
future because because essentially you
have to run the computation that like if
you I'm not sure there's I think there's
a name to this what I'm talking about
right now anyone knows but I'm not sure
what is the name but anyway if you study
if you read into cellular automata you
might find that you know like a term
that describes a situation where where
even if the universe is deterministic is
not predictable or you can maybe see an
article of determinism in Wikipedia you
might find it you can also look up
freewheel you know they have articles
like that anyway so back to the so so
there are many obstacles to the you know
the automated here improving
proving everything because first of all
so yeah even if you found a system where
you can just run programs to keep it
running you will find all theories in
the universe even if that is true and
even if you have you know you know you
have a computer system that's 10 billion
times then today then you can still not
find you know new theorems because
because possibly possibly because you
have to compute for a billion years
you see that's one of the obstacle even
you if you have the automated computer
system it might be you know you may take
you 1 million 1 billion years to find to
find the theorem because you know I mean
regardless how powerful is your computer
you can assume it's you know billion or
ten billion or gazillion billion times
more powerful it's I mean you see all
these are related you still have like a
billion years to compute it so that's
one obstacle then there are other
obstacles like when we study into the
foundation of math you know these logics
you know you realize like as a
programmer okay I started to you know I
studied them I read them I realize it's
not so simple you started to see okay so
logics so there's this this model this
system you know logic system just like
the Ukrainian geometry you know you you
you gradient geometry know you cried you
know hyperbolic or elliptic there are
different systems so you study logic you
realize that okay there's this logic
system then this you know first order
logic then there's a second order logic
you know they have pros and cons then
you have other things like motor logic
then then type theory you know the you
you kind of like this bunch of things
and it's not like one is better than the
other
it's like pros and cons you know it's
like programming languages you know you
think oh this one programming language
that's also open turns out you know it's
just this bunch of logic systems in yeah
so it gets very deep and
complex so you end up so you know like
I'm thinking oh if I just study logic
then they all know you know the solid
foundation of math so it's not like that
so there are different schools of math
each who have sub schools you know they
differ you just likes philosophy then
logic you know logic there are different
types the each has pros and cons so it's
not like one soft so then you have got
their own incompleteness theorem okay
that's that's another thing we haven't
talked about yeah so you know so it's a
very interesting ok I think that's kind
of that's that covered what I wanted to
cover basically you know I
so we covered crisis of math in history
the importance of foundation of math the
different schools of philosophy of
mathematics and today's situation where
we have you know we we try to have proof
systems you know automated proofs theory
and programming languages like Haskell
is kind of what Haskell you know it
should be said you know Haskell is not
actually it doesn't have anything to do
with proofs really is it rather is just
a pure functional programming which
which are heavily associated with these
things we are talking about you know so
there are several languages like this
one called that is a programming
language to do proof and many has cars
you know familiar with you know heard of
you know it's kind of a frequently
mentioned together with Haskell and
there are several others there's also
you know there are several others you
can find them on you know if you keep
clicking on Wikipedia you find them yeah
that's that's basically okay okay yeah
that's what I want to talk about today
18 minutes yeah that's
I think I'm gonna stop its read comments
so let's have some chat random chats so
say hi so come by and say hi in the sea
so Dania was saying okay let me magnify
the window and
so Daniel was talking about the geometry
on the sphere okay no 93 Panaji
okay I think Dan you know is disagreeing
with my characterization of spherical
geometry okay okay yeah maybe you are
right you know so Dino says on a
different subject the no say is Cantor's
incredible proof I once saw a refutation
of Candace diagonal argument on a blog
post some crackpot yeah they are a lot
you know math math you know in the field
of math is quite different from
programming you know in programming
anyone can say anything you know that's
why you have programming
flame wars you know foreign language
frame was you know like oh oh he is the
best overall functional programming or
or some new you know paradigms like
agile you know had your so but but
in math you don't have things like that
math everything is like almost
everything is you know well defined and
but however they are also crackpots in
math but they are not like programmers
you know they are kind of different
crackpots yeah there's quite a few you
say okay so so let me clarify so what's
the difference of a crackpot in
programming community and in math ok
here the here's the difference if you
are a crackpot you know you you cook up
some idiotic pseudo scientific
pseudo science idea and in in the
programming community you can become a
hero like for example I would say a few
people I'd rather you know probably it's
better not to mention name okay yeah you
will become a hero
like a leader of some big with giant
corporation and with you know millions
of programmer follow us you know they
think let me just say for example Opie
oh oh he is the greatest thing you know
oh we will solve everything
this happened in programming community
and pro you know / laziness you know
pearl you know it's supposed to you know
this order had more than one way to do
it that those are crackpots and for
several years they've being right
rampant in a programming industry like
every programmer believe it that's some
of the example then there's lots of tons
of examples like no sq our own osq how
is the best thing because SQL has these
problems then today it seems that the
days of no SQL is good you know and you
know so it's very common
this happens in programming community so
what I'm my point is if you are you know
you can be a crackpot but in programming
community you can be you can become a
leader like a hero like you know for
Idol you know for tens of years but I
mean for for for like 10 years or 5 or
so but not so with math now in math
there are also crackpots but typically
this you know these people they don't
they don't get big ok they will not
become an idol by fire you know a lot of
mathematicians not really they don't get
big and every mathematician who actually
studied you know the math you know no
nose can tell they so the crackpots in
math they only fool the mathematicians
you know like outsiders yeah they are
such people like there are people are
saying that there are such people you
know they they have a great number of
followers non mathematicians he himself
you know he say you know I'm the
greatest mathematician you know one
person one goes to five because you know
and I have a lot of followers but they
are not mathematicians did you know so
that's a difference a crack party in
programming you can become an idol hero
and with with you know friends you know
the funds we all you know come to you
but for the mathematic
shankrappa that you that does not happen
okay usually that's not the case your
followers you know if any it's not
mathematicians okay so I have a lot
comments a Dewey's okay so let me yeah
they said I've been talking for 90
minutes let me finish me the comments
quick so they know you got a lot of
things to say like I got okay so so I'm
gonna you know I gotta skip some
comments sorry because I gotta go I'm
gonna get off Daniel says Brewers
intuition intuition ISM is a bit nuts
brewer quite clearly thinks that
classical mathematics is false so see it
hegemony said so she says one problem I
have seen in many programmers is that
they believe certain difficult topics in
math are actually quite easy off for
example you know like programmers and
mathematicians they are typically
separate communities you know they you
know they are not yeah of course you
know there are programmers there are a
lot mathematicians who are programmers
in vice-versa but in general they are
just like two separate communities
it's like gamers ok gamers and
programmers you know cameras is its own
community you know you a bunch of gamers
playing you know overwatch you know
playing in for tonight whatever is today
minecraft they have slash you know love
me they do means they do you know they
love that gamers and programmers that's
a different community but however they
are quite a lot you know programmers who
are also game us you know but in general
they are the odd you know they are
different their mindset
you know they are just different same
thing with mathematicians and
programmers you know program usually the
programmers they I don't you know they
idolize mathematician usually like they
they all math but in general programmers
they don't know nothing like like they
don't have the basic undergrad like for
example you know sorry for saying is
adjusting okay all those haskell
programmers you know the haskell
programmers they talk about old-time
theory Oh theory or category theory
theory you know improve oh I so you know
curry
Howard isomorphism you know but then you
look at them you ask them what's a good
theory they don't know what is a group
they don't know what is a group like the
fundamental building block of method
they don't know most of them are like
that you know the some of the you know
today younger generation they talk about
Haskell all day Oh theory because oh you
know referential transparency because
this is therefore you know the this that
that math then they don't know what is a
group what the that's why I don't
like you know yeah well you know because
you know that's why I don't like the I
usually you know attack those you know I
don't like pop you know whatever is
popular hey Jaden Jaden Sarah's so let
me see
homotopy type theory yeah I want to oh
my god today I actually I wanted to show
you some links and some and it turns out
you know I didn't cover them you know I
by the way Jung this guy Jung bass he's
a great mathematician okay he taught me
many math over the past five years you
know he he's a math Prager okay he well
professionally he is now a quantum
physicist okay
he that's his research area right now
you know country but but he he's also a
math Prager you know he talked about
math like educational not just you know
there are a lot occasional math out
there like typically they're like
community building you know funny funny
mobius strip they show you how to you
know create a mobius to it you know
those are those are fun but though they
have no depth this guy john-carlos space
he when he talked about math he talked
about depth you know well typically you
have to have a undergraduate you know
just undergraduate math degree to to get
it you know what that is actually true
but anyway so so you know so i enjoy a
lot of his you know you can learn from
it but even if you don't have a math
degree you can follow him because you
have to start somewhere you know just
just meet just read one and whatever
then if it's you know you know if it's
far ahead of you think then don't you
know ignore it you know it's you have to
start somewhere so anyway he is say so
he's a quantum physicist you know he and
he has there are several his sweet
videos on youtube you can find just
search his name John pace okay and he's
also a big fan of category theory you
know he's a
category theorists and he has websites
anyway so I highly recommended you know
you follow him he's on Twitter
yes but so there's this homotopy type
theory okay so that's another topic I'm
trying to learn this this is something
I've been really interested this is a
kind of a new foundation you know one of
the approach one of the school of
thought for the foundation of math and
this foundation this school of thought
is amenable to programming you know so
if you are Haskell coder you would be
interested in this highly because this
way of treating mass can be codified
into programming languages you know and
so so this this book is free on a web
but it's hard to read I try to read it
you know it's how to read so you have
table of contents you know type theory
versus v theory you know it's how to
read and its invented by this guy vadoma
vadoma kovarsky russian he died like two
years ago
and you know here is one of his alko
it's you know it's great way to read how
I became interested in foundations of
math so he tells you his journey and
he's by the way he say he also won
awards in math by the way this is
something I want to say to any of you
programmers you know if you really want
to learn math you know you cannot just
okay let me say you know let me say to
ask ask our fans you know kind of like
you know the pup has comments if you
really want to get into math you cannot
just say oh I'm just going to stick to
category theory you know it's not like
just like that you have to learn you
know you have to learn you know
basics of logic the the basics of you
know goob theories almost fundamental
for example you know this guy who
created the foundation you know this
homotopy type theory this is new by the
way so this is actually cutting age you
know in in a math proofs community this
is kind of cutting age only began in
that last ten years and it's created by
him and he you know so like John Hayes
told me actually you know you see so he
wrote this article how I became
interested in a foundation of math you
read it you see the history it's
fantastic ok you know it's not in the
nose and by the way this article also
was shown to me by based on am i
frozen ok so looks like ok so this
article am I still talking ok so this
all about was shown to me by base and
John Bay is also said you know he told
me here that you know venomoth Podolski
was better at math than most of us okay
he's being polite he is one of the great
mathematician okay base you know he says
okay vadoma is was better than math they
most of us and he has spent years
mastering homotopy theory before
inventing homotopy type theory okay so
this is critical so it's not like you
know he just invented homotopy type
theory he's he studied years in homotopy
theory which is very interesting
homotopy theory is a you know that's
it's part of the topology very abstract
and and difficult you know so anyway so
what I'm pointing is that you know if
you are program you you know don't don't
try to you know don't think you're gonna
cut corners you know I'm just going to
the graph theory and I don't know Methos
it's not like that okay if you so what
so Sid says creeper so we back in the
mine kappa oh man what are you guys
talking about
okay we got a TRO I guess this Luiz
Sara's guy I don't know what he's
oh that's a book by John bass yes yeah
yeah so I think that's it for today so
thank you guys for coming
yeah that's it for today 100 minutes
okay so thank you guys bye