welcome to another episode of star talk
show today we are going to do e-max
lease coding fantastic emac this this
coding and so we are going to write a
function a command actually i already
wrote it but i'm going to do some
alternative algorithm so we are going to
write the emax command that inserts
random characters okay
so
let me let me
show you okay so open a new buffer
on the pink window you can see all my
keystrokes and command cores you can see
the function name uh hold on a second
so let's turn on highlight the current
line so you can see where my line cursor
is so you can see all the function names
and
all the
keystrokes i type and uh i'm using a
kinesis advantage keyboard right here
and this is ultimate hacking keyboard
you can go to my website and see the
review okay sorry keyboard
kinesis okay for example
so you can see
kinesis freestyle keyboard this is a
good one i recommend and ergonomic
keyboards and you can see my reviews of
my keyboards and ultimate hacking here
okay so that's about keyboard so let's
so so so let's show let's show okay so
for example something okay so i want to
insert a random
string okay
do it you see there it is okay
do it another random string do it so the
command i'm calling is
this one okay
insert random string and here's a code
oh actually you can see the code so
let's go to the source code and here is
the url and open the url and show in
browser so you can grab the code there
okay so we have several uh commands to
insert random number you can insert a
random number let me let me show you
okay
so go to cassas talk show today
talk show today and let's paste in the
link okay
so you can later you can go to the
website so um so let me show you the
several different
ones okay
insert a random number insert a random
number three digits okay if you want
more than three digits you can
say control u
then
call the command oh that doesn't support
control u
wait
does it no it doesn't
uh it used to uh so
so so anyway so that's the command okay
so let's go to the source code again so
let's see where is the source code okay
so
insert random string
so insert random number okay it no
longer takes a
uh
you know arbitrary allows you to insert
yeah okay the dc the this is about
design okay so we are writing a command
that insert random
number of digits and
usually in emacs you can
write the command such that control u
then call the command then your
you'll provide alternative alternative
parameters like how many characters how
many digits you want to insert but in my
case i removed that because i thought
you know just call it again every time
you add the three number three random
numbers okay so that's the insert random
number then insert random
uh
kind of string kind of
then you can also have
insert random hexa hexadecimal okay so
here is a hexadecimal chord again
do it again
okay because i insert random hex
okay
do it again
and
and do it again
do it again
do it again random hexadecimal you can
see there is no this is
0 to 9 and a 2f that's hexadecimal
okay so we are going to write the
command so we are going to
[Music]
uh so that's hexadecimal so you you have
insert random numbers you have
insert random hexadecimals
then you have insert random string
you know so then you started to see q
and w and capital y
and in this command let's see control u
and do it again
oh it doesn't support the universe i i
think i removed it anyway so different
insert different
random digits or strings this is useful
for example when you are in html you
know in in programming often you want to
insert like for i
id purposes like a random
id for a tag or for uh and also by the
way you also have insert random uuid
okay
uuid so insert random uuid uuid is this
huge um
thing you know you can look it up
wikipedia uuid that's a uni basically
universal random string something like
that
supposedly you know the possibilities
there are more than the number of atoms
in the universe it is true a lot more
than that so
supposedly
for any
function for example you know especially
microsoft use this often you know if you
are using microsoft you go to your home
directory you can see
you know some files named like that
microsoft use this uuid often and also
in a game second life the virtual
reality
am i doing good say hi guys okay okay
two people watching
so insert random number so so
so uh uuid so we have a bunch of them
and today we are going to uh recall this
okay so let's let's begin so let's um
cut that
let's go back to the talk show and let's
put it um
here so we have a
record of what we
pasted them
okay so you can see uh kind of random
numbers okay so
now we want to
modify the code okay so let's begin okay
so let's show the code so what this
this do what
the current implementation is that
okay so it inserts any of these random
characters okay you actually
predefine them you know and these bunch
of random numbers include a to z
0 to 9 except
no vowels so there's no a
so there's no a no e no i no
no u and also there's no one there's no
capital uh there's no
uh o there's no capital o z
neither and there's no zero so you can
see because these characters are
confusing and there's no
uh capital i
or
l
lowercase l and actually i don't i don't
think i include l at all because you
cannot see it here
so
so you start by defining a string that's
a character set then you define a base
count base count is what is how many
is how many characters you want
yeah
count x
something like
uh base count length character set no
that's uh how many how long is this
string that's a
base
can you consider that as number number
base for example for hexadecimals you
the base is 16 because there are 16
different possible symbols now in this
case the length of that is the base
count okay
so that's the
that's the base count here then you have
count x which is how many times you want
to insert now okay so now
you know
i so today i just had a whim kind of i
thought of why don't i rewrite this
because this is
this is not uh
this is very fast you know efficiently
you know fast enough you know like you
you won't be able to see um delays but
however i'm thinking using a different
algorithm
which is based on ascii characters let's
just do it okay so
so anyway so once we know the
the number of
the length of the string and how many
digits we want to insert then we just
insert you know in emacs you just call
two times do that many times and each
time you insert you insert pick from
element
an element from the character set
then you do a random you know you pick a
random letter so that's how this
code works okay
so now
so now we want a different um
algorithm so let's let's put it here
so in insert random two let's just
name it that okay
and uh
insert
okay let's
do
oh yeah you see this line this
documentation is actually incorrect
because
i removed the
that
i think wait
yeah i think
anyway so
i want to write a new one okay so let's
begin fresh okay so let's delete the
whole thing
so we are going to write this new
command
with a team different implementation so
first of all it's going to just insert
any any one of the
ins let's write it down okay insert any
of a to z
a to z
and zero to nine insert any one of those
characters okay remove that
and put the version date okay
uh now
now let's uh
yeah let's start so
so
you know so so let me show you uh
another thing okay so you see
you see the reason this algorithm is not
super efficient comparatively speaking
is because you know if you want five
digits you have to do times you are
doing it five times each time you pick a
random character from this uh char set
you know you have to do it five times
now
in
now as opposed to for example there is
for example let's write a insert text
okay hexadecimal
and and in this case you can just
say
insert okay
random okay a random number let's say
random number that let's say that one
million or something okay and you want
to format it okay so you you you want to
turn the number into a hexadecimal
there's a building function
format okay
so format
the percent sign x will be hexadecimal i
think i'm pretty sure
then you just put this random number
there so that okay so
this command okay
this function now will insert a random
hexadecimal okay let's evaluate it okay
now let's call it let's let's call it
call
because i insert x do it you see there
it is
call it
there it is call it there it is call it
there it is call it there it is so
in this algorithm you can see
it only caused the random function one
time
you know the whole thing it doesn't
matter how many digits let's try uh more
digits okay uh wait
let's let's increase the randomness you
know
10 million gazillion okay let's
evaluate the code and let's do it call
it
you see code chord
chord
chord chord you see now the hexadecimal
is much longer but however it's still
one shot you know one one random number
so this
is what i want you know i feel like you
know doing this
instead of going through the alphabet
you know pick a number and do that
multiple times
okay so now
okay but you see so this algorithm is in
insert hexadecimal so there's a building
format that converts a number a decimal
number an integer to the hexadecimal
okay but there's no but if you want to
insert you know any a to z
you want a number base basically that's
number base of 36
so it's each digit would be zero to nine
and a two z okay it's more than a uh you
know for example zero to nine
um
then
a to z
and also capital a two z
so how many total total of that is you
know that's 26 that's 26
uh that's 52
so this 62 so you need you you you are
having a
62 based number system
but however there's no building command
to do that okay there is in wolfen
language actually
let me show you
okay a bit digression because because
nobody is here watching my stuff oh
fantastic
fantastic thank you guys
or flamio thank you for you know being
my loyal patron you can't prove this
wasn't a random number
that's correct uh and i want to ask
what way do you recommend to dump emac
list data structures
like records to the screen for debugging
usage
i'm not sure what you mean actually
exactly you so explain okay
so
you want to ask me what do you recommend
to dump emac these data
emac these data structures
like records to the stream to to to the
screen for debugging usage okay so
so in e-mail so let me okay let me let
me
maybe explain that answer that okay
so
so you you want to basic so in emacs
most syntax has a print um dot
am i going to answer that or am i going
to continue
because i start to digress in multiple
directions
let me let me show the let me show the
wolfram uh
thing first okay
yeah so so multiple ways which one to go
first okay so
uh
comments okay
if if uh
okay keep keep comments okay
so let me show you the random number
okay so random
random integer okay so
you so there is a function random
integer
and
this is uh
11 to
let's say a billion something okay
so that's a wolfram language
what i'm going to show is that i'm going
to show you know normally in all
languages in c c plus first emac list in
this
okay am i still i'm am i still alive i
think my computer flows
yes my computer froze
caused
by wufan
language
god
but is my video is my video am i still
streaming
say something
say something guys okay i think i'm
still streaming
that's
okay yeah my i i had a hard freeze
wufang language
that's because it's sucking up all the i
think it's sucking up all the memory
okay so now
let's let's do it again okay
it shouldn't i don't think there is a
okay what i want to show you is that
what i want to show you now is that
is that in all the languages java
javascript per python whatever languages
you have a function built
that turns a integer
to a hexadecimal or octal number okay
for example you can
uh you can for example let me
demonstrate okay so for example i have
this
uh let's say you know again run it
you know i can run it
or that's a
hexadecimal okay or i can change it to o
then it will insert a octal number you
see octal number
octal number is one uh zero to eight
basically always zero to eight
so hexadecimal octal but however these
languages doesn't what you know octal is
eight hexadecimal is 16. what about 15 i
want a number system that we you know
that give me
that turns converts a number integer to
a
based number
what about it you can do it you have to
write it yourself what about 14 i want a
14 base system you can do it because
what do you know why because the
the c and c and unix idiots they made a
condition
to such a degree that the programmers
don't even know what is base 14 means
but wufam language does okay let me show
you
so
so let's say random number 1 to 10 okay
so that's
uh oh it gives you wait
oh yeah do you know why
we had a crash before because i was
asking wufang language to return like 1
billion
at least of one billion items so that's
why it's eating up all the memory that's
why my computer first it didn't crash
but
so so yeah that's why so so but if you
want to random number from 1 to 100
that's what you do okay so you can see
so you see 51 or you can actually do a
table you know let me show you
a table of random numbers 1 to 100 and
how many times let's say uh 100 times
let's say 10 times okay you see
now
now let's so i want to demonstrate
wolfram language where it converts a
number to
any number based system you want okay so
how do you find the function you type
base okay
i don't remember the function name
offhand so you type base
and let's say basing code baseline
baseline position base number base okay
something about number base
uh
base form okay open it
exactly that's what we want base form
okay so let's let's let's let's do it
so base form
okay so what is the
what is the syntax i believe we just
let's say 100 base two
let's say 10 base two okay yeah that's
that's what it is okay so let's say 10
base 3
there it is you see and you can see the
subscript okay fantastic
now let's say base 16 okay
10 10 in base 16 that's a
subscript 16 okay
now what if what if you want 100 base 16
okay that's 64 okay now if you want what
what if i want base 17
there it is okay now what what if i want
a base 50 okay
requested base 50 should be an integer
between 2 and 36 okay so it doesn't have
so
so let's do 36 maximum base is 36
why because it uses the you know the
alphabet a to z
in addition to zero to one so you got 36
space 36 distinct symbols but if you
want more more based on that then you
have the question of
what you know what what symbols you're
gonna use so by default it's just base
16. okay
so now now we can do a random
integer
okay random integer of
one two
one million or something okay base third
36 okay let's try it again
so you you started to see um okay the
number is not big enough let's say big
okay so you you so so that's what we
want you see that that is actually what
the function we are trying to write in
ufam language is basically just one
single line okay that's language
so you know that's what we are trying to
do today so okay
uh so
so now
i finished demonstrating uh language let
me let's go back okay and let me go back
to the
oh base base base 64 okay that's a
special case and wufang language has
that okay let me show you and emacs also
has that okay so
i believe
yeah
base64 uh decode uh encode okay so
base64 in code region okay so for
example
first so for this example you want to
encode that to base64 and you just call
base64 in code region there it is okay
now base64 is a special case it's
because it's often used okay
you can look up wikipedia basically
it uses all the alphabets
including capital case and including i
believe eating also includes some uh
punctuation symbols but that's a special
case so in wufan language you also have
that so
so what is the function name
base base in code there it is this one
base encode b encodes the byte array ba
as a base 64
string okay so
based in code so you want byte array
okay so what what byte array so let's
let's
let's give this um
the same uh
string here but except you cannot have
the
double quote because you have to escape
the double quote
okay so the whole thing will be a string
there it is so we're gonna uh
we need also double quote
escape there okay so the whole thing
will be a
string in wolfram language okay so let's
paste it here
you know we are encoding a emac this
function in language do it
okay so
wait my syntax is wrong so it doesn't
take a string okay so let's look at look
up the documentation so
encodes the byte array ba so it requires
a byte array
so there is also base 85 ascii okay so
okay you need a byte array so it doesn't
take string so you need to
i believe by the array can convert a
string to uh bytes okay
now let's try again
yeah
how do you convert the string to byte
array
uh string two byte array everything must
be very formal so you have to say string
two byte array okay
okay let's let's do that it's a string
two byte array
paste it
okay
did we match everything correctly yes
what
yeah what's going on
oh oh i copied it incorrectly god
you know that's because of the
formatting thing okay so because you see
the wolfram language is actually
actually hidden it's doing that so we
actually just want that
okay so
delete the the hidden thing
just that okay fantastic now let's
verify
so k g r
one z n
there it is k g r one
one z n and and ends at s
k s k k
oh uh the ending is different because
because i we we got some uh
line return let's do it again okay copy
it
paste it here
now select this carefully now call
base64 in code region
there it is ksk
wait why does it
not ending the same
uh
wait when did it start to differ
d-a-w-m-d-a so
d a w m d a okay
then w m c k
p k
okay so the last
three digits differ because
and well it you know because probably
because of the um
line return
anyway yeah yeah i don't want i don't
want to spend time to figure out you
know some some line return characters at
the end okay
so okay so that's about that now
now let me address the question okay the
question about
how do you recommend how do you double
image this data you know imagine
straight up for example you have a
vector
to uh you know usually you evaluate it
you can see
you can see that's the output so you
don't actually need to dump anything so
because what you see is what you get
so that applies for array that applies
for a list
you know for for a list you can so we
can see now so but you are talking about
a record so for certain emac data
structure emac this data structure there
is
uh no printout form for example um let's
go to
these okay
tutorial and and let's look at hash
table
okay so emac this has a hash table
and you can make a hash table like that
okay let's copy that
so let's uh hash table okay so let's
where are we
where do we do it here okay so let's
start a new one here
so hash table so here you create a hash
table evaluate evaluated okay let's show
the ping window evaluate that then you
then you uh
then you
describe variable
my hash okay
wait why is it not
evaluate
then describe variable my hash
and you can see what
set cue my hash evaluate it okay
then
then what is evaluate my hash there it
is okay so here is what it returns so
that is the
printed representation of the hash table
it begin with a pump sign and s
then then hash table then whatever so
this is a special case
for certain data structures in emac disk
when there is a
uh
you know when when there is no read
syntax for it but in in the in the case
of hash table actually you do have a
read syntax for it
but anyway that's
you know so you are seeing it
okay so let's go back um
okay so let's add some you know add some
items into the hash table so
put hash okay
let's copy that
so we're gonna add some hash evaluated
then
we want to know the value of my hash
evaluated okay so you can see at the
bottom
there it is so you can see you know the
joe 19 that's one entry of the hash
table so that's a print replace print
read
that's
that that prints the read syntax that
represents the hash table okay
now but you are talking about record
okay i actually don't know about the
record data structure now a record data
structure in emac this
is
is like a vector which is like a tuple
of python okay it's like a vector but
each element can be different type
from other elements so they don't all
have to be the same
type
so in imac this vector
every element must be the same type
wait
wait uh no you make this vector every
element can be a different type for
example this works
but a record is such that
you know i i haven't used uh emac this
record before so actually i do not know
your answer in particular if you are
asking about
vector
so comments okay comments based on what
i just said if you still have a question
or not okay so let me read all the
comments i have to work with java in my
new job still pay the bills indeed java
java and c plus plus
and
in golan
in python okay so what is language based
on does it use jit or is it completely
interpreted
either way okay so you can but usually
it's
usually you would say it's just
interpreted okay
uh you cannot it's not
it's not a language where like c or java
where you have to or golan or rust where
you have to almost
compile into a compiled object then you
can run it
but
you uh
you cannot do that generally speaking
okay
so anyway anyway that's it uh so why is
q white space what do you mean white uh
white space i don't
know what you mean by white space
so
okay anyway how long have we been going
in 40 40 minutes
okay so now what do we do do we continue
to write this um
yeah let's continue to write this
function and then then let's um okay so
so let's do some cleanup first okay
so
let's go to talk show
and
today's talk show
we we talked about
um
uh base64 okay so let's let's do it okay
base64 encoding
so let's
copy that
okay put it here
then base60 encoding of
ufam language let's also copy that which
is this code
okay so that's good that's full frame
language base64 encoding
okay we're gonna i'm gonna show you in a
moment so let me just clean up here
so that's emac this this is what that
that's the command you do
base encoding something okay
and
okay so let me move here so you can see
it
and okay so what this is a bunch of
random numbers then we talked about the
representation of
of
emac this data structure printed
representation okay so that's this part
wait yeah that's this part
so let's put it here
okay
and the syntax color the whole thing so
this is what we talked about today base
uh and arbitrary number base okay so we
also talked about arbitrary number base
so let's
let me
show that
let me put it in the
here
so that's wufam language
okay so we talked about
you know we we showed some emac this
code for doing
uh
for generating random strings we showed
some
the building function format to convert
a number to
hexadecimal or octo
okay so
and we uh
okay so now
let's
let's write a function
with a
different algorithm to convert
to yeah let's let's quickly write that i
want to think let's you know let's
to finish this instead of just wandering
off
okay so i want to write a function so
the insert okay so this is what we want
to that's a documentation and we want to
insert okay insert something and we want
to a to z
so first of all what we need to do is
ascii numbers okay so we look up
my reference on ascii characters because
i need to know
the range of characters so if you want
to if you want a to z
[Music]
so 0 to 9 is 48 to 64. okay so let's
write uh here so ascii
character is 48 to 64. you know what
does that mean you know
for each character for each character
there's an associated number which is
you can think of it as the id
identification number for each
for each character okay this same thing
in unicode so usually this number
is called the code point for that
character okay but usually the official
terminology is code point yeah but you
can just think of it
as a id okay the integer id so every
character is associated with a integer
id okay so for
for the digit 0 to 9 the s characters so
that's 48 to 64. okay and and and for
a2z
so a begin with 65
and
z
z is 90 okay
and the lower case
a starts with 97
to
2z 122 okay
so 62 so how many total number of
characters
so anyway uh
total charts okay so basically so we
want to
generate a random number okay so
so let's let's uh
you know continue coding non-stop
oh yeah so yeah i think that's because
of the white space
uh
when you get a big hash table or a
record during runtime it is hard to make
sense of it maybe it's a record maybe a
hash table oh okay so in that case
you have to write a function basically
to
so your question is how do when you have
a hash table in emac list or a record i
never use record data structure anyway
but suppose hash table if you have a
hash table in emaclis and you want to
print it usually it's uh you know
confusing so in that case you just have
to write a function to print it each
entry yourself that's what
um i think that's what you are asking
that's what i do
uh in some languages you have to do that
you have to do that in in golan okay
yeah
it's interesting let me show you golan
because in some languages you turns out
you need to do that in other languages
you have a building
function or library just to print
arbitrary nested you know data structure
but in usually in low-level languages
such as scolan you have to write that
yourself and in the case of emac this
i think you also have to write you that
yourself
yeah
because sometimes i i do because for
example let me let me show you golan
example first okay so
uh in in so in golan you want to print
um
slice okay slice is a good example a
slice is basically like a
a list or array in other languages slice
in golan is basically a
array that can change size okay so it's
flexible you can change size and change
change elements and
um
so where is it okay so slice
so here you can see gol go land tutorial
on slice
and there it is
how do you print them
it's a problem you know exactly you know
if you use a default
um
you know it it prints the whole thing in
one long line you know
when when you have hundred items it's
hard to read so you want to print them
one item at you know in each line so you
have to write a
program so there it is this function
print slice okay that's a golden example
now in e-mac this
i believe i also did similar for hash
table
so here is a hash table so but sometimes
you want to you know if you just ask
emac emax to print it it's one
incomprehensible line there it is print
hash table okay so this function it will
print them nicely one entry
per line
okay
that's
hash table okay so that that so let's go
to my tutorial
um
so let's put it here
go to today's talk show
okay that's emac this
print hash table
and
[Music]
there is scolan
print slice okay
now now let's uh let's finish this
function okay insert random number so we
got so we
so first of all let's say insert 0 to 9
48 to 64. so we want a random
uh what's uh what is the
okay limit
68 to okay so that's uh kind of annoying
so you
so here generate the random number
okay so that's so what you want to do is
um yeah
so let's define
a function
where
64 minus 48
so that is the
digit range okay that's the ascii digit
range okay
so so now you want to
okay so let's
let me show you okay so let me just code
this okay so let's
start
digit range start 48
digit range end 46
then digit range
and minus start okay so let's hold on a
second
so i want to actually
i want all my variables to start with x
that's my personal convention okay
prettify the code so digit range start
end
then
then uh
a
low
az range okay
okay so low ac range begin they begin at
72 97 122 okay
one two two okay
okay now
next
cap okay
okay capital case 65 to 90 okay 65 to 90
and
okay
then we
have minus
okay
then we need a cap okay
okay i think that's
my variable names are too long but let's
let's let's not worry about it so we got
the range let's say wrench digit start
60 48 64
uh and minus start okay so this is
reversed this is reversed
glad we found this
okay so low and a z okay so that's
that's that
okay we got a wrench so now we want to
generate
um
oh my god how do you do this um
let's let's just gently start to uh
generate okay so
x digit range
so that gives you a number plus i
got
you know in emac these syntax the the
nested paren
you cannot do arithmetics
easily
so you want a random number plus the um
yeah plus the start
okay
so that will
return
this line will return a random random
number between
to
64 okay and that in emac this
a character
is represented the character data type
there's no character data type in emac
disp however a character is represented
by an integer of its code point okay
that's its id
so therefore this gives you a number
between 48 to 64 and that represents the
character and then you can print it
you can print it you can convert the
character to string okay so let me show
you so char to string yeah so
uh
so hold on a second so let's declare a
new num and
random digit okay
okay so that's another new variable
set random digit equals to
that okay
so now we can
charge string
insert
okay clean up the code so so here is our
code that just insert a random
digit for now okay let's evaluate it and
let's call it okay
let's try it quit
do it
real number of argument lamp.com oh okay
so we got of course we got the parameter
we don't need that parameter
evaluate it okay show the ping window
call it do it all right call it
do it
symbols value as variable is void okay
so random digit
x digit range end
okay x digit range and
symbols
variable is void what
so let's copy the here
copy it and search it make sure we don't
have sparing errors so why is it
void
x digit range end okay
okay
why is it void
x digit range end
what what what is the arrow
what
let's let's let's go let's see
where is the error
let's call it again okay
so shrink the code
evaluate it call it
do it
symbols value as variable is void x
digit range and
symbols value as variable is void
oh i understand you see because we are
using let declaration here in let
declaration the any
any of the variables you declared here
do not know the value of the variable
you declared previously
so here we are calling x digit range end
which is defined here but however it
doesn't know you know it
so you have to
use let
asterisk so that will work okay evaluate
it call it do it there it is so there it
is okay so do it
do it do it do it do it
okay
okay so some some of this is incorrect
it shouldn't insert a colon
but anyway so this insert one character
that's correct um
god we need to fix our code so it
shouldn't insert a colon
so where is the ascii
so let's double check our ascii
so 029 48 to 64. so let's see ascii
48 to oh
oh 257 not 64. yeah we got it wrong so
to
57 okay so let's
57 is the correct
there it is okay
so we fix that let's fix something else
now each time this you know it generates
a random number
how do we do this you see that
what i really want is to generate a
huge random number once one only one
time only once
then
convert them into uh you know alphabets
uh but right now
our algorithm is not
correct he's not doing the right
uh on the right path
so right now it's you know it's just
generating one single digit
how do you um
yeah
okay the problem is more than i thought
you you cannot
you know if you
only want one
called a random number only one time
if that is the restriction
and you want to turn that random number
into
you know into a
36 based
number notation
it's
it's easy to do however
it's fairly inefficient because then
basically you have to do a loop end
times looking up characters um
okay so
okay so any anything else i think that's
it for today we so that's one hour
i mean so so so how do we
solve this problem okay so there's some
change you know as you code you notice
something
so if you really want to just
quote a random number only one time
then try to convert that number to you
know
let's make it simple let's not include a
to z you know let's just say a to z
you know let's say all lowercase and uh
zero zero to nine
so you want to convert it to a 36 based
number system
you know just like um
like here you know
so so you know like like these examples
uh you
so in order to do that
um
yeah you can do that uh
you can do that
so
okay it's not so trivial so one of the
brainless
way is to is just to build a lookup
table like that you know like a bunch of
strings
then you just
take the position you know once you got
the num
you you you process so once you got the
random
well yeah so my thought is not complete
but anyway one of the ways to do a look
up tables
so you have to do it many times
that's not good
the other way is to you know so you want
to turn so it's math-based
approach so you got a number
you got a huge number you want to turn
into a
n-based
numbering notation yeah you can do that
but
oh god
but again
yeah but again you have to you have the
digit problem because each time
you know you got a number you want to
turn that into a digit
you know in into a digit which means one
of the alphabet one of the letters
how do you do that there's no magical
way you have to
either reference a you know again
reference a string or a vector or a list
to get that actual
digit
then you have to do a
concatenation of the
other characters
okay so that so yeah you can do that but
that is
yeah that's a different algorithm but
it's not a it's not more efficient than
just this
this way yeah
so
okay i'm kind of
so uh
haircut is looking pretty good okay i
think that's it for me
i'm kind of
at this point you know i'm wondering
where should i go now um
so it so let's make sure if we were
correct so if we
want to only generate
the random number one time
if that's
the criteria
then what we need to do is
is really it's pretty cumbersome
yeah because then you need to do a lot
of powers computation to find out
what is the number for each digit
then
do a lookup to
convert that digit into one actual
symbol one of the letters
so that turns out if you want to do that
for the goal of generating a random
string that is actually much more
inefficient than
than just that
okay so
so that
yeah that idea is gone
but what are some other ideas such that
such that you can generate a random
string
but without doing a you know loop
n times
you know how can you make this more
efficient
okay i don't think there's
i don't actually
i don't think there's a way not at least
not in a high level language sense i
mean if you are doing c
yeah you can you know
use memory bit detailing you know
bits and you could you could do that but
from a
high level algorithmic point of view
i don't think there is a
more algorithmically efficient way
because ultimately you have to look up
you know if if you want n digits you
have to look up n times
if you want five digits you you do have
to look up five times
eventually
okay that's that's my thought for now i
could be wrong i'm
i think i'm pretty correct on that
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching
bye guys
okay shutting down in
in two minutes
you know so
so this code it generates a random
number then only converts to one digit
yeah that's not good
and also this chart to stream function
is fairly expensive you know you don't
want to call a child to string
end times
there is there some clever way you know
there's probably maybe there's some
clever way clever way
of using the building format for
hexadecimal
so you just double hexadecimal
hexadecimal is 16 based
so if you double that you have 32 based
uh
but can you actually do that
i i'm not sure okay
okay bye