Hello, good evening. Welcome to another
episode of S talk show. We are going to
code Emac Bisp very technical today.
This is my keyboard ultimate hacking
keyboard UHK80
Logitech
G450
no 502 track ball. Fantastic. My
workhorse and NIA trackboard. You can
see reviews of them on my YouTube. So
now let's start. Uh let me show you my
screen and let me show you what we're
going to do today.
Emac visp coding. Okay. So this is just
going to be me relaxed doing my own
things. I'm I'm going to code emacisp.
We are going to write a command to
delete all Emacs backup files in a
directory such as for example you can
see Emacs convention the backup files
name has a ta on it see that character
that character is officially known as
teday now how do you pronounce that
character let's see
uh teod okay that character is
pronounced tilda in unic code. Okay. So
by emac convention you have a back file
backup file. So for example we can make
a backup file of that one. Do it. You
see by comm by emac convention any file
ending with a to means it's a backup
file. Okay. So we want to write a
command to delete all these back fi back
backup files recursively in all the
subdirectories. Okay. Now I have some
some red wine and now let's have this uh
espresso vodka
a little bit to enjoy life. Okay. So if
you are here say hi. If you are not here
play at 1.5 speed.
to sooththe my soul. Okay, now let's
continue. So, we're going to write a
command to uh delete all backups in a
directory recursively. Okay,
in fact, I already have the command. So,
let me show you. So, for example, you
can see allowed backup here. So I can
just press press press and do you want
to delete all these files? Say yes or
no. Yes. And those are good. So if you
go to the directory again now press U2
to uh G to refresh. Refresh. You see all
the backup files are good. So I already
have the command but I want to make some
modification
which I'm going to show you. Okay. So uh
describe key press uh describe key
press.
So you can see the command is uh delete
Emacs backup. X ah delete Emacs backup
and the source code is right here. Okay,
that's in XA-ED.el.
Okay, and here's a source code. Not many
lines but we're going to make
modifications. I will tell you why.
Okay. Well, the reason is first of all
this one is calling you see it's it's
calling the EMAC XAH list EMAC backup.
Okay, which is uh which is defined right
above it right here.
Uh so
so what I want to do is to not make them
dependent. So I'm just going to um
move this code into itself, you know. So
I don't want dependency. Okay, that's
one thing. The other thing I want to do
is that I don't want to I don't want it
to ask for confirmation. Okay. Now this
is about user interface design which is
a pervasive issue. Pervasive issue in
programming. You know you have to user
interface design. It may it be graphical
user interface design and or it also
occurs in designing a function interface
or command line interface also called
you know the Java would call it
uh API application programmers interface
Java began that jargon in 1995 which is
idiotic okay anyway what I'm saying is
that this command involves interface
design. Okay, interface design may be
API which is a function of you know the
the design of the function interface
like what argument it's going to be what
semantic of the argument or it can be
applied to uh graphical user interface
design which is um for example a website
navigation buttons is a example. Okay.
So you can go to kasar code. Okay.
Now kasali code. So let's copy that
kasali code. Let's go to it. Go to it.
Uh code and let's say uh
info. Okay. So let's um
uh
press press do that show in browser. So
we add the info. So it makes it no more
clear that this is my website. Anyway,
we digress. Okay. So,
so if you uh if you guys are here, say
hi. Love to see your comments. If you
guys are not here, play at 1.5 speed.
Okay. Now, let's let's do the Emacs
coding. Okay. So, let's uh did we finish
introduction? I think so. So, close
showing browser. Okay. So we gonna code
uh delete xah delete backup. Okay.
So let's begin. Okay. So um section um
so the command so the command is
describe key. So hold on a second. Let's
show the ping window.
x a delete backup. Okay. So let's show
the command. Go there. Copy it.
Okay. Well, first of all, so let me tell
you guys what's this doing. Okay. First
of all, make a backup. Make a backup of
this x a
file. Okay. Uh
make a backup. And what I want to do so
version the update today. So so you see
first of all it's calling this uh this
thing x list emac backup.
Okay. So if you go up you can see the
code is here. So first of all let's not
make it dependent. Okay. So let's
actually just copy the file.
Copy it.
Search it again and replace it the code
here. So
file path equals to
x a list emac backup x list emac backup
input. Okay. So the input uh is from
uh the input uh is by if you call the
command interactivity
the input uh by default is the default
directory which is whatever the current
file uh is in. So if I call it now you
know whatever the current file. Okay.
So now
I am fif uh I I I am 40% drunk. Okay. I
had some red wine before. So I'm 40%
drunk. Hello SCP again. Will it delete
all the files in the directory or just
visited file? All of them.
Not just visit all of them. Okay.
So anyway so so first of all it caused
this you know we can look at we are
looking at the source code and we'll see
okay so let's copy that okay and and and
okay so this is what it's doing okay so
so instead of calling it let's try to
make it independent okay so here is the
entire code of the defend let's mod
let's begin to modify delete the
comment. Uh, delete that. Delete that.
Delete
delete delete. Okay. Interactive this
default directory. Okay. So,
so what are we doing? So, okay. So, we
want to yeah input the
um
Okay. So actually
so x path will equals to
um
directory files recursively call this
function to recurse into that directory.
Okay. And uh and uh we want any file
that ends in a tilda. So that's a
regular expression for any file ends in
a tilda. Okay. So this is a regular
regular expression pattern for that.
And uh so so
okay. So what uh custom?
Okay. What? Whatever this crap.
Okay. The list of files is just this
command. Okay, we got um and we don't
need this anymore. This delete. Okay, so
this this list of files X path is just
directory files recursively and uh on
the input argument which is from here.
Okay.
Okay, that will work. Okay, so actually
this will work. So this is the whole
code. Copy it. So now we don't have
dependencies. You see we are not calling
the
where is it? list empty does. We don't
need that anymore. So search for that
you uh
delete empty directory. Okay. Actually
we are uh
yeah we were calling Emac this backup
but now
not anymore. Not anymore. Okay. So
let's go to it. S delete e Mac backup.
That's it. Okay. Copy it. Now go to talk
show.
Today's talk show and we can paste the
code here so people can see it. Okay.
Section
new section.
New emac this code block is it and
delete this daytime and to-do
syntax color the whole buffer show in
browser. So that's today's talk show. So
you can see we got the code no
dependencies. This is code by itself.
Okay.
So you get you know directory files
recursively uh get all files then you
just so if it's interactive if this
command is called interactively
then you uh you ask the user do you are
you sure you want to delete them
[snorts] you
so if the command is called
interactively that's a second argument
there optional argument okay so that
means If if the user either press the
key or meta x okay to call this command
then you that's interactive p predicate
is true. So if that is true then you
check if the file path is more than zero
that is there is some file to be
deleted. Okay. Then you ask the person
delete this Emacs backup.
You ask the person because it will show
the buffer because when before we were
calling the command, it will show the
buffer. Are you sure you want to delete
this files? Then if the person if the
person answers yes
uh you know when this returns yes then
it will map delete file to this path
just delete them all otherwise
um I mean you know delete them and say
it's got otherwise
so otherwise if the the number of uh
backup files is is not greater than zero
then you say no backup file found.
Okay. And uh so basically that's it. So
what what is the other one? So let's see
uh
close that.
So if interactive okay
so if it's called interactively then do
that if it's not called interactively
simply delete it right away. Okay. So
that is a command. Now what we want to
do? We want to make a we we want this
already works. Okay. Uh how do I know?
You can test it. Run the current file.
Okay. So let's say go to the directory
and uh you see there's a lot backup
files there. So you can just
s delete
um
backup emac backup. Okay, do it
delet this backup file. You see now it
doesn't pop up the list of files because
we removed it because remember we will
cancel. We were calling you know the we
were calling a command to list the
backup files which creates a buffer but
now we don't call that command. So it's
like organ
so that you don't show the buffer. Okay.
So, so that's why it's no buffer is
shown. So,
anyway, so we like to make some more uh
modification to this command. Okay, what
you want to do is um don't ask. So
instead you see
you see one of the problem with
interface user interface design is that
you don't want you want to try to not
ask people for questions like you don't
want like whenever people call a command
you don't want to oh by the way uh is
this files you want to delete answer why
for sure if you want you know Don't
don't do that.
You know you you want the user interface
such that whenever uh people execute a
command just do it. Okay. Then you
always have a undo ability. So when
people actually found there's some
mistake they made they can undo it.
Okay. That is the proper design. That's
a better better design. Okay. Don't stop
the word and ask user a question like
are you sure this is the file you want
to save? Are you sure you want to delete
this file? Are you sure you know show
show a list of file these files you want
to delete? Are you sure? Don't do that.
Never do that. Simply do whatever the
command is supposed to do. Then you
provide a undo feature so that if people
re realize it's a mistake they can undo
it. Okay. So that way why because that
way you have smooth mus muscle memory.
You know when people call when when a
user calls a command or by keystrokes by
uh uh keyboard shortcuts they have
muscle memory. They know what they're
doing. You know they can just press it
and do it do it do it do it do it. They
don't have like they don't they don't
you don't want to like they press some
command then all of a sudden oh by the
way is are you sure you want to do this
you know that's no good okay so this is
a tip about user interface design also
command function command interface
design okay
but are dependencies wrong in this case
why refactor okay
yeah dependency see is um
okay you see I'm doing that because I
have RSI right here
right here okay uh be since like four
years ago
so um that's why I'm doing this
to sooth the pen
okay so the dependency basically
that's a software software engineer ing
issue usually you want to avoid it as
much as possible. Okay? Because for
example in our case you know in our case
of um of uh delete uh which one is it
here
delete Emacs backup. So
you you know before we have we are using
the dependency of uh you know of list
which one um
yeah this command emac list backup which
is only actually just few lines. Okay so
when there's only a few lines just
repeat it. Okay, like you don't need to,
you know, actually the actually the mo
most important is just almost just one
line this line.
So that's why
you see uh what
uh so basically just almost just just
uh
where are we? Yeah, just this line
almost. Then actually there's another
line just just print all these list of
files in a buffer.
Okay. So what I mean is that if you can
as much as possible remove dependency
because because dependencies turns out
it's lots of headache because whenever
you need to like show people this
command then you need to show another
command you need to find out the
dependency and you need to show them oh
by the way this requires that you need
to get that at that location things like
that. So,
so it turns out I I think it's rather
it's you know you better just repeat
some lines of code than having
dependency
you know I I know the idea to the
software engineer the idea of dep
dependency is attractive because you
don't duplicate code you know because
everything is like elegant you you know
this one relies on that one that thing
relies on that thing you don't have code
repetition you know, so it's like one
good system. But the problem is when you
when you try to distribute the system,
there's actually a lot obstacles to
prevent you from having a coherent
system.
Unless you tell people like download all
my packages I've ever written in in in
this one thing, which is what happens
with Emac this, you know.
But but you see
anyway so that's a situation with
dependency. Okay. So anyway so so this
command we are writing and right now we
uh
we
remove the dependency but there's
another problem which is um we are
deleting the files and asking people
okay don't ask. So let's do let's remove
that.
Don't ask. Okay. Delete that.
Uh
and uh so instead of deleting them, move
them to a directory. Okay. So move them
to a directory. So let me just do it
instead of is instead of explaining.
Okay. So um
so let's just say
create a temp directory here. Okay. So
that's my temp directory.
Uh lots of temp files
close. Okay. So,
it's going here.
Okay. So,
Okay. So, we kind of like we are doing
um lots of codings. You guys don't know
what I'm doing, but let me just do it.
So we are trying to create a temp
directory for backup and just copy the
files there. Okay. So let me just do it.
So this way you don't have to ask people
are you sure you want to delete. So like
you don't actually delete them. You move
them to the directory. So let me just
code it.
Uh I heard that it can take months to
learn Emacs. Is Emacs easy to learn and
customize if one doesn't know lisp?
Yeah, that's tricky. Okay, so you can,
you know, you can check out my EMAC
uh website, Emacs tutorial.
Uh there's sections about, you know,
practical EMAC uh practical EMAC
tutorial, Emacs init setup, keys. Is it
easy to learn? Relatively no. So
compared to VS Code is much harder to
learn. Uh but it's more powerful. Okay.
It's much more powerful and much more
efficient.
So it's, you know, you just have to take
the trip and decide for yourself. Okay.
And my website.info
is a good source for Emacs. Okay. So
[snorts] you want to go through
practical EMAC tutorial like go through
a few a day and then then go to the
Emacs init setup go through a few a day
and also Emacs keys. So anyway,
uh so let's get back to this uh I want
to code this uh god so a lot coding. So
I want to um so about learning emac bisp
technically you do not have to learn any
emac bisp to become proficient in emacs
but however
it's kind of very fruitful you know be I
I I have known emacs uh users who
doesn't know eac but who has been using
emacs for more than 10 years in fact
vast Majority of EMAC users who has been
using Emacs for more than 10 years, they
don't actually know any Emac list. Okay,
that's that's normal. That's a
situation.
The Emacs users, they've been using most
of them, you've been using Emacs for 10
years, they have a lot in files. They
have, you know, copied from the web
hundred hundreds of lines of innate
files. They don't actually know eac list
basics. Okay. Even despite the fact that
all their init file everything in a init
file is actually eag code. Those are all
these all these are eag code.
So you don't have to know any eacisp.
But knowing even a little bit Emac this
helps you a lot
uh
in understanding Emacs. So when you like
install packages when you decide which
package you want when you try to config
your init files if you know Emac this it
helps a lot in understanding what's
going on. Okay, but it's not ne
necessary. And if you are zoomer today,
well, you can just use um VS code like
so open in VS Code or do it just um VS
code. Okay. Now, VS Code. So, so why
should you spend the time to do Emacs
instead of VS code? Because VS code,
it's a commercial uh thing. It's got
lots of problems. The memory usage is
like by default 10 times smaller than
Emacs. There it is. VS Code 540
megabytes just to open one file right
here. Uh right here, you know, VS Code
one file. Wait, did we just close it?
One single file. 500
uh 500. No, 450 megabytes. Okay. Now in
EMAC in Emacs we've been coding Emac
this and several files we've been
opening um it's only 50 megabytes okay
you see 70 megabytes while VS code is
using 380 megabytes so
basically
uh basically uh like 10 times okay five
or 10 times so that's VS code and can
you escape that situation. Why does VS
code use so much memory? Well, the
reason is you cannot escape it because
that's open source but it's from a
corporation. So corporation code tends
to be just larger bloat you know you
cannot there's nothing you can do. Okay
so anyway back to emac list. Okay. So,
Emac this, you know, Emacs is good for
if you are truly
uh kind of a programmer into computer
science, you are obsessed with it. You
want to you want to have full control
and you know that's useful. Okay.
Anyway,
so we talked a lot [ __ ] crap. I'm not
going anywhere, but I want to code this.
Okay. Uh,
so I want to copy instead of delete. Uh,
God.
So you want to make sure that directory
exist first of all. Okay. Uh, [laughter]
so you want to make sure that directory
exist.
What's going on? Interactive. Okay.
Just do it. Okay. Not
active. Okay.
Okay. So you if exit exist
when not exist you want to create it.
Okay.
Okay. So if the file does not exist
created this directory. Okay. Then then
just move all files. Not copy. Move.
Okay.
Move frame. No.
[sighs]
What about move file to trash?
Does that uh is it workable? Let's see.
move file to trash basically um to the
trash when delete by moving file to
trash is in the new
Now you see it's nice function but you
don't know if that's supported on
Windows.
Uh you see that is a problem because
lots of complexities.
Um
so let's just know
uh
now what is the emac command to move
file rename visit file okay so
uh
crap
okay I don't know so let's go to eac
this my tutorial let's see if I have
covered it.
So right now you want to go to emac
this. Yes. Go there
and go to files
text processing cion commands uh write a
command. Okay. User input writing script
packages file buffer. Okay. So you want
to
Yeah, you want to move file. So read
file buffer functions read file content
a string. Uh so you want some kind of
open file read. You want the system
uh
move file, rename file. Okay. So you
want uh kind of directory functions.
So where are they? Core shell commands
uh work directory file path functions
there. So default directory get file
path parts. So you want uh actually move
or rename.
So that would be here somewhere.
File name contact directory path file
name as directory miscellaneous
file name wait
what
where is the rename
rename or move okay you see search for
move
not found and search for rename
Not found. Jesus.
Let's see. Uh, rename.
Oh, okay. There. Rename file. There it
is. You see the this is a nasty problem
from Unix because Unix consider rename
file and move as the same.
Uh, so it's kind of stupid. Okay. So
anyway, rename file is what you want.
So,
so rename file. So, let uh rename file
there. Okay. So, you don't want copy,
you want to rename, you want to map
function
lambda.
Okay. Lambda. What the lambda will do is
rename or move. Okay. So now delete file
and
apply the map to the path. Okay. And
okay. So what do you want to do? So
rename file X new name
uh god
new name. You need to like conc.
Okay, so this is would be odd. Conc
with the name X with a slash. Okay,
this is going to be weird. Uh, you see,
do you guys see what I'm doing?
Why do you choose it over Vim or Neo
Vim? Well, Emacs is just better. Okay.
Uh unless you have more specific
question, okay, uh then maybe I'll tell
you. But Emacs is just better.
Okay. So we uh so if the directory does
not exist, we create it. Then we map a
function
to rename files for all the file path.
Okay. Now rename file X
to the what's the new name? The new name
will be the temp directory
temp backup
plus the current directory. So the
current so that was going to be a long
name Jesus.
Then that also include the drive letter.
So it's very annoying. God
optional if already exist. Um,
so the new name is going to be
for now. Let's just
let's just um
let's just uh file name no file name no
directory. Okay.
File name s directory something.
So how do you get rid of directory? File
name s file name directory. File name
non directory. Okay. File name non
directory.
File name none directory. What?
File name non directory. Oh
file name none directory. Okay. So for
now you just get the file name just just
put them there okay don't worry about
so optional if already exist uh
okay if already exist
uh
yes okay because you know you going to
write the backup anyway so
okay So map lambda rename file
map C that's correct. You don't want you
don't need the output. Okay. So then
moved all backup files
to
to list. Okay. So you need to say
okay that is our new function. I believe
it took me a while. What the [ __ ]
So delete Emacs bug backup. Okay that
that is like took me a while. Now we can
look at the old code.
Okay. So let's look at the old code.
Okay. So let's look at code.
Here's a look copy old code. So we can
like here is old code. Okay. It's using
the it's calling this function to list
backup files. Okay.
Comment it out. And here's a new code.
Now there's no dependency. Also, it
doesn't actually delete those files. It
simply move them to this to this 10
backup. Okay. So, let's try it. Let's
see if that runs. Okay. So, open the
directory. It doesn't exist. Okay.
But it will create it when we call it.
Okay. So, now eval the buffer. Make a
backup. Go to the directory. And let's
try to bite compile it. Yes.
Okay. Unused lexical. Okay. So now we
don't even need this interactive P. So
let's just remove it. Okay. Backup. Go
to the file. Make a bite compile.
No error. Correct. Okay. That's good.
Delete the backup. The compile of bite
comp byte compile file. Delete it. Okay.
And now evaluate buffer. Perfect. Now
all we have to do is you see all these
all these backup files. You can see uh
actually let's not do it there. Let's go
to talk show
and let's make some backup files. You
see make a backup. Make a backup. Make a
backup. Okay. So we made some backup
files. You can see now call the command
saw delete backup file. So do it.
Wrong number of argument. Okay, we got
an error. So let's see. Um
what what
number of arguments? Okay.
Uh wrong number of arguments. So let's
fix that.
Okay. So this should be actually that.
So that should be um that refers to the
users directory.
So make a backup. And
so why is what is the error message
[cough]
is a full phone call interactively
wrong number of arguments.
Oh,
okay. Delete that. So, let's see did
that evaluate the buffer.
Uh, so that's
so when code interactively it will
supply the default directory. Okay. Now
go to the talk show. Go to the
directory. Now call sdmac backup. Do it.
Wrong number of argument. What?
What you talking about? What you talking
about? Do it wrong number of arguments.
Why?
Um,
so Roan says, "I was already using Doom
Emacs for maybe 6 months. Then I've been
trying new vim and sublime text and even
VS Code.
Uh,
okay. Roan says, "I have a more specific
question, but I'll try to lay it out.
It's not about editor wars, but it's
more about paralysis by analysis.
You probably think I'm very stupid. I
was already using Doom Emacs for maybe
six months. Then I've been trying
Mvim and Sublime Text and even VS Code.
Okay, your passage is incomprehensive.
broken true
like I you know like what are you saying
kind of incomplete and incomprehensive
despite its five lines
you know like what what do you mean
paralysis by analysis
and uh and this line you probably think
I'm very stupid that's like
nonsequittor it doesn't relate to
anything. Why do I think you know then
but maybe you are addressing to someone
else but even so your line doesn't make
sense. So then but the final line seems
the most important is that you you are
saying I was already using doom emacs
for maybe six month then I've been
trying mim and sublime text and even VS
code law. So
I mean so so what is your point?
Are you saying you you stayed with Emacs
doing Emacs or are you saying you
switched or are you saying like what
what what are you saying?
What kind of truth? [laughter]
Okay. So I let me go back to what I was
doing. So I need to fix my code.
So why do I get um like um this
this wrong number of arguments
evaluate the buffer wrong number of
arguments.
Okay. Make sure every argument is uh
okay so I'm not sure why am I getting
the wrong number of arguments talk show
let's do it again do it okay now turn on
debugging
which is the command and toggle debug on
arrow. Okay, now do it again. Do it.
Okay, now so you can see what is the
actual like um
what
help command arrow? What? Uh what
back trace. Okay.
Wrong number of arguments. F lambda then
move back up. Okay. So
number of argument function lambda input
t. Okay. D. Okay. So something
So, did they did it create this
directory? Let's see.
No, it didn't even create this
directory.
lambda input. So lambda input t
what
god this this today's session
turned out more annoying than I expected
because I was thinking we're going to
finish this smoothly
and in like 20 minutes. Um,
okay. So,
okay. Says he means he can decide
between the two. I'm saying I kept
switching without doing any real work.
Okay. I'm just jumping around. Okay. But
having written it out in here makes it
sound a little dumb. Okay. So,
uh yeah. So, that's um that's more of a
personality problem I believe. So, I
tend to have that problem. So, you need
to fix that problem.
You know, you you need to get on, you
know, you need to like be more goal
oriented.
set set of a schedule or whatever task
list of things you need to do and just
do them.
Not thinking about not not thinking okay
because we I think I believe we focus
too much on thinking on philosophy on
what should be what is better things
like that. On the other hand, there are
people who is just
doers like like a lot of the Unix type
of people and Vim users like they they
are brainless you know so they don't
have to they don't think well half of
the time because they are brainless so
for those people they don't begin to
think because they they don't have a
brain so they just need to do things
they they just start to do things okay
so whatever come to them VS code they
just use use it okay they they don't
think about oh maybe are there others
maybe I should you know try others
before no that's not what they do same
thing with the Vim people typically
because Vim is built on building you
know it's a default in Unix so they you
know they they are more like average
people they just you know they need to
do this in order to progress in life
because their parents told them to
because it's their job. You just need to
do it. Okay? Like don't like what what
you doing thinking about oh what what is
better what what should it be? What is
the design? You think too much. Those
people for a lot of them they don't they
don't have a brain to begin with. So
they just they don't have this problem.
Okay. So maybe understanding that will
solve some of the issue. Okay.
But on the other hand, you do have, you
know, the the the philosophers's problem
which is thinking too much. Okay. So
anyway, so let's go back to this uh
problem. Um
you see
you need you know society needs like all
kind of people. Uh you need you need the
designers, you need the doers, you need
the slaves, you need the thinkers, you
need the philosophers, you need the
mathematicians,
you need you know or even lawyers and
politicians, you know, you need all sort
of things kind of. Okay. But you you
don't you don't need you don't want
criminals. You don't of course you don't
want bullies um in society. Okay. So
anyway, so what so what Jesus
uh so what am I doing here? So that this
is very annoying because I thought this
should be done by now. You see we are
doing you see right now we are doing a
emac command of deleting Emacs backup.
You see for most people, you know, also
relates to your question for the VI
users, you know, they don't worry about
this. Why? Because you just go to shell.
You just go to shell and if you are on
Unix, you just remove, you know, you
just type the command remove dash f
whatever. Um then uh then then then that
tilda, okay, of the current directory.
Okay. But you got to be careful because
one mistake which does happen now and
then you you [ __ ] up all your files.
You see this is the Unix people. That's
their word. That's their [ __ ] up. You
know they don't care. You know why? Why
do you have to uh like in Emacs like
spend all these hours thinking about
writing up a command to delete the
backup? the Unix idiot they will say
just just go to shell just go to shell
remove dash f or whatever in the case if
you are in powershell there's similar
command right that that's typically
their their thought flow you know nobody
like in in this this type of people the
vim type of people they they are
thinking you know you are wasting time
why do you need to do that just dive
into shell or in emacs you can press the
command And let me show you what to
press. You know the band self. Uh not
not there, not the band, but the the um
m um was it shift? Uh what is it?
Uh meta.
I don't have the meta key. I don't even
have meta key in my life keys. But what
is it?
Uh
okay. But but we can do meta x coh shell
shell command. Okay, cool shell command,
co-process shell command, co shell
region.
Uh, not that command, but this is a lot
command, you know, you can just call
shop command. Then you type rm-ref
you see that's what these people do. But
then you see, but you see why don't I do
it if it's so good? Well, because it's
got problems. First of all, it's not
visual, you know. First of all, I'm I'm
in this directory, okay? like Emacs
allows you visual clarity. Now I want to
delete all backup files in this
directory that I'm looking at. I don't
want to like type the path. Okay, I'm
looking at this directory. I just want
to delete all backup files in this
directory and all its sub directories.
Okay,
I don't want to think about oh by the
way are you on Unix? Are you on Linux or
are you on Windows? uh it depends on
whether you know which operating system
you are on. Maybe you are on Linux but
not BSD or BSD. BSD fine got the other
options which is not compatible or maybe
you are on Mac OS you have to you know
on Windows doesn't work because if you
are on Windows you on Windows you don't
have the find command the Emacs rely on
the remove the the the remove that Emacs
rely on. So you can do that on Windows
you don't have to worry about that.
That's of idiocy of these Unix people.
You see that's why Emacs what you doing
Emacs for? Because Emacs has everything
is meta X. You should have a command and
you should not have external dependency
depending on other people's [ __ ]
command
which is very problematic which might
delete your whole entire system.
Okay. Mistakes.
So, so that's so that's why you don't
want that. Okay. This e this vi the vim
the vs code idiots.
You don't want that. Okay. That is why
we spending time to write this command.
Okay. And in fact I already have it done
you know but but but
because we are going extra step you know
because we you know this command is
already written like two years ago okay
but I didn't want to have it query the
user like proper list like are you sure
are you sure are you sure before you say
yes are you sure this is the actual
files you need to delete You know I
don't want that. I want to whenever you
call a command you're just done.
Now if you regret it later then you
undo. Press a key to undo. All things
come back. You see that's this these
things are called design. These things
are called the progress. The progress of
humanity. The progress of computer using
the progress of programming languages.
the progress of interface, you know, not
not not like 10 years ago, you don't
have, you know, like you don't have, you
know, like you can't do nothing,
you know, like you you don't have
browsers. You you can't, you know, you
can't have a picture inside a browser
because Unix does not allow it.
Everything must be text only. They don't
allow, you know, what do you mean you
you need a picture? You cannot. It's not
allowed. You know, that's Unix
[ __ ] That's their thought,
you know. Let's let's see a picture.
Okay, so video tutorial. You can't have
videos. Jesus, videos are lawyers. You
know, you you must be text only. That's
Unix [ __ ]
That's why you know, so we have progress
over the past 30 years.
Emacs in it for example. Let's see
pictures. Introduction. Uh, you know, we
need to see some pictures. Wait. So,
where is it? Uh, Emacs in Emacs
tutorial. Download, show version,
launch, exit. Okay. So, let's see. Uh,
change font size. There it is. Oh,
graphical user interface. How do you
change font size? You click on this with
the mouse.
You see the Unix [ __ ] They don't
like the mouse, you know. They they
think, "Oh, the mouse is a problem." You
know, they got lots of problems.
the Unix [ __ ]
Okay, that's a vi that's a Vim user.
That's a vi uh Vim user. On Windows, you
got kind of different different crowd.
Okay, anyway.
So, but but I mean in computing there is
design, there's issue about design.
There is criteria about what is good and
what is bad. There there are different
programming languages and it's not just
oh just use whatever tool that's you
know at hand that's idiots thinks that
okay so in the world there's different
type of people they are those idiots
they just do whatever they do they you
know maybe they make a living good
that's good for them but we are thinkers
I'm a thinker okay I don't I don't want
to like every time I I don't want to
type the RM whatever [ __ ] I want to be
able to press a key to be the most
efficient.
That's that's that's why we are doing
this writing this and and in fact um
creating a different version but
actually we got a problem. So uh but I
started to rant because I'm 30% drunk.
Uh maybe I should get another shot or
something something.
But you see I've been thinking about my
live stream like what am I doing with
the live stream anyway? You know
actually think this is an interesting
question. You see today
um today the the era we are in the AI
era. So let's digress. Okay. the the era
we are in
it's truly it's really a new era. Okay,
this you know what how shall we call it?
It's like a AI era. Okay, perhaps that's
the most fitting word uh AI era. You see
all these are generated by AI. This this
one is about Star Trek. It's amazing
video.
You see AI era. So whenever you have
question why are you watching me? you
know like whenever you have question you
ask AI the AI can like answer all your
questions
so
so there's a lot consequences and
Twitter is kind of becoming code Twitter
is becoming like uh like you don't need
people like you don't need people like
nobody interact with any other so
so there's a lot change in society okay
there's a lot of change in society and
uh
you know so
anyway
okay so I'm saying I'm keep switching
okay so okay yeah so you guys are not
saying anything but okay
so we didn't finish this writing this
code there's some problem
what is the problem I don't know so
eval the buffer let's try it again okay
Why does it say go to a directory call
it TDD max backup do it? Why does it say
like
wrong number of arguments? What?
Oh, so it's getting two arguments.
What?
Okay, this is wrong. Okay. So this
oh there it is because when we we said
you know when this command is called
interactive we give it two argument. The
first one is default directory which is
the file path directory path. Then we
also passed it a true argument T for
true in by Emacs convention. So but
however
the command actually just take one
uh argument because we we removed the
optional you know that's [clears throat]
why okay so that's why CD mistake okay
so this is our old code we commented out
so this is our new code so eval the
buffer again now go to some talk show
drop into the directory
Okay, refresh the buffer. So you got
lots of files. You see you got lots of
files.
Uh 1,600 files. Then now you call delete
emac backup. After we do this, you know
when we call this cancel. Okay. When we
call this, it will move all these backup
files into into the kind of your
personal backup temp directory. Okay.
Let's see. Do it. Do it. Okay. Mistake.
There's error. [ __ ]
God.
What the is wrong number of argument?
What the [ __ ]
What
is that? Uh what? Uh
refresh. Okay. So, we still got error.
What? So,
evaluated. Okay. Make sure it's
evaluated. Oh, wait, wait. You changed.
You didn't change. You need to remove
that. Okay. Now, evaluate the buffer.
Now go to talk show. Now go to the
directory. Now, call it. Now once we
press enter all these backup files will
be moved to to the Emacs uh directory.
Okay do it.
Fantastic. You can you see done moved
all backup files to this directory. So
go to the messages buffer. So you can
see move all files moved there. So now
open that directory. Open it. Fantastic.
Can you guys see? Successful. Okay. So
we did a lot of digressions and rent but
eventually we are successful. You see
you see the next step is to implement a
uh undo.
So you want to you know so that requires
a lot of thinking because in EMAC you
can't you know the normal undo
doesn't fit because the in EMAC the
normal undo is just undo text editing it
does not it's not meant to undo you know
when you move files or or stuff like
that. On the other hand, the similar
situation happens in uh operating
system. For example, on the Mac, you
know, like typically when you undo, you
can undo in text editors or you can undo
in a drawing program like Photoshop,
right? But but on the Mac, you can also
undo like when you moved some file in
the desktop in the Mac f finder. Okay.
on Windows I you I think you can also do
that somewhat. Okay. But on e but in
EMAC when if you want to undo to be able
to undo like moving files
uh that's not expected. Okay.
Because Emacs and do is not like that.
Emac and do only focus on you know text
editing.
So you got this issue. So if you want to
undo this moving files, you need some
kind of um you you cannot rely on the
default undo
command. You need to some kind of new
undo command. Which brings up the
question, do you really want that?
because nobody would know because that's
not a EMAC convention
to have a new undo to undo the moving
files.
If you so if you want that that means
people have to learn about that command
which may not be what you want. Okay. Uh
also if you want to implement that you
also right now you have to you know
because it you you know this directory
doesn't know where these files came
from. So if you really want to implement
and do you need to have
you know you need to have like uh
information about each of these file
where where they came from. Okay so
that's one issue about this command. The
other issue is that you could you know
previously we have seen
uh we have seen the command like move to
trash using the Microsoft Windows
trash.
So we I don't know if that works well.
You know, if it does, then that's a
solution because we can just use the
Windows trash command to
to move files to the trash. And if you
want to undo, you open the trash and you
can like
Windows allows you to put restore, you
know, soal restore the file to the
original location.
Okay, that's one. So for example in
Emacs that command would be
there move file to trash. Okay. So this
is the command uh and it's implemented
here but it's a bit complicated because
it depends on lots of um variables and
and also it depends on the operating
system of course. So if you use this
command, would it work well on Windows
on Mac or on Linux?
For one thing I know is that the window
the Linux trash system is like crap.
Okay, it's like utter crap. Totally
broken the the Linux implementation of
the trash idea. It's complete idiots
the Unix [ __ ] Okay, but anyway,
this is 10 years ago. I don't know,
maybe they improved.
It just doesn't work, you know, on on
Linux when you like put things into
trash.
If you have a lot of files, it takes an
hour to to delete files into the trash
like like takes an hour or if you have
it on a USB stick because that what
that's my experience, you know, you have
lots of files, let's say few hundred
files on USB stick. So you delete them,
they go to trash, right? But then it
takes like an hour to do so like [ __ ]
idiots on Linux. The Linux [ __ ]
you know, like why do I get angry?
Because like usually when you talk to
the Linux people, you know, they they
are tech nerds, right? They say, "Oh,
why don't you do that?" You know, they
know so much about technology, you know?
But actually but but actually the most
simple things like deleting files into a
trash they it's broken. But these people
that they don't mention it they never
mentions it. This Linux [ __ ]
Okay. So so there's this move file to
trash. We can see how it is implemented.
Okay. So in eag so you can see how it's
implemented but also
so you know so okay so it's you know
okay it's fairly complex oh my god you
see how many lines are Jesus uh let's
see what
where is it uh let's do it again copy
the function new file paste it 150 52
lines. Okay. So, emac this mode. Okay.
150 lines to move file to trash. Okay.
And
oh god. You see so it's you see you can
see it's fairly complicated
which means
could be errorrone also you need to
check you know on different operating
system.
So another you know another solution is
that you can you can check you know what
OS you are on and just call PowerShell
you know just call the Microsoft
PowerShell command to move file to a
trash instead instead of relying on the
Emacs implementation
of moving file to trash. So there's lots
of you know like kind of different ways
to implement the thing.
Anyway, so that's the command we have
today.
And uh so now it doesn't ask you for
confirmation anymore. It just move the
all the all the files to the directory.
Okay, I think that's it.
Okay, bye guys.
Okay. So today this is not satisfactory
because um
it just move all the files into the
backup.
Okay, but that's it.
Hello. Uh bye guys.
Bye guys. Bye.
Thank you.