good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of exotic show today is August
today September 8 Sunday
Theo crock p.m. san francisco time and
good morning bathroom you
good morning Xetra good morning Abdo and
so what is today's topics
today's topic is bathroom uses
functional explain functional
programming with JavaScript anything
else anyone else let's see z Truong okay
let's move the window here let's prepare
let's start sauce start command log mod
so you can see all my Emacs commands on
the left window such as cruiser right
moo-coo the right move cosa up down left
forward backward and so on
look at the left window and okay so guys
so explain javascript explain functional
programming with JavaScript concretely
would that be a good topic anyone
everyone so we are good we are good to
go today z Truong hi hello Abdo Abdo was
it you who asked something about yeah
explaining javascript let's go to a talk
show page so type type guys type it's
not Hawk show yesterday show yesterday's
topic so yesterday we did explain
functional programming but most of that
so that was 90 minutes and most of that
is rather not with code but rather about
concepts about you know I'm just
explaining in the air we
the actual code and I exchanged some
history theory code how their
theoretical computer science background
90 minutes you know and by the way
anyone watching this offline you can
always you can always you know when you
watch your video make it speed up one
point two five times usually that's
better for my video
good morning web dog have not seen you
for months you know because I remember
you with a clown face
so wave dog says I abandon you Max and
ma vie s code soy boy now
I heard vs code is pretty good you know
a lot people actually I know there's
another Emacs guy who also abandoned
Emacs and went with vs code so maybe I
should do that
vs code first thing I need to do is to
create X off like he's India's code and
I think it can be done
okay bath Amir says good topic okay
creepy clown face web dog says
functional programming is for people who
pretend to be good at math not really
okay so in that style in that start
style of saying functional programming
is for people who who idolize math but
who don't know nothing about math that
is that is functional programming okay
so actually it's pretty good I I do
functional programming you know I'm a
big fan of functional programming so
okay so let's let's this yeah let's
let's to explain functional programming
with respect to JavaScript then yeah
maybe let's do that so let's see text
topic let's see
Abdo
okay someone else asked about functional
programming with oh it's a guy from
Chile Chile and his name is okay you
know I'm doing video I tried not to be
too verbose in you know wasting time but
that's a long way to go for me I forgot
who said that it's a guy from Chile I'm
pretty sure attached - yes - - says yeah
about JavaScript okay so let's go on
let's go on with the explaining function
of wearing with JavaScript so what what
are we going to explain okay so let's
begin let's start to write our topics
because that way it's more organized so
it's explained functional programming in
JavaScript okay there is a lot to say
about that
and in fact ninety minutes is barely you
know we can cover something in that so
first of all in JavaScript I have some
articles that is about functional
programming so if you go to search for
JavaScript in-depth with my name and
you'll find functions JavaScript
functions this section and there is a
page about functional programming in
JavaScript now this page is about the
very basics so we can actually start
with that and I'm going also to explain
Korean example of
currying in javascript and example of
closure in javascript okay and yeah let
let us get the topics first so we gonna
you know cover them closure
Carine javascript does not have list
comprehension okay
and arranger of currying example
function of programming in JavaScript
okay iterators okay you have iterators
but that's not functional programming
okay so let's just begin then let's
let's see where we go and keep the
comments coming okay comments and
questions if there's anything you are
not sure what i'm talking about or if
you want you know like also sometimes i
forgot a question so oh I forgot where I
was and you know if you want me to go
you know answer that just type it yeah
type type it free D a functional
programming JavaScript okay so okay
javascript function of i mean first of
all javascript is a language that's
javascript javascript is based based on
two languages scheme this itself
javascript is based on scheme Lisp and
language called self okay I don't know
what itself but apparently there are
some foreign language phonetics who are
saying Oh self is a great great language
they trying to tell you to look into all
the time like Julia like some people you
know some people want to tell you about
Julia's and people will say so has cow
you got a learner's going like that I
have a friend or Master Dan who is
telling me about self often anyway I
don't know self ID but I know scheme so
anyway javascript is based on scheme
please
and self skin this is a functional
language of the old times like today
like times change you know today when
people think about functional languages
based and they look at this and this has
lots of mutable variables in fact you
you can barely call list without
variables and also function you know
really you've function returns a
function that's because these some list
technicalities so in this enchanting in
at least common list an eMac base a
function to not you usually do not have
function that returns a function but in
scheme disp that happens often I think
yeah I think so anyway javascript is
based on scheme dispense self and from
scheme Lisp is most of the functional
features in JavaScript came from a
function can take a functional argument
and it can return a function and it has
lexical scoping that all these are firms
scheme B's and as far as I know the firm
self JavaScript got the so called
prototype prototype inheritance system
from self which is the opie prototype
based inheritance system is entirely
different from Java Python Ruby you know
in Java Python Ruby you define your
class then you create a object all those
classes have inheritance you know you
have a you know you define your class
then you can extend it so you got a
different class you know you can so you
eventually you have a tree of classes
you know they have a structure hierarchy
of classes then the class themselves
they do nothing
they are like definitions you know they
just define the classes and then you
create object out of a class those
object are the real thing you work with
so that's that's Java Python and Ruby
and most other in PHP as well that's
class-based from
space Opie object-oriented programming
languages but in JavaScript the opie is
entirely different has nothing to do
with that you know the the Java class at
all it's entirely different it's that's
why it's called prototype based class
system
moaning Seema's so we are taught we are
going to do a functional programming in
JavaScript explaining that so let me let
me go back to JavaScript a little bit so
Jack go to Mike JavaScript in depth and
you can learn about product prototype
paste or P now this is critical like I
talked before in my video and you know
you have to understand this well
JavaScript hope he is entirely different
from Java or Python Ruby so you if you
want to read that you have to read this
object and inheritance this section
object overview object type you know and
stuff so but anyway today we are going
to talk about functional programming
yeah so let's that's so that's the range
of JavaScript based on scheme based in
self and that's why it's JavaScript is
very very functional but not not not so
good because JavaScript has tons of
Watts Watts terms of quotes problems you
know but remember the the guy who
created Jason what's-his-name quak quak
fold Crockford you know his name good
morning Erin Python era's is Python
professors reporting for duty now Aaron
is the number one the number one answer
the guy who answers Python questions on
Stack Overflow
right right so Aaron is the top Python
expert and here I'm just gonna flame
Python all the time anyway so so
javascript is
faison skinless in self okay and so it's
very functional now remember the guy who
created jason who wrote the book who
wrote the book
javascript the good parts cord what's
his name what's his what whatever
crawford who invented jason okay and he
wrote javascript the good parts now this
is about nineteen nine two thousand
seven that is what made javascript
popular because before that javascript
is considered you know hated by hackers
every hacker hated by everyone
JavaScript and Python and PHP are hated
by everyone
so anyway Crawford created JavaScript
the good parts and he is a one he is the
one responsible for making javascript
pop popular you know back back then
together with not J's not years came
after his book he made it popular in
particular functional programming in
JavaScript he he is responsible to kind
of make us small revolution you know
industry so then people started to you
know like the good parts at least the
good parts of JavaScript functional for
me okay so good on you man it's good to
be on top expert so so that's okay so
let's talk about functional programming
JavaScript so let you know I'm just
gonna talk about basics because most
actually most people don't know the
basics so so I was JavaScript function
of who I mean JavaScript okay so here he
is a page okay now I'm going to talk
about it without looking at the page
much but you know after the video this
page will be good notes you know you can
after video then you read you know this
page maybe start to do some code
we'll be wonderful you learn
tremendously you know you have to code
to actually let the stuff sinking so
okay
javascript in so what we're gonna talk
about so okay I'm gonna look at my notes
and talk about it okay so let's create a
JavaScript let's go here okay we're
gonna explain curry we're gonna explain
closure and Korean those are rather
advanced and let's create a JavaScript
page so we can start to write JavaScript
console log 1 plus 3 okay Avada buffer
for okay that's that's javascript now
let's create a function constant arrow
function now this is in JavaScript 2015
so constant arrow function X let's say
return X plus 1 okay that's a function
then you call one three okay you call
the function with three and granite we
saw these four because three plus one is
four now this is arrow function this is
the syntax of our error function on a
left hand you say the argument on the
right hand is the body okay and this
error function is new in 2015
now let's talk about error function well
I'm not going to talk about error
function but here's a page about error
functions so you can read about it our
function you see the basic syntax is is
like that but actually it's slightly
more complicated so okay let me put the
link here it's slightly slightly
complicated for example another way to
write that is let's say let's let's see
return x first one so when you want so
if the body is more than one expression
here the body is just an expression
you know simple you know one one unit
expression but if you wanted to be more
complex then you have to use the curly
bracket then you can do for example you
can say let x equals two
well let's say let y equals 2x first one
and return Y okay run it okay multiple
multiple definition are not allowed
let's do it again
so you see that's the answer for so when
the let when the right side is more
complex then you have to use that syntax
so so it's a bit more the syntax is a
bit more complex and first you can have
destructuring you know parameter
destructuring
and the rest parameters things like that
so read the page if you are not familiar
with error functions so anyway error
functions let's let's just use that
okay so learn it for correct okay good
now a function can take a function as
argument okay and a function can return
a function as argument now first of all
when you code JavaScript and if you want
to do functional programming then it's a
good idea to always use error function
okay if you like functional programming
then in JavaScript always use error
function okay now the alternative of to
our function is the old-school like that
I'm gonna show you okay the alternative
to our function is you say function then
you give a name then you say X then you
say return X plus one okay
now comment that out okay now let's run
it for okay so this this is a
traditional way to define a function but
it's got problems it's got lots of quite
a lot problems it's it's got a it's got
name hoisting problem it's got
functional expression versus declaration
problem it's got nested function problem
it's got argument object problem lots of
problems you can read about those
problems in in this section defining a
function in this section function
so here's this page explains how do you
define functions so error function is
good then the keyword function is not so
good you got lots of issues you can read
in detail so there are so many many
pages about that it's hard to explain
you know it takes a twenty minutes to
explain because javascript is very
convoluted so if you like functional
programming do not use this and also let
me mention you know in in industry code
if you work in a company then everyone
is gonna use this you know you you you
you can't just go your own way and do
everything functional because in
JavaScript in you know the code in the
industry everything is object you got
this you know everything you you know so
that's the thing but if you know but but
functional programming techniques is
also frequently used so in industry code
you will see this almost all the time
but you will also see error function so
that's what I'm going to explain this
part so we move that okay so let's go
back so yeah functional programming to
use our functions okay that's good for
you now now let's let's see explain
let's explain one more thing so function
function function taking argument taking
function as argument okay
we're gonna explain that so let's here's
a function its name it f1 and let's
create another function constant error
function let's say f2 now let's say x f2
equals 2 what are we doing we want to a
function that takes another function as
argument so ok so let's let's do this so
this function f2 we are take a function
we will take a 1 R 1 argument F ok and
it will return
it will return whatever F evaluated at
three so you see what I'm saying so this
function we just defined a function it
has a variable F and the return value is
f applied to three okay now we're gonna
call it so let's call it constant
console.log which is for print we call
f2 and we give a we give it a argument
an argument is f1 so f1
you see we defined here FY is a function
let's see what it returns it returns for
UC so this is an example of example of
function taking another function as
argument okay so this cop let's delete
that close that and let's put it put the
code here so showing browser there it is
you know that's an example of function
taking an argument as a function now let
me show you a function returning a
function as a function returning a
function example okay
oh these are fundamental basic
functional programming techniques so you
have to know it function taking an
argument function as argument function
and function returning a function as
argument this is all critical and in
fact in JavaScript is used every day
every every project you'll see it used
hundred hundreds of times every 500 line
so you know every 200 lines you will see
one example of such you know function
taking argument as function and function
returning or function and oh and why why
is this critical because when you talk
about more more advanced concept like
careening like crochet although an
function composition all those involves
these function taking a function as
argument or function which returns a
function
as a result okay they all involve these
so you have to kind of master these
basics so let me show you an example of
function returning a function so so
let's open a that's defining a function
again constant arrow function so we want
a function return a function so okay so
let's say let's say gg gg ok let's say
the function takes one argument okay and
it returns a function okay so so so
let's say we turn okay we turn arrow
function oops
our function okay we turn you see we
return a function expression right here
and this return function will be a
function that takes no argument and it
returns X first one let's say for
example so do you guys understand what
this code is doing we just defined a
function G G okay this function G G and
this G G takes one argument okay one
parameter and it's body basically just
immediately return a function you see
this is a function error function it
returns a function this function takes
no arguments is X plus 1 so what will
happen if we call GG 3 you know type it
guys I wait for your answer okay before
I run it let me let me read the comments
I diversified my approach and here got
hired but then went deep
he's area like a lambda yes error
function is just like a lambda exactly
yes six arrow function our lambdas yes
yes indeed nice I had forgotten I need
to learn Java scream or some page my
teach me yeah check check out my my my
tutorial thank you guys and you know if
you like it post it you know that's how
that's how you become popular on Google
you know such or other search engines
okay web dog posted these
incomprehensible thing let's see what
that is by the way anyone knows the
answer what happens if you call GG well
that's probably too basic you know I
shouldn't
that's too basic also a web dog says
what is this just five bind okay this is
a this is what's called interpret a you
know that that's inter interpreted
string so just five find a just bind I
don't know what that is what is just how
implementation of just left us and I
exercise to the reader okay so anyway
that's probably something advanced I'm
not going to cover not gonna talk about
it let's continue on you know we got our
finish oh it's a monad okay that's
interesting that I'll check it out later
okay we gotta we gotta finish a lot of
things here so so this so this will
return for you know obviously let's run
it oh it returns a function oh wait wait
wait wait so you see right GG returns a
function obviously but the thing is you
now since GG is a funk
you have to eat you have to code you
know give you a argument and have it
evaluate so let's do it so that's how
you do it so if I run it you see the
answer is four you see okay let me let
me repeat this okay so G G is a function
okay
example of a function that returns a
function okay G G is a function it takes
one argument and it returns this
function and this function basically
just add one to the argument so now we
call gg
you know when you call GG 3 it actually
return a function for example we can
show type of okay you see it says a
function you know the type is of a type
of function for example let's do this
equals through vennett
you see it says true so what Gigi
returns is a function now we have to
call that so that that is why we have
this line we we have it this line okay
let me show you this this so this is
this returns for
okay so you see all returned true so so
okay so so this is an example of
function returning a function okay let's
put it here color at showing browser
okay now a function taking our argument
and function returning or argument all
critical things now what what are the
other things we want to talk about midsi
arrow function okay you learn arrow
function apply a function to a value
that's simple you just put the
parentheses after it you know that's how
you call a function yeah let's show this
this should is you know because usually
when you type in real-time people get it
more deeply than otherwise
so console.log create a arrow function X
X plus 1 and so that is a function now
we want to apply that function to three
then you just put a parenthesis 3 ok
then returns 4 that's how you that's a
general way to apply a function you know
meaning you code a function with the
argument you know just like just like
the traditional F 3 you know that just
like that so this is a applying a
function by putting a parent to the
right of it applying a function that is
colle okay so that's that's that put it
here okay that's that's how you call a
function now let's see function type is
a function we don't care about that
assigning a function to a variable
that's also critical okay oh these are
fundamental so so let's let's do that
okay actually we showed many example of
that here already because you see you
see error function is a function
expression it's lambda you know it's an
expression so you can actually assign it
to a variable you know
functioning is a value just like any
value you assign it variable so you see
you can see here let me go over a
tangent a little bit you see functional
programming in your sense is very simple
you know it's you just have concepts you
know very small concept and you you
combine all those concept to create
programs so here we see that we have the
concept of a function then you have the
concept of assigning something to a
variable and obviously then you can
combine them so you are assigning a
value to a to a variable name and this
variable name now it becomes a function
you know so this in a sense this is
actually a simple simple idea you know
in programming as opposed to you know
you have function function function and
function declaration you know definition
declaration like defend or something
like that or then you code but so so
once you have lambda if you know it's
most it's simpler in that sense you just
compose concepts so okay so that's about
assigning a function to variable okay
then function and function returning a
function we showed a example of that
function taking a function as argument
we show the example of that and function
composition okay now here is starting to
become advanced now in order to do this
you have to be thoroughly familiar with
you know be comfortable with the
function on returning but functional
taking function as argument so this
function composition is the you know the
most fundamental you know after after
after what we just expand you know
function composition its using math
everywhere so you have function
composition then you have closure you
have currying you have Y Combinator's
now the white Combinator is the most
complex and theoretical it's actually
useless
it's 100% useless useless in actual
programming but you know that's how
the Y Combinator the the startup you
know the program website is named after
Y Combinator so by the way I I did a
video about the new kind of science
where I explained some of these things Y
Combinator that that is a good one for
those of you guys who YouTube who are
interested in in this computer science
related subjects a new kind of science
cellular automata lambda calculus Turing
machines Y Combinator so that is last
week or five days ago just such for a
new kind of science where is it
UNIX pestilence science tech growth plan
curves
keyboard UNIX pestilence language as a
centricity scientific programming here
math languages scientific programming
new kind of science this is this is
August 28th okay so that's that's good
to check out
so in okay so okay 35 minutes so let's
explain function composition okay let's
create a new JavaScript that's function
composition example okay so we want
function composition so what we want to
do so first of all yeah what what we
want to do what is the goal of function
composition the function composition is
you have a function constant area
function so let's say F okay let's say
this okay let's let's stick with X plus
1 okay so here's a function it just add
1 ok let's create another function let's
say it minor minus 1 so when you have
functions like you want to call okay
let's call them call F ok so let's call
F 3 okay now you want to okay here's the
thing
you see you are calling F 3 now and
after that you got a result you want to
feed that without to G and get a new
result let's see what we get
we got three you know it's like doesn't
do nothing because 3 plus 1 is 4 4 minus
1 is 3 so it returns 3 now you when you
call a function take its output and feed
it to another function that's very
common because the in function remember
in functional programming that's all you
have you functional program is committed
to parts function definition the in
function call that that should be the
whole entire entirety of your program
different functions call them that
should be it ok no object no inheritance
no nothing
define functions and call them
when you do functional programming like
that one pattern that comes up you know
all the time is that is sequencing of
functions like these you know because
once you call a function you've got a
value what do you do with that value of
course you you wanted to feed it to
another another function that's that's
functional form I mean that's that's you
know so these patterns happens all the
time so now there's a new idea what what
if you can create a new function let's
say F G let's say H that is the
combination of F and G you know like
like this example you know if you know
function change in a sense you call a
function change so you can so you can
define it like this okay so let's do
that so constant arrow function we
cannot define H and H is gonna take two
arguments let's say X Y okay takes two
arguments and what we want to do is
actually so simple let's let's just
write it here so let's just write it
it's like like this okay
yep that's almost that's it okay that's
it I think that walk
so you see G H is a function that takes
two arguments now these two arguments
are both supposed to be functions and
what it returns it returns you know one
function feed into you know taking
output of one function feed it into
another actually this is not right we
need we need an argument here let's say
let's let's cheat a little bit let's
just say let's put in here okay let's
just make this walk so any any questions
any comments let me okay let me finish
this you know keep the questions coming
okay is there so far so good so so let's
run this okay so let's run this and see
what happens so let's we are going to
call we are we are going to call
console.log okay H and and give it F and
G and give it three okay run it it
returns three as he expected okay so
this is an example of functional
function composition but actually it's
not pure because because because we got
in here originally what we wanted is a
function that originally what we wanted
wanted is a function that takes two
other functions and returns a new
function this new function will be
equivalent to you know to calling the
two functions combined okay we can do
that so let's try it again so let's so f
so f takes two arguments both of them
supposed to be functions and it needs to
return a function so I have to think I
have to think about it okay so let me
think about it so why is X x and y are
functions h2 needs to return a function
so so Y is a function okay so there's a
way I can do it but
so so any questions so far make any and
you know it's
okay so let's get back to these so let
me just okay maybe walk out walk this
out then so H 2 H 2 is H 2 is a function
that takes two functions ok give me give
me a minute ok
takes two functions and returns a
function so it needs to return a
function and this new function is x and
y combined so Y is a function so this
function we needs to so actually so one
way to do it is like this okay
so one way to do it is create a arrow
function so arrow function let's say
let's change your name because because
it's more clear this way more intuitive
so takes two functions F and G and
returns a function and this function
will be yeah that'll work
this function will be F and G combined
okay that that should work so you see we
got a nested function situation here
so you see h2 is a function and here is
its definition it's an error function
and it takes two arguments both are
supposed to be functions and here is the
body of h2 and the body is actually
another function you know so we got a
nested function happening here you see
this is another feature of functional
programming language you should be able
to define nested functions so it returns
you know a new function this new
function takes one argument and yeah
that should work okay so let's do it
so what we're gonna do here is call
console.log
actually it's oops let's just copy this
console.log FG okay first of all let's
say yeah let's just write
nan nan is not a number this is
incorrect oh yeah oh wait we should say
h2 okay now let's try it again
correct you see it returns a function H
to here returns the function let me do
this okay
type of type of that equals to function
okay
donate it's true let's do this equals to
three
okay its own or return true now f2 is
correct it takes two functions and it
returns a function so far so good now we
want to see actually let's let's put it
this down it's a matter of trivial style
I first about them all the time you know
sometimes I feel this is a better way
and other times I feel the old comments
should be you know below the function so
I I do that you know all the time on my
tutorials so anyway so f2 is a function
now what we do is we give it a value I
mean we apply it remember how to apply a
function you just put a parenthesis and
you put 3 and the result should equal to
3 let's run it true great so we actually
so this is a success so actually so
let's take out edge here let's just
replace that take out edge we don't need
edge here yep ok let's put it here
showing browser so that's that's a
function example of function composition
so no comments so so so far so good
comments guys comment
okay so so now let's move on to let's
move on to great okay great thank you
thank you AB da okay hi hi
spinal camp so we we did we actually we
finished this page about the most basics
of functional programming now we can
explain we can go on we can go on and
explain Crozier and Karine okay we can
go on and explain Karine let's do Karine
so why not use mock down I don't use
markdown oh I don't use smock I don't
use lockdown I don't use egg mod I
because I being hand hand manually
writing HTML since 1996 so I am so used
to it and with the help of Emacs and my
own dev you know commands you know so it
works perfectly for me I don't use
markdown so I use HTML you know you know
like like 10 years ago there's
tremendous controversy like like HTML
versus markdown and by the way before
mark town becomes the universal standard
there are many many many different
so-called light markup systems you know
I don't remember the names even but if
you go to Wikipedia you go to markdown
page you can start to see all the others
ok it's it's kind of good now because
now everyone is like markdown org mod if
you are Emacs fan but back then you know
there are all these and it's
controversial and I'd like hackers talk
about it all the time you know yeah pen
doc 10 doc is one of them you know they
talk about it you know there are so many
different variations of light markup
and even today you have for example it
let me show you okay I started to
digress but I'll get back right away so
if you see for example sock code go to
programming actually go to a hacker code
then you go to the bottom you see search
for mark down wait what mark
history death persons new software tech
okay new software tech stuff and locks
lots of stuff yeah I don't know so it's
just so sorry markdown I'm gonna get
back to the function of who I mean just
in a second this this this is gonna be
just one minute so mark now I have a
tutorial here then you are see Hammer
hammer
sass llamo slim oh this crap you know
they are all markup languages they all
try to do some you know they think they
are good very popular even today you
know they come and go you know some son
becomes very popular then not so much
you know so hammer is one of them Hema
is for kind of translates to HTML yes a
template for HTML then you have sass for
CSS SAS has two versions because you
know the things change they have two two
versions one is based on Python syntax
so maybe you like it error so what so
SAS you know is SAS is for CSS okay it's
an alternative syntax for CSS but it has
two versions over the years not now they
have two versions one is based on like
Python you know in indentation then the
other one is based on like CSS you know
with brackets then you have llamo llamo
is another one based on Python syntax
you know I don't like the indentation
syntax I have a lot to say about that I
have Alico about that then you have slim
slim is another intent ation syntax for
HTML okay so you know so that's about
that and and also all these are kind of
some of these are actually Rio there's
also must most mustache like I think if
you are in Ruby community you have a
bunch of more you know and very popular
too but even before all these they are
quite a lot other map mark light markup
for example there's a BBS when PHP is
ruling the world
everything is PHP you have the what I
think it's called BB bulletin board
markup that's based on PHP syntax yeah
okay so there are so many you know I you
know I I I'm just used to HTML I stick
to a simple version of HTML and and I
don't I don't use Oakmont much okay
let's let's get back to JavaScript bits
let's start with the Korean okay Korean
in JavaScript okay so so what is Korean
okay so so first of all curry is
decomposing function that has multiple
parameters into a sequence of function
functions each with only one parameter
okay that's that that is the concept of
Korean and in programming languages such
as Haskell and Oh camel ml standard ml F
sharp
they all have Korean building that is
whenever you define a function that
involves more than one argument
it automatically decomposed them into a
sequence of functions each one only have
one argument so when you call these
functions like chain them together it's
equivalent to the original function with
multiple arguments that's that's what
currying is so in fact in languages like
Haskell and DoCoMo they they technique
they don't they don't allow you to
define a function of more than one one
one parameter because at heart
at the core of a language you know you
only have function with one argument and
why is that why is that good because
fear because of theoretical computer
science okay we are not going to get
into about that but let's let's show an
example of Korean JavaScript
now of course javascript does do not
support automatic Korean you have to do
it manually so let's show example so
constant arrow function let's define an
error function again let's say two
argument and let's say we return X plus
y okay
now that's a function with two arguments
say three and four and we return seven
returns seven true okay and now we want
to curry that is we want to we want to
write two functions F 1 and F 2 such
that when they are each one has only one
argument and such like when they are
code in sequence they are 100%
equivalent to these FF so let's do that
okay concern arrow function f1 ok so how
do we do that it's very easy okay so so
when you actually do it you have to
think you have to think a little bit
yeah handle bar is another another
example of the you know the mark up
language template that converts to HTML
handlebars very accomplished programmer
but he's a creature of his ok yeah there
are so many of these marker light markup
languages ok so let's get back to this
so we want to write two functions F 1
and F 2 such that such that when when
coding sequence they are equivalent to F
F so so let's make F 2 F 2 should return
a function ok so this you know this
needs to you have to think about it
which is you know this is how you learn
functional programming when you when you
really want to understand curving and if
you are you know if you are using
Haskell or camel you know you read about
curving and but it's all automatic you
don't really get it you kind of get it
but you don't because it's automatic you
know but when you actually use a
language such as JavaScript that does
not do it automatically you try too many
you know code it yourself that's when
you're actually really the the concept
sinks sinks in you realize you know what
you like you you will run into many
errors like syntax errors semantic
errors but once you get it once you
eventually you'll get it then you you
know you learn a lot that way so so
right now I'm like stuck it's fine to
think about how how you do this so two
functions so f 2 so what we want first
of all let's see what let's let's show
you what what we want to do so the
result should be this is what we expect
okay
so f 2 we call F to give you an argument
then we call F 1 then
why and it will equals to this is a
result this is the desired result we
want
so F X Y so instead we have F 2 we call
F 2 X then result feed it to F 1 yes and
and F 1 takes a argument of why that
should be equals to that okay so so
first of all this is kind of the spec so
f 2 so now we know what F 2 should do so
f 2 take an argument and returns a
function it returns a yes it which it
should return a function wait
yes so f 2 should return a function f 2
takes the argument and return a function
okay Ariel the function will
like that okay the wipe for this one
something something like that so f2
takes a takes a value takes a value of x
and it returns a function this function
will take a value and first press first
X right first X that's right
so here so that's right so that's that's
f2 now when you give f2 now now this
result which is a function will be neat
we'll need to go into the input of x1
okay so here the the we've got we'll
need to go into the input of F 1 so f1
will take a variable which is a function
f and it will return actually
yeah
so f1 will take ff1 will take a function
oh yeah so f1 will take a function and
f1 will also return a function that's
right here'll function because you can
see here you see the result of f1 should
be a function because we are going to
feed it why there so f1 will return a
function what this function will be that
easy ok so it will be like this so yoko
f it will co f with the input of
he will return a function
yeah I'm getting CD this is probably if
I rehearsed if I rehearsed your walk oh
this is that right so app to have to
give a answer right away equals to is
that right
maybe you are right but I have to think
about that well if I you know it's like
the they are two branch of thinking if I
focus each one you know let me just
continue my my own thinking here so okay
so let's just try this see if that works
let's see if y equals to Y is a function
I don't think that work you know this f1
equals to Y is argument Y okay so let's
run it let's see what happens so here
let X equal to three okay let y equal to
four okay
let's just write let's see what happens
yeah I don't think that's you know
there's some syntax error we need to fix
yeah that after some fix your work but
it's similar to that so f1 needs to f1
takes a function at C f1 takes a
function and f1 should return a function
that takes one argument so you turn a
function that takes one argument maybe
maybe that okay maybe that oh it worked
okay moonbase also give you answer I
don't let me just get on with the the
way I have it here okay so I so now it's
successful so this F F is a function
that takes two arcs and now we want we
define two functions F 1 and F 2 okay
such that such that such that this is
true you know when we call F 2 with one
argument then we feed it to F 1 then we
give it it another argument then it will
equal to F F X Y so this is true so
let's change you know any value it's
true so that's so great so success you
know that that's an example of currying
you know meaning the composition
function with multiple arguments into a
sequence of functions each one takes
only one argument you see this this
function only have one argument this
function only have one argument
so that's Kareem cut it place it here
syntax color it and we have today's
notes you know all these we cover today
i have you know i have them i have
written tutorials here in detail how
long have have I been talking so you
know one one in seven minutes so you
know you guys can actually read it here
and also about Korean about Korean let's
go to my I think I have a tutorial let's
see let's go to prom in job ins and go
to Korean yeah so I have a example in
Mathematica in email is in Perl in
JavaScript
you know so I have those examples okay
so we covered actually I think this is
pretty good I think it's really good you
know these things you know again
currying is not actually practical so in
JavaScript actually you don't use it you
know you never almost never use it even
in industrial coding even if you like
functional programming very much that's
something you don't use you know because
currying is for decomposing function
into function with just one argument why
you want to do that it's only because
theoretical computer science advantages
and like like in Haskell you know they
want to they want you know in Haskell
case in a case of Haskell or meta
language you know okay mo F sharp they
do that because so you know they are
type you know strictly typed language so
so it would be simpler so every function
is just one argument every function is
only one argument that's simply because
one argument you know each argument has
types so you can so you reason so
whenever you have a function with you
know three arguments let's say it's
common you know if you want to plot a
function or surface you know or math
functions you have you have you know a
function has many arguments you know you
can you can rewrite them so it they
become you know functions each one each
with only one argument you just chain
them together so and and and from a
logical point of view it's much easier
to reason you know you have what type it
is
it becomes what type you know you know
you have that's that's why historian
DoCoMo they have that but you know in
practice they you know that's only for
theoretical advantages in practice you
don't you don't do that manually
they are like occasional reasons to do
that but you know let's not get into
that
you know typically that you you just
don't do that so that's about Kareem and
but the composition and other things
functional functional returning a
function nested function and function
taking argument that's all critical and
in fact you you have seen actually we we
used all of those things when we want to
do composition and when we want to do
Kareem you know we have nested function
we have function return function and
function taking an argument function
that's all that all happened that's very
practical and then there's another thing
about closure I don't know if I should
go into that closure again you know in
my opinion it's no good you shouldn't do
that
let me put this link here closure so
anything else guys so so should we go
over closure Oh what else like one hour
and 10 minutes so 70 minutes now
anything else
mooom bass snails handlebars
so what else so which type of Emax
format do you use I use the one from the
you mean what distribution let's go to
my Emacs blog practical Emacs where to
download and on this page you have you
know I'll tell you where to download you
know you have Windows versions
precompiled Windows versions Mac
versions and Linux the one I use is is
this one Mac Emacs for Mac OS X I just
use that one they have a new version
right now it's 26.3 that just came out
last week I think
and right now my version is 26.2 yeah so
I need to upgrade ok let's let's let's
cover the closure then just for wait ok
so let me think what what's important
about functional programming Emacs well
blog closed it sat up show
ok so functional programming in
JavaScript what else are important arrow
functions yes our functions
closure so okay so let's go - crow shirt
let's go to closure closure so go to
programming jargons go to closure here
is a page that explains closure oh I
already showed it okay so it's already
linked here so you have closure in
JavaScript you have closure in Python 3
Python 2 does not have closure you
cannot do it you have to do it in Python
3 and then you have closure in : so what
is closure closure is comments guys
comment I'm you know maybe closure like
I explained yesterday so so okay so let
me finish then just let me explain
closure then that's that
there'll be it for today so closure
there are a lot confusions and Miss
informations on closure and closure is
one of the thing that programmer hackers
types you know they chanted all the time
just like just just like the other
jargons we talked about yesterday
you know closure Marcos monad tail
recursion currying you know they blow
the you know you hear these other
promotions every day on social networks
on Hacker News on reddit you know it's
like and also like Turing machine Turing
completeness you know is crap oh crap
because those are fairly advanced
concepts you you have to really know the
basics very well to actually appreciate
them and and most of them all these
jargons mentioned so far they are many
of them are not practical okay
they are not practical things but anyway
closure okay so let's talk about closure
closure so what is closure closure is a
programming feature okay so there are
many
nation's many different definitions one
of the most critical definition I would
say the most correct perspective a
closure is that closure is a programming
language feature okay this isn't
important
closure is not some particular function
probe culture is not some particular
programming technique although in some
perspective you can say it's a
programming technique or idiom okay you
could say that and closure is not okay
so most importantly closure is actually
a programming language feature okay and
what what what is this feature it is it
is a feature that results from well I I
talked about this yesterday you know for
ten minutes
so and let me so okay let me finish like
in the in decisions
okay so closure is a programming
language feature how does this feature
came from it came from three things one
is lexical scoping okay one is nested
definition of functions you know nest
nested functions which we just we showed
some examples of nested functions so
lexical scoping nested functions and
functions that returns a function these
three things okay lexical scope nested
functions definition and function that
returns a function when you have all
these three features in a programming
language then something strange happens
that is when you have a function that
has a nested function and when this when
this function returns this nested
function what happens to the function to
the return function when that function
actually cause a variable uses a
variable that is
not in the nested function okay this may
appear complicated it is actually that's
why it's a that's why there's a lot
missing there's understanding but we're
gonna explain it okay we cannot explain
it with code so remember next next
lexical scoping okay first of all you
need to have neck lexical scoping then
you need to have a nested function then
you need the function to return a
function that is basically returned this
nested function was the value of this
function and also this when this nested
function actually uses a variable that's
that's not local to it it actually uses
a nested a variable that is part of the
outer function okay when all this
happens and so so when all this happens
when you call this function it returns a
function which returns this nest this
function there is a curious question
what will happen to the value of the
variable you see because this seems to
be a paradox because on one hand this
variable of the result function is not
local to the nested function it's not
local it's it you know it's the variable
is actually defined in the outer
function but however the outer function
is kind of good because the outer
function finished you know it returned
the nested function so you know my hand
you know this variable is already gone
you know the value is no oh ohnio you
know in whatever language you know Neil
you know what it is good but on the
other hand you have lexical scoping so
lexical scoping is supposed to capture
the variable that this okay remember
remember this this is the context this
is the context and the origin of the
concept of closure and and this happens
in the context of designing programming
language that is you you are a you know
you are a you are designing you are
creating a programming language and you
run into
this problem because you know when you
are a functional programmer you are
creating your own greatest language you
know you want lexical scoping yes you
want to be able to have a function with
nested definition depth nested function
yes you want that because that's nice
because sometimes a function you know
you want inner functions that's only
used by this function you know so that
feature is nice you want to have that
but you also want to be able to have a
function that returns a function you see
that's that oh you are you want all that
but now you got a problem what happens
when user return a function that's
nested but it actually use a variable
that's not local you got this problem so
that is the region of closure so what
what is a choice of closure closure
basically the return function we are we
all maintain the variable value wheels
will be there we all still exist even
the outer function is gone so so does
that make sense that that that is the
origin of closure okay so so let me we
are going to go into code in a moment so
but so so some remember crucial is first
of all it is a program programming
language feature okay
it is a feature meaning that some simple
main language will not have it like if
you do you know like what we said you it
will behave
you know badly you're not have the the
behavior you expect so so first first of
all remember this is a programming
language feature then after you
understand that
then in a programming language such as
JavaScript
it supports closure when you when you
code that and you return you know you
have a function that returns a nested
function you could call that closure you
know so you can say oh this function is
a closure so in this aspect in this
perspective you can say closure is a
technique of
functional programming is it's kind of a
technique or or a specific function you
can call it a closure but but remember
these are just different aspect
originally what it really is is a
feature is a particular feature of
programming language and it's about a
function that returns a function with
the lexical environment okay so let's
show some example of JavaScript that
that is a closure okay so I hope did I
do well on that I hope I did it's it's
you know it's slightly complex because
when you get into advanced functional
programming this happens a lot this kind
of the you know convoluted thing happens
a lot and one of the greatest example of
this happening is Y Combinator you know
you can try you know like try try to go
to Wikipedia try to read about Y
Combinator it is very hard to understand
you know because you have function that
returns a function that takes a value
somewhere that you know it's very hard
to understand so closure is kind of a
similar thing but it's not too hard once
you you know once you look you know
persist and know it so let's try let's
create a function let's create a closure
in JavaScript
okay first of all create a function
that's let's use our function it's
always use a function so f constant
arrow function f f is a function that
takes no argument let's say let's say
it's well actually it's easier just to
copy what I have here because that's
save time you know it's save time let's
just copy it so prepare to creative
closure so here we have a function named
Gigi so here's a function body and
inside the function we declare a local
variable X and then we declare another
function nested function you see F F is
a function and this function uses the
local variable X you know the variable
outside of the function it uses that and
it just returns let's not use that let's
just say X first one X first one okay it
just returns X first one I mean just
increment X okay it increment X so if F
is a is a inner function then this
function simply returns it returns to F
F okay now now when you call GG GG is
this function okay now you call it and
you and what is the value it its value
is a function remember because it
returns a function so now it returns a
function and you will assign that
function to CC okay now see C is a
function now if you call C see what
happens
let's analyze okay when you call CC when
you call CC what if what is the value of
CC the value of CC is the value of
coding GG and what is the value of GG
well the value of GG
is f basically this inner function okay
so when you call CC it is actually like
calling F F here you know it's calling
this function and what happens if you
call that function let's let's try to
see what happens so when you co f f it
increments x by 1 so X is our internally
zero so so now the result is 1 you see
then when you call CCU again it
increments X again it becomes 2 and when
you call it again it becomes 3 okay so
let's try it okay so you see it's all
true so this works out you see so so
that's closure okay now remember this is
no longer functional programming you see
this CC because remember functional
programming is about function without
side effects meaning that every function
its output entirely depends on the input
the arguments now this CC is not that
like that because each time the argument
is no argument but now the output is
different every time you call it so this
is CC is not a function it's not a pure
function it's not a function it is it is
actually a function with side effect
which is not a function at all in a
strict sense so it's it's it's very bad
it's anti functional programming so
that's why I say never use closure you
know some people you know they they say
oh I love closure that's all crap the
moment the moment you use closure is it
ceases to become functional programming
you are in fact you know doing anti
functional programming ok and also let
me mention crucial is the ancien of
object-oriented programming ok remember
first of all you need lexical scoping
then you need function with nested
function definition like
that you know we we should allow you
know the the programming language must
allow miss the definitional functions
okay as a feature then you need the
ability for function to return a
function you need these three then what
happens what happens when you do a
function that returns a function that
uses a variable that's that's in the
outer function that's closure when this
happens you have a crucial situation
okay this crucial is the origin of
object-oriented programming in fact what
we you have what you have here CC this
CC is now a class like Java Java Ruby
Python okay what you have is actually
now a class okay and this X is the is
the data is that what they call you know
static variable is either class variable
or instance variable dim it depends okay
so anyway so what I'm saying so here is
you know you can see that closure is the
origin of object-oriented programming in
fact this this gigi is actually a class
and this CC is actually a object you
know you when you when you call it when
you do this CC equals to Gigi this is
called instantiation okay this is called
creating an object so it's idiocy from
from from this point ants from this
point on so that is why I say don't you
know the kosher is no good closure is
the antithesis of functional programming
and that should conclude on that now
that concludes today's talk show
functional programming in JavaScript
concrete explanation of functional
programming with JavaScript
okay so let me with me the comment and
that'll be it
so if you have a comment stab it now and
we're gonna shut down in one minute
so era hoses closure when a function
closes over a variable you know auto
function scope and can later use those
variable even when not in outer function
scope yes yeah so you are doing great
cuz I just started watching and I
thought you said closure was a
programming feature and was very
confused yeah crucial you know you know
the crucial language you know that this
language closure they borrowed the term
closure I suppose yeah you know I don't
like it
you know the rich Hickey you know I
suppose you know why would he do that
because because you see you see a
paradox here because on one hand which
he key he is very much into functional
programming you know he loved functional
programming in fact he want to closure
is you know his language is most about
immutability functional data structures
you know no no no change of values so
anyway he loved functional programming
but however he named his language
closure you know Papa you know it's a
it's kind of like a pun to the closure
concept it's a pun so that's a very
annoying to me you know wait where the
you do that you know you talk to
that and you know in an enclosure the
language you know closure base for the
language I suppose actually they
actually I'm not sure they actually
encourage the closure thing and I don't
know if they do that or not but the name
is just annoying sabatham you says
what's really common and useful real
world example for closures and returning
don't spell it wrong remember okay
remember closure with s not J okay
closure is not CEO J you are ye okay
kosher kosher is not J okay
let's emphasize okay so what's so
perform you say is what's really common
and useful real world example of closure
and returning function okay remember
those are two different things this is
important bathroom you so when you have
a function that returns a function this
is critical this is fundamental and this
is useful this is used all over the face
every day in every project function that
returns a function okay now don't
confuse it with closure closure is a
when you have a function that returns a
nested function and and it also uses a
outer functions variable okay so it's
kind of kind of complicated and it's you
know so when you have that that is
crucial okay now if you want to do
functional programming you don't use
that you are some people too okay okay
it's like depends on your opinion okay
but this is very different from just
function returning function functioning
function that returns a function a this
is useful used everywhere but function
returning a function such that that
function uses some other variable outer
function that's not good that's not
functional programming okay people do
use that for you know people do use so
white wise closure use useful closure is
useful because you use that to implement
object-oriented programming you know
that that is a major use every
object-oriented you know function of you
know like Java Python they are you
actually basically they are doing
closures and all of them they are doing
closure okay so that is why closure is
useful but that's not functional
programming okay
yeah so in other words crochet is just a
function that maintains state and in
fact that that's what you do not want to
do in functional programming functional
programming a function you know you
don't want to have a state never yeah
okay damn marketing yeah Hesperia oh
yeah so
so we remember bathroom you remember
it's very different
okay closure and function on returning
function when you have a closure you use
all these features you use the feature
of lexical scoping you use the feature
of nested functions you use the feature
of function that returns a function
oh these three when you use them
together in certain way you have this
kind of thing called closure okay that's
that
don't confuse don't confuse it with on
you know all the different features of
functional programming yes Thomas if you
you know yeah you know what I explained
this enough times I think with many
repetitions yes every class Java class
is kind of so-so closure is or ancient
of object-oriented programming in the
style of Java because when you have a
closure that's a class you know iid
explained that so that's that's about
that okay so bathroom use says show me
one of the most common and useful
example for function returning a
function we just showed many examples we
just showed for example in Java in for
example a functional program in Java
Script we showed composition right when
we showed when we showed composition we
need to have a function that returns a
function you know so that's an example
and when we showed when we showed
closure that also happened you know we
need function that returns a function
they are not used you know in JavaScript
okay so you are asking what's the common
use beside this they are a lot use of
function return a function is over the
place for example in JavaScript in
industrial code
you have things like you have things
like no especially in in callback
functions you know in typically they
call it callback functions function
taking an argument that we you know
functions taking another function as
argument in JavaScript a mother
industrial coders they call that
callback function why is it useful
because especially is used in notches
because then you have promises you know
once you kochiyama skip you know like
once you get into you start to color our
JavaScript you your your your C it's
everywhere
you know it's everywhere yeah real world
example okay so real world example well
okay well the easiest real world example
let's go to my one of my packages name
we all see it let's see yeah so yeah
good question so let's go to let's go
through the let's go to Sartre okay so
this is my
okay show is showing qualms so this is
my package that does plot with
JavaScript Dom in SVG I talked about
this a few times for example this this
code this code is this page and it you
know this is the code and it needs to
JavaScript code and the code is just
okay here's the library and this is a
code you just say parametric plot you
know two parametric plot that just
generate these sign prods but the
library
this is library and is uses typescript
you know typescript and it's 500 lines
so we need to check do I have a function
that returns a function I'm not sure I
do but that's such okay so all these are
function definitions we want to see a
function that returns a function
I don't think I have it here but you
will you know it's like okay for each
wait wait
yeah for each you okay it's here here
it's used in for each all the time
basically every time you use map and for
each yeah that's a that's a except that
actually answer the question you know
about the map right let's show an
example okay let's go back to my sock
page go to today's talk and common most
common example of function taking a
function is in map and for each wherever
you call that that actually you know
this a function that takes a function
because map is a function for each user
function and their argument is a
function okay so this is most this is
the yeah this is absolutely this is
probably the most used example of a
function that takes a function well but
what about a function that returns a
function yeah okay so there's another
example let me show you function that
returns a function okay first of all let
me show a function that takes an
argument let me show you example of map
in for each
okay so anyway so web dog has some
answers probably real-world example okay
so we award the example let's say let's
let's demo map okay
so constant constant so let's say a is
array let's say 1 2 3 4 okay I want to
add 1 to all of them so a a dot for map
ok then map takes two arguments the
first argument is a function the second
argument don't worry about it
yeah because Java has lots of wats you
take 10 minutes to explain so so we need
a function here error function so X here
we just say X first 1 X 1 again ok
so that we turned that that that does it
so we just need to ok so constant result
equals to that okay so let's let's not
say let's say ok so that works so it
returns 2 3 4 5 we just it applies this
function to to every value of the way
you do this all the time when you use
Dom okay so you know you do this all the
time when you use Dom you know I could
show you an example but it is common you
know you have to you know it's common
when we actually do Dom it's very common
everyday it happens every day
then ok so this is an example of
function that takes a function okay so
just to be sure let's write it out
every day example okay okay so that's
everyday example what about everyday
example of function that returns a
function okay that's also very common
for example in JavaScript you have let's
go to the function call apply bind
okay so bind bind is the one
so bind is a function that returns a
function okay why do you need it well we
have to explain the value of this they
they know take a 10 10 minutes ok let's
not do that but but that bind is one of
the function you use often not not that
often but you use often it is you know
it's part of JavaScript so in JavaScript
you have a function bind that returns a
function and and and and in loud faces
in promises promise also you know in in
other places you know it when you
started to code actually to code
real-life JavaScript ok that's it for
today so thank you guys for watching and
[Music]
yeah closure and part of okay so you
like closures and partial functions for
callbacks okay yeah okay so that's it
for today so hope to see you guys next
time and for you guys and all the people
watching you know if you like my stuff
bye my JavaScript tutorial you know
PayPal in patreon yeah okay so it's
about me so bye guys