Good morning, good evening. Welcome to
another episode of Sound Talk Show.
We are going to code Emacs Lisp.
Okay, so
there I am drinking coffee.
And how are you guys doing?
So, this is technical nerd uh
old coder
that we're going to do technical stuff.
So, if you are a
non-coder, this is not interesting to
you.
And even if you are a coder, this is
very esoteric. So, this is about Emacs
Lisp.
Uh so, I'm going to
So, here's what we're going to do, okay?
So, show my screen. Can you see it? Yes.
Is it beautiful? Yes. Okay.
So, you can see so we are going to
we're going to demonstrate Emacs command
convert
uh
image to WebP Emacs command convert
image to WebP. Support lossy and
lossless both versions.
Okay, so we're going to show you the
command. Then, I'm going to show you
convert all images. So,
yeah, let's you know, so okay, so let me
start to do it. So, go to the directory.
So, here is all image files. So, you can
see this is my like my past talk show.
So,
uh you know, images. So, many of them
are PNG files. So, let me highlight all
PNG. Press press press PNG dollar sign.
So, you can see all those are PNG files,
okay? So, [snorts] and I can convert
them. So, PNG let's go to the first one.
So, let's see this one. Open it. So,
that's a Wolfram language long time ago,
4 years ago, I think. 2022 Advent of
Code.
So, [snorts] I can press the command
press the key, so you can see this is a
uh yeah.
Press press
press, so you see now it became a WebP
format. You see? Same image. So, this is
WebP. This is PNG. WebP, PNG. Now, this
is WebP lossless. WebP format supports
two versions, both lossy and lossless,
okay? So, you can see I just called the
command and that command you can see
it's called cwebp
uh in the pink window you can see it.
Can you see it? If you are here, say hi,
okay? Let's pop out this chat box.
I would enjoy your comments in real
time. Okay? So, and this is all Emacs
and technical, so okay.
So,
today we're going to talk about this
image conversion mostly. So, the By the
way, so where is the command? Like the
command I just called, let's see,
magnify this uh window. There it is.
cwebp
dwebp to lossless WebP, okay? And
there's a lossy version, too. So, let's
open this image again. So, you can
press, press, press, so it creates a new
file. LS, you see the word LS there,
that means this is lossy and this is uh
LL means lossless, that's my convention,
okay? So, you can open the lossless and
open the lossy.
Same image, okay? So, let's see, open
the lossless, delete it.
Open the lossy WebP, delete it. And we
just have return to the just the PNG,
okay? Cuz I'm going to do a we going to
I'm going to convert the entire
uh PNG files here. Actually, let's do it
now, okay? So,
yeah, so first of all, delete the
backup.
Uh press, press, press, delete the all
those backup, refresh, okay? Now,
highlight all PNG files, PNG dollar
signs, so you can see all these are PNG
dollar signs
files, many of them, okay? And we just
going to convert to WebP lossless.
Okay, but before we do that, I need to
commit my website Git Git commit, so
that in case something went wrong, I can
return. Hello guys, we got good morning.
We got people here. Bantu, hey Saga,
good to see you. Glad to see you. Don't
know who you are, but
but hi Bantu. Hi Dosima.
Dosibelean.
So, Dosibelean, I remember your the
name, but how are you? So, I don't know
who you are, but
So,
yeah, convert PNG to lossy and and loss
PNG to lossless WebP. Okay.
And we need to commit
Okay, let's commit. Let's see what we
got. So,
drop into my Xah Talk Show
xahlee.info.
So, start a Emacs shell e-shell
instantaneous. So,
Git status.
Okay, so Git status, you got talk show
new files 7
797, that's a future. 798, 799. And the
talk show
to do JavaScript talk show to do and
Okay, let's commit them.
Press press press Git add add them all.
Press press press Git commit commit T. T
means nothing, because it's, you know,
the commit messages is very annoying.
When you commit a lot, you know, you
like I, you know, I commit several times
a day
like
13,000 HTML files for the past 15-20
years. So,
uh so anyway, so it's done. Okay, so
it's done. It's all committed.
Uh if anything went wrong, I can
I can uh revert. It's like uh
auto- automatic fixing any damages like
the Borgish technology.
Okay, so yeah, so okay, we committed.
So, and okay, so we going to do that
committed. We showed the image files and
oh yeah, we wanted to uh do the keyboard
blog. Okay, anyway, it doesn't matter.
View and compare files file size. We
kind of did and fix all links in HTML.
Okay, let's begin.
Okay, so open that. So, yeah, we already
um
selected all PNG files. So,
press press press.
So, right now it's doing, you know, this
few hundred
uh
PNG to
lossless WebP.
Meanwhile, let's start another Emacs.
Wait, why isn't it starting? Do it
again. Now, it is slow.
Yeah, This this window disk.
Okay, there is a new Emacs. Close the
to-do.
Magnify and
turn it pink orangeish
and
uh control
to magnify, huge, okay?
Now, what we want to do is go to this
local, check local links. So, this is a
Go language
that will check all
links on my website.
Okay, is it done yet? No, it's not done
yet.
Uh
You see, it's funny that you cannot see
the process going in. So, you can see
this is Emacs. This is Emacs. It's, you
know, it's calling the
cwebp here. It's calling this command.
So,
you know, it's it's doing the
conversion, but it but the command
actually doesn't show any CPU usage.
It's like
I sup- You know, okay, it's fine finally
done, you see?
Finally done.
You see, you got all the WebP uh
images. So, let's let's do that. So,
uh
Press press press, highlight WebP.
Uh wait. I want highlight lines. Press
press press.
WebP
yellow. Okay. So, all the WebP is now
yellow. Uh let's magnify.
Okay.
Okay, so you can see
each WebP, they are are they smaller?
Yes, usually by uh you see, WebP PNG
WebP is 17K, PNG is 27K.
This one, WebP is 6K, PNG is 9K. So,
usually they save like 20%, okay?
And all these PNG are already extremely
optimized. Okay. So, you can see so
So, okay. So, what we going to do? Um
So, you can see there's WebP and PNG
twice as large. And the PNG is twice as
large. Let's open that one.
Okay, that one You know, why Why is this
twice as large? It's because we didn't
um
uh optimize it. Let's Let's try. Okay,
so this PNG is twice as Let's try
optimize it.
Press.
Uh wait. So, press press press. That
will optimize it. You see 0% decrease.
That means this
this PNG file is already optimized and
it's
>> [snorts]
>> uh 125 K
kilobytes.
While the WebP
uh
version is
67.
Yeah, so twice as small. Amazing save,
you know.
So, anyway, so you see it's done. Okay.
Now, since this is done, the next thing
to do is all these directory.
So, how many how many are there? So,
let's see. Uh
count
uh
count matches
uh WebP. Okay, they are 497
occurrences. Can you see?
See, 497.
So, now
Now, we go to Xantus Show. Close that.
Go to um Xantus Show. Let's go to
today's talk show. We want to find
um
links to those PNG files because we need
to change it. So, let's go
X out find text. That That's my personal
command.
Find.
Wait. Let's see.
Okay, close that. Okay, let's go to talk
show.
Let's
make this larger so you can see talk
shows. So, let's go to yesterday's
yesterday 2 days ago talk show. Okay?
So, you got some images there.
Search for image tag. So, there is a
image. That's That's already WebP, okay?
So, okay, so we want to search for
You see So, let's go to the earlier talk
show so that we can see some PNG there.
Search for PNG. Uh, not found.
Open this one. Search for PNG. There.
Okay, so what is this? This is breathing
Elon Musk. That's a
amazing AI-generated video. So, that is
episode
So, this is X Talk Show episode 762.
4 month ago in February. That's amazing.
Amazing
breathing Elon Musk. Okay, so do we have
some pictures here?
It's a YouTube, okay? So,
fantastic video.
And it it Anyway, it's not Let's Let's
get back here. So, so you see So,
there's a PNG file. What we want to
search is we want to search all things
like that, okay? Search X Talk custom
command. So, in this directory, find all
search patterns. So, there we go. 1 2 3
4. So, you can see You can see the the
scroll bar. So, there's like
thousands of them occurrences. So, you
can open each one.
For example, this is p Oh, this keyboard
photo in PNG. This is Okay, this this
This is like 5 years ago.
Uh
but Oh my god, I didn't you know, like
photos usually they should be in uh
they should be in uh
um
JPEG format, but you know, so I didn't
convert. So, anyway, so
So, close that. Close that. So, so you
can see
go all the way down. So, you have
you have about, you know, so many
How How many files? Press press
Wait.
Press press.
So, you can see
uh
217 files, okay?
These files contain
embedded PNG tags, okay?
200 uh
217, okay? Close.
And close that. And we want to um
So, you can look at each one.
So, basically
So, let's say this one. What is this
one? This is uh
This is AI generated
geo This is few days ago, okay? So,
So, we want to change all these
um
.png into .webp. So, let Let me do it,
okay?
So, call the command sub find replace
text. You can see on the pink window on
top there, okay? So, call it. And what
do you want to find? You want to find
text like that, okay?
And you want to change it to
low line LL LL means lossless.
.
webp, okay? Change all .png to webp,
okay? Do it.
In this directory only? Yes.
All HTML files? Yes. Okay.
Done. Okay, so you can go through all of
them.
Open it.
Now you can see this is uh
WebP. Open it.
Eyes of the Pepe.
I love this
this uh cartoon.
So, that's done.
So now, okay, open it. Now drop into the
directory so you can see all the old PNG
files still there, you see? And there it
is, Pepe. You
you see? So, let's
split the window.
Open this Pepe and open the other Pepe.
One is PNG, one is
uh WebP, okay?
So, so now we want to let's uh
You see?
Um so, this is a drawing by Alan, 5
years ago, 2020.
Uh Alan of of a a friend.
Uh so,
so what we doing? Yeah, so
so we need now to delete all those PNGs,
okay?
So, let's
press press press PNG dollar sign to
select them all. And let me show you
this fantastic command. So, we selected
about 400 image files, right?
Now,
uh
press press press. That calls the
command that moves all those selected
files into this new directory it just
created.
So, you open that so you can see it's
all PNG files, okay?
So, you can, for example, go to the top,
open it.
Next next next next next to all PNG
files. Next, next, this is all my Excel
talk show stuff.
Uh Pascal theorem, fantastic, generated
by AI. Next, next, next, next.
Going to LaTeX, this is also by Alan,
fantastic guy. It's uh referencing to a
mathematician, a friend.
So, you know, so anyway, so all these
PNG and now let's
uh drop into PowerShell.
And magnify control L, so we can see.
So, let's uh what So, [snorts]
so you can call
the size.
Okay, so all these PNG is 84 megabytes.
Sizeable, okay?
Close it. Now,
select all.
WebP this time, okay? Select it. Now,
press press press
They are all moved into this new
directory. Open it. So, you can see all
our WebP.
Now, open. Next, next, next, next, next,
next. You see similar
same images.
Right, so close it. Now,
now drop into a PowerShell again.
And uh magnify.
And then now let's the size, that's my
custom PowerShell command. The size 61.
So,
Okay, so the PNG files together is 84
megabytes.
Now, in lossless WebP, they are 61
megabytes. Saved 20 megabytes, okay?
Okay, so now
Now, we need to move the WebP back.
Okay, so let's let's do that.
Go to the
uh parent directory. Okay. Now,
yeah, actually again, just call this
command. Okay, watch.
Press
press press. That's unravel. That's uh
direct unraveler. Okay. So, that will
move all files in this directory.
Refresh.
You see, we'll move them out
to to the to to the parent directory.
So, you see, so all the WebPs are now
here.
Okay.
So, now close. Now, we need to Oh, we
already changed it. Fantastic. So, so
fantastic. We are done.
We changed about 400 PNG files
to WebP, and we also made changes to the
HTML. Now,
one more thing to check. You see,
because some of the links, for example,
this image,
it may link to For example, if you
observe where is the directory, so it's
in a directory named I
for image,
then, you know, in the current
directory. So, go to the current
directory, go to the top, you see the
image I
I directory, then go into it. That's all
those images.
So, but you you could link to For
example, any image link, you you could
link into a directory outside the
current directory. Like go Like go top
to the parent and parent then to another
directory. So, you are linking to
another directory outside of the current
directory and its subdirectories.
So, that is possible. So, when this
happens, you know, let's say you if you
have some random PNG,
you see, when this happens, but you
change them to WebP, but but we didn't
you know, we we only changed PNG in the
current directory, so that's a problem.
So, some of these change, if they link
to a directory outside of this
directory,
that that will now be broken because we
just changed it to web P, but it doesn't
exist, okay? So, what we can do is how
do you know
there this
script, okay? So, this script, of
course, it's on my website. You can This
is Golang script. Open the
homepage, showing browser.
Golang validate website local links. So,
this
Golang script, you can you can grab, you
can get. Just search for xardi.info
Golang validate website local links.
And it will So, for given directory, it
will check all HTML files.
Any link that's invalid, it will report,
okay? So, let's run it. So,
run.
Okay, it'll you know, take 20 seconds or
so.
Hello ACP.
Do you shell out to program to do the
conversion or is it there a building
function that converts images? Of
course, I wrote it myself.
>> [laughter]
>> I'll show you how that's done.
Actually, did we explain in last
episode? I I guess not.
No, I
So, I wrote it offline. So, for those of
you don't know,
let's go to xah talk show.
Okay, what is this? Episode, so this is
February, so let's go to today's talk
show.
Okay, go to today's talk show.
Um
that's today and but
last week
so
episode 794,
we talked about new image formats.
The wide color gamut and HEIC from Apple
and AVIF is upcoming new format and JPEG
XL
is new format supposed to be the best
and we also discussed WebP
and the CSS okay LCH color. So we did
you know we talked
and so
but yeah but I don't think we talked
about how to convert but let me show
you. Okay, so you have to do is
xnview.info. Okay, let's see search
xnview um
image tutorial.
Just search for that
and you'll find xnview image magic
tutorial there.
By the way, it looks funky because I
made the font to be 32
minimum.
So
so that's why the Brave
search and other website they don't look
so good but my website still looks
perfect.
Uh by the way, this is the old xnview
talk show that was you know me.
Uh that's what you know one of my very
early Oh, this is actually people
drawing artworks of me. So this is
year 2020 5 years ago. 5 years ago I was
looking like that.
And uh
people drawn some artwork of me.
Thanks to those people and uh
uh many of them
you know some of them
I don't have the name but that's because
I think they didn't want to
have their name included.
But usually I add the name whoever
created them. I have the name, the
artist.
So, anyway, so that was the Yeah, 5 5
years ago. Zumwelt.
This guy is a keyboard
you know, the keyboard fan.
Anyway, this this is 5 years ago and
that is sync. Okay, so
>> [laughter]
>> So, we will Yeah, so we are talking
about image format. Okay, so let's go to
Saudi image
image tutorial.
So, this is
my early one of my early tutorial on
ImageMagick since 2007. You know, lots
of stuff. But, you go here
to the parent
index. So, now here you can see how to
convert image PNG JPEG to WebP. Okay? I
wrote this in 2016 when Google began the
WebP. Actually, they began in 2011,
I think.
So, anyway, and and I updated so So,
this is how you convert JPEG or PNG to
WebP. Okay, so it's all explained here.
You just go to the Google website to
download the cwebp and dwebp, you know,
they have different tools to convert to
PNG to WebP or from WebP to other.
And also
for animations, converting GIF animation
and stuff. Okay? So, how do you convert?
So, here is a command. You can see or
convert the entire directory.
You can do that.
Uh and but Okay, so that's how you do it
in shell. For example, if you are in
shell.
But, how do I do it in Emacs? Of course,
I wrote a command. So, let me show you,
okay?
Uh so, let's do one thing at a time. So,
okay, so what is is
posting Pepe.
>> [laughter]
>> This is drawing by Alan. Fantastic. I
love this one. Because [snorts] of my
head I type in so much my hand pain.
Um
Yeah, so okay. So, let's go to okay. So,
go go to a directory. Go to the
directory. Go to the
a PNG file. Go to the top and we looked
at Let's Let's show something
interesting, okay? It's mathematics,
okay? That's one of the This is one of
the Advent of Code we were doing in
Wolfram language. So, but let's see if
there is something Okay, let's see this
Pascal's in Barbie style.
Okay. So, you see? So, this image
So, what I do is you see? Press press
press. You see? Now you got a WebP
format, okay? So, what is the command?
So, that command is
Uh
that command is Xara Dia to lossless in
WebP, okay?
And let's show the source code. So,
describe key.
Press press press. There.
Tab IO runs the command Xara Dia to
lossless WebP, okay? So, you can open it
in Xara Dia.
Okay, so here is the source code. Not
too many, okay?
I don't have it on my website. I just
wrote this
last week, you know, like actually a few
days ago.
Uh
Yeah, and so
uh
So, what if you wanted you see?
So, I had it's in Xara
Dia package. It's not available. Because
they all these packages they were
available on the web for 10 years, but
nobody give a And I died of
hunger. So, about 5 years ago I removed
all of them from GitHub.
So, it's now just
private to me, Okay, if you want it, you
can pay me, you know, like pay me $100.
Search on the web, okay, you will find
my page for them.
And okay, so but
okay, but how do you so suppose I
have the tutorial somewhere. It's not
it's easy, okay.
Like like um
I can put it I can put it for example.
So, copy that. Okay, copy that. Close
it.
Go to the talk show. And go to TeX talk
show showing browser. I can put the code
here. So, you know
So, let me just put the code here. So,
let's see where where section
That's something like this.
So,
Emacs Lisp paste it. Syntax correct. And
go to the top. Remove the to do. Showing
browser.
So, for those of you Emacs users, you
want the code, you can just grab this,
okay. Of course, you need the C web
command line from Google.
So, just press a key or convert, okay.
It will convert all selected files.
If none selected, it will convert the
current
file
on the cursor.
So, for the loss
for the lossy version, you can simply
modify this, you know, this to lossless.
Lossless is just a command option. You
can see dash lossless.
So, if you want a lossy, you can just
remove that or replace it with dash Q
then a number.
By default, it's 75, but you can make it
85 to increase the quality.
Okay, that's about the
how I do it. This is a Emacs code. Now,
let's go back here. I'll get to the
comments, okay? So, go back here. So,
this checks all my links in
you know, in 13,000 HTML files. So, are
there any bad links? Yes, there are.
So, let's make them self-find mode. So,
now you can easily navigate to jump to
You see, watch the
scroll bar. So, because they can
indicate where I am.
So, you see, go up, go down.
Okay, so go up. So, actually go all the
way down, so you can see there is a bad
link.
Go to it.
Like we said, because why is it a bad
link? Because this link
in South Talk Show directory, in South
Talk Show, but it links to a directory
outside of South Talk Show.
So, it was PNG, but now you changed
that. It doesn't work anymore. So,
we can fix that. So, let's see how many
others.
So, you see, all these are the same.
Same situation in math directory.
Now, this in Talk Show. So, wait. Why is
that?
That one, let's see.
Oh, that's just the That's in the in the
current directory, but not not in the
Okay.
So,
So, let's see. Yeah, so in some in other
directories,
Okay, so we can fix that.
Uh you know, so how do I fix this? There
are about 10 of them. You know, for 10
10 of them, I can fix manually. For
example, open that.
Then just change
find replace that
ll.webp
by
just PNG. Do it. Now, open the file.
So, now you see the file. Fantastic and
beautiful. This is Wolfram Language
wallpaper plot tiling, okay?
So,
close that. Then,
uh
Oh, god. So,
where is the uh there? So, next
So, you can do the same. Open that.
Replace. Do it.
Do it. And open the file. So, you can
see this is another
mathematics.
Beautiful.
Uh we did
live Wolfram Language
uh geometry inversion, my favorite
topic.
Okay, so close that. So, that also
fixed. So, we can just like go through
them. Fixed 10 of them.
An- Another approach is that you see
eventually, I think I'm not sure. I
think I'm going to convert
you know, the 30,000 or PNG and JPEG all
to WebP because WebP saves file size
significantly.
So, another So, instead of, you know,
fix them fixing them back to PNG, I can
just go drop into the math directory.
For example,
this directory for example, let's change
it, okay? Fix it.
Uh
>> [clears throat]
>> wait. Open.
Oh.
Okay, so wait. Undo.
Open. Okay, that's another tiling, okay?
So, for example, in this math directory,
there's tons of image files. So, one
approach is just go through through all
my
image files, convert them all to WebP,
then convert all links of images of JPEG
and PNG to WebP.
So, I don't have these issues anymore,
okay?
Yeah.
Anyway, so yeah, so that you get the
idea.
I think that's it for today, okay?
So, I'm just going to deal with them
offline.
So, what else? That's it for today, I
think.
Uh
so,
Empty grocery bag says, "Uncle Oxa, I've
been really enjoying your archived
streams. I'd like to try Mathematica.
I'm too cheap to buy it. What do you
think about
WLJS?"
So, Empty Grocery Bag, uh Wolfram
Language is free to use, of course.
Let's go to uh search for Wolfram
Language, you'll find my Wolfram
Language tutorial, and you just go to
download
Wolfram Engine, free to download. Then,
you can install, you know, that gives
you the like the kernel, the engine that
essentially the compiler or interpreter.
But, if you want all these beautiful
image, you know, Wolfram Language
graphics, rotation, then you need to
download um
you know, you can download the open
source like the uh
go here. What's the difference between
Wolfram Language, Mathematica, Wolfram
Engine, Wolfram Script, you know, you
know,
I'll explain. You need the notebook, so
there is a Jupyter notebook for Wolfram.
Wolfram Lang uh
Corporation made it, okay? So, it's
free.
So, anyway, so you you can use Wolfram
Language free
for personal, you know, hobby.
But, if you are really into it, of
course, then you can buy the Wolfram
notebook, you know, the Wolfram
for student or hobbyist, it's like $200
or $300.
Uh was it a year or something? Or you
know,
you know, check their website. I don't
remember.
So, these days software they sell by
subscription. There's no longer
like software you buy and you own it for
life. There's like
those those days are gone
since like 15 years ago.
So, you like you subscribe instead, then
you can use on your phone or whatever
and they have cloud services.
So, anyway, use for free or if you
actually, you know, really seriously
use it, then, you know, for math or
whatever, engineering,
you can buy it, you know, just
subscribe.
And, you know, what about like
alternative? Like
So, alternative, well, there's some like
open source
alternative, Python,
uh MATLAB Well, there's a Octave, which
is a MATLAB MATLAB clone.
MATLAB is commercial, but this is no
comparison to Wolfram Language. There's
a
uh there's like the the the the math,
you know, the like they are okay?
There's Maxima from the Lisp the
phonetics. There is there's, you know,
there's one from Python. I talked about
that so many. There's like
I think a few. Just search for Wolfram
Language versus on my site, you know.
Uh
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah, let me show you, okay? So, there's
a lot, you know, and I talked about
this.
Uh jeez Jesus.
Anyway, the summary is that any of these
open source, there's no comparison. This
this is a Wolfram Language is a
magnitude
uh
better. Like a mag-
you know, not not just 100 times, more
than 100 times. You know, there's no
comparison to the open source. Like if
if you can do it free, nobody is buying
Wolfram Language, you know. The the for
for corporations, they pay thousands of
tens of thousand dollars.
You know, like the research, NASA
research in rockets and whatever
for it.
So, uh but anyway, so you would you
know, for you open source so poor
students,
you want to see my opinion about that,
well, you can see here, okay?
So, let's see. Where is it? Uh so, wait.
Wolfram Language history, okay. What is
this? Uh so, Wolfram Language coding
miscellaneous, okay.
So, um history then unsorted, okay.
Wolfram Language great Wolfram Language
coders, bugs, lambda calculus
lambda calculus
Yeah, SageMath, that's another one. Like
idiots, like the open source phonetics.
What do you think So, what do you think
of SageMath? What do you think of
Python? Can you
>> [laughter]
>> What What do you think of Maxima?
Maxima, Maxima, you know. Open source
phonetics, they always ask these these
you know.
Uh
there's no comparison, okay? Like
Okay, so but the open source but you
know, if you really want, there are
three clones and tools, okay?
So, there are
So, this is Wolfram Language kernel for
Jupyter, okay? That's by Wolfram. There
there is also Wolfram Language
JavaScript notebook, that's pretty good.
I heard from Juan, a friend.
So, you need to download the Wolfram
Language engine from Wolfram, you know,
free. Then you can use this
Java- Wolfram Language JavaScript
notebook. I think that's what you're
saying.
>> [snorts]
>> Which is uh which is like a front end,
okay? Which is like
alternative to the Wolfram language
kernel for Jupyter notebook. Okay, they
are just
So, they allows you to have these
graphics.
But the computation is still, you know,
you need the Wolfram engine, okay? Then
there's also like the cell Wolfram mode,
okay? Then there's a closure integration
with with Wolfram language.
Okay, there is X spread use. This is
very The X spread use is Wolfram
language written in
Uh
you know, anyways, in Go language
in Go language there's Math effects is
also Wolfram language written in
whatever Rust or whatever.
Uh
I forgot.
And there's Oldest. This one Simja is
like this one is like 20 years ago. They
kept changing names.
They they they changed name for like
three times. Now it's called Simja. It's
like
written in Java.
More than 20 years old. You know, they
they try to be a clone of Wolfram
language. You know, basically copy
whatever Wolfram language do and but
But [laughter]
But you know, you can't you can't
exactly copy everything because it's
copyrighted, you know, or you know. So,
then I don't know what's their deal.
They they they they they change names
like every few years. They change names
something.
I never used it though.
Uh but you can try them. But you know,
you run into you know, you spend hours
hours to check oh is you know, does it
work? You know.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Uh
>> Do I use Claude?
No, I have not. I use AI heavily.
Mostly Quoc.
And I have demonstrated many quite a few
times.
Uh I use AI heavily.
To you know, just Quoc. Okay. N-
Uh however, and
And I'm very impressed. Like I have a
lot very esoteric technical questions
about programming languages.
In Wolfram language, in computer
science, in programming language theory,
in parsing, in or in JavaScript
practical web dev, you know, JavaScript
framework or CSS questions.
I have a lot questions.
Okay, so and I can show you many of the
question I recently asked AI. I'm very
impressed. Okay, AI generate, you know,
like write a tutorial for grid layout
and AI did it. Okay.
Most of the time it's pretty good. I
mean, it's very good as an introduction.
You can ask it to generate a tutorial,
write a tutorial for anything. For for
Rust, for example, the Rust Rust
programming language.
Let's see uh you know, just
>> [laughter]
>> in 5 seconds you'll you'll type a Rust
programming language um
tutorial. So, where is it? So, let's
see.
So, this is uh grid test. So, this is
generated by AI. Okay, in few seconds.
Grid CSS grid. I'm right I'm trying to
write a tutorial for C you know, I'm
learning CSS grid.
Which is out for by now 10 years, but I
never actually got into.
So, CSS grid, you know, so uh and this
is uh this is a tutorial. Okay, and what
is this?
uh, grid
test. Okay, so this is uh, yeah, I'm
testing something about grid.
And so anyway, so AI let's see AI
What is this? To do. Okay, so
So let's see.
I got thousands of to-do. They tends to
be piled, you know, I just pile them up.
So here is AI generated Rust tutorial.
You know, it it's good for like for
beginners, like you never touch touched
Rust before. So it give you very good,
you know, well written overview. You
know, there's some mistakes, but
still better than nothing.
And
to be sure it's better than like more
than majority 50% of whatever Rust
tutorials on the web.
They are written by Indian Pajit. You
know, they are like paid 5 cents per
hour to write to copy and paste the Rust
tutorial. Lots of that tutorial websites
are like that. Okay, Rust Rust, Python,
or whatever. You know, it's
And AI generated, you know, a Rust
tutorial in few seconds. So there is the
the and and look at this one. AI
generated, you know, I I
didn't know how to do this in CSS, you
know,
generated code and it works perfect. CSS
flip.
Which involves um,
like 3D stuff in CSS perspective, you
know, I you
So and AI generated, you know, uh, type
hint, you know, recently I
I learned that, you know, Python they
started to have type hint. So AI write
me a tutorial of Python type hint. There
it is, okay. Then you just read it,
okay, I learned.
You know, pretty good. Then AI Okay,
that's another take and and uh Python
path. Oh, yeah, so recently I learned
you know, Python added a new library
path library about 10 years ago because
I asked, you know,
so you know, Python's got the lousy uh
path operations. So, let's
So, for example, my Python tutorial,
very old, from 2005, I still update it
though.
But, it's
it's not as frequent as my uh let's say
Emacs list. Anyway,
so it's still my Python tutorial still
still pretty good, okay,
for beginners.
But, for example, if you want to do
manipulate path, like what we are doing
today, you know, when you have path
names, you want to get a directory name,
you want to get the file extension name
or without the extension, things like
that. So, every programming language you
have
kind of like a library or how to do it,
okay? So, in Python,
you can go to that uh your need. There
are structure
functions and class, modules,
miscellaneous, regular expression, read
write file, they are work directory.
Okay, here is how you walk a directory.
And uh and here is how you uh like path
related functions whenever you need to
deal with directories, you see?
os.path.dirname
and stuff. And it's not very good, okay?
So, but Python created a library that
fixed that.
And so, I I learned, you know, so this
from pathlib import Path, you know.
So, and and then I asked, where does
this come from? Look, you know, when did
Python created this? Then then it tells
me, oh, from Python versions, you know,
10 years ago, so they fixed that. And
so, this problem is now
you know, you can you know, it's fixed.
So, anyway. So, that's a usefulness, you
know, example of AI.
And oh, make file. So, on Unix, C and
C++
idiots,
they created they have this make file
thing, you know, it's like universal for
them. If you don't call code C or C++,
then you don't know this, you know, I've
been coding for 30 years, I never
actually learned make file.
It's basically only for C and C++
people,
typically.
Even Java, even Java, you don't you
know, you don't do make file
Anyway, so I was you know, so so I just
asked AI, you know, write me a tutorial
make file and just it just did, okay?
Make file.
Then this
asked AI to generate a keyboard for me,
okay? So, anyway, I asked a lot
questions um
about it. Not I mean, this this
questions so far are
easy questions, common. Like everyone
want to know how do you, you know, write
a beginner's tutorial, but I've I've
I've asked questions
that are esoteric programming language
theory or mathematics, you know, I've
asked those questions or Wolfram
language.
And it answers, so I'm very impressed,
okay?
And and if you want to see that, you can
of course, of course.
My 1,000, you know, 13,000 articles,
swami.info, okay? So, you go [snorts] to
there's a section on artificial
intelligence somewhere.
Uh
where is it? I don't have a dedicated
link, okay? So, wait.
And search for
artificial
No. Uh let's just go through the
Chat GPT. Chat GPT, who is this guy X
Ali?
>> [laughter]
>> Chat GPT says 2023.
Okay, then the parent page
uh my collection of AI articles. Then we
want to Yeah, so here I have documented
some of the questions, early ones,
about the questions I asked AI. Anyway,
so it's becoming so common, okay?
Everyone knows.
However, I never used
those tools like Claude or Anthropic,
you know, that's dedicated to
programming.
Uh which I think I should, you know, but
you know, it's it's it's like becoming a
necessity.
But I never used them.
Okay.
Wilhelm Wilhelm, I'm doing fine. Wilhelm
says, "AI will make people lazy and
content mediocre. Agree or disagree?"
That's hard to say, you know, like you
don't you know, that that's what we
think now, but you don't have to look at
AI for that, okay? Let me magnify this.
So that you can see.
So right now a lot of people will think
that AI, you know, the next generation,
they're going to be brainless.
Because AI just answer everything. They
they never start to learn anymore. And
this also of course there are reports
how university students, you know, they
just ask AI to do their homework. So
they don't actually know things. They
don't
they don't learn, and you know, when
faced with a real problem, they are
unable to
to to solve it. Or write an essay, you
know.
But however, you don't have to look at
AI. Just look at the Zoomers, okay? Like
a lot of you guys, like you guys don't
know, but look at the for example, a
Stack Overflow. A lot of people have
made fun of it. You know, like people
the programmers, you know, they don't
know how to code anymore before AI. You
know, they just go to Stack Overflow.
Whenever they have some questions, they
you know, Stack Overflow. Stack
Overflow, copy and paste. They don't
actually know exactly. For example,
my tutorial, right? I usually go into
depth, like what what is this type,
exactly how they work.
But
since even 10 years ago, since like the
Zoomers, they don't care.
Who cares how it works? All they care is
like, oh, you just go you type this and
you know, you get this and that is like
the structure, then you just copy this
and and that works. That's how Zoomers
work. A lot of them, half of them.
So, these idiots, they became
incapacitated. You know, they they can't
really actually work or write a library,
like you know,
So so that those are the Zoomers, okay?
So now, but to but
but the the world is kind of still
moving, you know,
So, we can ask, you know, before we ask
the question about AI is it going to
make us stupid? We can I think yes. I
think actually yes, it's a real issue.
But you don't have to look at AI. Just
look at like 10 years ago. Look at the
Zoomer generation. Do they
do they not know things older generation
know, like how to write the essay? Like
today's Zoomers, they can't write a full
sentence.
They they you know, they are used to the
Twitter, Instagram. They can't think,
they can't read a book. They just like
blub blub, you know, little memes and
posting this Zoomer
It's not just a few of them. It's
actually quite rampant, okay? All over
USA, especially the white, uh, you know,
Americans.
So, these people do So, so the question
is, do they Do you think they actually
has been,
you know, their capabilities has
decreased since previous generation. Is
that true? Is it truly I mean I mean, if
you really want to know, is it you know,
is there a brain truly like they their
IQ decrease? Actually, that's true.
Okay, their capabilities in writing, in
understanding about the world, about,
you know, or about coding, the Zoomer
generation, they
their capabilities, you know, their
abilities decreased. That is actually
true, okay?
I mean, you you want to ask this very
seriously. So, look at all the data or
ask all kind of all different type of
people. You can ask professors,
you know, there's all kind of
statistics. You can ask people outside
of USA, you know, and you can look at
all kind of things.
Right? You want to know if this is true.
Is it really true? Or Or maybe maybe
it's just a meme. It's what you think.
Maybe it's just because you are old. You
are a, you know, you are a boomer.
That's why you think, you know,
you know, older people always say, "Oh,
they don't make things they used to be."
But actually, that's just that's
actually just a meme. You know, maybe
the like
usually,
the newer generation are always doing
better, okay? Like because of the
scientific progress. Like today, for
example, the Wikipedia and today AI,
like you can know things
instantaneously.
Today,
like let's say 20 years ago, it's rare
for a person to know more than one
programming language. If you know more
than one, like
you know, C and Java and and Pearl or
whatever, you are you are considered
like fairly advanced.
That's this is true in 1990s.
You know, not like today. Today every
company use, you know, you
you need to know at least two or three
programming languages.
But not in the '90s.
But you see, but today it's so common.
It's like
everyone knows more than two languages
at least some somewhat. Why? Because
you got Wikipedia, you got tons of
tutorials, you got 10,000 video
tutorials, you know, they
So, that's progress.
And also people become healthier, you
know. Every generation they live longer
because the science is, you know, we eat
healthy healthier. So,
even IQ improved.
Okay, so generally it is true the later
generation they do better, okay.
But however, but
but when it comes to Zoomers, it seems
to me
there's a like retrograde, you know,
they're going backwards, okay.
Anyway.
So, about the AI question, we don't
know. That's a big question mark, okay.
That's a like big question mark.
Uh
can you make some Mathematica term
rewriting tutorial? Huang, I you know,
did did you not read my website? Like my
website is all about
Wolfram language term rewriting. Did you
master Did you read every bit of it?
Term rewriting especially. You're
talking about, you know, then you need
to
uh read pattern matching function, you
know, this section, okay.
>> [sighs]
>> I'm a C and C hat and I even make
make files, okay.
Empty grocery bag. Are you the guy on
Twitter
like calling me uncle?
Uh
I donated it. Okay, what what
>> [laughter]
>> You donated to U fun JavaScript. Why did
Why didn't Did you donate to me?
Let's see what Google thinks
about what? I forgot what's the topic
about AI about whether AI is making
people stupid.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Bye,
guys.
Oh, you don't participate. Okay, I also
donate. You did one.
Thank you. I don't know what I don't
recall, but
great.
Um
so, what we uh what
So, let Let me see.
Uh I think that's it. Okay, so close
that. Show today's talk show. So, we did
this
WebP thing.
Yeah, we demonstrated all that. Oh,
yeah. So, there's another
So, write a F# script to go through a
directory recursively. For each PNG
file, call WebP to convert it to So, we
So, another thing what I want to do is
to you um
to learn how to use F# today.
Yeah, but it's too late today. Okay.
Uh so, we do that another day. Okay,
bye, guys.
Bye, guys.
Bye, Juan.