hello welcome everyone welcome to
another episode of Pixar talk show today
we are going to code
several languages so let's so let me
show you so we are going to continue the
speed comparison of a seemingly simple
task of find and replace of a thousand
files in a directory
and we are going to compare Golan python
emac this and Wolfram language so we did
you know in the past three days we we
did all that and today the main thing is
we're going to code Golan from scratch
I'm going to show you and I'll explain
along the way how to do that and uh
along the way I'll talk about some uh
interesting things about you know
algorithms or programming or these
different languages okay so we're gonna
continue today
and in particular these are some of the
topic we I want to go over today
so one is we're gonna improve our fan
language code
uh that's one thing and we're gonna
explain some very interesting phenomenon
when you do multiple pairs of find and
replace okay that's one thing and then
another thing is that in a in the past
we've done you know speed comparison of
1000 files small files
you know each one is like 1K or 2K but
this time we are going to do one huge
file let's say one 10 megabyte file
uh let's see which one which language is
faster because they are uh quite
interesting different you know the uh
find replace
so one single huge file and we are going
to also code Powershell to join 1000
files into a single file let's explore
how do you do that in Powershell which
is a fantastic New Shell better than
bash the 30 years old 40 years old Unix
baggage Powershell okay then then lastly
we're gonna write the Golan version
today so today is going to be 90 minutes
probably around there so if you are
watching offline you know play it in 1.5
or 2 times speed
I'm going to do it leisurely you know I
don't want rush because every time I
Rush the result is not so good
so
uh two people watching fantastic okay so
let's begin coding today so on a pink
window I'm using emacs and sound fly
Keys you can search those words you'll
find my website and I'm using of course
I'm using exposed keyboard right here in
the ultimate hacking keyboard so full of
macros you see showing browser
you can find my keyboard page just by
search for it and you'll see I recommend
exposed it's fantastic and also this I
also recommend okay I talked about that
many times
so
let's begin coding okay so first so
let's see uh what is this keyboard blog
Pros okay the uh sound talk show today
first of all let's go to yesterday
because we have several code there we
want to copy over
so yesterday so you can see we did
this is a Powershell for copying
directory is over 1000 files and measure
the timing of each different languages
and here is the find replace pairs we
want
and here's a result from yesterday very
interesting result you can see
you know there's a first time result and
second time result they have different
timing
because part of the reason is because
when you do it the first time it takes
the time to load those 1000 files to
memory so once you do it once
some of the files are in memory so the
second time is much faster the second
time is also faster because
many of the pairs no longer exist in the
files therefore when you do it the
second time only some of the pairs you
have to replace and the right to disk
So reading file and writing to disk
these are very costly operations so very
slow so
so we try to when we do this speed
comparison we try to eliminate the time
to read from the disk or to write to the
disk that is why today we try to do one
single huge file you know
so anyway the the speed uh from
yesterday very interesting result you
know you can compare the first time
python happen you have python is fastest
then e-macb then wufam language but if
you compare a second time emac this is
the fastest
python become the slowest
and Wolfram language you know there's a
huge inefficiency there I'm going to
explain and we're gonna improve it
this inefficiency because that's because
our coding error nothing to do with
Warframe language
uh also yeah there's something else I
want to explain about the very
interesting
uh issue when you want to do multiple
pairs of find and replace in sequence
there's unexpected result I'm going to
explain and and that wolfam is doing
much better because essentially the emac
we spend python their code is just wrong
if you really want to do it correctly
you have to
like double the code actually but
Wolfram one single line does it Okay so
yesterday here's the emac this code
about 20 lines 15 lines here is a wolf
and Landry language code 10 lines or one
single line
uh here is python the the most
voluminous the the most of the verbose
okay python
uh okay so now yeah we copied them over
so let's copy the code over
so I'm using stuff like keys inside HTML
mod
so we want to copy all this copy
close showing browser so this is today
right let's put it here
and remove all the syntax coloring so we
can see
you know the plane code here okay so
first stop is the Wolfram language
uh
okay so here are the things we want to
do okay the
[Music]
um
first of all let's do the copy the files
over to the Powershell so we are pre uh
so we have the files we can do the
factory place on okay so let's go
through Powershell
okay pop it out uh wait make a backup
pop it up okay so
let's go to this directory okay that
exists
uh and by the way this is the emacs
manual emac lisp manual you can download
from the you know search it you will
find it 1000 pages
so we're gonna
okay we're gonna start Powershell
magnify
and okay
we're gonna remove those uh existing
files because you know we change it okay
and now we're gonna copy over
copy over okay open now it's a fresh
copy okay
okay
now pop this back
uh now let's do the wolf family language
okay let me let me explain
something we have to do with them to
improve it okay
so here is the Wolfram language code now
let's see uh video check audio check am
I doing good say hi guys
hello uh guybrush
okay video check audio check okay
uh yeah yeah
so
guy brush says for your information you
might to check the code from yesterday
the python code includes files in
subdirectories oh you are correct thank
you thank you for that pointing that out
uh yeah we need to fix that um although
this directory is just one single
there's no subdirectory so uh so that
should doesn't really matter but anyway
this is good point thank you
oh Jesus what's today's task you know
that's very annoying because every time
you I I just explained I just spent 10
minutes explaining so anyway let's
continue you can you can just go to the
link on the on the YouTube you know
description you can see you can see
these you know today's
topic that we I just talked about okay
let's back to wufam language so here is
the wufam language that does it so here
is a list of pairs replacement pairs
that's a syntax of the list and each
element is actually a rule uh that's
kind of a special thing yeah but anyway
you can just consider it as as a these
are pairs okay find string and then we
have the replace string okay then all
you have to do you you define this
function you know process file equals to
that function and uh you know here's a
function body
the parameter is final path
then you say module module is a local
variable so in this local variable you
have you know these these file content X
content you just read string that gets
the whole files content into a string
and here's a new content okay so new
content equals to string replace content
and this this pairs so in Wolfram
language all you have to do is just call
string replace it does you'll do a bunch
of them one shot you know that's very
you don't have to write a loop you know
or map or for each you know it's just
that's one of the characteristics of
wolfam language any function it has
maximum utility you know uh you know so
one shot you can replace all these pairs
so you save it to new content now the
last part if old content equals to new
content then do nothing because there's
no change otherwise you write to write
string which right to file file path and
new content okay very simple so this is
a function that process each file given
a file path then all you have to do is
you just
um scan is like for each
in JavaScript or map C in this so you
just apply this function to a list of
file names to get these file names
that's what you do file names you know
star HTML so you get all the HTML files
okay
but now the this part this part is
extremely inefficient because if there's
no change you know typically this file
content is huge right you know 2K or 3K
kilobytes
so if they if there's no change you are
doing you are trying to compare you know
this huge stream that's very slow
inefficient so rather what you want to
do you want to do uh what we did in emac
this and in Python is that to determine
if a file changed you don't want to do
this okay very inefficient instead you
want to know
given each of these um
this fine string do they occur in the in
the in the content okay if they occur
then that means
you know you you are going to do some
replacement so this file file change
okay so now we want to uh
given a string and another string we
want to find whether the string exists
in the in the
in the in the file content okay that's
what we want to do
so how do you do that uh
I don't I don't uh I don't remember
offhand so let's go to uh wolf um just
search for it you will find my Google
farm tutorial then you'll see a page on
the most useful stream functions join
string substream
occurrence okay so we delete substring
from a string string to list these two
strings string to number
list those string functions okay so
let's search for occur
uh
okay it's not there what what should it
be let's see
uh let me start Wolfram language
notebook so oh
I forgot that is that's a python
documentation
star Warframe language
Sam hey Sam don't worry about it okay
you know there's you know
don't worry about it about it because I
tends to be you know I often
I came out as rude
so so we'll find language started and by
the way you can do if you want to know
all functions that contains the word
string that's what you do so which one
is it
uh you want to know if a string contains
some other string okay so let's see so
usually that would be find or
uh
something read string
casts
okay so we should do this faster
string count okay string contains Q okay
that that will do string contains q u is
true if part of the stream entry stream
pattern
okay that is one of them
string contains Q
stream match Q will also work
okay let's just let's just start to code
it okay
okay that returns either true or false
any function that ends in Q returns
either true or false nothing else Q
means question okay so string contains
stream match
can also do it what's the difference I'm
not too sure
string part string position okay string
Q string okay basically those two okay
oh string start Q
okay you don't care okay yeah these two
functions so let's have a look let's see
um
how do they differ which one is more
appropriate more efficient for our
purposes so let's look at their
documentation
stream match Q uh test weather stream
matches stream pattern
okay so basically you want the string
pattern okay yeah and what was string
contains Q is also a pattern you yields
true if any string uh matches during
solution
okay
uh basically they are similar
uh it's just that the difference is that
okay so
by the way there's a ignore case true
okay by default it's Force
okay string contains Q they are similar
the difference is that
I believe stream match Q the pattern
must match the whole thing
I'm not too sure
but let's you know we can
since we have the woofer language we can
click quickly test it actually we have a
lot things to do so we shouldn't waste
time by
you know a b ABC some thing okay so a
pattern
here's how you do it okay let's see
regular expression
um before we do that it just say
something
okay false
now what if we use the pattern
so we want a regular expression
okay regular expression and we want to
say
any uh let's say some okay let's see the
sidewalk you see no because you want you
need you know when you go stream match
it needs to match the whole thing so
what you can do is you can say anything
but no more
Plus
and anything one or more
you see
okay so we don't need string match we
just need string contents that's the
appropriate one okay good morning Greg
and Doc
okay uh string contains Q so here is the
string which is the content and uh
you know
so we we need to test uh okay
here should be fine string okay
so we need to kind of do a loop through
them okay how do you do that can you
can you give a list to the string
contents so that you don't need to do
Loop
yes exactly like I said this is a
characteristics of Wolfman language you
don't have to do a loop yourself you
know you can just
so all you have to do is to take take
the first part of these string pairs let
me show you how to do that
okay so that's a pair of strings
you know it which is uh
a list of
you can think of those are technique
technically called rules but you can
just think of them as list of these
These are pairs okay so you can map
first
let me show you a short syntax so you
want to map the function first to
find replace pairs okay
that's what you want
so the full Syntax for that you know we
are using a shortcut here you see Slash
add but the full syntax if you want the
readable form more I mean not this is
more more intuitive for beginners than
you do that
okay they are the same thing
so we want to
um
yeah so let's use the more readable for
beginners
so you see so here we'll return a list
of the find string
okay and in fact we can just do that
yeah so
so if this is true
then that means the content contains the
fine string and we need to do find
replace okay
so if this is true yeah so wait if this
is true
see string contains
string contains yeah yields true if any
substring matches any of the pattern
okay
so if this is true so we don't want the
testing of equality
okay let's just do that
if
that's true
then we have to write to string
else no okay
okay that should make it faster
let me show you the speed difference
okay so we compare two different uh
so here's one way here's a more
efficient way
we can comment out one of them it's
coming out this one for now we're gonna
test the speed
so but here the new content we still
needed yes we need it
okay why don't we do this hold on a
second
okay so that's one way
that's one way the other way is
is that you just remove that
okay and
you don't even need new content okay so
new content
you don't need it anymore because it
only occur one time here so you can just
say here so it becomes so extremely
simple and you don't even need these
oh you do so
yeah you you do need this variable X
content
so here's one way here's the second way
they differ by this checking whether
they're
you need to write to file okay so
comment this out now let's run this okay
uh copy the code
copy the code put it back
now let's put the code into a file
so the file is
here open it
this is from yesterday
selego paste okay
save
close
copy the line back to Shell
paste it so we're gonna test test the
timing now
do it
from yesterday it's about it's going to
be
um
six seconds
yeah so six seconds and during the
second time
the timing yesterday is
um language
2.7 seconds
okay there it is check so this is
algorithm from yesterday by comparing
the whole
file content okay
now
let's
let's use the new algorithm
so common of the whole new
and let's start over
remove all the files
copy the files over
now learn it
good morning guys say something okay say
something
ah it's still six six seconds what the
so before
it's six seconds so it did not save much
time
let's run the second time
uh the second time is even larger longer
what
wow fact the second time is even taking
longer
hey hey hey hey void machine
so we have a problem God this is so
annoying each time we do something there
is a
um
why is it so this this string comparison
okay so basically it's telling us that
this string comparison is
is faster than
checking if
checking if the content contains any of
the fine string
that's that's incredible that's
how is it possible I mean how
I don't understand I don't understand
uh is there something else it changed
new content
here content new content
I don't understand
if new content equals to Old content do
nothing otherwise otherwise
right to file right
and over here
if you know
if
I don't understand why you should uh
let's go to the file let's see did we
make the changes correctly I think so
yeah this and the blind got screwed up
yeah that changed let's search for that
yes you see each each that happens we
did one
two three three times if we run one more
time
you know then then it's gonna be
one two three four yeah
so it worked
oh wait we we
um
yeah but it um
okay let's
new content okay
I don't understand now let's try to make
these two
to be exactly the same okay so let's
just replace
if by this
I mean uh
okay and let's just replace this line by
these
put them here
okay
so now let's try this okay
start over
uh
yeah because there's no fire there
remove nothing remove them copy it
now run the Wolfram language code do it
six seconds
okay six seconds
and do a second time 1.7 seconds
now two point
six
why why is it 2.6
2.6
oh yeah that's right so yesterday it's
also 2.6 right
so okay
okay that's good now let's
use the new algorithm
okay in fact we don't need this new part
okay
uh in fact this
this line let's we can also change it so
that we don't need this no
all you have to do is this means not not
equal okay
so
so now both of them are have the same
structure
okay coming that out
okay now it's two over
you know
copy them
Wolfram language
six seconds yep
okay now second time
should be faster please
2.7 same
uh interesting we didn't improve any
speed it looks like these two code have
the same speed
for some reason
2.7
hmm
uh
I wonder
it will be the result will be different
I mean these two lines will make a
difference when you have huge files that
is
we're gonna join 1000 files into one
file
are you guys there say something
okay so anyway so here is our Wolfram
code okay
copy it
close it
and uh wait
make a backup
close it and let's uh
let's let's go to the Wolfram language
part
DVDs okay
yeah
okay
hello hello you few
so great let's continue so
okay we we tried to improve the Wolfram
language and since the speed is the same
no difference okay now let's do the next
thing
uh shall I explain the sequential
problem first of all let's
okay let's let's write the Powershell
let's do this thing let's try the
Powershell to join 1000 files into one
file okay
let's do that
okay Powershell so let's uh
let's let's start here
when hello when when
Powershell
showing all files in the into single
file okay in Unix all you have to do is
you just say cat
and uh you know that's all you have to
do if it's if you are in
Unix bash Linux
but in Powershell I think that will work
too so let's try it
CD xxxt so you see we have a
doil again you know
so let's say cat
cat Star HTML
um cat is an ads2 let me show you okay
cat is a Alias to get content
but I'm not sure it will do the same
thing as Unix join
uh let's redirect to let's say XXX okay
let's see if that works
um
it's taking too long
huh it worked so let's drop into
the directory let's see if we had walked
okay so go uh open it go all the way to
the bottom there it is
power I shall open it oh my God it uh
you know there's a problem it added
extra line breaks
so this file XXX is
seven megabytes
okay I want to do this properly I don't
want just you know I don't know what's
going on there
so you know because when it's so in in
Powershell you have this operator pretty
much like
Unix but there's some differences it
will add for example have used you have
seen it will add this
um
let me show you you know you it will add
these line breaks
so I'm not too exactly sure how or why
but you see apparently each line breaks
becomes two or three
so yeah I don't know
so anyway close it
now let's go to Powershell and let's see
if we can do this properly
okay
so my Powershell tutorial I spent like a
year almost to to write it check it out
okay complete No Nonsense
technical
tutorial and easy to understand for
beginners okay Powershell tutorial okay
meanwhile let me just mention now that
if you like my you know my videos my
stuff pay me okay
uh that's important you know I want also
to
to just like every YouTuber you know
tell you to support me patreon me
Amazon gift card or PayPal okay
thank you okay so let's go back to
Powershell so we want to know how do you
uh join all files let's see let me see
if I can quickly do it properly
so
so wait so so you can you can uh you can
get all files then what do you do
join string string operations okay
string operators okay so you have length
and join is Plus
but now you have a
a collection of fire paths
uh you want to actually the easiest is
just to look at the Powershell
cat
um
documentation
so cat is good content okay so you can
see get content
so you can type help cat and online
then you go to the online online is
better the web version because you have
the formatting much easier to read than
this bunch of you know the Unix
tradition
so okay so
get content yes examples get the
contents of a text file limit the number
of lines get content returns
example get specific line
get last line get the concept contents
of alternative data stream no
get raw content okay real content we
might be interested so that it doesn't
add
you know the line return
okay so you can say raw okay use filters
with get contents yeah so this way if
you use the filter option you'll be
significantly faster
then if you just use the you know the
Shell Club
that's a tip okay
significantly by several seconds
when you when you use any LS or the you
know you want to use the dash filter
because anyway uh anyway that's a good
tip
get final contents as a spider array
okay I don't know it's delimiter
delimiter encoding
encoding the default value is UTF no
boom okay that's good
uh exclude filter yeah we want to use
that force force we override the
read-only attribute
okay so I think I know what to do first
we'll override that read-only attribute
or create directories to complete a file
path
okay yeah include literal path path raw
ignores new line characters and Returns
the entire constant contents of file in
one stream
with the new line preserved that's what
we want okay
so first of all let's just try that
so let's see
cat
filter okay then uh
you want to say raw that's right
then
then this part is also tricky because
when you do that that is actually
equivalent to let me show you okay
when you do when you use this
this
um
that's actually a Alias by some
mechanism to the uh let me show you
print okay
so
string okay value types Powershell
programming Powershell value types
string we want print
okay data structure Loop and iteration
input output here print to string point
to screen
okay and write file so let's check print
to screen screen first
right I'll put printer screen or send it
to the pipeline if there's a pipe okay
uh
okay
so press command output okay so we want
uh
maybe right output Echo right now let's
check right to file
set content okay that's the proper way
okay
so we want to pipe it to
set content and let's double check for
sure
no new line do not add that encoding
default to utf-8 okay set content
okay and no new line
and uh
and the file name
okay something like that
close that
5x that's right
do it
command get contents
uh and command pipeline position one
Supply
values for the following parameters path
oh okay we forgot you know
Ctrl C to cancel so we need let's copy
these two emacs
I'm gonna check the comments okay I'm
gonna read the comment you know being a
minute
so let's let's the Powershell yeah so
uh yeah so cat you you just say a
directory okay that
to it again
Escape
paste do it
get content unable to get content
because it is uh directory please use
get children instead and idiotic
how complex can get
uh
uh all right so there is is an example
of
get specific line
get the last line get the content of
alternative data stream
get raw content use fielders there okay
so
oh oh yeah so you have to say path okay
so this will be
let's do it here
paste paste do it
fantastic so this is how you
concatenate all fires
um
all files in in
this store open it refresh open it
okay but we got this new line
problem got new lines lots of issues
the you know the new line convention
between Unix Mac and windows
let's do it again let's let's do it
without the raw and see
do it
um
across it
is it done yet
close it yeah I think emacs stuck
okay
damn you don't have an article about
Mike Hawk I don't know who that is
uh here's the problem you see
now if you say
no new line yeah God
now it becomes like that
no new line literally
cancel now emacs stuck because
okay
her herodo says
such as an unrelated question have you
met company mod in emacs have you yeah
of course I have used it I don't
recommend it you know uh
so first of all are you using sound fly
keys or not answer okay if you are here
answer
are you using stuff like this or not
uh
okay it doesn't matter you know uh
instead of company mod I would just
recommend use using a brief
okay
but you can surely get it to work okay
so maybe you can let me close this
emacs now stuck
okay how many people are watching am I
doing good
oh God we have a lot to do
two people five people
yeah the emacs now stuck I didn't
understand stuff like he's oh that is
that is my package okay so anyway
uh so anyway yeah so you can use company
mod it's pretty good so if you are not
too familiar with emacs I can recommend
it
yeah but setting up is also a little bit
complex
but
so there's no easy question I mean easy
answer
so let me just say company mod is pretty
good
but setting it up
takes some know-how okay you just have
to persist
and I don't use company mod because I
find that you user interface are knowing
and too slow so instead I use a brief
just search for Saudi emacs a brief
you'll find how to I use a brief and I
also use complete uh what's called
hippie complete hippie completion so if
you just search for
this emac stuck
search for uh cloudy emacs completion
you will find my discussion about
several ways and how to go about okay
that's basically it's headset
emacs stuck now close
this is a long this is a major
um
critical problem with emacs when you
have a file that's one single line emacs
becomes unresponsive you know every
operation when you press right arrow key
you know whatever you do it takes
several seconds to
to actually know about what you are
trying to do
that's a problem
you see this command we just did that
combined 1000 files into one single one
and now and no line breaks and now emacs
is freaking out
yeah we we might have to start a new
emacs
let me give you another tip about emacs
I have my emacs set up so that there is
almost there is no state that will
um
that will
interfere with emac startup so I can
start up another emacs right away
without asking questions
so you can try that yourself you know
start a new emacs see if it asks you oh
because there's already your instance do
you want to something yes or no okay if
it had do that
I don't like it it's no good okay I mean
it's also good but it depends on your
workflow I don't want that so I can
start any multiple instance of emacs
without it asking me if I want to start
it because there's already you know a
occurrence or something anyway so I have
now civil emacs
so but anyway the the old one is seems
is not working
yeah so now the old one is back
okay so now
um let's try again this time
just a filter
only file starting with x
okay
so now refresh
now it's only 19 kilobytes okay open it
open it yeah no it's much smaller but
still
one single line
but now we can let's see what is the
let's remove the no new line
okay do it
okay if you do that then you get this
repeat it
new line
so what if I say now we say oh
okay then we get uh you know this is
really uh
problem
wait is it because the all these files
oh because they
they are up okay let's this we
have to do this refresh
okay remove all of them
because it's in use
remove them
what in what in use
is it that close with rhyme language
okay close to Fan language don't save
close it
now remove it
because it's in use
what what is in use
nobody is using it
and see
uh
probably back
I don't think is anyone is using it
refresh refresh
because
yeah idiotic oh because the
current directory you see we are in the
directory so we want to go up
now remove okay now if we open it you
see it doesn't exist
uh weights
the directory doesn't exist at all
let's go to it
go down
then delete the backup there's no XX
okay
now
copy them over okay
are you fresh
there it is okay now
open one of them okay it's good now
let's do
this cross
now let's throw the Powershell
uh let's see
that no filter no new line let's do that
and see wait
let's add an X here
so we concatenate all
files starting with x
what oh you have to CD to it
Okay so
let's do this
concatenate the that directory
okay
there
so we don't have to CD to the
do it done now let's go through it
to refresh refresh I'll go here here is
the file
open it
fantastic beautiful that's
that's how you do it
uh and now let's rename the file
one big file so hold on a second we want
to
copy all
XX dot big
okay
and
yeah
so this is how you do it
should be seven megabyte this file so
let's open it
go up one directory there it is
six megabyte file open it fantastic
okay
127 lines okay
close
okay copy the file path
this one delete
okay
because because now
here is a big file
let's make a
let's put it here this
okay
so this is this is the launch file we
want to test okay open it
yeah
close it
and now we can what we do we test the
Wolfram language again let's see how
does it make any difference
okay
so let me see the comments just like
Escape keying or terminals thank you for
the comments generous comments smartest
Turkish person
just use vs code
uh
what happens to
when that happens to icg and web
beautify yeah
okay
so now we have one big file
and
you know we completed this task
Okay so
and now and that's done this way now we
want to test the Wolfram language to see
there's a speed difference when you have
one um
one big file okay so let's open the
Wolfram language file so the Wolfram
language file is this one
so
so now the final path is
um
is that
and what's
so engineering
input file so let's change that to file
input file
ah
so instead of that you would just say
instead of a scan
you know instead of scan you just say
that
okay
so now let's go back here
let's run the Wolfram code so Wolfram
code is
this time
it
two seconds okay so when you have one
single file then it's much faster
do it again
1.8 second okay do it again
1.8 second okay
now now that's using this first
algorithm compare file content
okay so remember the timing is 2.4
basically two seconds 1.8 okay two
second first time then 1.8 now let's
refresh
remove them all
copy the files over
and now
cut them together
okay
and now
let's do the wufan language but but with
this this new
uh check if it contains algorithm
do it
two seconds okay first time
1.8 same thing yeah
okay that doesn't really matter okay
Okay so
that is for that okay so
um
so let's return them to the way they are
so
okay so that's the Wolfram language code
backup close okay now let's do the next
thing
explain the sequential replacement
problem okay that's very interesting
where is Ruby version hello George
George um I have shortcomings in Ruby I
don't know it well so the Ruby version
relies on you so please do post your
Discord solution so tomorrow also we are
tested okay
now let me explain this very interesting
problem about sequential replacement
okay
so the problem you see we are replacing
several pairs of strings find and
replace strings now
there's a very interesting problem okay
so let me uh let me let me show you
where right now
in all these languages wufam language
python emac disk they are all incorrect
incorrect except wolfam language wufem
language by this um
yeah let's let's put the code here
by this single line of code is correct
all the others emac this python uh let
me let me put a code here okay
so uh so let's
paste it there
color the whole buffer make a backup
showing browser
so this Wolfram language essentially one
single line does it correctly while
the emac this
and the python they are actually
Incorrect and what is the issue let me
show you
so you go to sardi.info and search for
find replace okay very interesting issue
uh so I have so many here find replace
feedback feedback loop problem
so
you know suppose your input string is
ABCD you know as simple as that your
input string and your replace pair is a
replace a to C and C replaced by D okay
a to c c to D now if you are going to do
this sequentially
you know then you'll get dbd
but if you are going to do it you know
let me see how do I explain this
um
ABCD a2c c2d
so a2c so you should have C starting
with C so you should have c b then C
becomes D so you should have CBD
but however when you do it sequentially
a becomes C then you start over then the
first C becomes D so you get d b d d
That's what you know so the result a
becomes D that's not what you want
so this is a
this is a like a feedback loop issue
and typically this is not what you want
you know it you know when you have a
string find replace pairs you know if if
the find string doesn't occur in
original you don't want it to change
and this happens
in real life when you want to for
example encode the Ampersand character
uh you know
so you have to you have to read this
yeah
yeah so
um
yeah when you want to replace you know
when you want to encode any of the for
example in HTML the characters you need
to encode are that that in Ampersand you
want to encode them as uh as
10 percent less or equals to yeah
less than equals two you want to encode
them as
that and
that right so you have three pairs you
know the the first one you want to
replace by that the second one you want
to replace by that the third one you
want to replace by that
so you have three pairs of replacement
and but if you do them sequentially then
you're gonna up your encoding of
that because that ampersand
you know that less than equal uh less
than sign becomes Ampersand LT but when
it comes to Ampersand that Ampersand
becomes
amp again so you got you you got
up
so this is a very interesting issue and
the way our current algorithm
you know in emac this all have this
problem
so but not Wolfram language you know
wolfam language when you do this it
doesn't
uh have this problem but this problem
happens when we do in emac this
sequentially and also in Python
because you just Loop through the find
and replace pairs
so how do you solve this in in fact to
solve this you have one way is that
one way is that by checking the
checking the find and replace string
checking that if they is it possible
that they will form a new string
that will happen in subsequent find
string that's one way to make sure that
doesn't happen if it doesn't happen then
you can do them sequentially
usually that's the case when all the
fine strings are different and there's
no and and they'll replace string it's a
bit complicated because when you find
some string by another string then this
new string have neighbors right
so the you have to consider the new
strings neighbor do they form a new fine
stream in the later sequence if they do
you got a problem
so so one way to do it is check to check
out if that you know you you are going
to create a new stream that happens in
the subsequent find string another way
so
one General solution you don't even have
to check the input is that
you first
first you do this find replace by
replacing each fine stream find stream
to some intermediate random string that
will never happen in the text let's say
random you know what random string that
will not happen in the text then
you replace those random texts by the by
the desired replacement string so if you
do this this way it's going to double
your
your time your algorithm double the time
it takes
so that is the issue so this is
this is a big point for wolfam language
wufam language you know they solve this
problem internally I do not know what
algorithm they use there are other
algorithms but gets very complex because
alternative algorithm is that when you
do the find replace you have to mark in
the content you know every time you did
the find replace you you mark their
position to
to to to store their positions so that
your program knows this part
should never be changed again
so that that gets very complex
so that's a big point for wufam language
of course if you want if you actually
want to do them sequentially you can you
can just Nest this function Nest Nest
this um
this uh string replace function which is
also very easy to do so anyway that's
the issue so
so like I said you know this is a big
issue you know this is a big and
practical issue you don't want this
Ampersand to be up you know it's
it's this is not just theoretical issue
it's it actually real world issue so the
proper algorithm is actually
for this emac baseball and python we
have to
we have to for each find replace pair we
have to create the intermediate string
for them to replace two
and that I did in my sapphine package
you know
I demonstrated before but let me show
you one more time okay so you let's open
the you know this directory so let's
let's let's say I want to replace uh
that okay the word that let's magnify
okay so I want to replace the word that
by that one two three okay Enter
and it asks me a directory yes and asked
me a pattern for the file names HTML
uh
directory depth starting with 0 to 99
right changes to file yes fixed case yes
fixed case in replacement yes make
backup yes
okay this is the fine package written in
emac this so you can see all these are
done okay now if you drop to the
directory refresh you can see you have a
you have the backup
and let's say let's open one of them
search for that
you can see it becomes that one two
three
there
so you see this fantastic by the way you
can see all those Ampersand that's why
it's important when you want to
listening so so what I'm trying to say
is that in let's go to the source code
of sa um
it's not fine okay so you can see I have
the algorithm that replace them to
intermediate pair so you can see here
Sapphire replace text
uh
the depth so yeah literally place where
is it
Okay so
oh not here wait yeah that's not this
one so the not
not in some fine package okay because
some fine package only do one pair at a
time
so you don't you don't have this issue
but but the package I'm talking about is
this one Cloud replace pairs okay
so in this one you because in this this
is for emac this coders so you can open
it I can show you you can search and
find it Cloud replace pairs it allows
you to write a you know find replace
multiple pairs by this single simple
syntax
as opposed to
as supposed to you have to write a loop
yourself you know you can just do it
just like Wolfram language
so if you have now you have multiple
pairs of fine replace so you got the
issue of the feedback loop
so
so I have to so I have to I solve that
problem here by using a intermediate uh
string
here so you see it it generates a
uh temp map points okay that's
interesting
which which does make the code more
complicated fairly because when you
generate intermediate
replacement stream then you got the
problem what string should it be you
know if you're gonna have a random like
uuid which is like 24 characters that
that's going to make your uh algorithms
significantly slower because if you have
let's say 1 000 find replace now you are
adding 24 characters 30 32 characters
each for each pair
so
so that's the interesting you know
issue
okay
so that's that part so are we going to
so three o'clock four o'clock right now
is 70
80 minutes so I guess we can now do
Golan shall we
what do you guys think
okay we did the Powershell we explained
the sequential replacement problem which
is uh
I mean put the links here so we can see
it
okay and
yeah Excel replace pairs it's here
okay so
sequence shall replace my problem
yeah it's here this article
feedback loop problem
Okay so
let's see what's next
test on one single huge file we did that
with the Emax
uh now shall we do it on
yeah we need to write the Golan version
yeah
and
[Music]
if we test on one single file a huge
file
okay shall we
so now we have two choices now we do all
these languages test their speed on one
single huge file or we start to write
Golan version which one do you guys want
say it okay we're gonna do
yeah we need to make progress so we're
gonna do one of them at least probably
be ready to go then okay say something
guys
okay let's let's do a Golan version okay
yeah so let's uh yeah that's okay cool
let's uh let's start right the Golan
version find replace multiple pairs
um
from scratch
Golan yay okay Colin I haven't coded
Golan for a long time so go land every
Golan fire you need this
template so let's explain what we're
gonna do so just like others we're gonna
need to um
some of it okay so we're gonna need
okay find replace multiple pairs in your
directory and uh we need the input
somewhere so first of all how do you
define multiple pairs so the pairs we
want to replace are something like that
okay so golden every golden needs this
templates now
uh how do you represent
uh so we need we need the nested pairs
it can be a struct or it can be uh
nested array
so let's go to my Golan tutorial I have
encoded Golan for for a while it's just
copy our code actually
so because there's already a code
have written work directory which what
we
we need that working a directory
we also need to
um
read file
but there is a
code already written examples fine
stream find replace there so we're gonna
borrow you know here
so
here you know it's pretty elaborate so
it's the to skip
found east finally replace pairs okay we
need this this is uh struct now Jesus
so here
finally pays pairs it's going to be a
this means it's
it's a array okay it's a ray
and
yeah you got God you're gonna declare
the type
yep oops
so here we're gonna declare the type
which is a struct
it's just like a hash table or
dictionary but with the fixed keys and
uh yeah fixed keys so here we declare a
type struct with the key find string and
replace string and their value is a
string type okay yeah so we declare the
struct then here we declare a variable
of
whose value is a array
find replace pair the strot so
array of the stroke Pairs and
so we can start to
for example the first string is here
okay and the replace string
is that so we're gonna need multiple
pairs of these
four of them okay
so
here will be
that
okay
let's do it this way then Lambda becomes
okay then number becomes
okay then we don't need this part so
declare struct
and
a slice okay it's actually a slice okay
so we got four pairs of fine replace
pairs okay
then we need to okay then what's the
next
so we declared the find replace pairs
um
let's see
let's
clean them up a little bit so we need
the input directory okay so we need um
ah
input
and
so golden syntax she said right
and I think so
right so yeah so that's the input
directory then
then we need to declare a function
I mean Define a function that takes a
file path
and do the replacement okay
so
so let's just copy and copy and paste
with our function to
where is it
oh God
and let's just copy it
so here is our function
okay not too bad
function do file takes a parameter
path which is a stream
and then
I'll put nothing
Jesus I forgot how do you declare a
function that I'll put nothing I suppose
that's the way
okay so you content bytes you read the
contents by calling OS read file okay so
you need
a bunch of import
you know you don't need nothing like
that in wufan language
I suppose yeah you need format yes uh
uh actually not really
okay you need to print you know
sometimes you need you need i o file
system yeah you probably need
all that
time you probably don't need okay let's
just leave it
Okay so
read file that when you do this it gets
you uh
array of bytes now check error then
contents you turn array of bytes into a
string
um
so wait a minute are you doing this with
so we are not using uh
we are not using a
array of
runs which is array of unicorn
characters slice of unicorn characters
because in Golan you have the issue of
string versus
um
slice of bites which is mutable string
is not mutable but you can turn a string
into a slice of bytes which is mutable
or you can turn it into a
a slice of runs each run run is a
Unicode one is the Angola and run is
just the 80s uh meaning or character
Unicode character
so
stream is not mutable
meaning that every time you change
something it regenerates the whole
string very slow
so you want to turn the string into a
slice of bytes or slice of runs
and what did we so if you want to
understand that I have that fully
written out
here
you know
so but what did we do here so so in
Golan every function that reads a file
or
any any regular expression function they
are typically three versions one version
just works on a string another version
works on a slice of bytes
and another version works on a slice of
runs
so very cumbersome
you know which one to use depends on
your purpose if you all you do is
reading file not writing or not changing
anything then just use string immutable
but if you do want to change you know
parts of it often then you want to use a
slice of
bytes if you are doing you know internet
streaming or video streaming you want
the bytes you don't want characters
but if you are doing text processing
which is the our case you do want runs
uh you know which you know a slice of
characters because
with bytes you know each character may
be one two three one two four bytes you
don't know how many
so you so you want to use slice of
um
runs okay and here is the you know the
explanation how do you convert them
so but our code what are we doing so we
are reading it as bytes okay
array of bytes then check error then
we turn the bytes into a stream okay
that's the content we turn it into a
string
okay now let's go back with what is this
code do
script to find replace multi not
multiplayers okay so it's actually
okay so it does replacement as well
okay it
so it turns the bytes to a string then
changed equals to force then
four this is the for Loop
for each of the pairs strut
found equals to string dot index content
pair fine string okay
so if it's found
you know and so go land you know if it's
not found it returns negative one which
is kind of annoying I mean because of
those low level languages they do that
so if it's not negative one meaning it's
found you found a fine pair some some
fine string then content equals to
string dot replace
okay so this algorithm so far is just
like our lisp and python
so when it's found you replace it
strings dot replace okay strings strings
is the package name
so replace this method
then you put the content there and the
pair find string and pair replace string
and negative one I forgot what is
negative one anyway
so if it's found you reset the content
then you set change to True okay
and you do this for each of the pair
okay so so far so good
now if it's so now if it changed then
you need to write cut to five okay so we
don't need this print remove the print
and if right to file right two files
should be always true okay so we
so uh okay it's not found here so
actually
let's just remove that
so if changed then just do this okay
now if two backup yeah we don't care if
two backups so
remove that too
so if changed we write to file
path
turn the string
back to
a slice of bytes okay
then write file permission it's a
Unix
it's you see this is this is of the
this is what makes a difference in
high-level languages in low-level
languages you know so because in emac
this in Python in Wolfram language we
don't see nothing like this like what
the is this
well but goal line is a low level
language but even though like low level
you don't neces you don't you don't you
you shouldn't have something like that
you know zero six six six four four
that's an actually an octo octal
notation for the Unix permission
but because skolan is from raw Pike and
he's a Unix phonetics so he adopted the
Unix you know thing
a cryptic thing as part of the goal line
so you write to file you have to specify
this permission and of course this
permission doesn't exist in
I mean it's different in in Microsoft
Windows in Mac OS or in other operating
systems it's just a unique thing okay so
anyway so if changed
um
we write to file write file then this
Arrow usually a very
tedious in Golan everything Returns the
error you know Gold Line returns two
values you know then anyway
so if
change do you write to file then then
return Neo is the function yeah so
return new okay so that's the two file
function
okay so then now your job our job is to
Traverse the directory
okay so we so in the main part here
we need to say we need to list all the
directories of this input all the files
and
and apply two files to each one of them
okay how do you do that
so here is the main Jesus
another big chunk of stuff copy
okay paste it here magnify
now let's deal with this
okay script path Arrow path okay we
don't care that's for reporting you know
like reporting which script called you
know
okay
so printing you know it's printing out
the report
time
final pass script path in directory file
regular
file rejects filter we don't care
actually we do care we want all only
HTML files right to file we don't care
do backup don't care
file list we don't care we don't have
print slice finally so you don't care
friendly base pairs I don't care okay
now if length finalist is greater than
one of course
uh
then do it okay so where is our file
list we don't have file list okay
you know in this script I do have a file
list
you know you can add uh that's when you
want a specific list of files you want
to to find replace
because otherwise you'll just do every
file in your directory
uh using a regular expression to filter
out you know extension or whatever but
sometimes you don't just want specific
digital files
okay so that's what this file this is
for okay and we don't care so therefore
therefore
removal that remove that and just this
part and
don't need that okay
so now we just do walk directory input
okay so input we need to change the name
go to top
the goal and Convention is typically
with short names in contrast to lisp or
wolfam language you there usually you
have very long names very descriptive
in general functional programming
languages you have long
fully descriptive names but C and Golan
you have very short names
so
so now we walk the directory in
directory and P Walker now what's P
Walker okay
so P walk
search for
key workout we have to oh God
you know so in Golan
in order to work a directory you have to
Define this worker thing
yeah you can just yeah you have to okay
so let's define
this walker thing
P Walker takes a file path
then take some
yeah this next is
anyway
anyway so ah near me after that
let's just ignore we don't care
and maybe we do care so
oh so anyway so the P Walker So
eventually it goes to file
yeah you need this because because of
the Golan is
so
uh but now we have a problem we are
trying to filter out some part here
that's why we have a string any
so let's just copy it
but yeah so here is the string any
let's just Define it
so string any match any returns true if
x equals to any of y
so we were using these two
to to filter our directory
to filter out certain a list of
Expressions regular Expressions list of
strings to filter out
okay so let's just include that
and to skip
the two skip okay and let's include that
too
because I haven't coded
um
Golan for a long time so I don't
remember it will take me a long time if
I actually try to write it cleanly
so the two skip is empty okay
yeah so go back here so if stream match
any skip don't skip anything so actually
so if skip then to skip
actually the whole part here can be
empty you know you can just like
yeah and then we'll walk I think
but then Golan will complain when you
have a function not used or you know
golden will kind of complain so anyway
so else we don't we don't want to skip
any though so else
match string
so here it is actually using regular
expression
a file name rejects oh this here is
actually using
um
this is to filter out a file name path
okay so we have we need this file name
Rejects
okay
so actually
so we can do Define here
that will work yeah
okay
so file name Rejects
all right
something something too far okay that's
it I think maybe I can we can try to
learn it now let's go to the main and
let's see
prints
if right through file
then print uh
we don't want to print we don't care
okay done okay
so let's try to run this what happens if
we run this
it's
check one more time okay
first of all let's try to backup then
let's format the code okay go format
okay done fantastic no syntax zero
so now
those are the libraries we need input
directory file name rejects okay
uh find replace pair struct structure
then here's the actual find replace
pairs each one we are using this tick
quote which means literal I I believe I
forgot
string okay
uh string
backslash Escape raw string vitro that's
right
so that is literal string that's right
so we don't have any we don't need to
escape bigger expression stuff
okay then
the two skip which is nothing it's a
slice of string
we don't have anything
is it used anywhere let's see
yeah it's used there okay
okay then
stream match any is a function
we have the function two file okay
and then we have the Walker thing
okay I think we can run it
let's let's copy the whole thing over
first
remove it
copy them over
and now let's run this go plan Bennett
finished
you see he says finished now let's go to
the directory let's see if it did
anything
open it
fantastic you see that works now list
matching lines that
fantastic you can see
it did the change now if we run it again
this will happen you know that random
string will happen twice it's running it
again okay
close close
run it again
finished
open it
open this
matching lines that you see
fantastic
one shot
there's no no debugging
now
we can
okay now we can actually so we need to
copy all
copy all put it back into our talk show
and now we need to create a new
hold on a second let's copy it here
so now we need to create a new file for
the goal lens so we can run it in the
Shell so let's go here
remove the syntax line
measure command
so this will be called go okay
and go
yeah so now we open that yes create
paste paste previous paste previous
paste previous that's it that's it
okay
save and close
open fantastic close copy this file
and this window we don't need any more
clothes
remove that okay now we can
paste here run the Gold Line
and see how fast it is
do it
that breaking the the other ones are
like six seconds you know two seconds
goal line is zero zero zero point zero
two seconds Jesus
oh go land my God
now let's let's let's
refresh okay remove everything
copy them over
run the Golan oh my God
0.02 seconds
Jesus that's
20 times length 30 times faster than any
of the
uh emac this python Wolfram language now
let's make sure it's correct okay let's
open this up
no it didn't work
it didn't change
all right
okay this is the force excitement
now what is the problem
what is the problem I don't understand
let's open the goal line Gold Line
let's check
oh yeah because of course the gold and
syntax
you are learning python if we are
calling python to run go idiotic
okay
we need to fix that so what is the
command to run go well let's see
what is the syntax to run go
that's part of my
uh here so Golan
I believe it's gold run yeah so you have
to say go run okay close so you have to
say
gold run and where is my executable
located
get command go
there it is okay
it's very annoying because you want to
see the full path
the Powershell is like you know it's not
showing the full path but we don't need
to
but one way you can do it is you can to
to show the full path is
all right
I believe it's full name there
okay I don't know let's go to go let's
go to Powershell
Furniture full name why is it not
that should work why is it not
okay so here is the full path of the
Golan okay just doesn't matter
so now
so now we just need to say go red yeah
so here okay let's do it all over again
remove the the
copy it over
now run Golan for the first time
four seconds four seconds
now is it is it faster than the others
let's see
well slower than python
Jesus what
it's ruined the second time
the second time is one second
okay now let's go check the file to make
sure it actually worked
open it
you see it did he did Now list matching
lines that you see
it worked you see
so when you run Golan second time it's
one second okay let's do it again
remove everything
copy them over
you and Golan
four seconds
hmm
what four seconds that's
even slower than slower than emac this
what the
second time
second time is significant significantly
faster okay let's let's uh
okay now let's um
that's about it for today so successful
fairly
I mean even we did lots of talking and
coding but still success successfully
done
go speed so the first time is
um
4.6 seconds
let's
unbelievable the second time is 1.1 okay
now let's see
okay Powershell
fam language
the string we need to replace
here's the result
can you believe it slower than python I
don't think so
I think algola needs to be improved
but however the interesting part is when
you run second time
Gola is faster than them all
huh
okay that's it anyone still here
that's it for today
thank you guys for watching buy my stuff
okay donate
interesting uh yeah very interesting and
I think tomorrow we're gonna continue
thank you we're gonna continue
because right now there are more things
to do okay so
right now this speed are reading you
know 1000 files small files
we need to do one
that is one single huge file you know
like we did before today one single huge
file and also we need to increase the
find replace pairs okay let's increase
them let's say
I don't know let's say increase them to
20 or something
and let's see so this is a very
interesting problem the problem seems
simple you know finally replace but
there's a lot intricacies there's a cash
issue because reading file is the
bottleneck it's a casual issue how do
you know you know the operating system
already loaded them in memory you don't
know
you know so it's a cash issue this and
uh there's a writing to file issue you
know you there's when there's no change
you don't want to write too far because
that takes a huge amount of time
and then there's an interesting feedback
loop problem
which all these languages our code is
incorrect it's acceptable fan language
you know who fan language is just
Superior that way
then
there's an interesting issue of the
second time when you when you run it you
know this
you see not current you know the the
current result is um
interesting you know you cannot say one
language is better than them all because
right now
if you can see the second time Goliath
is faster than them all
and and emac this comes second
if you can see the first time then
python is
fascist
Okay so
interesting for for some reason the
python the second time it doesn't
become faster
I
can you know maybe we have some bugs so
again thank you uh one of you
who found a bug in Python so
so if you have you know look at the code
of course you know just go to my website
you will find today's code in yesterday
I'll be moving all the code to today
because each day we improve on this code
so
so you'll find the code and you know do
try to find a bug or do some improvement
you know and if you have a version let
me know you know on Discord or Twitter
post your to your git
uh let's let's find out you know let's
have a deep conclusion on on which way
is uh is fastest and things like that
okay thank you guys and I think so I
think that'll be it for now tomorrow I'm
going to do something else tomorrow or
next day uh maybe take one day break
we're gonna do something else because
we've been doing this for the past three
days so then we're gonna come back this
and gonna have maybe some kind of final
conclusion
and if you called Ruby or other language
you know post your code so we can
compare thank you guys
bye guys
so let me go put the I'm shutting down
Okay so let's put Golan
let's go put the golden code
we have Golan here
okay so open it
copy close
paste okay