hello guys good morning welcome to
another episode of sun talk show so
today we are going to do a coding
challenge I'm going to code Wolfram
language okay let's start with fam
language
um
move from
okay
I'm gonna code Wolfram language to
answer this George's coding Challenge
and I have to start a new uh Wolfram
language file and
evaluate it started
and let me explain Okay so so yeah so
let's magnify magnify so you can see so
George posted a coding challenge to our
Discord forum and here it is I'm gonna
read it for you okay so the coding
challenge
and I have a bet with Dia and actually
right now we have already several
solutions by different people you know
we have uh several people posted the
solution triangle
cheated the idiot okay and you know
several people posted the solution in
different languages oh yeah Dia Zephyr
uh and the triangle and several people
so I claim I'm going to code this today
right now in Wolfram language and I
claim my code is gonna be the shortest
then them all python Ruby JavaScript or
whatever show this but
also the fastest okay the most fast
Speedy the most performant
that's a word performant okay then all
the solutions so what is the challenge
okay
so let's um yeah so let's read The
Challenge and uh and I have a bet with
Dion okay I I have a bet with Dion so
Dion is gonna bet whether my program is
gonna be the shortest and fastest and so
okay let's begin
so the the coding problem is that create
a function
such that when given an array of numbers
Returns the number that appears an odd
amount of times Okay so
only one number will ever appear an odd
number of times so there's a unique
solution and there will always be one
number that appears an odd number of
times okay so given an array or at least
whatever your language calls it
at least and and it's at least a bunch
of numbers
and many numbers occur several times
okay so you want to find one of the item
that's a number that occurs an odd
number of times okay and this that the
and that's unique you know there's a
unique answer so here's some example
Solutions I mean the specification of
the problem okay and try to think of the
shortest Solution that's the fun part
you know that's the fun part of the
so-called lead code lead code
shorty solution and you know the
shortest or the most elegant and the
fastest those are all good uh criterions
Post Your solution in thread okay so so
okay I'm gonna start to do it okay
so yeah so Wolfram language so let's
save this in desktop uh
let's say let's name it get odd okay get
r dot MB that's the Wolfram notebook so
okay so this is this might me take me 30
minutes I I'm gonna try to do it as fast
as possible over 30 minutes or I'm gonna
try to be shortest and fastest then all
the others then python you know then
python Ruby JavaScript or even go land
now I'm not sure if you if you call that
in C
I'm not sure I can beat it I mean even
in in Golan possibly okay I don't know
for sure okay but I'm gonna try maybe 30
minutes 240 or maybe in an hour so let's
begin so
you know you're gonna watch you you're
just gonna watch me coding okay and
meanwhile
if you like you know you might try to do
it you you know um it's probably it's
probably going to be boring for you
because I'm just gonna go technical on
wolfen language okay so so I'm gonna
begin now uh
so the so you want to given a list so
okay so let's just begin uh X this
equals to something okay and let's Okay
so let's uh for example
so you also want to make sure you handle
special cases like a array of a single
item right so for example uh let's see
so here is an example from George so let
me start my solution here
uh okay so start a Wolfram language code
code block okay and this is the wufam
language
in fam language solution okay let's just
do it okay and let's start to code
Wolfram language okay so Wolfram
language so X list
that's the uh Define the input okay so
that's the input
uh so so so so in this case seven
because seven occurs three times seven
seven thirty seven
so the solution is seven so you want to
define a function
uh let's say get odd okay
get all these function and okay let's
just uh let me code it
uh wolf you know I'm using Wolf star
wolf and mod in JavaScript I mean mod in
Emax that's my own mod you can find if
you just search it you'll find uh it on
GitHub because I will find mod then I
can evaluate it here in emac so I can
paste it I'm gonna paste it in Notebook
okay so but I can type it faster in
emacs so uh that's why I'm doing it here
so
so the function will take a input okay
so input will be let's name it X
distance okay
and here is the function body okay body
Okay so
so okay I have to think about it so
Define a function so this function takes
a list and the output is the output is a
single number that's the item
that occurs an odd of number times so
the output is a number
uh and it's a part of the test an item
in the list okay so and uh
so you want to count so let me write
some notes for myself okay so actually
uh let's go back here so what the the
plan of the algorithm you know
this is my the process of how I code you
know different people have different
styles I tends to be
first of all a logical analysis you know
some people start to code right away
trial and error you know which uh is you
know different styles so I so so first
of all I want to
um yeah so count so basically you want
to
um
count number of
of occurrence
for each and every item
return
the item that's odd count okay so
essentially you can't so you have to
count
okay so you can so
I'm thinking whether you can abort in
the middle once you find the answer but
I don't think so because you have to
cover every you have to count everything
so
uh
yeah because otherwise you have to
go all the way till the end of the list
otherwise you wouldn't know if that
occur yes okay so count
um
count a number of occurrence for each
and every item so for every item so for
every unique item you have to count it
so one of the you know one of the most
common
intuitive solution is is to build a
dictionary or hash table so every time
you take a number
see if it's it already exists in your
hash table in your dictionary if not you
add it with a value of 1. if it already
exists you add it
if you know if it already exists you
increase the count two by one
so after you do that you got a hash
table
then
then you go through the hash table yeah
then you go through the hash table and
find the one whose value is one okay so
the let's write it down so it's um you
know so it's clear to everyone who come
to watch the video so
okay
e uh most
intuitive algorithm okay
hash table build a dictionary
for
if I go through the list for each
python
add to the hash if it already exists
increase
value by one else
add
to hash
with value of one okay so that is the
algorithm okay
so that's the most intuitive algorithm
we can do that in Wolfram language but I
think I got better way you know so that
algorithm is probably okay now you know
that this algorithm is probably how
you're gonna do it in every other
language this is yeah this is the most
common so now let's think about is there
some kind of shortcut like a trick or a
mathematical formula to to do this
you know another way for example if you
can is that you get you know you try to
get all the unique
if you can maybe there's a you know if
if it's very fast to get all the unique
items in the list because this list is
going to be
lots of numbers
and uh most of them will not be unique
because each item will happen several
times
right you know by the spec so the unique
item will be actually a small subset of
the list okay so if you can get a unique
item you know the unique items you still
have to count it
okay so let me so maybe let's just uh
you know walk you know let's just
brainstorming okay
another way this is probably not a good
algorithm not I mean not efficient get
or
unique items in the list
because
the
most of the time assuming the list is
random
random-ish most of the time
the unique
items will be a small subset of the list
okay
of the Beast okay
then
then you just
then you still need to count each then
you still need to count the
occurrence
of each unique item
okay that's then then that kind of uh
made it pointless
because is there some kind of magical
way
to
um okay so let's go on to the next idea
so another way to solve this is you can
reorder them
that's right
you can sort the whole list but sort is
fairly expensive yeah probably not not a
good solution
so the whole list the advantage of a
sorted list to begin with is that you
you can once you find a different number
then you know that that is it the number
of the occurrences of the particular
item
okay
advanced
being that
when you go through the list
and when you see a different
number then you know
that
the current number
no longer occur in other words you can
find our currencies by partition the
list
into subdists then you just count the
length of each sublist
but you do need the algorithm that
compares differences between items okay
so that's another way I don't think
these ways are faster than the simplest
cache I mean the hash table solution
okay so okay let's that's enough
thinking let's start to you know who fan
language has lots of building functions
this problem
the way I saw it I'm thinking this
already building function for it
something like that okay let me show let
me try to find it okay Taddy
there it is a function Tabby okay
tally Tad is the elements in this this
thing or the distinct element together
with their number
that's it that is it that is a solution
okay let's let's do it
uh we don't okay tally
tally
and and uh and and xx okay so XX is the
input
so yeah so okay so that that's already
the solution isn't it
okay let's run it let's see what we get
okay function okay so let's add the
semicolon so we already got the output
here so the the output is this
so one occurs twice seven occurs three
times
three occurs twice is that right that's
correct then once you get this then all
you have to do is you
you won't get the item
such that the second element is odd
okay so now yeah this is a solution I
think I'm gonna win the bet okay so okay
so Wolfram language let's go to my own
oven Language tutorial you know I'm
promoting with my language within
language you know who from research is
donating to me sponsoring
you know my videos so
so I have written a tutorial of the
whole you know I've been coding Wolfram
language since 1992 and it is my
favorite language I've been coding it
for over 10 years since 1992 every day
you know uh and so
um so I want to yeah so let's look at my
tutorial you know I've been working on
it again so
right now we want to get the
item in a list such that the second
element is an odd number okay so here is
all these all the possible functions to
get the list
so you want you can use pattern matching
which is in general much slower so I
don't want to use pen imagine or you can
use
um I can I can try both ways so pattern
matching is a solution then the other
solution is just go through each one and
apply a function select okay so here is
so if you want to get parts of an
expression
bio function you can use select you know
you give it a filter function you know
there's a building so you you know
that's you know we just copy and paste
okay let me show you okay so select is
one way
so
select in so select the Tidy result then
then here will be a function
um
okay
okay I have a shortcut so this is
powerful Wolfram shortcut
uh I'm gonna I'm not gonna explain
okay actually so let's okay first of all
let's remove this part there
okay let's not use the shortcut because
the shortcut is hard to understand for a
lot of people so let's use yeah but
however we need we are doing a bet of
the shortest program so actually I do
want to use the shortcut but let me do
the the full form first okay the
function then the argument so what is
this even Q okay so we want to test the
second argument so second argument
oh God so if you take a element that's
going to be much slower so actually
maybe the pattern matching is faster
let's try it okay
so the second element
is odd okay
there it is okay so let me let me show
you what's what's going on clean the
code uh
okay so let me show you explain uh you
know you guys um
you know ufan language is just like this
so here is the function already so
remove that so taddy first of all we get
Tabby and then we select okay select
text two arguments first of uh the first
one is the data okay the second one is a
function so this function is gonna be
um
odd in the second argument okay so
function so this part size stand for the
input of the function so we take the
second part
and we check if it's odd
then if it is
then return it okay
but the thing you know this will work
but however it's not the most efficient
because it will because we know that
this problem there's only one odd
you know one of the items that's that
occur odd number of times so once we
find that we do not to you know select
the other ones so
so this is not the most efficient but
but
let's just run it so to make sure it uh
it's correct okay so get our X list okay
let's run it
seven three you see that's the result
you see this is the correct result okay
here is the
here is the correct result let's put it
here okay let's put it here
seven three okay in fact actually we
need to we need to return a number so we
don't want the list so we want to so
once you
select once you select it then you want
to
take
the
first element of the first element okay
because here is the output that's the
nested list you want to take the first
element which is this list then you want
to take the first element that's seven
so let's run it again
uh okay so you forgot the unique Parts
okay so there run it
there it is you see seven okay so this
is our um
first solution okay that's not efficient
that's this you know let's let's do
another one okay let me run this in
Wolfram language so you can see
um I mean let's run this in notebooks so
you can see
the net you see seven okay
let's put it here
okay so now
let's make it faster now we we're gonna
do the timing we're gonna write the
command to do timing and we're gonna
write several Solutions okay so this is
the first solution okay get out one uh
get odd one so that's the second
solution
now we know that there's only one
occurrence so let's do let's now let's
do a pattern matching okay
pattern matching okay so the function
will be
you want to so you are given a list
that's a result of Taddy
okay let me write it out so
so that you can understand
result of Teddy
is
that okay
okay it's
[Music]
so this way you can see
result of tally essentially
is the solution okay so we can do that
that will return true you know you can
you know let's run it
yeah you see true
uh
you see okay so but so first solution
then second solution let's use pattern
matching so when you use uh so you are
given a list a list like that now you
want to
select an element such that the second
element is odd
now you want to do this by pattern
matching okay so how do you do that
um
yeah so let's go back to uh so pattern
matching you you use the cases okay so
let's let's do it here so second
solution
uh
so you don't do you don't say select
okay so let me copy
so you want to say cases
okay cases the first uh element is the
data the second part is a pattern
right the second part is a pattern so in
this case we're gonna be the pattern is
gonna be a list
and X anything
okay so at least
X
foreign
X is a number
the second part is um well actually X
anything that you know we don't want to
do extra computation because we need
this to be as fast as possible the
second part is going to be odd so and
so underscore means anything anything
with a condition
okay with a condition so we want to do
pattern matching
by applying a function so it's a
we are doing both kind of a patterns
such that
this function returns true okay so
pattern syntax so let's go to pattern
syntax
so uh
yeah test okay test is e uh odd
Q okay
okay so this is the pattern matching
solution
okay so let's
let's do it here
hello guys hello Reaper
PHP Wings Reaper has a PHP solution
we're gonna check out well not in live
stream but you know we're gonna check
out all the solutions to see who is
faster okay run it
pattern matching okay again true you see
it's selected seven so that's correct so
I actually I need to go faster okay so
you need uh once you get the result you
need to take take the um
take that okay done it
okay seven seven is true okay let's
let's just uh let's just say equals
seven that's true
run it
you see true true fantastic so we have
two solutions now
uh but both of them are not the most
efficient because they actually go
through
all items we want a solution such that
once you
get elements
that the second part is odd stop okay
so
so actually I wonder if that's uh that's
already part of the taddy function so is
there a
let's see taddy maybe there's an option
so
indeed there is an option
the second argument test used
test to determine where the pair of
elements should be considered equivalent
okay we don't want the test give a list
of the first representatives of each
equivalent classes
together with their multiplicities now
okay we want uh options such that
it will just select
okay so is there an option so one easy
way to find out is you type options okay
options and give the function name taddy
to see if there's any option no okay
okay so so we have to do this uh
manually okay so uh second solution
third solution okay let's
let's select by function
but exit when
first found okay
so select that function so
um
yeah so let's copy that
third third solution okay
select by a function this function but
once you find find it immediately exit
so in that case you you don't want to
use select
because select doesn't immediately exit
Okay so
okay let's check if there's an option in
select
pick out all elements E1 of least for
which criteria one is true there it is
pick out the first n elements for which
criteria is true so all you have to do
is give this n to one
this is fantastic so
select list Criterion and end okay so
select okay so let's clean this up so
you can see uh easy so you can see
select so select at least a Criterion
yeah the Criterion and third argument
one that's as long as as soon as you
find it return it okay so now let's
let's
do this is gonna be my
submission okay let's run it uh let's
run it
seven three fantastic so we still need
this extraction
okay let's show the pink window so let's
run let's copy that do that select do it
true true true true or true so all these
Solutions are correct okay and this
solution is the fastest
yeah or you have to you need this one
okay I think that's actually that's
that's my that's going to be my
submission so we copy that let's run
this in Wolfram language so you can see
you know it automatically colors you
know that
so you see the net
it's all true so this solution works
okay
uh what about some special cases you
know uh
edge cases uh so
when there's one element it should work
yeah okay my solution I actually that
this should be my solution okay
uh okay let me think about what else so
any any questions any comments let me uh
take a break then how long have I been
30 minutes 40 minutes so we did 30
minutes
uh maybe I should start now for the for
this video because
um
you know it's better for the video to be
short and then I'm gonna walk offline to
see in what ways I can squeeze this into
more tight coat you know in fact we can
optimize already so we can let me show
you okay so
um fourth solution remember we want the
shortest code possible so so in this can
be shortened a lot okay so for example
let me try Okay
so function so this function you can use
a short let me show you okay
fourth solution okay four and this
function part we can rewrite it so that
yeah so
you see this function can be written
like that okay so it's even shorter
um
but let me let me tell you okay so this
should be faster I mean not faster but
shorter but let me give you a another
fifth version
let's also keep the document document
same as third solution but shorter
syntax okay now the fifth solution is
is going to be
um
okay
same as fourth but faster okay
now how do you make it faster because
every time you extract an element that's
actually slow okay so what you want to
do is actually transpose the tally okay
let me show you
uh let me explain
let me explain what's going on so you
have a
okay let me explain okay
so you have a matrix right now you can
transpose it transpose means uh means
you're gonna have uh
uh
1 7 3 then the second part is going to
be
2 3 2. you see that's transposition
you have a you have a two by three
Matrix now it becomes three by two
Matrix so once you transpose it all you
have to do is you you want to find the
first
the first row
actually you want to find the second row
you want to find the odd number in it
okay get the odd number there
so in this case it's a second item then
you take the second item from the first
row that's your answer okay that's so
that is what we are going to do here
so you gonna transpose
okay this is gonna be faster even
because transposition is a extremely
fast operation in Wolfram language
because Wolfram language is like a list
I mean it's like a list language so
it has lots of operations that works on
a entire rectangular nested list the
most efficient way faster than
then you can do in C because the data
structure is structured in in such a way
to optimize this kind of operation you
know because linear algebra you need to
do lots of this so transposition so
we're gonna transpose
we're gonna transpose this tidy result
and then we're gonna
then we're gonna do a select okay so let
me let me write it okay so transpose the
categories result then we're gonna
select
we're gonna select this thing from from
this result
and uh
so okay transpose first okay so let's do
it here you transpose it then you take
the second
you take the so you transpose it you
take the
second element okay so you take the
second element okay then you select
then you select right so then you select
from there you want to the and the
criteria is just odd okay that's all
that's all there it is odd
then you only want the first one okay
so once you get that
let's let's assign it to
um
yeah once you as when you do assignment
it slows things down you know we are
really trying to squeeze speed here
so
so you transpose
you take the odd
and only the first occurrence of it then
you got the number which should be the
three okay but oh but you want the index
here you want the index
you don't want the number you you want
the index of this
thing
uh okay so you see a select indexed
then date select select selectable
select cell I don't think so select
first oh
okay so instead of
you know we shorten it again
so we instead of Select give three
argument we just say select first okay
um yeah so so that's gonna be another
solution so
anyway select first
trap selection what is that
trap selection okay that's some system
selection select select evaluate
said that replaces the current selection
in a notebook okay that's small
interactive thing
that's a notebook programming like when
you if you program Oak mod files that's
what that those are uh you know
selection evaluate just like emacs you
know you can like manipulate the
notebook
um
so I don't think so
okay we are kind of getting
out of focus
so can I do this quickly
so fifth solution same as possible
faster so
once you transpose you get the number
you get a number but you don't want the
number you want the index of this number
Okay so
so you don't want to select
so you don't want to select you want
the
you don't want to select you want the
index of that number
so
okay I think I'm kind of stuck
and this is getting more complicated
uh okay let me just run it so you can
see what's going on okay
so select first
don't need that anymore
okay
so this is the fifth solution
fourth solution
the net
choo choo choo choo Force so yeah so
yeah the last one is not done yet
okay so you see it returns three which
is the correct answer
but we need the index we don't we
we need the index not the
okay anyway now we have four Solutions
now let's modify them so
let's modify them so we don't use select
we use select first okay so let's try
this one first instead of Select let's
say select first okay we don't need that
the net
uh Parts specification
okay so wait
the net
oh okay yeah so yeah so if you use
select first then you
yeah so you just need the first one so
we don't you you know you can just save
first
more shortcut
unit
correct seven seven seven seven three
Okay so
so yeah so that makes it uh
yeah this is this is the fastest okay so
let's replace all these uh previous by
just that
okay then it
you see all correct now we can also do
this
uh
and do that so we run it
okay
so we have all these Solutions uh
Solutions but the fifth solution I still
need to work on
uh okay I think maybe that's it
how long have I been doing in 50 minutes
okay
um
yeah so let's copy let's run them in
Wolfram language okay let's rename
here
you know lots of so let's shrink it a
little bit
okay run it so it's all seven so the
only one we still need to work on is the
solution number five
I hope I can do it in this live stream
so
um so you need the index you need to go
through it you need to you need to get
the index number but you don't want to
use anything that's like map because
be because you only want to get the
first occurrence then exit
so the first occurrence then exit so in
that case so this is a problem
so given at least you want to select by
some criteria
and the result shouldn't be
the result should be the index of the
item not the item itself that is the
problem we are trying to solve so
okay so so this problem belongs to uh
get an element of the list no not really
get the index
of a list
that's right you want to get the
occurrence right so you want to get
the index where a certain certain
criteria occurs okay and only the first
one so once you find it exit immediately
so in that case uh
so let's look at here
count by pattern actually
you know there are so many wolf and
language Solutions you can there's also
count
uh
uh count okay so let's go back
position
exactly position is what we want okay
you give it a pattern it Returns the
position kind of like an index if the
list is flat
it returns Returns the index right yeah
position is what we want so position we
can use now let's see if there's
something more convenient
sought sort by reverse rotate right now
ordering no join Union intersection
referral no partition no split split by
uh no gather
gather is is that you group a list of
items into sub lists such that
they match some criteria
you know such as you know gather all the
same items right so before we were
thinking of the algorithm that we
arranged the list to like sort so gather
does that without actually sorting
so gather does that permutation minimum
maximum fat and transpose pad left so is
there um let me think an is there a way
okay position is our solution let's just
get on let's let's finish this solution
then that's it for the video
uh so Fifth Fifth solution so you
transpose you
you transpose it then you um
you
you don't want to select first you
transpose
okay
then you yeah so you transpose first
then you want to call position
foreign
the first
argument is the expression there the
second argument is a pattern so
um
the pattern will be this one this is a
pattern
underscore that matches anything but
must satisfy this function okay
okay so that's the pattern and then
level spect
okay level spec is uh I'm awesome thank
you
so level spect you know Wolfram language
when you have a list in most languages
when you have a list you have a function
like map you know that can apply a
function to every element in a list but
however if you have a tree or Matrix you
want to apply just two rows or all the
leaves of the tree then in all the all
the other languages python Ruby
JavaScript you cannot do it in fact it's
very painful to do it because they they
at least are generally flat you know but
Wolfram language these are almost always
arbitrarily nested so you have lots of
nesting so
almost every function that applies to a
list has a option level spec that can
specify you want to apply the function
specifically to specific level like for
example when you Traverse a directory
you know first you know the depth Unix
would call it depth but here the level
spec can be just one level or a range of
levels or negative one means all the
leaves of a tree
so
so here you can specify a level spect
the levels will be just one
you see so here is the level of spec
okay so uh infinity level n Only so the
level will be one okay just level one
then the last argument is one because we
want to check in thank you Reaper
hahaha
money money is everything thank you
uh so I think that's it okay
so
get the first in object okay so let's do
that okay let's run it
two that's what we want so we got the
result of two fantastic now once we got
the two
okay we need a variable we need to need
to save this okay so this is gonna be
more work uh okay so now let's do a
declare a local variable okay a local
variable
um module that's how you define a local
variable so module is like this let okay
so this variable will be
that okay
so X data okay so X data equals to that
okay then whatever body okay the body is
gonna be this whole thing okay
so this is how you define very local
variables okay so local variables now
you have a you have this transpose this
is the data okay
um
yeah okay so let's do something here so
hex data
then do that then get the position so
this position let's run it
okay so you can see the result is that
now once you get that you want to
okay so this is gonna be longer code
okay so data
data you want to data the first element
okay so let's actually
okay the first element of the data then
then you want to extract
these okay actually
okay this code you you wouldn't
understand but that's it I think that's
it run it
okay we got some error so
right so uh so you want uh yeah so okay
I know what what's going on so
so hold on second
so the first of the data so you want to
apply
okay I you know I'm not gonna explain
because it it's gonna take too much
um
yeah let's let's let's be um
so we it's gonna be let's do this fast
okay so let's
so you get the position
you know let's let's write it out it's
remember this returns that okay so you
get that and you want to
this is gonna be fastest but the code is
much longer okay
so
the first part of the data and you now
you want to essentially extract that
um
okay so let me look up almost done
almost
so I need to look up parts okay get
elements
the Pod syntax so if you do that okay
that returns to multiple parts
so you want to
get
first element
then the first first
okay so you want to say
pod
position
then you want to say
the first element of that and the first
element of that okay
then
then actually
okay this part is incomprehensible to
you guys I suppose
that's it that's wait what what
yeah so I think that's it
doing it
there it is this I believe is the
fastest solution
okay
this is the fastest solution so you know
let's copy them to Wolfram language to
The Notebook so we can see the result
here so we have
add one R2 R3 out for five Solutions
okay
run it
fantastic they all worked uh yeah and I
believe the number five solution is the
fastest the the fastest and we can clean
up the code
so let's say sixth solution
we can make it
shorter okay now let's try to make it
shorter this um
okay so that make it one line
okay so that
then
okay that that
make the whole thing one line okay 6 th
solution okay
run it
yep it works
copy the whole thing paste it here run
it you see all seven we have one two
three four five six Solutions okay
now of course this can be shorter too
this can be made even shorter yeah
yep
so seventh solution
wait let's clean up the
okay seventh solution same as six but
but
shorter okay
even shorter Okay so
the function
yeah so the function will be
um
okay
okay there it is
function okay
yeah
so seventh solution
rennet
oh wait did we Define oh yeah we forgot
to change the name
seven planet
fantastic backup now copy the code back
to Wolfram language learn it
seven Solutions all correct answers so
this is my
uh this is close to my last offer
okay so let's modify more
eighth solution
shorter
okay now we we are starting to
manipulate this little variable names
okay so data
just become X okay
and this first can be shortened okay so
actually let me just massively start to
you know do things that you normally
wouldn't know what I'm doing okay so
yeah
there it is how much shorter and shorter
now let's see module
uh I don't think you need
if you only have one variable do you
need the first argument to be at least
uh I don't know maybe
so anyway eighth solution okay so also
here we don't need
um
there's a lot Improvement to be done so
first so you can just say
uh
okay
eighth solution
so first X then position that that that
that that
okay
run it
fantastic copy the code back to from
language paste the whole thing
learn it fantastic okay
um
now we are starting to just ditto with
code you know like syntactic or change
it like remove you know remove the
spaces remove this redundant spaces but
that's not really uh good there are some
more optimization to be done here
because but that's it for today okay
so I'm gonna go offline and gonna work
on this small and let's see how how good
it is let's see if I can beat python you
know so
there's a lot more to do so I'm I I need
to continue to call this and I also need
to write a program
that generate arbitrary uh input for for
this coding problem you know arbitrary
valid inputs so that I can test this on
a input that has a a Million numbers you
know because we need to know how fast it
is so then we need to do some timings so
we can run a timing on all these
different solutions I'm pretty sure they
are progressive you know like um
okay let's pop this back to emacs and
let's
syntax colored let's show in browser so
here we have the Wolfram code and we
have uh you know many solutions
it's magnify you know and I'm pretty
sure the
the progressive the more the the later
ones are faster in shorter uh
but we need to time it okay okay that's
it for today
bye guys
how many I probably lost all the people
Okay so
if you like my stuff donate okay buy my
emacs tutorial check out my uh you know
donate uh patreon patreon me
by my emacs tutorial my emacs packages
my JavaScript tutorial
and uh
stuff okay or just Amazon me a cup of
coffee or something bye guys
here's a solution
and yeah okay