hello everyone welcome to another
episode of soundtalk shows so we are
going to do emacs
lisp coding
so if you want to
learn emac bisp this is the right
channel
okay so today is going to be very
focused i'm going just to code three
uh emac list commands
and if you have questions about emacs or
um
emac lisp just ask me okay in the live
comments
okay let's begin so what are we going to
do so there is some uppercase sentence
actually so let's see
um
so for example let's go to
so what does that okay so let me
demonstrate
up her case sentence okay so let's in
order to demonstrate that i need to go
to some
some uh
some other let's let's go to
get some articles about
text so down the rabbit hole so alice in
wonderland
wonderland that's always um
okay on the wind on the pink window you
can see all my emacs command cores as i
move the cursor and so on so you can see
here we have a um
let's make them all lower case okay
so lowercase let's magnify
capital case every uh first letter of
the word
capita capitalize every
character
and lowercase so you can see
here is a lowercase let's um
hold on a second let's expand this
so there there it is okay so there there
it is so i want to so i can press a key
so it will capitalize the every sentence
so okay so let me let me show you the
full story so i have a command that is
this one
okay so one of the first command is
toggle letter case so let me introduce
that to you okay in a bit then the other
command is um
is this one uppercase sentence okay so
let me show you so let's see
okay that's too big
so
so what we're gonna do
so what we're gonna do is so we have a
text block here so toggle letter
sentence uh toggle letter k letter case
will
cycle among three
uh situations press it one time will
capitalize the first character press it
again
it will um
[Music]
i forgot what
okay let's try again press it one time
capitalize the first character press it
again capitalize the whole word press it
again
lowercase the entire word so that you
see that's the situation so let's try
again
one time two times three times one time
two times three times always in that
order so you can
develop muscle memory when you call that
command so the command name is that okay
so let's look at the
source code
describe
function
and that's a function type the function
name and jump to the source code so it's
part of some fly keys so you can
get a code in some flat keys it's on gnu
emacs alpha then gnu imax alpha or you
can go to this url
and grab the code so it's very
convenient because in default emacs you
have
three separate commands to do to do the
thing actually you have like seven seven
commands
to do each
uh
each type of capitalization different
differently
depending on which one you want so but
with this command you can you know you
just have one command you can do it um
you know
you just have one command so it's
you can just bind one key to it
so this is convenient so that's one
thing
the other thing i want to show you is
this command
up case sentence okay let's describe
function okay here's the documentation
for the function describe
up case sentence basically
when you have a uh up case first letters
of sentences of current block or
selection okay there's also the code
here
and you can
you know you can grab the code put put
this code in your emacs ini file and you
have this convenient function so what
does that function do is that
for example
let's let's put some period here okay so
for example when you when you are
chatting in discord or if you are on
twitter usually uh what you typed is not
properly capitalized
uh for example so let's put um
okay let's put some
comma here i mean let's put some period
okay so suppose this is your
paragraph
and
uh and uh
and uh
so you see each letter
each sentence are not capitalized so you
can just call this uh
function
up case sentence so let me do it
you see
and it highlights all the changes so
this is very convenient especially when
you are
um
for example you typed something in the
chat uh
you know normally i don't capitalize the
first letter because it's convenient but
if you want to block it later on you can
just copy it and and paste it here and
press a key you see it capitalizes the
sentence
okay the let's go to the source code
okay uh and uh it's also part of
stuff like keys
uh actually i wanted to make some change
but i already changed it
before i did the video because i wasn't
sure i'm going to do a video okay so
that's that command any questions no
okay so
now let's move on to the next
thing okay so what d block we don't need
okay so let's move on to the next
hold on a second let me
put this in a text
this alice in wonderland cut cut cut put
them there
and i want to demonstrate the next
command so here is a command
and here is another one let's
make them markup code
and
make them into a list
and select the whole list cut it and
back to here put it here and show in
browser
okay so that's another that's another
example so let's
cut this delete that also put it here so
showing browser
so here's what we talked about so
now i want to do this one we format
lines okay so let me show you that one
so let's let's try it so so what it does
is that for example i call the command
so this is a very kind of long line
let's copy it let's make it big
so i pressed one key if the whole thing
becomes one line i press it again
it you know it makes sure that each line
is no longer than 70 70 characters
now in emacs you have a command called
field region uh
field region okay
so what does so let me show you what
does that
do so
so let's put
put the command name here
make a list showing the list showing
browser so field region is a building
command in emacs
and
what it does is that for example if you
have a long line you can meta x
field region
and
it will cut
it will be formatted into multiple
short lines
uh very convenient
but however there is no building command
to unfeel to do the reverse
so
i believe you know
maybe they added let's see
let's let's describe function fear
region okay
let's see the documentation
so field region is an interactive native
command block
uh no interactive this is both um
field
prefix so
now i don't remember they have a they
added a command
in the past five years to do the reverse
uh
let's try it let's see unfeel
yeah i don't think they have it so i
wrote a bunch of commands to do that so
for example my version
uh
my version these start reformat lines
will do it so press a key it becomes one
sentence press it again it becomes
truncated okay so that is that function
now let's look at the source code
so here's the documentation
and it's also in stoplight keys and
there is the web page
so you can also grab this code and put
in your init and you'll have this
command
okay
but there is uh something else i want to
cover okay there is something else i
want to cover
uh yeah the problem of fear region so
the problem of fear region it's not just
it's not just that you know you don't
have a version that to convert a line to
a long line
so if you want to do that in emacs using
the glue emacs what you have to do is
you press ctrl u
for universal argument
then you press a big number let's say
let's say
99999 okay
that means
that gives
so when you do
control u
which is the command universal argument
that gives then you type something for
example we type 99999
what does that do is that the next
command you call it will feed
whatever you typed as an argument to the
next command in emacs so now
so let's try again okay so
control u
for universal argument you can see in
the mini buffers it says c u
then you type 99 okay let's do it again
control u 999
control u
99999 okay
then
then you call the field region command
so you do meta x
field
region okay
so that's what it
do now because
our cursor is currently on empty line so
it does nothing but if you move the
cursor here
okay
uh then you
press ctrl u
then you meta x
then you say feel paragraph okay
do it you see uh wait what
let's uh
let's do it again
meta x
field paragraph what
uh you have to do field region not view
paragraph let's try it again ctrl u
meta x
field
region
what
okay maybe because we don't have a
paragraph because emacs is trying to
look for capital letters
when it tries to determine paragraph
and when we tried the field region
version
[Music]
we don't we didn't select the region
that's why so let's try it again
so first of all select the region okay
now you know
select select the region
ctrl u
then meta x
then
confirm region do
it what's going what
this is odd uh
what's going on with the
wait the way this is
i i'm not sure what's going on hey or
flamio uh thank you
hey alan long time
wait not
an uncle
okay so oftlamio has a i hope i hope
distro start including sapphire kiso evo
mod in a set of emax packages
yeah i hope so
but anyway now it's on
nanganu
alpa so you know
let's see
let me show you okay
there it is so it's on free software
foundation's website uh not not there or
here okay so
here you can see on gnu's
website but it's not glue
so anyway so
there is something odd um there is
something odd
i'm trying to demonstrate this
so
select the region
ctrl u
meta x
field region
it's not working what's going on so
okay so let's start a emacs plain glue
emax fresh let's see what's going on
okay
so
where is my e-max okay so
bing
e-max e-max 27 e-max 28
run e max okay
and dash q that means no init
okay so this is uh let's let's close
this
and it's taking a while
okay there um
now
okay so you can magnify great so now we
are in glue emacs
so now let's try let's try it okay so
copy this paragraph
and the new buffer so i've i don't
remember the keys
so switch buffer is ctrl x
b
okay then just type something random to
create a new buffer
now paste is ctrl
y
okay now magnify
so now we are going to control u
then meta x
field
paragraph
tab okay do it
it doesn't it didn't work
it should work um let's try again now
this time
undo
ah
you know in default guru emacs if you
press ctrl z
it calls the command to icon
iconize the window basically hide the
window
fairly bad so undoing new emacs is ctrl
uh
let's try this yeah
that is control slash yeah that's the
undo okay
now ctrl x
1 to expand the windows okay so now
let's try this again now
ctrl
slash undo
so what we want to do
so go to the top control space to select
it
then all the way down to select the
region
then ctrl u
99999 to give a argument universal
argument to the next command
now
meta x
field
region now we have a region so
this should make the whole thing one
single line
ah something something something
something is wrong or something is
broken let's see what's going on field
region let's read the documentation uh
maybe there's some change in imax 28
fear region is an interactive native
compiled dis function in that file it's
bound to okay menu bar something
something
uh
fear each of the paragraph in the region
okay by the way that's the emax jargon
field it just means
reformat it just basically just means be
format
it would be interesting to look at the
history you know why does it emax called
call this command feel
yeah i don't know i don't know why is
that
why you know it should be
more intuitively it should be just
called reformat okay so anyway feel each
of the paragraph in the region okay
region is a text selection
a prefix argument means justify as well
oh yeah that's right okay
yeah okay
yeah i forgot so
so let's see from fear region from true
position yeah okay that's idiotic the
you know so the emacs the gunnery max
field region and field paragraph command
are extremely idiotic
so the you see what happens is that
in order to set it
you know they they use the value of
field field column this is a variable
okay the variable is a
number that that number tells that all
these field commands
uh just
what what is the maximum
number of characters in each line
so if you want to convert
you know a bunch of short lines to one
single long line
what you have to do is you have to
change this value this variable's value
field column to something huge okay so
so let's do that okay
uh let's go back to gnu emacs you know
so that you can actually show um let's
see
now i don't have my shortcuts and
everything so it's going to be super
slow when i'm working group emacs so set
q
field
column
uh is at the right
yeah field column okay uh
and let's set it to
99999 okay now you can i want to
evaluate this this code so what you do
is
control
x
e
okay you can see in in the mini buffer
it's done now i don't know how to
enlarge the font in the mini buffer
let's let's do this uh
so let's how do you enlarge the font
let's go to the set default font
okay so now that should be good
okay so
again evaluate this list code okay you
can see in the minibuffer it's done
now we just
meta x
what
and do
meta x
field
paragraph
okay now you can see
now it's correct you know the whole
thing is one paragraph you know so it's
very inconvenient for example in in in
my customize command i
press one key
press one key your toggle you know but
in gnu emacs first of all you have to
you have to
change the variable you can do that by
calling
set variable okay you coset variable
then you type
field column
okay and now you give it a value okay
cancel so that's how you do it in green
emacs
so all these are very
um asian let's say
so
that's why i created you know
the command you are seeing
okay i was playing okay so i was
planning to actually to code some emac
lisp
because there is something i need to
fix i need to improve let's go to the
um
you see here's a source code for this
not this one
saudi format lines okay describe
function
there is a source code
so reformat lines that's the
there's something i want to change there
anyway let's let's go back to
let me finish explaining the field
column and stuff in emacs
so
you you do have several problems and
you know
basically it's inconvenient let's see
search for xari emax
field region
you will find my article that describes
the problems
okay so this is reformat
lines which we just demonstrated but
what is the fear regions problem i have
several articles
one of the odd
problem is described here we haven't got
into yet
but there are other problems uh let's
see
open them
hard wrap lines yeah so here this is a
tutorial on how do you hard wrap lines
in glue emacs so you can see you have
several commands field paragraph field
region
field paragraph we will just work on the
current paragraph fear region is that
you have make a selection first
if you don't make a selection i'm not
sure it'll work actually it does i think
because of the
yeah it doesn't it doesn't actually you
see
you see right now the whole thing is one
line
and let's call
fee origin call it
you know because we didn't make a region
so it doesn't actually select the whole
paragraph
so anyway so you have all these versions
of field command so and you can also
turn on auto field mod that means every
time you press the enter key it will
just reformat the paragraph above for
example let's
turn on auto field mod okay now i press
enter i gotta the cursor needs to be
here so i press enter you see so as you
type you know every time you press enter
you'll just do the field
then you also have oh yeah so there's a
more even more convenient set field
column
you can meta x code and set the set uh
how many characters you want per line
and there's also ruler mod let's turn it
on
okay so ruler mod shows you know this
kind of convenient um visual clue
but anyway so these are inconvenient
because then you have to d when you know
when you call field region you have to
make a selection first in gnu e max
that is
control space
then move your cursor
you know once you have a selection then
you call the command so it's it's not
good
so the first step of improvement is to
just to write a
uh command that does the reverse
so you don't have to
you know set field column
then call the command
then set field column again to change it
back to 70.
so you have these simple commands
unfilled paragraph and field region you
know you can copy it and put it in your
source code that will that will work so
that solves one of the problem unfeel
which is a major
complaint
of emacs you know for for a long time
what i wasn't sure is i think
they uh i i don't know if they
fixed it
in the past five years maybe i forgot
so that's that's that fix is one of the
problem but there are other problems
that is
let's look at
um
so let me go to
yeah so the other improvement is this
command
auto toggle field and field region
so you don't have to make you don't have
to make a selection first
when don't if
if there's no selection it will
automatically work on the current
paragraph
now if you make a selection then it will
work on in in a selection so it get
reads of this choice you know
mental decision
and
it will also toggle you know if the
current line is short you'll just toggle
it in too long if the kernel is filming
you just toggle so you can
and also work on the selection you know
so you can do it
um well that doesn't work that way
anyway so you
that's this command i'm you know that's
this command because i feel or unfeel so
that's the next level
of improvement
okay
that's that's another thing okay now let
me let me tell you about another problem
of emacs field column okay
that's why i wrote this song reformat
reformer reformat lines now the problem
of field column is this okay
so for example i have
this line this is one single long line
and
if i call
field paragraph okay
now let's copy it put it here let's call
field
paragraph
okay you can see that it adds it adds
space it adds indentation in front
now if you are working in code in python
in images in golan in whatever cc
language you know this is no good
so anyway this so the point here is that
the field
emacs field commands
not just exchange white spaces to
different white spaces but it actually
add extra
sometimes or delete extra white spaces
okay
that is a problem
sometimes not desired okay sometimes you
don't want that sometimes you do but
sometimes you don't want
okay that's one of the things for
example let's see
this example
okay
so uh well
so let's paste it here
let's paste it here save close three
open so we get rid of the
highlights
so you can see we have this
paragraph okay now if you call
uh if you call
field paragraph
okay they made some change in emacs 27
or 28
because before it becomes
a single line
with all these asterisk removed wait did
we do it right let's try again
so select the whole thing called
field region
uh
oh yeah so with yeah so yeah with a big
field column value so i forgot about
that so
you see
you want to make this into a single line
so usually what you do is
set q
that
99999 okay
so evaluate that
then
call
field paragraph do it you can see now it
becomes a single line this is how you do
it in gnu emacs but now notice that the
asterisk
is gone
so let's
you know the asterisk basically emax
removed the asterisks characters
you see so so the point is that the this
field paragraph
um or field you know these field
commands actually
you can say corrupt your text or you
know
because you and
the worst example is this okay
the worst example when you have a
chinese
you know here in this
paragraph you don't have any space at
all for example search for space you
don't have any space in this uh
paragraph
now copy it paste it here now if you
call field column again
i mean for your region let's
set it back to 70.
eval
okay now you call
field region a field paragraph
okay
you can see
it made them into
separate lines shorter lines but however
now turn on show space you can see
in chinese you don't want this okay you
you cannot add extra space in your text
because
let me show you okay because when you
show in browser
i mean that's not the right thing to do
you cannot do that
so let me turn off the white space
okay so
make this a paragraph makes this a
paragraph showing browser
now
magnify
uh
wait where's the
they they look identical here
but however
okay so there is this character
jinsan young susan
okay so it looks looks like the browser
improved
because before
looks like browser improved because
before they would add a space here
between the characters you'll see you
know between the characters there you'll
see several space let's try this in uh
chrome
okay let's open in chrome let's see if
in
behaves the same way in chrome browser
indeed it's not fixed so in firefox
browser you know we're getting into
technical details you see these two
almost identical paragraphs of chinese
the difference is that one of them has
you know uh
end of line characters you know here so
three of them
when you just display them in firefox
they make no difference but if you
display them in
in chrome browser
there is a difference let me show you
let's see where you see
you see
there is a space
after this character
but you don't see it there
so if you are a chinese you know reader
you know if you are in chat you know if
you read chinese
you you don't want that you know because
it's disruptive you know it's not it's
iso
so you see that's a problem so you don't
you cannot you know you don't want that
so this happened because you are calling
field paragraph
essentially the point is that
between no space
no space between characters it inserts a
space white space
okay so that's one note that's you know
that's the that's a problem that's the
problem of field paragraph okay so
the point is i want a command
where
it doesn't do any of those all it does
is exchange white spaces characters you
know maybe replace multiple spaces by
by a line return or read
you know or change line return into a
space
so consider
any sequence of white spaces are
equivalent and nothing else you know
the command supposed to only do that
so that's that so that's why that's why
i have these
reformat lines okay so for example if i
copy this
line
paste it here let's let's paste it here
okay
and i call my command it does nothing uh
it does nothing because it didn't find
any white space in this paragraph
so there's no opportunity to break it
you know because it sticks by the
principle
that the command
the command only exchange white spaces
uh where is it
there sorry format reformat reformat
lines okay i think i think that's it so
today we just cover talked about um
some of the details of reforma reformat
lines
uh
okay
i think that's it thank you guys for
watching
the code that code is always running how
does it works i'm only more or less
familiar with wufang language
uh was it supposed to be unfear region
okay
okay thank you guys orthodox celtic
orthodox hi
how much is
html mod
i think i'm selling for
let's see if you like my stuff buy my
stuff okay so html you know it they have
been open source for like 15 years
but
i become hungry and no money
so
and forty dollars
a big one forty dollars yeah
so you can you can buy my entire
packages for a hundred dollars
that's probably better
uh html mod
you know because it's actually the most
difficult mod 5
000 lines
uh you know
written in the past
10 years exactly
well may 12th it's
it's 10 years anniversary
you know i've been working on this for
10 years so
okay thank you guys for watching uh bye
guys
you