hello guys welcome to another episode of
some talk show
today we are going to continue
the Advent of code
so we are going to code event of code in
Wolfram language yesterday it was a
spectacular struggle
uh so yesterday
we did you know the past two days we are
doing Advent of code live coding so we
did problem one uh where's problem one
yeah problem one uh then problem
two yesterday yesterday turns out to be
three hours affair you know the first
hour is pretty good the first half hour
I was talking about programming
languages you know many of you young
people are wondering which language to
learn
and uh you know I was doing a bit rent
on that
and also the meaning of hacker so check
out yesterday's video meaning of hacker
and what language to learn okay the
first hour then we are coding event of
code
analyze the problem then I was talking
about the
the essence of mathematics the issue of
how do you convert a real life
description uh certain you know some
sense of the problem how do you turn
that into a mathematical description
with precision and that is a non-trivial
thing and that is the problem of the
event of code day two I think most of
the domain of code problem is going to
be like that they describe it you know
in in a kind of story-like way and you
have to turn that into a specification
once you have a specification then
things have
uh usually usually easy okay so there
are two parts of the problem one is you
know
do an analysis you know think about it
you know turn that into a spec then once
you have a precise spec
then usually it's much easier much
easier then it's just about coding
so but the problem of turning a sun
fuzzy concept of the problem into a spec
is very difficult in fact that's the
essence of math Okay so yesterday we did
that then it turns out you know I had
some
um
uh problem with you know modular
arithmetics you know it took two hours
to eventually got the right answer so
here's the solution in Wolfram language
code uh just basically one single line
that's a solution
okay and and yesterday was two hours and
40 minutes today we are going to
continue problem number two every
problem there are two parts so we start
the first one we're gonna continue
problem number two then we're gonna do
uh problem number three okay so now I
get I got a taste of what this event of
code is I'm just going to be relaxed
I'll try to do as much as possible today
and try to focus on the problem but
don't worry I'm I'm not going to worry
about oh I'm going to do a good job and
finish it fastens and so on because
you know the as they say the process is
the fun part you know that we are doing
this TMI hi what's your keyboard is at
okay you must be new so this is expose
info okay so I want you guys to go to
kusali.info or
uh
sardi.org okay so kasabi.org is my
primary my central website I had this
domain for beginning year 2000 so for 20
years now then it split into Sally info
about 10 years ago and others but now
it's so now the con and also split into
many other domains but now it's all back
so sadi.org
then you you have sally.info sally.info
is all about math programming Unicode
keyboard technical stuff you know for
those of you nerds uh and uh saudi.org
is some other things English writing
Linguistics literature writing style
things like that and the songs you know
I talked about this many times
introduction to my website so
so I like you guys to those of you find
me interesting you want to you know
spend some time on my website
because usually it's a case you know you
got all these frequently asked questions
like almost for any YouTuber as well you
know people have questions but you
covered you talked about that a million
times
okay so sorry that info then you go
there then there is you know several
videos there's a keyboard okay so this
is uh they are right now currently 1 000
articles so you just go to Ergo
keyboards and uh
then there is expose all the information
and review and details are there okay
that is this keyboard and the other one
is automatic I talked about this
tens of times in my video okay so back
to event of code
uh
I recommend expose okay what is one of
the keyboard I recommend
you should go out and buy it now
okay so but let's do Advent of code
today okay so
um copy the paste copy paste copy the
link here go here close close Okay
yesterday's solution
uh doing a dependent of code number two
let's copy that here because we need
uh the code to solve it
from yesterday so here is the Wolfram
language code and here is Wolfram
language again I have a tutorial on my
website just search for Sardi wufam land
you'll find a complete tutorials and
video tutorials in the past
learning yo do you find the event of
code problems to be typical or typical
of common problems encountered in
software development
well basically all these exercises
basically all of them including you know
something became popular today you have
lead code you know that's a website that
so lead code is a website that's uh all
basically
exercises or toei problems and then you
have Euler project which is also a
programming problems you know simple
Euler project I believe that's what it
called
okay let's have a look about project oil
okay oil is a mathematician okay so you
go there you know so that's another
website for all sort of programming
problems but the end of a code once a
year oil project and there's another one
called lead code that's uh
it's a Malaysian Zuma's thing idiotic
you see they advertise themselves as the
the words leading something something
crap okay let's turn on JavaScript
you know this idiotic website if you
don't have JavaScript they won't show
but once you turn it on
that's JavaScript is the conduit of
Trojan Horse you know they can track you
they know everything you do including
which part you are looking at you know
where do you pass and all that so anyway
these codes you know some
some Zuma they want to cope in life the
[ __ ] idiotic so they create you know
the website they make money money is the
key money makes the world go around okay
everything is money so they created this
you know pretty good website you know
and also
not not too bad you know it so all these
websites they are programming exercise
websites
Euler code a project gorilla usually
focused on mathematical problems like
find the prime number or things like
that you deal with numbers
lead code is just a
you know I'm not I don't not you know
I've I've done like one of them you know
it's just provide me problems all these
problems including advantable code they
are toy problems okay they are toy
problems or used to be called
programming exercise
okay and if you want to be dramatic you
can call it
um you know programming challenge
or sometimes on the YouTubers you know
they want to you know you want a job
right you want to get into Google lots
of money free food Facebook and all that
you know so they allowed YouTubers these
Zoomers scammers
you know they these days they The Zuma
generation have a jargon they call it
grifters you know you just go on YouTube
you make something traumatic every day
so that you got lots of viewers
followers one million and you become a
millionaire and what they talk about is
just uh [ __ ] you know they talk about
drama and [ __ ] every day
so that's wasting your time so anyway so
this all these are toy problems uh do
they have anything to do with real life
no uh almost almost nothing nothing
whatsoever to do with real life coding
problems
however toy problems are very important
and useful it in in the sense that they
help you learn a language you know you
can go to Python tutorial there's a
hundred by pajit
that's another word I learned you know
by by lower level you know Indian people
they don't know what they're doing a lot
tons of it you know or they all all
these scam websites you know or not
technically scam but the idiotic you
know they are trying to make money
that's that's money okay they run ads
they're trying to make money but their
information is usually low quality so
anyway so there are a lot of tutorials
on python JavaScript particularly these
languages you know
um so when you learn you can just read
it but that doesn't help you need to
actually put hands-on experience so at
the end of code is one of the website
that helps you you know do you need to
practice so but ultimately it's for
beginners okay the Advent of code lead
code you know project order those are
all for beginners
you know let's say you know for young
people for students many of you are
hey Ethan Ethan is a mathematician I
want to mention Ethan is a great uh guy
so Ethan knows stuff I believe that's
who you are right Ethan Ethan Ahmad sad
Discord so you know my followers are
uh very diverse you know a lot of you
guys are young people you know college
students or teenagers or so-called need
or whatever you know uh meme posting
Chan you know you know a lot of people
but I also have certain percentage that
are professionals and mathematicians and
I really appreciate those people
and of course a lot of my peop followers
are also uh keep not programmers but
they are into keyboards you know they
are into all sort of um
keyboards okay so you know because I
have a huge website so keyboard
ergonomics Mouse you know what's uh
what's the deal with them which one is
better ergonomics you know what to do
when you have hand pain you know lots of
us
um have hand pain so you know so I also
have a lot of people who are into
keyboard they are not really programmers
so my audience is pretty diverse and
they are all over the Earth some are in
Europe in Africa Canadian China you know
uh so anyway so I so I hope that
answered the question all these website
toy uh
toy problems okay so
oh yeah let me mention so besides all
these websites of toy problems I myself
did a lot because when you are very
interested in programming such as me and
many of you you know you are obsessive
you want to especially the beginning few
years you know you are trying to you
know what's the best way to given at
least let's say you want to partition
into a sub list you know what's the best
way to do it in in whatever language in
python or JavaScript or Wolfram language
colon you know you do that a lot you
know there are forums even 20 years ago
30 years ago news groups so for example
in the 1990s I was doing these kind of
problems all day and every day with
Wolfram language you know what's the
most elegant way you know sometimes
people you post a snippet you know how
can I improve this to be you know there
are many judgments okay let me talk
about Judgment of the code
there are many criterias to judge a
piece of code for example here is a
solution
to yesterday's Advent of code problem
number two day two the first problem
okay you know so it looks like that
uh but how do you judge for for example
in your programming competition you know
so there are uh I'll just simplified
there are two primary criteria to judge
a piece of code doesn't matter what
language it is one is speed okay or
efficiency algorithmic efficiency so
given a solution in one specific
language
you want to come out with a code that's
fast the most fast the fastest than them
all given the input is a million a
billion you know you know usually your
billion is too large but usually you
know 10 input length is 10 or 100 or a
thousand your code
if if fast you know speed okay speed
also usually include algorithmic
complexity you know the computer science
jargon
algorithmic complexity that measures
that measures the growth rate
uh well anyway we're getting into
another topic so this algorithmic
complexity which measures memory
consumption and also the number of steps
your code is doing
it measures the proportion of those
things with respect to the input size
the ratio so when the input size grows
it it it it it
measures how much your memory
consumption grow and all your number of
instructions grow so if the memory if
the input size grows linearly
but your memory consumption goes
exponentially
that means your algorithmic complexity
of your solution is very bad it's it's
it's very bad okay depending on the
problem but anyway so one criteria to
judge which code is better is the
is this is this
you can simplify the algorithm complete
the complexity let's just say speed is
just to measure the speed of the code
okay you have to try different input
size okay so if you know so let's see
whose code is the fastest when the input
is huge okay that's one thing
the other criteria is to judge a piece
of code is the Elegance of the code or
uh
gravity okay so in other words a a rough
measure is how many characters how many
characters does your code contain in
comparison to the another solution of
the same language okay important it must
be the same language because different
language
the brevity is different Okay so
to summarize how do you judge a quality
of a piece of code one efficiency or
speed you know there are many technical
details or algorithmic complexity but in
summary let's just say efficiency and
speed that's one criteria the other
criteria is the Elegance of your code or
brevity of your code which may also
include readability
anyway we're getting complex because
because readability is not necessarily
uh
braverty because for example you have
UPS
absticated
obfuscated competition
or programming golf programming golf is
a competition where you can write the
shortest program to solve a problem
shorties means the major the count of
number of characters
so for example this this one if we do
num a count of characters
okay 199 characters
but then we can shorten the variable
names you know for example this function
I named it you know 20 characters let's
change it to one here so there's a lot
issues details but
basically again efficiency speed
brevity of the code and readability and
also Elegance that's basically the how
do you judge the criteria to judge you
know a piece of code solution okay
so you want to all these These are
important issues as a as a learned as a
you know student of a programming
language you want to
Master the language so you can so you
know which construct is is uh what is
its level of efficiency and uh
and uh you know and how to write the
same thing in a shorter way and more
readable so
the but efficiency and speed is the most
important efficiency okay efficiency of
the code
Okay so
So Yesterday here is the solution so
let's
um
so I'm starting to talk on and on so I
hope this video do not end like
yesterday two hours in 40 minutes okay
so let's let's start to uh solve this
problem anyway I'm gonna just be relaxed
so if you are watching this offline you
can you know Skip around or it's
probably boring or
make it play at speed 1.5 or something
ah
okay so you know you young people there
are many false beliefs because you you
guys read too much [ __ ] you know today
especially today uh online you know
Reddit how can you see it's all
bullshits so first of all I would
recommend you guys stop reading any of
those 4chan
read it
Hacker News or almost any other stop
reading them okay
you can do it you know you know stop
reading them that's what I say because
you guys many of the young people say
full of idiotic you know wrong
information so here's a question this I
thought lead code is good if you want to
get a job no that's what the guy is
trying to sell you know because
programming you know to get a job is
basically essentially the goal for just
about everyone when you are young when
you are a student you know when you are
you know
so lead code will advertise themselves
oh if you do this you're gonna get job
no okay you do lead code you never get a
job okay
foreign
so so let me put uh something positive
so how do you get a job Master a
language
you know you know this programming
problem story problems are very fun and
uh communal so like right now what I'm
doing you know I can talk to you guys
it's very it's fun you know we can
explore and chat but that's not how you
get a job okay it it does help you learn
a programming language but if you really
want to get a job I recommend once you
know the basics of a language
create a website create your own project
okay
you know I don't know what project you
know there are so many you know many of
you into games or writing a game engine
learn how to program a game some of you
into cyber security which is not about
programming but about lots of knowledge
and admin stuff you know some of you are
into Network networking that's another
giant topic you know
uh so there are many ways to go but I
recommend once you know the basics of
the language
focus on one language okay one that if
you want a job if your goal is to start
a career okay for you young people there
if your goal is to begin you know you
want to get a job so you can stay
comfort and like me you know who's been
very bad
so uh so you want to get a job so you
learn the basics of the language once
you know it you start a project big or
small you know a project of your own you
know then Focus publish that project
make it polished make it useful try to
try to uh you know the the more useful
to other people the better okay some
like Facebook for example Zuckerberg
which is a scam a human scum okay but he
but he you know when he's young he
created a project and that now becomes
the you know one of the richest people
in the world so do something like that
you can you can try to do that
create your own project okay
not forever you know in these
programming games or competitions so you
can prove to other things that oh I
served more problems than you that's
idiotic okay let's do some project
that's useful uh
and your own that's also important you
know you do this event of code that's
you are contributing for someone else
success now I by the way I respect this
guy you know the vendor code you know uh
he's a apparently a Christian and he you
know I respect the guy very good okay
but what I'm saying is that once you
know
the programming language you want to
start your own project
and the real life code that's that's the
difference okay some some of you asked
what's the difference you know are these
represent real life code no not at all
okay so but once you start a project
that becomes real life
uh code you you started to learn lots of
things that that's not fun okay this
programming exercise lead code event of
code project ruler that's kind of fun
and toei that's why they are you know
fun but once you start to do a real life
project you have to learn database
different protocols different you know
you have to read tons of document
documentation some of them doesn't exist
you know so
um that's real life coding okay
real life coding is almost almost
basically never like this lead code or
whatever okay never like it
and what about interview okay yeah
interview you know they they sometimes
show these toy problems but
but if you have real life coding
experience the all these story problems
become stories to you okay so don't
don't just like oh I'm going a master
lead code and so I can get a job I can
pass interview no you're gonna fail
okay you want to pass interviews
there's no easy way just like losing
weight okay you you want past interviews
Master language to a real life project
of your own put it on GitHub or whatever
and make it you know
satisfy your need some people other
people need you know do that
foreign
so we just random chatted for almost an
hour so let's let's start to do coding
then okay so let's yesterday rock paper
scissors so I need to okay let me just
you know take my time and do it
so we already did 30 minutes okay so
yesterday the problem is Rock scissor
paper a twisted with a Twist A variation
of it okay so I solved it by using
modular arithmetics oh let me mention
one more thing
so as far as programming problem goes
like I said in the 90s I did tons of
them every day you know just trying to
come up solutions for uh this list
manipulation and things like that for
example and I have so so I have written
quite a lot about 10 10 not not many 10
or 20 programming exercises on my
website
so here's one of them very interesting
programming problem construct a tree
given its edges you know this is written
in 2014
when I was dying of hunger I don't know
what I was you know doing I was
like many of you you guys you you know
you might say it's a mental problem so
I know programming very well I know
mathematics I'm bright you know I can't
do the problem but I do I failed in life
in some sense okay so this is a problem
given to me at Google
I was trying to do interview and I did
miserable but
um anyway I'm now going to go into
details because
it's a [ __ ] very shitty interview
um and the guy
don't know what he's uh doing
um very bad very bad experience in my
personal life
but in any case I document documented
you know this problem and I wrote a
solution after the interview you know
and uh so and I put and then I asked
people other people to come up with
Solutions so here is my solution which
is one of the most efficient okay
one of the most efficient okay this
Google interview problem
uh and then but there are they are
always always better programmers than
you just like in everything else okay so
there's a guy who created a python
solution
uh this guy
Ting you Ling okay a Chinese guy he
created a python Solution that's more
efficient than mine
and shorter than my too and more
readable than my you know my Approach is
top down approach and I actually I spent
five years five hours to
to write this code five hours after the
interview I failed I failed the
interview but after that
I've spent five hours
took me five hours to create a solution
but then someone else this guy he has a
solution
that's faster than mine
simpler to understand
better algorithm
okay and shorter so fantastic okay by
Ting Yu Lin
then there are other bunch of other
Solutions you know that's typically
online they don't know what they are
doing they are far more like a magnitude
inefficient you know if you give it the
input is 1000 length then they they took
an hours and things like that you know
so lots of other Solutions Solution by
Young uh you know
um timing comparison and solution in
emac this that's fun you know then
um solution enclosure list
solution in Shen this Shane lisp is one
of the you know Advanced lisp created by
this smart Tower a very strange guy
the solution in uh you know it was a
News Group uh comp.land.lisp
about seven years ago okay and in fact
the problems about tree construction you
know I have actually that's one of the
things I'm uh expert of so I did a lot
of that tree Construction
uh anyway so that's one one of the My
article about programming toy problems
okay
so let's go back to
um
yeah sure you can uh submit new
Solutions you know usually I have a lot
to do though so if you submit
I'll probably look into it but I got so
many other things to do I should I
really shouldn't be doing this Advent of
code but since I started I thought you
know I should finish you know go all the
way
um because I do have a lot you know I
never liked programming exercises
because my opinion is that there are so
many so many home basically infinite
number of problems that are not solved
okay unsolved problems in programming in
humanity in mathematics so once you know
the language spend your time
to solve something that's not solved
okay not this programming toys you know
that's that's fun yeah but you know uh
for example on my website I have a huge
amount of things I need to do okay so
let me show you an example
uh
what is this project or the lead code
you know these young people's thing
so for example I what
what I want to do with wolfam language
is really to get back
into get back to mathematics okay so
these are the things I need to do many
of them are out of date I mean well not
really but it would be nice to upgrade
them you know I wrote this all these 20
years ago 20 years ago it was the most
popular
website for mathematics okay so 24 for
about 10 years from 1990 seven to
2007 so for about decade many of my my
math website is the most popular linked
by all universities over ten thousand
okay I have a I have a history of links
and so on
so remember this is this is
20 years ago
okay so you have animations it was in
QuickTime but QuickTime that format
became obsolete so I changed them to
give so this is very old but this is
done all these are done 20 years ago so
mathematics that's that's what I was
doing when I was young so
um
so I hope you do you know maybe uh it's
a good advice that you guys do something
similar you know something makes make
something this is uh you very useful
resource for students of math calculus
you know that's why it's linked by all
over by many University departments
Okay so
but but this is kind of old you see the
images are very small and the
Mathematica package is you know quite
outdated you know outdated by uh by
basically 20 years so what I really
might my passion my is is about geometry
visualization in mathematics okay so
that's what I really want to do you know
there are tens of
uh
Pages this is Rose curve of uh so
so that's what I want I need to work on
you know not not the Advent of code you
know another thing is I need to get you
know just like you guys I need to get
more focused you know different
personality
um I'm not a very focused guy so I go
over take over places
so anyway so you know yeah so let me
show you some of that so for example a
gallery of surfaces you know this is
differential geometry it'll take you a
few years to know about to understand
them differential geometry so
you know although I mostly do
programming on my YouTube
which I'm an expert and but compared to
mathematics programming is much more
easier okay mathematics it's not it's
not easy this this is also why you don't
see a lot of [ __ ] on math but you
see tons of [ __ ] on programming like
patterns or oop or object you know
oriented oh Azure or this this way let
that language or is this language better
just you know
tons of crap you know something
something injection by the Martin
something Martin Fowler
crackpot I consider him anything he says
is a crackpot you know it's [ __ ] you
know
you know the uh Martin Fowler in agile
and whatever you know in unit testing or
a new library in Python in JavaScript or
whatever
in programming is filled with with this
garbage okay
but not so
not so much in math because math is
difficult and very precise you can't
just [ __ ] you can't just push it
some methodology or new paradigm or
whatever you know there are some math
crack Parts but much less you know
um so this these are the things I'm
really passionate about that's what I
you know that I need to spend time
especially with wolf fam language uh you
know buffam language is very suitable
for doing these kind of things
um yeah so
so you know all that all that um
okay
I think we are starting to uh lose track
so let's talk about uh advanable code
then
um yeah um this so hopefully next 30
minutes
let's make some progress here so problem
number two so it's about rock paper
scissors and uh I'm using modular
arithmetics here is a solution
this is the main body of the solution
and I can make the whole thing one line
of course
that's a power of wolfam language
okay and there is a part two
so it says now that let's move this here
so you can see it says now that you've
correctly
no no
that you are correctly decrypting the
ultra top secret strategy guide
you would get a total score of 12 what
okay part two so
I'm just gonna take my time to read it
okay
part two the L finish is helping with
the tent and sneaks back over to you
elf says anyway the second column says
how the round needs to end X means you
need to lose
y means you need to end the round in a
draw
and X means you need to win good luck
okay so they change the meaning of x y z
let's see how
let's write it down okay
so maybe I'm starting to get boring so
you know you can skip around or uh
whatever
so X means you want to lose okay y means
you
they change the meaning
Z means
okay
the total score is still calculated in
the same way but now you need to figure
out what shape to choose so the round
ends as indicated
the total score still calculated the
same way okay so each line there are two
letters
okay the first letter is a or b or c
and that's the first player
the second letter is x y or Z
that's a second player okay and you are
the second player
so now it says
now it says X means lose
y means straw Z means win okay so each
line you have a score
uh so but now they changed the meaning
of x y z
the total score is still calculated in
the same way but now you need to figure
out what shape to choose so the round
ends as indicated
okay so the score we previously
calculated is the same
but now the XYZ the second column
becomes a variable
what uh wait what
the example above goes like this okay in
the first round your opponent will
choose Rock okay it's whatever let's
copy this okay let's copy this and write
it out
so first round is a y
so Y is draw
so we we if you are given the line a y
so that means
so you
so you also choose Rock So Y is a draw
so a is Rock so what you want to do is
also a
this gives you a score of one plus three
why because
Rock have a score of one
and three
is a score of draw
so one plus three equals to four so I
don't I don't I don't quite get it so
before
so before x y z y means
X is Rock
Y is Caesar
so before
you have one two
ah God this problem is complicated
and you lose you lose means zero so your
score is two before is that right
uh
let's try it
so that's how we compute
so actually
let's see
so before
if you have a line a y
then your score is eight
because
Y is a score of two
and Y beats a
rock paper
scissor so yeah so paper is two
paper is two so a is Rock so you beat
the first player Therefore your score is
you win so if you win you have a score
of six plus you choose Y which is
paper so you have a score of two so two
plus six is eight okay
that's a second you know that's a day
two problem first problem so that's why
you have eight but now they change the
meaning of Y
so they are saying that it must be a
draw
it must be a draw also that you also
choose Rock
rock is X
so therefore your score your new score
is four I don't I don't quite get it
they change the meaning so
okay so let's read down
but wait let's focus on this
so you need it to ending a draw
so you also choose Rock okay this gives
you a score of four
so what does it what does it imply
uh
so in the second round your opponent
will choose paper B
okay okay
your opponent chooses B
and you choose Rock X
with a score of 1 plus 0 equals to one
so paper and rocks so you lose so you
get zero but however because you put up
rocks or your score is one so one plus
zero is one okay
in the third round you defeat your
opponent's Caesar with a rock blah blah
blah
so the third case is CZ okay and uh
and therefore you win
and first
wait the third the Z x y z z is Caesar
the third round you will beat your
opponent Caesar that's not correct
this you know the advantage code
although it's a Well written problem but
I think they their description needs to
be improved
because sometimes it's a bit hard to
understand in the third round you will
defeat your opponents Caesars
with rock for a score of one plus six
but that's not the case because
previously
the third round
your opponent put out c c means
Caesar okay
so it says in the third round you will
defeat your opponent opponent Caesar
that's right Caesar with rock okay but
but what you actually put out is z
so x y z so Z means you are putting out
Caesar two
right
so Caesar versus Caesar that's a draw
so but here it says you will the video
opponents Caesar
oh wait so because they changed the
meaning of the second column so
so Z here means draw what
right the new meaning right the new
meaning
z Oh Z means win
Okay so
now Z means win so in order to win
you need to
put a rock which is X
so you win so okay so whatever yeah
now that you are correctly decrypt
decrypting the ultra top secret strategy
guide
you would get a total score of 12.
okay so that's four plus one plus seven
that's 12 okay
following the elf's instructions for the
second column
what would your total score be
if everything goes exactly according to
your strategy guide
and this idiotic problem
so they change the meaning of a second
column so you you need to basically
throw away
or
that has been said about the second
column where x equals to
Rock y equals to paper and Z equals to
Caesar so forget about all of that
but now it's just x y z indicates
lose draw and win okay lose draw and win
lose draw and win
and
so what is the question uh so so your
problem is actually just compute the
total score okay so just like yesterday
you write a function
and compute each line okay so you write
a function compute each line now the new
issue is that the second column they
have a different meaning
okay now I know and I understand
so the second column
indicates
lose draw
or wing
so the second column now has a score
because lose means zero
draw means three score of three wing
means six so the second column the
letter
contributes a score
to the to this this function the final
result
so you want to you know previously just
add y okay so let's start to modify this
line so let's start to write code
okay so we can actually we are making
progress now
it's um yeah so
let's say F2 compute line
okay compute line two so now x y
we can say
previously we converted y to
uh either 0 or 1 or 2 previously
you know if it's X then it's zero if
it's y
um
you know this is what we have before
x y z so before it was like that but now
there's a new value for each okay
the new value is
that
Z is for Wing is that correct
okay so go back so
X lose my draw in win okay so let's we
can add
uh
let's write them down so let's go slowly
and solidly
so we we don't end up like yesterday
spending so much time
okay
so here is
the meaning of a second column they
contribute to a score okay
back to code
okay so now
so now this Y is so
so before we have why is that we can use
yesterday's code
so now it just y plus y times three Okay
so
here y times three
and we don't need plus one anymore
okay let's win
draw
lose I mean loose draw Wing okay so now
why put y times three is what we want
okay
and and what else so
so now we know
and now you need to find out yeah now
you need to find out
what number to use to beat
your opponent
and and use that shapes skull okay
so so
okay not not difficult we are almost
done
so you need to determine what you need
to put out so what you need to put out
is very easy is y is X plus one
okay X Plus 1 and mod so let's write
down okay
X Plus 1 mod 3. that is a number
between 0 1 and 2. and this is number
you need to put out to beat your
opponent
okay and uh so zero represents Rock
one represents
paper
2 represents Caesar okay but what is
their score
for each one of them
one two three right so it's one two
three
so all you have to do is that plus one
uh yeah so all you have to do
okay that first one that's it
okay so wait let's do that
it's
that's our new function I'm pretty sure
it'll work okay
um
okay so yeah
so now we got a new function I'm pretty
sure it will work okay
this new function f compute line two
so now when you have a input
when you have an input you change them
to numbers you turn them into numbers
into a sub list
a list of list of numbers
then you call compute line two
okay that should get you the answer okay
copy all
now let's clean up the code you need to
also
just for
better maintenance okay that's it
so select all paste and evaluate
do it
15 okay let's see if it's correct
incorrect okay the new
result should be 12.
okay that's incorrect
close I think
okay so any anyone still watching say
something are you watching me you know
are you trying are you learning some
coding stuff with wolf and land
okay so now
our logic is wrong somewhere because we
got 15 but the correct answer is 12.
for this example input
okay so first of all
it says the result should be 4 1 7.
let's see
four one seven I got five three seven
so
something wrong
Greg and dog hello
so
we got it wrong let's find out what is
wrong okay
let's revisit our logic
so so let me go back up make a backup
so
you see so the problem is a lot about
understanding it
in the first round your opponent will
choose Rock okay in the first round your
opponent choose Rock
and you need to you need a round to end
in a
draw okay I think our logic is wrong so
you need it
x y z so what is X Y Z again
X is loose Y is true
Z is win you need to memorize it okay
lose draw win
so
loose draw wins so y means uh y means
straw
so we install
so what are we doing so
wait so B4 x y z is one zero one two
that's how we converted the XYZ value
to 0 1 2.
and so first of all let's compute the
let's compute the loose draw Wing so all
you have to do is multiply by
by three
that's right so six times three times
two is six
three times one is three
three times zero is zero so that
represents yours your uh
your loose draw Wing score
so that would be
that would be here y times three
right
that's correct
and but so why is this incorrect then so
then you need to find out what do you
need to put out in order to beat X
so X has the value of I mean the First
Column the first column which is ABC so
ABC also becomes 0 1 2.
which is the x value here so
so you
so in order to Beat It
if the opponent is zero you need to come
out with one if the opponent is
one you need to come up with two
if the opponent come out two you need to
use zero to Beat It
so how do you get those values so
you know we can we can try to write this
out
so
true beat opponent
to be enemy
you know enemy is easier word
guys
so you basically just do that
um
one
two
and zero okay that's what you need to do
so in order to get this value in order
to create a function that Maps zero to
one one two two to zero all you have to
do
is you
to modular arithmics so the input
plus one for example zero plus one is
one
and Mark 3 is also wait so let's see
wait
so the input if the input is zero
zero plus one is one mark three is also
one
so that means you yeah so that means you
come out with one to beat it okay
now if the input is 1
1 plus 1 is 2 2 mod 3 is also 2. so
that's correct now if the
if the enemy uses two then two plus one
is three three mod three is zero
so that's also correct so this
this the right side is what you need to
put out
but now you need to convert those to
to the school
so uh
so rock
paper scissor in that order okay zero
one two
has a score of one two three rock paper
scissor rock paper scissor
you know the order of this game is
different in in how we Chinese call it
so in English it's rock rock paper
scissors rock paper scissors in Chinese
it's gender sutopu so in Chinese it's
gender
pool so you you know I have to con I
have to because that's how I grew up
with it
but in English you call Rock Paper
Scissors okay
so rock paper scissors each one has a
score of one two three
so in order to convert
what you put out we are using zero one
two so you just add one right
yeah you add one
so if you put out one
your actual score would be
one here means rock paper paper
which has a score of two so you just add
one
yeah so I don't see where
why is the logic incorrect
English language is soulless
so
so what what do you think what one of
the logic do you think uh where did I go
wrong
did you did you do this problem
uh
so let's read the problem again this
nasty
so I really need to think I don't want
to end up like two more hours
okay
uh you know sitting too long I need to
get up and walk
I usually do that every two hours
so it says the answer should be eight
one six so where did I do wrong
why is the first one eight
the first one is eight because so the
first input is a y
and y means win no a y means straw
so the first one a y so it needs to draw
he needs to draw so
it needs to draw
so a choose a rock
your enemy chooses Rock
is represented by zero
what
aybx CZ that's the that's an example
input that's correct a y b x c z
so a is Rock
so it says
the first round your opponent will
choose Rock a okay correct and you
should choose paper
this ends in a win for you
why should I choose paper
why indicates a draw
you know this [ __ ] this [ __ ]
problem
I thought why now in the case this is
this the second one or the first one
oh part two [ __ ]
[ __ ]
okay here so the the proper solution is
four one seven okay
four one seven
which is I got it wrong I got five three
seven okay
so why is the first one full well it
says the first round your opponent will
choose Rock a okay that's right
and you you need the round to end in a
draw why
that's right because y represent a draw
so I yeah so I want it to be a draw why
so you so you also choose Rock
okay
and this gives you a score of one plus
three equals to four why because one is
rock and three is a draw so therefore
one plus three equals to four so the
first round the solution should be four
I got it wrong now why where
did I went wrong okay let's check
so opponent is Rock in my system that's
zero okay
so you need to run you need to run to
end in your draw that's right because of
Y so you also choose Rock
so that means I also choose zero
so in our solution here
mod X1 Plus
mod X1 mod 3.
so opponent is Rock So this x is zero
zero plus one is zero plus one is one
one mark three
is one
wait wait okay so I see where the logic
is wrong you need it to be your draw
okay but however this formula is always
a wing
that's that's where it's wrong this
formula is always to come out something
that wins okay but it's not you know you
need to be a draw so
so this x shouldn't be X it this this x
should be
okay yeah I found the problem
so you need to be either
lose draw or win
so first of all you need to determine
what you want to be loose draw or win
lose draw or win lose draw or Wing okay
let's memorize it Loose draw wing
so
so what so
so let's write it out okay so
loose straw or wing
so that also means
so if you win if you want to win the
solution is
X first one
mod three
okay that's a solution for winning okay
let's let's put it there
okay now if you wanted to draw
then you just need need X
you know the same as your enemy
if you want to lose x minus 1 mod 3.
okay yeah so that's x minus one plus
three
that's right modular rhythmic
arithmetics very powerful
now we got a picture
those drawing let's double check
loose
lose your opponent whatever your
opponent minus one
because I think that's correct draw is
the same as your opponent and Wing is
yeah so
so which formula to use depends on
what what is y should be wind uh
loose drawing
yeah so here so so we have to do is
modify this part then plus one because
that represents a score of whatever you
put up okay
so how can we now the problem is how can
we turn this into a closed form math
formula you know another we can do this
by a switch statement or conditional you
know if Y is zero if Y is 2 if Y is one
then we do this
that's a typical programmer solution
but in this case there's an elegant
Solution by because we are using modular
arithmetics so this should be be able to
be
consumed into one formula okay let's see
how to do it
yeah so very easy so all we have to do
is
um
yeah so this can be consumed into one
formula and my solution is gonna be B
demo okay and solution is going to be
the most efficient of all solutions I
can tell you right away
including our solution for the first
problem
now let me digress a little bit you know
because I'm doing the Advent of code for
the first time there's there are problem
specification is not 100 exact because
they had never mentioned whether the
input is a string or not you know I was
just assuming it's a stream
so but if you assume it's a string then
you have to do a lot many stream
manipulation first you need to turn the
string you know into a list of least
then turn them into numbers that's extra
step but nowhere in this in the problem
description says that the input is a
string
you see so therefore
in order to make yourself and also they
don't they don't require you to submit
your code so they do not do any sort of
con you know all they require is that
you give them the number as a solution
doesn't matter how you get it you know
you can you can ask your friend what's a
you know in a sense they don't actually
require you to post a code also they
don't they do not specify if the input
should be a string or whatever you know
in fact and they do not require you to
actually write a function as a solution
you in fact you can write you know using
bash or whatever procedural you know
lots of variables
to get the same answer
or in fact you can use emacs let me you
know for example
you don't you don't need to actually
like write a standalone program you can
just start with empty buffer
and just these numbers and just for
example replace a by zero
you know when you have a huge input you
just replace you know do find replace
replace a by zero and do interactive
using emacs you can do that
yeah I should demonstrate that some of
the you know some other time so
it doesn't require the input to be a
string it doesn't require you to write a
function it doesn't require any of that
or it requires is that you
have the answer okay your number so so
my my code here is actually Standalone
so that's actually doing a lot
um
preparation which
I don't need to because they'll make it
much simpler so I don't have to think
about string conversion and so that all
that anyway let's go back to fix this
so so what I'm saying is just that the
event of code doesn't actually require
you to submit a code or anything it just
requires the answer so so the essence of
of this is that you just need to have a
way to solve this
typically in a programmable way
but not necessarily Standalone program
okay so and and the meaning of that is
that you can use a spreadsheet if you
want you know you can just use a
spreadsheet so that's an entirely
different ways of computation
or you can you can get fancy you know
going into computer science you can
write a cellular automata to solve this
problem that would be interesting
okay but anyway back to this um
so we know what's the issue now so we
need to convert this
um so the input we we need a function
let me let me think about it we'll we'll
get to it okay
loose straw Wing loose straw Wing let me
just memorize zero one two
0 1 2
so
so let's combine some needs um
it's
let's try this
okay let's combine this into our system
and we don't need that
neither okay
make that make them into one single
thing
okay so now it's much easier to
understand
so
loose draw a wing
loose draw wing
so so
okay so you see the difference between
this Formula Three formulas one is
negative one one is zero and one is
first one so that corresponds with 0 1 2
very well so you have to do is
and Away here so y will be
minus one that's right
so all you have to do is add minus one
in this formula let me show you okay
first y
minus 1 and minus 1 plus 1 cancel out so
you don't need that anymore so that so
now here is our new formula okay copy it
do it
that's still incorrect
[ __ ] you need to think about this come
on
five to eight
five two eight it should be four one
seven okay that's still incorrect but
very close now
okay
oh you have a plus three
so actually so it's so
plus three okay maybe I forgot that
okay
foreign
so
x y z lose draw Wing loose drawing
thank you
loose drawing minus one zero plus one
so
so y minus 1 so actually
my minus 1.
I think that's right okay
four one seven come on please
four one seven twelve correct okay here
is the most efficient
solution to this problem
you know we can we can we can simplify
the formula here because you see
negative 1 plus 3 we can just make it
plus two but let's
that's the most I declare I can tell you
again I declare this is the most
efficient solution okay for the problem
number two
okay we don't need that one anymore
okay and it's just remove clean out code
okay
now I'm pretty sure are you certain yes
I'm certain now let's get our input
okay we got the input yesterday so
where's the input
so let's let's do it here
select or paste
okay for 1 7 12
check example input check now let's get
our input from yesterday
so yesterday there is a big input
here
okay so let's go to it talk
yesterday
okay here Arduino code so that's the
input okay huge okay
copy it
new paste
evaluate okay we got the input
close
copy it
uh
okay
make a new
Fame language
um
and remove the input remove that
okay so compute it
paste
compute
the biggest
okay here is our solution one three one
three one
now pray to God I don't get this wrong
am I sure
yes I'm sure
submit
that's the right answer you are one gold
star closer to collecting a nerve star
fruit
[ __ ] you
Hefty buffer thank you for help
yesterday but today it's smooth
you know some you know a bit smoother
much more smoother than yesterday so so
far we talked for 90 minutes I think
that's it okay
so can we go into the problem number
three
can we go into problem number three yes
I think so
okay let me clean up and let's see what
we're gonna do maybe we'll go into
problem number three or maybe we'll just
be it today okay
uh okay let's clean up the sound talk
show
so that's today
Advent of code day two
you know second problem ergonomic
keyboards here is the day two solution
basically that single line
um
and here is some
explanation of the problem
quite tedious okay so let's delete that
we don't need that
okay so that's it for that let's see
what else let me click let me do clean
up and okay
so
are we going to do the next one or are
we going to
say goodbye for today
it's okay let's close this cling up
don't save okay
um
okay let's read the comments and let's
see where we go
can we submit new solution oh yeah so
Ethan yeah so JR says do you plan on
doing a chat GPT programming stream
how strictly you will find you know I
can do chat GPT chat GPT is very
interesting and uh
okay let me talk random then okay
because talking random is always fun and
I can advertise my website stuff because
usually there are so many topics
including politics you know a lot of
people would be interested in my opinion
and uh
but half of you you know you don't watch
you know many young people that's a
situation with YouTube you know many
newcomers you know they don't
they don't spend much time but anyway no
no that's not my point I mean okay
so
so I want to talk about
um
chat GPT okay so I recommend you watch
one my video here okay
saw talk show 2022 12th fifth
DG a doctor go search
qqiai drawing open AI poem
and some politics of 184 Laura and
certain
and emacs 29 core formatting so you go
watch that one so
so my opinion I made a claim that
that the year
2023 is the real beginning of artificial
intelligence I mean the other you know
there's a milestone so today you know
I've been I have been observing AI for
the past you know 30 years since I
started programming that's why I'm
interested in lisp and in wufan language
because this is the granddaddy of
artificial intelligence research you
know that's why that's how this
you know a big industry artificial
intelligence at least in the 1980s
mostly you know uh sponsored by U.S
Department of Defense you know military
serious stuff
and internet is also part of from you
know from it that's how internet got
developed you know military
basically indestructible communication
system that was internet originally
what it is about indestructible
communication system like you can bomb
you know like telephone Network or
whatever you can bomb This Not That Oba
done and and you know you don't have
phones anymore it doesn't work anymore
not so with internet so internet you can
destroy this knot that it still works
you know because of this
the packet swam it's quite quite a
technology you know internet package
from you know they just they blindly
follow local rules and essentially keep
the communication still going you can
you can many not knots destroyed and it
still works
that's original concept of Internet okay
indestructible communication basically
but today because of a giant cooperation
is all controlled so it might be
different today
you know in some in some sense okay so
that's about internet so
so I was I'm making a claim so that's
you know artificial intelligence is how
I got I'm very interested in that topic
you know I've talked about AI in my past
videos too you can
you know Eric you know again let me say
you go to kasali.com and there's a
search this will search or
seven thousand titles on my website so
you can type AI for example you'll find
um
all the titles containing this the word
AI but
you know closure function chaining
Mantra board set explained uh state
affairs of DB DVD rippers that's 20
years ago you know what's what is
algebraic data type that's a lousy your
local
brain fog language
in the file design problem that's brain
[ __ ] is a
it's a idiotic language you know one of
those language that that
it was created to mean to be a very
difficult incomprehensible thing however
I learned something very fundamental
from brain [ __ ] because one time I was
doing homework once for for someone else
you know you pay me I do homework for
you
hundred dollars okay hundred dollars for
like two hours you pay me I do homework
for you so one day I got you know I was
dying of hunger pretty sad story you
know you you won't understand
so but you know I was I was doing brain
fog and I learned something critical
because I was never I'm I'm you know
because my interest is is high level
programming you know mathematics
Foundation of mathematics logic
what I'm not interested is code diddling
like the C C plus plus Unix idiots you
know they they are type this hacker they
are interested in code detailing machine
code you know compiler memory memory you
need to manipulate memory Malak or
whatever [ __ ] okay I'm not interested in
those things I'm interested in high
level programming and proof systems type
Theory Haskell for example you know how
how do you you know high level
mathematics combinators Lambda calculus
theoretical computer science that's what
I'm interested in so
when it comes to brain fog it's new to
me it's new because you have to
manipulate this thing you know but but
brain [ __ ]
is very fruitful to me because I started
to realize how
how
um how brain [ __ ] um
you know I realized many important
principles one is that there's you know
many programming languages they for
example python they try to design it so
that for any problem there's only one
way to do it
okay that's the most idiotic thought
because it's not possible it is not
possible theoretically to have just one
way to do it you always have like
different ways and you don't know which
one is more efficient because there are
different
um issues okay anyway so if you dive
into brain fog
you know a lot hackers are interested
this is a thing you guys are interested
a lot of you see you know the industrial
programmers who don't know nothing about
math or types Theory but you would be
interested in brain [ __ ] you know then
you can tell your team friends see brain
[ __ ] you know brain work you know anyway
you you you try to code it solve
problems you realize
lots of the lower level
algorithmic issues so anyway brain fog
turns out it was fruitful
for me
uh
so anyway so yeah so I was saying you go
to Saudi search so for example type
artificial intelligence okay
but some of the article I didn't fully
spell it out so that's why you don't get
um
you know so I have an article these this
this article I also considered great
okay this is about the nature of
artificial neural network okay which is
today's all the GPT chat bot is they are
using that that's their methodology they
are basically using massive statistics
with one billion parameters you know to
and they need to be trained in order for
this today's you know AI to work they
first of all need massive amount of data
billion billion
Peta whatever you know
without that it doesn't work it can't do
nothing you can't do a thing but once
you have this huge amount of data or in
the case of Chess or go it can play with
by itself
because it can generally generate data
on the fly so you just let it play by
itself then then in few days you'll beat
the best chess player you know that
happened just that be the best chest
computer program written by human just
by you know you create this neural
network thing let it run by itself after
a few days you beat any any other
computer program human has written that
happened you know that's all relying on
you know neural network machine learning
okay so you have ai which is a huge
topic and then you have many different
methodologies approaches
for the artificial intelligence then one
of them is machine learning
and Below machine learning one of the
methodologies neural network okay but
the but there are many problems with
neural network you know neural network
is the most nasty because it um
because you you know you can it knows
things you know these AI parts for
example the chat GPT or others they know
things but they they don't they cannot
it's impossible for them to tell you
anything about it how do you know what
you know they cannot tell they cannot
tell you any Theory they can you know
they just know they learn things but
but by a way that's
impenetratable you cannot see how it
works you can see how it works it just
knows stuff
because of these
kind of statistically based machine
learning pattern recognition you know
prediction you know
so neural network is pretty nasty
I mean not in in a sense not not
necessarily nasty because it does it
actually work that's the point you know
it just it worked you know you can
you know you go uh chess you know it can
beat any human or any other programming
human written computers it just that's a
goal you know
so anyway so I was trying to show
I was telling about Saudi search and
my interest in artificial intelligence
which got me interested in wufan
language because I want math is my
interest you know wolfen language is the
best and
and then also this of course today
artificial intelligence research is not
done with this I blame the Communist
facets okay that's how I that's why I
blame I blame the common disp [ __ ]
since 19 after 1990s you have this all
the common these phonetics or skin
Fanatics you know they are the
industrial programmers they are nothing
like the original communities people who
actually think about things they are
just the Babbling common lisp is the
best thing skin is the best thing emacs
is the best thing these [ __ ] idiots
they
so anyway today this basically died okay
if you want to do AI research that's C
plus for us
I blame I blame these common these
people because they
they they they became a cult once you
became a coach you don't have Innovation
anymore because you have the proper
thought you know if you don't agree emac
this is the best you are they kick you
out you know the code situation Emax
okay
emacs and this so this is no progress is
kind of dead uh
maybe except closure closure but closure
is on Java in the Java world that's
anyway
Ai and stuff that's it that's it for
today
so if you like guys like my stuff okay
donate to me okay just go to my website
go to sorry.info in PayPal me
okay do that
if you want to my know my about emacs
theme just search it you know I have
like all the information on the website
most people don't read
so code man condemn 77 says sorry for
the whole topic I want to ask here
regarding your emacs tutorial oh yeah
sorry so I've been delayed there are
about three people
you know
so I will send it out today sorry about
that so because I'm trying to generate a
new version
I can generate it right now but I mean
but I need to do some cleanup so you get
the best version as of today so sorry
about that code condemn 77 okay that's
it for today bye guys