Welcome to another episode of Sacha Talk
Show. Today is 2021,
June 24th, and today the main topic is
going to be Emacs with live coding.
Okay, video check, audio check, and you
are looking at my keyboard, Kinesis
Advantage 2
linear red switches, fantastic silent
red switches. You know, if you have
repetitive strain injury, you want to
get red linear light linear switches.
Okay, I highly recommend this. This is
my main, and this is the ultimate
hacking keyboard, okay?
Uh, okay, so video check, audio check.
Check. So, the main topic is going to be
Emacs live coding. Good morning, Toby,
and
Absen, and BDX.
BDX 5, okay. So, the fantastic image
artwork, this is a moth.
Now, this moth, okay? I'm not going to
tell you where it came from, this photo,
but because YouTube censorship. Uh, but
anyway, this
incredible intricate, this is the beauty
of nature, okay? And lots of it has to
do with mathematics, the dynamic
algorithms, or how shall we put it, the
cellular automata, the generation of the
patterns. You see how the nature, the
incredible beauty of the nature.
Okay, so that's a digression. So, but
mostly we're going to talk about Emacs.
So, the first 10 minutes, uh, 20 minutes
going to be Emacs Lisp live coding.
Good? Good? Guys, three people watching.
So, working uh,
working here, computer-aided world.
Okay, so let's see talk show, okay? So,
go to topic notes on the pink window,
you can see all my command codes and
keystrokes showing browser. So, what I
want to do, uh, let's see.
So, there are two things I want to do.
Okay, so let's see which one I want to
write a command to change. Okay, make it
so that when viewing browser. So, let's
do the first one. Okay, this might take
30 minutes actually. 30 minutes. So, if
you have questions, comments, post it.
Okay.
Questions and comments, post it. Love to
see your comments. Okay. And okay, so
first thing first is Emacs Lisp coding.
So, let's go to
let's go to see let's see my Emacs blog.
Let's see.
Um
Uh yeah, okay, let's focus on coding.
Let's just um
Yeah, my alarm clock. I need to shut it.
Okay, back. Emacs Lisp coding. So, I
want to command the uh I want to write
the command. Let me show you what I'm
going to do. So, you see let's go to
talk show. Talk show. Go open that. Show
today's This is a today's talk show
page. So, you see what I write HTML. I
work in raw HTML a lot manually
uh
like this.
For example, uh
I write blogs. And uh you know, one of
the most frequently used tag in HTML is
paragraph. You see the P and P. So, if I
show your browser, you can see you know,
like that as a paragraph. Now, if I
delete the paragraph showing browser,
then
Well, actually paragraph tag is um
optional actually in HTML 5. Oh, that's
yeah, I remember.
The paragraph tag if you don't have if
you have just a text like that, it
actually is a paragraph. It's uh let's
try some let's test. Okay, let's
uh let's
test this hypothe-
sis, I think. Uh
if you
don't have any tags, it's taken It's
interpreted
as paragraph as P tag
in HTML 5, okay? It's important what
version of HTML. So, let's show in
browser.
Oh, it doesn't. Okay.
Yeah, so you So, the tag the P tag is
still necessary because otherwise this
three things, you know, this three
things uh you know, it's it's uh joined
as one paragraph
uh by default interpretation. Okay, so
So, what I'm saying is that normally so
paragraph tag is the the thing you use
the most often in HTML page. So, but
even if you have fast keys for that, for
example, just two keys for each
paragraph, but still it's uh cumbersome
to always type that. Another way to do
that is I select it, then do it, then
show in browser, you see?
So,
what I'm thinking is that So, let's
remove those tags. So, what I'm thinking
is that
write a command so that whenever you
show this page, the current buffer, in a
browser, it will automatically find all
text blocks
that doesn't have any tag with it, will
automatically add tag like that.
Show in browser, you see? So, I'm going
to write a command. So,
let's uh
Let's begin to write a command, okay?
Then this document. So, we have uh let's
okay. So, Emacs Lisp code, okay, start a
Emacs Lisp code define.
So, this command is going to be
version
today's date.
Uh
So, this this command is going to add
add P tags
around any text block that does not have
any tags, okay? So, that's what this
command do. Let's name it. So, let's
name it site
HTML.
Uh
Let's Let's just name it something
simple, okay? Naming is uh Naming
requires some thinking to do correctly.
Uh let's just say wrap wrapped P tags
for now, okay? I'm going to change after
today, then maybe tomorrow this will be
part of the site HTML mod. I've been
talking a lot about that past videos.
So, uh the name might change. You'll
You'll see in my Anyway, so let's begin
with this uh name site HTML wrap P tags.
So, this will add P tags around any text
block that doesn't have any tags, okay?
So, uh
So, let's remove them. So,
Okay, so let's Okay, so let's begin to
code this command.
in current buffer
Okay, so let's begin to write this
command, okay?
Hello S Pen, okay. Uh so, okay, so we
want to add So, how do you begin? So, uh
let's I have to think. So, how do you
begin to code this? So, this is This is
going to fold the whole buffer.
Uh add a P tag to any tag, um, so
Uh, so how do you do this? Uh, I have to
think. Okay, let's let's look at the
HTML so we get idea.
So you want to search for
uh, let Okay, let's show the
show white spaces.
Make white space
spaces visible.
So you want to show
basically search for any consecutive,
you know, two empty line characters, two
new line characters.
And uh, if it's adjacent, if it doesn't
have any tag, then you want to add a P
tag like that. Okay, um, let me Okay, I
have to think about to do.
Um,
So there are two parts to this problem.
Okay, the first part is, uh, adding the
first
tag.
Okay, so let let's make it into a tag.
Let's see. The first part is to add the
beginning tag. The The other part of the
problem is add the second
um,
tag. Uh, the other part is to add the
second, um,
the closing tag. So the first job the
first job to write this command is to
to find an algorithm
that is the question of how do you
how do you determine how do you find the
places where you need to add
the tag. Okay, so that's what I we are
looking at. So you want to
So let me
you know, because I'm doing live stream,
so uh, live stream the the methodology,
the workflow is a bit different. So live
stream it's better for me to keep
talking. Whatever comes to my mind, just
talk talk it out Uh so you
so because otherwise normal if I'm doing
this offline, I would have to you know
think for 2 minutes and then have a good
solution.
Uh
But but you know, you don't want to uh
have people stare at empty screen for 2
minutes. So anyway, so the the first
problem is solving is to how do you
determine um
How do you determine the
um
Uh the uh
the the places you want to add a tag,
okay? So
So one way okay, one way is to find to
search or to search for any
uh you know, sequence of two new line
characters.
Then
Uh okay.
Okay, one way is just um okay, that
doesn't work.
You see because for example, if you are
if you are uh cursor is over here, you
can see here they already have a tag.
Here is already a tag, but you still
have two consecutive um
uh
empty lines. So what do you want to do
instead? You want to find it. So let's
let's just start to write, okay? Search
uh
research forward, okay? So that's uh
this is first of all, go to char
buffer
uh mean uh point movement, okay?
So go to the beginning of the buffer,
then search for
So two empty lines represented by that.
Uh this is a regular expression search
forward. So go to the beginning then
start to search that, but
however
you want to search that so that
so that the next character after
that Okay, so let me do this. Okay, so
the next
the next character So
So wait. So let's do
one or more empty lines. Okay, one or
more new line character.
So after that, the next character should
be anything like A capital A to Z or
lowercase A to Z.
Okay, so I think
uh that's one way to find, you know, to
find a position like that.
Okay, once you find that
So
um
Okay, you need to do a
when, okay?
So when
this happens
optional bound nil no error
true. I don't We don't want any
uh if you cannot find it, it's not an
error, okay?
Okay, so when this happens, then
replace match
Okay, uh
replace match by
by
two empty lines.
Uh actually one or more Okay, so now you
need actually you need to capture. Okay,
because you need to know how many empty
lines you did you found here. So okay,
let's capture. Okay, so to do capture in
Emacs this oops, yeah.
So to do capture in Emacs this, let me
show you.
So that is how you capture. So this So
this first part you need two
um backslashes.
Then two backslashes uh parentheses.
This is first part captures the a
sequence of one or more
what the sequence of at least two
uh empty line characters new line
characters. Then
same thing you have to do here, okay?
Uh
so you have to capture that part.
So once you find that, you
do replace, okay? Now replace the first
replace match. The first part is the
whatever number, you know, the first
captured pattern.
Then the second captured pattern. In
between them is the paragraph tag, okay?
Actually, I want a new line in between.
So okay, so that's that's kind of uh
that.
Then optional fix case true literal
true. Uh we don't need that that, okay?
So
this is a command, okay? So let's
evaluate it.
Okay, let's go back here. Let's
uh delete that, okay? Let's Let's try to
call it, okay? Wait.
So the command is xah HTML wrap, okay?
So let's go back to HTML.
Let's call it. Meta X xah HTML wrap P
tags. Let's see what happens.
It should
add beginning paragraph here and here
and here, okay? Let's call it.
Do it.
Okay, some
Okay, mistake. You see it added this A
and B.
Those are
you know, correct A. Those are
Those are ASCII characters. You can do
describe-char
and to find what they are. So, they are
control A.
Code point one, control A. Okay, ASCII.
So,
So, if you don't know what that is,
search for ASCII.
ASCII table.
So, here is a page.
So, control A is a start of head header.
Okay, so anyway, we
our code made some mistake. Let's go
back to the code.
Oh, yeah. So, if So, why is it um
Oh,
Yeah, okay. So, you you need a double
backslash. This is a major pain of
regular expressions in Emacs Lisp.
Okay, evaluate the buffer, then go here,
then try it again.
Do it.
Okay, then you got that. Okay, this is
wrong. Undo. Go back here. Wait, what
what's going on? Replace match.
Uh what?
Okay, describe function on replace match
and see what's going on.
Okay, you can see
this backslash n means substitute what
matched in nth capture, right? So, nth
parent didn't match, substitute nothing,
right? So,
what did we do wrong here?
So, it's actually just one.
Uh replace match
replace match fixed case true literal
false. Okay, that's why we did it wrong.
So, we want to fix case, yes, but not
literal expression.
Uh that's why we got, you know,
you know, backslash one when that's, you
know, we want the regular interp-
regular expression interpretation where
backslash one means the captured
pattern, okay? Eval the buffer, go back
to the
HTML, call it again.
Do it.
Ah.
Wait, why is it this
It it inserts
um
you know, you see, it inserted
that.
Okay, so
uh
So, let's
So, let's see what's uh
Wait, what? What?
Uh fixed case new text literal string
sub expression, so match case new text
replace match
replace text match by last search within
with new text. Okay.
Three points at end of replacement text.
Okay.
So, what am I doing wrong here when
research forward option bound no error.
Okay, bound and no error.
That's right. Bound nil, no error true.
And then we replace match, but something
is wrong.
Now, I'm pretty sure this is a capture.
Wait, how can I not get this right?
Okay, so time to look up at my Emacs
tutorial.
So, go to Xahlee Emacs practical Emacs
Lisp and there is a page about regular
expressions in in Emacs Lisp. Let me
just check that.
Okay, so near the bottom regular
expression in Emacs Lisp, there is
something you might to have to pay
attention to.
Uh
Let's uh let me let me magnify the
screen here once for all.
Okay, so let's check
what
uh some precautions when using regular
expression in Emacs Lisp. Maybe I
screwed up there.
So, here's the example. So,
regular expression search for word.
Yeah, so that looks right.
Uh and uh
I I I don't know what's going on. So,
let's why don't we go to the source code
of Xah Fly Keys. There's lots of code.
Then let's just search for
uh
rejects. I mean, let's search for
replace match. We will probably
find a example here.
So, let's see.
Okay, so
concat, so double slash. Yes, double
slash.
Okay.
Now, that Yeah, so you see here is
example. So, let's jump to the code. You
see, here is example.
Indeed, so here we have again a similar
code.
And this code is reformat sentence two
lines, okay? And here we have example of
regular expression search forward, and
we have a capture here.
Here. And then replace, you see, you
need a double backslash, okay? So, that
is it. The
usefulness of code examples. So, close
that, close that.
So, let's go back to the list code.
Yeah, so double slash, double backslash,
double backslash, okay? Pretty file the
code, okay? Evaluate the code.
Evaluate the buffer, go here, call the
command again.
Do it. Fantastic. You see that?
You see, undo,
redo, undo, redo.
You see? So, it it did that. So, now
let's continue working on go with this
flow. So, this only replace one
instance. So, instead we want a while
loop, okay? So, while loop,
while
search forward, you know, that for that
expression, then
then then you want uh do that, okay?
Clean the code, so
evaluate the buffer back here, and do so
let's start over. Let's let's copy this,
okay? Copy these three, new buffer,
paste it here.
Then call the command.
Do it. Fantastic. You see, it did it
here and here. Not the first one
because, you know, the first one doesn't
have uh
line returns, okay? Let's undo. So,
let's add some line returns. So, do it.
Call it. Fantastic. So, let's
That kind of the fixed the first part.
So, let's continue to code.
So, the other part is similar, okay? So,
what basically we just do this. So, go
to the buffer beginning again, then
search forward, and this time
you want to search for
two new line characters, but before that
it should be a
um
Okay, so we do like that. Search for
that.
Anything like that or a period or a
uh question mark or exclamation, okay?
Search search for that or any alphabet.
Or a number, actually, zero to nine,
actually. So, we need to add a zero to
nine here as well.
Improving our code.
Okay, so that and that
Okay, so actually so yeah, so that's one
thing. So,
then replace part
uh we need to add
like that. So, we
we replace it with whatever is found.
Then we add a new line character, then
the closing tag, then whatever
the number of new lines in the end,
okay? Evaluate the code.
Go back here, call the command,
do it.
Okay, something went went wrong.
Uh undo.
Let's test the simple case. New buffer.
Okay. New buffer, paste it here.
Let's uh let's make it like that. So,
let's call the code, see what happens.
Call it.
Do it.
Okay, the second part is not
done, okay? The second part is
incorrect.
So, search for Oh, yeah. So, these three
character must be inside the character
class, you know.
So, this is a regular expression syntax.
So, do it. Undo. Let's call it again.
Do it.
Fantastic.
Looks like that's uh we've completed our
mission, basically. The prototype. You
know, this is the code. This is This is
the fruit of today. Any questions,
comments?
Okay, so that So, okay, undo this, close
that. So, let's call it here. Let's see
what happens.
Do it. Fantastic. You think Fantastic.
Show in browser. Fantastic.
So, okay. So,
So, okay. So, so now, you know, this is
done. We don't actually need those these
parts anymore. So, we don't I mean, we
We need let because we didn't use any
variables.
So actually this is a code. Let's just
pretty fire. Okay, let's just um
Okay, for now let's cut that
and and go back here.
Paste it here.
Showing browser back in Emacs pretty
fight the code color it should go to the
browser.
Refresh.
Fantastic. Go back to Emacs delete this
paragraph showing browser in Emacs
uh in Emacs in in showing browser
fantastic.
So this is the command we set out to do
today and basically that's uh successful
but uh we can
there's a lot additions to do.
Depending on the new language good
morning.
So now
So what what's the next thing to do? We
can continue
with this Emacs this coding. Okay guys,
I need your reaction. You know, start to
talk.
Uh type your comments in chat, okay. So
how many people how many sponsors do I
have? Seven seven concurrent viewers,
okay.
So
So now we can continue to enhance
this
command add features or
we can start to talk random for about
for about maybe 20 minutes.
Let's see how long I've been talking.
I've been talking for 40 minutes
already, yeah.
Uh oops. So
you know, I kind of want to talk random
because I you know, I something about
Emacs maybe. So give your opinions guys.
If you are here
say something, okay. Questions about
Emacs list or
do you want me to continue adding
enhancement to the code here?
Uh or uh what else you want to uh do
next? Okay, okay, yeah. Let me let me
finish this, okay? There's something I
want to add, okay? So
So now we have this at least the draft
prototype of this function, which we
will add, you know, text to empty uh
text blocks.
Now we
What I want to do is add a hook so that,
for example, let me delete those, okay?
So ddddddd. You see?
You see it's showing browser. You see
we need a paragraph for each one of
these. So what I want is that whenever I
show a buffer HTML buffer in browser,
it will automatically call this command
uh wrap
HTML wrap P tags automatically call it.
So I don't have, you know, so this will
save you significant time, you know,
when you write a blog, when you write,
for example, let's go to my Emacs blog.
Let me show you, okay? So So go to my
Emacs blog, start a new section, you can
see new section. Then I just say
today I wrote a fantastic command.
And
the reason is it is fantastic, okay? So
now
normally, you know, I go back here, I
need I need to, you know, add a
paragraph. But now I just want to show
in browser, it should automatically do
that, add a paragraph. So
let's do that, okay? So close this.
Let's let's let's make this uh
uh function.
Let's Let me Let me tell you how to you
do that, okay?
So Elisp is based fantastic. So let me
continue virtual virtual blue sky, okay?
So let me continue, let me show you how
do you
how do you add this hook? So first of
all, the command to show in browser is
this, okay? Describe key.
Press the key. You see the command
name is actually
excite-html-browse-url-of-buffer,
okay? So, now we go to uh the source
code, which is in the excite-html mode,
okay?
Enter.
Here's the source code. Uh okay. So,
So, so what I I can do is that So,
where's today's code? So, today's code
Let's go to today's code, okay? So,
today's code is this one.
So, I can just simply Let me Let me show
uh You see?
I can simply add
Make a backup of this file. So, I can
simply add a call to this function.
Okay, let Let me show you, okay? Let's
just run it, okay? Evaluate the function
back to the HTML.
You see, this is talk show. So, you can
see here
You see, those are missing paragraph
tags. But, now if I show in browser,
it'll be added. Let's see.
Do it. You see?
Did you see that? Fantastic. Wait, what?
Oh, okay. Okay. So, you see,
it's added in the buffer, but however,
it's not showing up in browser. That's
because we switched to the browser
first, then we added those paragraph.
So, we let's fix that. Let's undo.
Uh
and go back to the code.
So, here is the code.
So, we
want to delete that and uh move it here,
okay? So,
uh we want to move it somewhere. So,
let's magnify the code.
So, let's see. So, here's the URL when
browser is modified.
Uh and uh it does some extra things. So,
the browser So, buffer modified P
is a variable building variable. Its
value is either true or false. True
means the buffer has not been saved.
You know, but that's how Emacs works.
So,
so when buffer has not been saved, then
you want to find whether um
basically you want to save it save
buffer, okay? But before you do that, I
want to clean up white space, you know,
that's just my
uh clean white space.
So, if that command is bound, just do
it.
Then, uh
let's just add here, okay? Let's Let's
Let's Let's add here and also
uh
actually
Let's just add here, okay?
Okay?
Evaluate,
you know, the code,
then go back to the HTML. You see? Now,
we're going to
uh show in browser. Let's see if it
changed. Do it.
Fantastic! You can see
uh it's done there, okay?
Fantastic.
Now,
Now, there's uh one more thing to do.
You see,
not everyone wants to do this
because
yeah, you know, I suppose we I you know,
this can we we can just have this and be
done with it. But,
I guess there are some situations or for
other people when they use my
ex-html-mode, they don't they don't
necessarily want to,
you know, automatically add paragraph
because maybe they haven't
you know, maybe they want this to be a
list instead. You know, they haven't
finished yet, but they just want to look
at browser first. So, you want to add
kind of a option
where people can choose whether they
want to do that. So, the way to do that
is
a a hook, okay? Emacs hook. So, let me
let me do it and you'll see, okay? Let
me just
uh
let me just uh start to code it so you
can see.
So, here is a hook.
Okay, so
so don't worry. Let me I'm going to
explain, okay?
So,
this
we're going to have a define var, which
is a declaration of a variable, and this
will be a
this var will be
exhtml-wrap-p-tags-hook.
So, so this is uh then the documentation
is
uh
the initial value is nil. The
documentation is
hook for
uh actually the hook for this function.
Hook for exhtml-browse-url-a-buffer,
okay? So, copy that. So, let's change
the name.
Okay?
So, we are declaring a variable.
Defvar, okay? Defvar, declaring this
variable. This is a hook. And the the
documentation is a hook for this uh
function. So, that means
you can add hook, okay? So, let me show
you how how it's done, okay? Add hook.
Okay, add hook um
add hook to this hook. And when
So, basically when that when this
function is called, you want to call
this function, okay? So, you can see
this is how you want to do it.
But, you know, that means as a user, if
you want this command, if you want this
command
to do something before, you know, when
it's called,
that's what you have to do, add hook.
But, however,
before you have before for this to work,
you have to first of all declare the
hook, then you you you have to also say
in the command over here, you have to
say call hook, okay? So, how do you do
that? I forgot. It's but then let me
look um
Let me look at how it's done. Call hook,
okay?
Uh
list function hook
Uh add hook. So, we have add hook. We
don't have uh call hook.
Okay, so
wait.
Uh
You know, so hook is automatically
called by the uh major mod.
Yeah, okay. So, I I know it's probably
confusing for you guys because I'm kind
of getting all over the place without a
good explanation.
But, let me do the ex- let me do explain
it, okay? Uh So, first of all, get go to
the Emacs Lisp
Practical Emacs Lisp, then click on
Emacs Lisp writing major mod.
Okay, I think
I might have explanation here
because I don't I don't remember exactly
how it's done myself. So, I So, let me
just
Let me just uh stumble around, okay?
Let me
stumble around and uh
Okay, so
So, where do I explain the hook?
Okay, so define font-lock-mode, define
face, color comment color comment,
comment command, your own comment
command, keyboard completion command.
This is all about how to write a major
mod. Create key map
uh abbreviation template text properties
overlay lookup doc. Okay, it's not
there.
Major mod naming provide required
Okay, I don't have hook here, but so
let's look at let's look at Emacs in
init section.
I might have it explained here. So,
what's hook? So, click on what what's
hook. This page explains
uh what is a hook in Emacs. But
does it explain how do you actually
create the hook mechanism for a
function? No, it does not.
So, this page is user-oriented. You
know, if you are Emacs user you might
encounter what is a hook. You know, this
page explains and it tells you how how
can you add a hook
uh
you know, with some building functions.
This is how you do.
But
this page is not a explanation to Emac
Lisp programmers.
It doesn't explain how do you actually
create a hook you know, for certain
event or function call
so that user can, you know
you know, add hook to it.
So, it didn't explain. So, okay.
So, I didn't explain. So, maybe I note
to myself, write a tutorial about that.
So, but
so, right now
I'm kind of in a mess because hold on a
second, I can explain it. Okay, hold on
a second.
So, this add hook, this is what user
have to do. Okay, so
but first of all, you define a variable
so people can look up
you know, the hook and see what it does.
This is a good thing.
But, the actual coding hook will be
somewhere here, okay?
It will be inside this function, okay?
But, um
Okay?
Now, the the question Okay, so the the
question for me is how do you find that
function?
I think it's call hook, okay? So, let's
see call
hook. No, it's not call hook. But, I can
find the proper name by looking at the
documentation of this function. Define
derived mod, okay? I think. So, this
right function define derived mod
magnify, so we can see.
Um then search for hook.
Okay, so
hook.
Okay, you can see near the bottom
um
Let's call highlight phrase hook. So, it
can highlight all hook names. So, let me
shrink, so you can actually see the
part.
So, here is the
you know, here's the documentation
for the function define derived mod. And
in here, it talks about hook.
Okay?
Now, this is kind of advanced Emacs.
This This is about how to write a major
mod.
But, what I'm trying to
tell you now is how do you actually
create a hook for any of our arbitrary
function.
Okay, so let me just look around. Then
then I'll explain it, okay? The the new
mod runs the hook and constructed by uh
uh drive function hook name, okay?
Run hook, okay? So
uh describe function run hook. There it
is, run hooks, okay?
So run hooks So let's look at the
documentation for the function run
hooks, okay?
Run each hook in hooks. Fantastic, okay?
Yeah, okay. This is the function we
want, okay? So let me explain.
Okay, so let me explain uh the whole
thing in a clear manner, okay?
Uh
okay, here. So
uh
So the code we are interested So let me
let me let me
Here. So
So let me just paste this, okay? So here
is the code
the these three code are uh
is the our interest. I'll make So
So there is a function CSHTML browser
URL buffer.
We What we want to do now is we want to
create a hook so that whenever this
function runs, it will actually call
whatever hook user added. So how do you
do that? We want to create a hook. All
you have to do is to create define a
variable here and create a name
CSHTML browser URL buffer hook. Then
inside the function body, call this call
this run hooks, okay? So you see, it's
very simple. Now, I hope that that makes
sense, guys.
Answer.
80 people watching, does that make
sense? You know, did I make a good
effort in explaining this after, you
know, 10 minutes I do?
So Okay, run hooks. So, this is what you
want, run hooks. Now, now do we need uh
should this be a symbol? The argument
should it be a symbol or just a
variable? I don't know.
Uh you see that's um
Yeah, Emacs list they don't have
they don't have examples.
Let's see some examples.
Uh I don't know. I Okay, so let's go to
In fact, let's go to
Xah Lee Ki again and search for run hook
because I have example. There it is,
okay? So, you can see it actually
requires a symbol the argument. You
know, this this part is kind of
confusing when you code Emacs list
because some arguments sometimes they
require to be a symbol
uh and sometimes it's just a variable.
So, in this case it's a symbol. It's a
symbol of the variable. You see this
hook thing, they are actually variables,
but you need to pass argument as a
symbol to run hooks, okay? So, okay, so
that's so we found the answer. So, you
So, so over here we back here. So, so
this is what you need. So, this part you
need to move it to uh
Move it move it here, okay?
Move it here.
Okay, clean up.
Okay, so this function now, that's good.
Now,
so we we define a variable a hook and
and you see this variable and we also
run it here. And for the user, so this
part this part is shouldn't be here.
This part is this part should be user.
You know, so delete that. Now
Now um
widen the buffer so we have we see the
whole code.
Okay?
So now we evaluate this part and
evaluate this part, okay?
So we evaluate buffer, okay?
What's my key, I believe. Uh wait.
Evaluate region.
That's eval-defun.
Okay. Wait, what's my key?
Eval region.
Delete w u, okay? That's in Vorai
keyboard and delete key is here, right
on my thumb. That's the Vorai keyboard.
W is here, U is here, okay? So
back to the code.
Eval region.
Okay? So you can see in the ping window,
you can see it's gold.
Now we evaluated that, we back to go
back to the talk show page.
And then we need to evaluate this add
hook, you know, whenever this hook
you know, uh
when whenever that event happens, call
this function, okay? Evaluated, okay?
Now
Now we we call the
uh we show in browser, it should add
paragraphs paragraphs. Let's do it.
Fantastic, okay?
So I
So that's it for today. Thank you guys
for watching. That's it.
Oh good. I think I guess I'm still
alive. Thank you. Thank you, virtual.
Good explanation. I actually have been
trying to use hooks for
um
org extension which have been tricky.
Okay, Hi Xah G says, Hi what color theme
in Emacs of Emacs do you use?" Okay, let
me
answer that.
And that that should be it today. Okay.
So, color themes
so
So, color themes Okay, so color themes I
don't like themes. Okay, so all you all
you have to do is, you know, you go to
just search for Xah Lee Emacs themes.
Okay.
You see, then you go to, you know, this
website. Set color themes. Set color
Emacs set color themes. Okay, let's
magnify.
Then, you know, I this page explains,
you know, the Emacs theme. How do you
use them? How do you set them? And so
on.
Okay, load loading themes and what's
available themes by default.
This is written in 2012, so it's like
actually 8 years old. I haven't updated.
Last update 2018. I don't use themes.
Okay, I don't like themes. I want things
I want things as simple as possible, as
ugly as possible. The The uglier, the
better the user interface.
Sometimes true. That's often actually
often true. I don't want I don't want
any kind of fluff. Anything I do in
Emacs must be functional. Extreme I'm a
extreme efficiency nerd.
Now, how however, for example, I love
Unicode. For example, you you see this
right arrow,
you see this summation, you know,
because they are functional, not because
they are pretty. You know, I don't care
for font, you know, lots of programmer
nerds. They are into fonts. You know, I
ran the I ran it about these four hours.
Into fonts, into like ligature. You
know, you know what is a ligature? You
know, like AE,
you know, that ligature.
I this I don't I don't want any of that.
I want functionality. But actually this
is this is a good thing, okay? So
paragraph
today we talked about it's represented
by this symbol and you can show white
spaces, you know, and you have section
sign, you know, function
wait, section wait, sec
Okay, then turn off white space, you
see, these are Unicode. I love Unicode.
So you can see actually you have a
entire page about Unicode, so you can
hand gestures, food, love symbols,
clothing. So let's search here. So you
you know, s e c, you know, dynamic
interactive
uh
Unicode search, you know, let's say p a
r
a
So these all all these Unicode Unicode
whose Unicode name contains the word p a
r a, paragraph. So where's the
paragraph? Right here. So you can see
you scroll down, then you have the full
um
You see? This one, so it's actually
called curved stem paragraph sign
ornament.
Unicode has ornaments. So that's an
ornament feature. Wait, where is the
standard paragraph feature?
Okay, so this character is actually uh
the the ornament version of the
paragraph
um
character. But there's also a a normal
non ornament
um version. By the way, here is the
interesting, you see, Ethiopic paragraph
separator.
This hexagonal
size, so you know, I love
then I love Unicode. Then then you have
c react c react c react end of paragraph
sign. So that's interesting. So anyway,
I have a section on punctuation. Now,
let's see where is the normal standard
paragraph symbol and why is my search
didn't locate it. Oh,
okay. So, the official name for the
paragraph sign is pilcrow sign. You
know, so here we are getting into
centuries of history, you know,
punctuation and writing systems. So,
this is called pilcrow sign.
And here's a section sign and here's a
asterin asterism, okay?
You know, I I studied all of these and
read about their Wikipedia, you know,
detail. This is fascinating, okay? Uh,
you know, Unicode. So, anyway, back to
the original topic. We were talking
about themes, okay? Themes. So, I was
saying I don't care for, you know, the
kind of fluff things.
How, you know, like
the Emacs nerds, the Emacs hackers, the
Emaclists, you know, those
typically the people you encounter other
than me, okay? Other Emaclists, hackers.
They
Oh, they love about the, you know, they
they they love the themes and they love
they want to remove the, you know, the
the the scroll bar. You will see a lot
of Emacs hackers do that. They want to
remove the scroll bar and remove the
menu because in their opinion those
these are crap. Not to me, you know?
I want
100% functionality, nothing else. But, I
want the menus and I want the scroll bar
because they are the most efficient way
to use Emacs because they they provide a
visual clue, okay? Let me shrink, okay?
So, what what's going on with the
uh, undo. Okay, so anyway, I digressed
all over the place. So, what are we
talking about? So, we want to uh, So,
let's hold on. We were talking about
themes, okay? Let me get back to that.
But, first of all, let me write this
down so we have a note of what we talked
about and go here.
Uh, wait.
Paste. Uh, ba- You see?
Now, with today's feature, I don't have
to add a paragraph here anymore. I just
show in browser
and it will automatically add it. Oh,
okay. So, we found a bug. You see?
Because the beginning um
character is not a letter, so it only
added the ending um
thing. It didn't add the beginning
thing. So, undo.
So,
Unicode is fantastic. Okay? If we add
this, then show in browser, then you can
see it adds uh properly. So, we actually
have a bug to fix. But anyway, we were
talking about themes. So, let me get
back to themes, okay? Themes. So, lots
of um
people like that. I don't like themes.
So, I want you know, I don't want I I'm
not using any themes. So, all I do is
just this one, okay? Set background
color honeydew. Okay? So, let's I can
show you. So, let's do it.
So, call meta-x set
background color.
Okay?
Then, let's say pink. Okay?
Enter.
And we have pink. That's my theme. So,
you see actually I don't have any
themes. So, basically, the only thing I
have is the set background color. So,
let's try again. Set back- background
color um Another good color is uh
seashell, I believe.
Seashell, okay?
Do it. Fantastic, okay? I I got to go.
Okay, I got to go. So, thank you guys
for watching. So, does that explain my
choice of themes?
So, you can do that.
Chug chug chug chug chug. Okay, I got to
go. So, thank you guys for watching and
uh okay?
I have links here. You know where to
find it. Thank you guys. Bye, guys.
Bye, Hi
I close down in 1 minute.
Okay, so we talked So, let me just clean
up what we talked about. Okay, here's
another bug. You know, this is the
parenthesis. That's why it doesn't it
didn't automatically add
uh you know, the
paragraph. Okay?
Okay, so I'm shutting down. Okay, so
uh yeah, actually I I got to go. So
So, that's it.