guys welcome to another episode of EX
talk show today we are going to code
emac lisp we are going to write a
program that validate
brackets okay so here's my keyboard
glove 0
fantastic ultimate hacking keyboard
fantastic NLEA track B fantastic and
here is the Logitech
g502 with a spin wheel the spin wheel is
fantastic but now my main is the track
board okay so that's my keyboards and uh
and there's also this SP board data hand
SV l b o a r d i will be using it down
the road okay you can search for my
reviews and other people's information
SV l b o a r d this is a fancy Advanced
keyboard if you have you know hand pen
or if you want you know uh reduce typing
discomfort things like that okay but now
let's do let's code emac disp we started
to do it yesterday but yesterday uh or
two days ago in my live stream we
started to talk about politics instead
so today we are just going to code emac
BP uh if you are watch watching this
offline uh uh not live you can skip
around because I talk
slowly okay so it's going to be probably
40 minutes to 1 hour so let's code so we
did this we did this
about uh 3 years ago let me pop out the
chat okay am I alive and uh let's
see uh wait am I
concurrent viewers zero
fantastic okay but I think I'm going
okay yeah
right so we did this about three years
ago and we just going to redo it uh we
did this live stream three years ago so
if you are impatient you can just go to
my website there is the emac this code
the problem specification you want to
you know give a file like that let's see
if I if you can see it yeah so given a
file you have a lots of nested bracket
the bracket can include square bracket
or round bracket or Unicode or or you
know curly bracket or curly or in
America it's called braces okay and but
you can also have like
uh Corner bracket right brackets you
know this is used in Chinese and
Japanese or you can have Turtle brackets
like that so but but you don't want
mismatch so if you are missing one you
know that's bad so you we are going to
write a command that will tell you if
the file is missing one bracket or if
they are mismatched for example right
now this right parent is
mismatched you see
uh well well well yeah you see so you
know if you move this one inside then
it's correctly matched so we are going
to write the program to do that that's
what we're going to do today so if you
are impatient you can just go to my
website already we you know there's a
emac this problem specification and we
already have a code
solution so this is emac L with
explanations so you you know code
explanation you can so you can read it
and you can write it yourself you don't
have to watch the live stream uh but
however you see this program is written
as a script that is you copy the script
let me show you okay so let's press the
key and delete that on the pink window
on the left is all my emac command
Calles and the key strokes for example I
press this key it will it it calls the
command smart delete and the key stroke
is E on the left I'm using a v keyboard
layout uh so e on vorak is the quy D so
on your keyboard is a d key there's no
control there's no meta there's no old
key because I'm using cly keys so I'm
using cly Keys which is a efficient emac
key binding you can search it you'll
find it it's free uh on G rep repo and
uh I'm using V keyboard okay so let's
undo so you can see this section is back
showing browser that's this section so
for example cancel cancel the selection
I press one key again go to the browser
refresh you see that whole section is
deleted so this is a combination of s
flly Keys the command name isar smart
delete and I'm also using K HTML mod so
if if you pay me buy my exi HTML mod
it's open source you get the source code
then you can have that otherwise you you
can have softlight
keys okay that's a pink window showing
all my commands it's useful because
sometimes you don't know I'm what I'm
doing you can look over there and you
can you most of the command I also have
the source code on my website so you can
go there and grab
it uh for example this smart delete if
your Cruiser is here if there's empty
lines white spaces you press one single
key it will remove all those white
spaces and now when there's a section in
HTML you press it again it delete the
whole section or for example undo let's
put a cruiser here you press one key
that whole o unordered list is G undo
you see all you move the coer here you
press one key that whole item of the
list is gone undo or if you have a
parent or bracket in you know let's say
something you C sart delete one key you
see that whole parenthesized text is
gone so this is you know some of the
power of the sof Keys you might want to
try it okay uh okay let me show you
quickly the source code then so there is
the website I talk about it often in my
live stream so you can see here is a you
know sofly keys and here's a video
tutorial how to install and so on here
is how to download on GitHub uh and so
on or you can you can get it from n
Alpa okay that's s like ke efficient key
binding and uh and basically you got
this you know so each key become is a
command it's more efficient than V I Vim
Neo or EVO mod okay it's more efficient
because less key strokes to do the same
thing okay that's soft like Keys now
let's go back to talk about what we want
to do today so so this we have written
this let me show you the code uh brief
so go to my emac in it or these are my
emac in it search for validate so there
it is validate bracket so this script
currently it is written as a script so
what does that mean that means you go to
terminal for example I'm on I am on
windows so I go to Powershell and you
just
run uh
emx let's magnify I believe then script
or batch yes uh I think there's a new
Option you just say script then you just
say s
validate you see H you know you run that
like the way you run python or any shell
command then you have to give a file or
directory so anyway so that is the form
of the script as it stand right now but
you see so but we are going to make it
into a emac command so in order to run
this you know if I want to check this
file has you know have whether it has
mismatched bracket I don't have to go to
Shell and you know then which file name
I have to check I can just metax code
the command in emac and you'll just
check the current buffer you know so
that's what we going to uh write turn it
into a command so once you have command
uh let me show you okay so once you have
command let's say
defund uh let's set this to
emx thisp mod okay D for defend so once
you have the command then you can turn
it into a script easily for example you
just here you know suppose here you
define the command you know simply a
single function then over here you just
call it then you call it here is the
argument from the shell you know I have
a tutorial on how to do that you know
you just uh emac tutorial search for
uh uh shell arguments so let's search
for argument get command line arguments
you see so this is how you
get the input from the shell and you can
pass it to your function so you just run
emac script my script name and argument
one two you know the argument may be
parenthesis maybe file name like because
there are so many different type of
parentheses maybe you just want to check
you know the round parenthesis
parentheses whether they mismatch or not
you don't care about other type of
parentheses so anyway so this is a page
that tells you how to get the arguments
from the shell command line it can be a
power shell it can be uh eell or can be
bash and so on or on the Mac
zshell so once you have a command you
can easily turn it to a script by just
call the argument you know get the
argument so so then you save save this
file and it becomes a script so you can
run it in terminal or you can run it as
a command in emac
fantastic hello
wzn hello
subet Mishra can we see your commands
the pink window
please thank you can we see can't you
see it there it is what do you mean can
you see the
commands so I don't know what you mean
so the pink window is right here you
know you can you already see it okay now
now let's work on this
okay so I'm going to write a command so
yeah so okay
so yeah so create a new uh yeah let's do
that okay create a new file
save it let's name it
validate
brackets. okay so let's just say you
know give it the temp name okay so
Define a
function uh
documentation
validate
brackets of current buffer let's just
say that okay uh we just let's say we
just focus on the current buer because
once this command works then you can
call you know you can have a eax work
directory command let me show you
okay uh let's go to talk show let's go
back to talk show paste the link close
that uh talk show today's talk show
showing browser go back here and uh what
is that yeah goand we by the way I also
have a version in goand fantastic okay
but anyway let's post link
here uh what I want to do now so close
that and go back here yeah so this is
original we need to we're going to code
it fresh so you actually know entirely
what I'm doing so first of all give a
name
validate
brackets okay yep that's you know uh
validate brackets of current perose so
once you know
you know once this command is done then
you
can create dates uh version date you
know for documentation purpose once
you're done you can just
call uh let's go to emac list emac LP so
emac LP so you can there's a how to
Traverse a directory there it is so you
just call this function and pass this
function so it can go through all the
files in a directory you know I have
like 10,000 HTML files but the the the
heart of the problem is to call this
command on the current buffer okay so
validate brackets of current buffer and
uh you know uh okay so we can start to
write it so let's create a new window
let me
um yeah so create a new window let's go
back to the previous so
H okay so we got a lot too cold a lot
too cold it will be 40
minutes how's going
everyone
okay I'm drinking watermelon juice
fantastic okay so concentrate so
okay so we want to validate the current
buffer okay
so the current buffer
okay so basically the algorithm is that
you know you you want to check Nest
brackets now let's forget about all
these different type of
brackets
um okay let me show you let me just go
slowly so if you are you know watching
this offline just skip around so we got
the work directory then we got uh yeah
let me show you the Unicode brackets I
talked about this quite often but it's
been a while so let me show you again so
in Unicode today you have lots of type
of GRA uh brackets so and brackets are
very useful because they
um they they are the unique character
such that they are pair
so once your Cruiser is at one pair you
immediately know without doing any sort
of passing you you know where is the end
position so you know that's what bracket
pairs mean there's a beginning position
there's a end position okay so so for
programming languages using bracket
brackets is a great choice instead of
using beginning and end like the Ruby
idiots and bad idiots you know beginning
end you know don't don't what use use
those keywords because the okay over
here so you can see there's your
well-known brackets parent square
brackets curly brackets or braces you
know parent brackets braces or in United
Kingdom they call it round brackets
square brackets curly brackets more
logical name but then you also have cly
quot single quote double quote then you
have you know like weird quote used in
Romania or other
countries then you have the the French
quote gulet sometimes it's called or
angle quotes then you have white
variants of the pan brackets braces then
you have have small variants you have
double
variants then you have Asian variant so
very useful extremely useful when
you uh design a programming language for
example and in fact it's used in some of
the languages for example Fortress
designed by the scheme guy uh what's his
name and also in wolam language but
actually they don't use the characters
directly
but um so here's a wolam language
fantastic I did this you know few weeks
ago about these curves
um and uh anyway so let let's go back
let's get this done okay so yeah
highlight brackets so these are all
different type of unic code brackets
there's also vertical versions and
there's
decorative uh brackets also these are
very common okay decorative brackets
quote End quotes and there's other
exotic ones you know you typically
you've never seen this
before and in Arabic language you have
this and also in tibetan language you
have this you know those are brackets
and whatever this language
is
oakam hello mty grocery bag
fantastic okay so we got the brackets so
uh yeah close that copy the link back to
emx close that paste it make a link and
make a list showing browser there it is
the most efficient way possible St like
ke okay of course you have you also got
the keyboard and some markers certain
markers you have to set up in order to
have like the way I have it so okay so
you know we showed some of the the
brackets we uh we want to start to write
this so the
algorithm did I already explain here
okay let me finish this part so here is
the page on how to code it in emac
disp and uh we did I explain the
algorithm how do you do this okay
um yeah so here is basic algorithm you
just go through let's say you only care
about the par paresis so you go through
the text from beginning you find the
first
parenthesis each time
you find a parenthesis you want to check
if it's already in a stack you know you
you you want to create a stack so every
time you find the parenthesis you push
it to the stack okay and you also check
in the stack if the last character is a
left parent so if you found the right
parent you check the stack see if the
last par is the left paren if it is then
you can remove that because they matched
so remove it and ignore the current one
find the next parent okay now suppose
you find the next parent which is uh
again a right parenthesis a closing
parenthesis you check the stack is the
last item a left bracket par if it's not
you got a problem you got a
mismatched bracket then you just record
the location the position of the current
Cruiser uh you know or report error or
something like that so that's the basic
algorithm find you know find the next
bracket push it onto the stack and check
if it matches with the previous one on
the stack if they are both open you just
keep pushing until you reach a closing
bracket and then you check the stack if
it's a opening bracket then they cancel
each other out you know then when you
reach to the end of file check your
stack if it's empty it's all good
because all cancelled out but if there's
some bracket on the stack you got a
problem because that means you have some
opening brackets that's never
closed so that's the basic algorithm RM
okay uh so here this page already
explained how to do this okay but now
there is a goand version so back then
like 11 12 years ago in
2011 13 years 14 13 years ago 2000
2011 I did a programming exercise asking
people to write this program so there's
a spec and uh we have quite a few
Solutions we have emac lisp and
someone contributed a python
solution okay so you can see uh python
solution
2011 then there is another python
solution I didn't
check yeah some of them didn't work so
you know for some reasons and I you know
go I didn't go into detail why it they
didn't you know so there's python 2.6
python 2 solution there is uh and what
is this solution
another python solution this is also
incorrect for some
reason and there is a ruby solution who
who coted this Ruby I don't
remember I have Robert clam okay I don't
remember who that is but you know these
are
2011 then there is also another Rubik
solution there's a pearl solution
uh so you know there and there's common
disp Solution by Matt who I don't
remember who's that guy common list
solution so and there is a ANC common
list C this okay I recognize this guy
Pascal J
Bugan he's a Le common Le expert okay so
I would trust this one to look further
oh pretty short
so
anyway so
yeah so you know that's interesting oh
God we spend so much time to go over
this so let's um I want to write this
command so let's do
it you know the reason I need because I
need it yeah because I have you know
10,000 HTML files and I use brackets
extensively so extensive TV so that's
why I want to have a command so let's
let's just start to do it
okay okay let's start to do
it now the easiest way is actually just
to check my existing code okay so here
is a test file let's open that file that
doesn't exist okay so let's let's create
let's just add a bracket so what kind of
bracket do you want let's say let's say
square bracket okay save it close so
that's a test file now this is a input
directory because this program supposed
to go through all
directories uh and this this code is to
make sure the input directory ends in a
slash okay that's a iMac this convention
if you have a directory path it should
end in a a slash okay
and also this home size old okay so we
need
to the new because back then this I'm on
a Mac or something I'm on Linux but now
I'm on windows so so this directory uh
should now be um you know
users instead of home
okay uh let's just go to keyboard okay
that's
that's this directory okay copy the file
path go back here paste it and uh there
it is
okay so now this make sure the directory
end in a
slash and uh and if the directory does
not exist stop reported okay and here is
the part where it gets the argument from
the shell you know but we are not doing
that
today uh and here is the list of
brackets you know the what kind of
bracket you want to check okay fully
document fully documented you know
that's my nature of my code all my code
every every every variable is all every
variable command or function is all
fully
documented That's My Style
okay so then you got the X rejects uh
what is this reject string of all pairs
to search oh okay so we started to get
into the code uh yeah so you got the
list of brackets here then you know they
come in a data structure called
associative list in lisp okay you can
look up
[Music]
my my my my tutorial on what associate
associative list is is basically it's a
list of pairs you can see it here you go
to Loop data structures list and uh what
is a list you go all the way
down then you see uh special list okay
so Association list which is just a list
but each element is a pair by this Con
structure okay
that's okay so that's what a list is
okay am I good
yes okay so you got the brackets then
you want to turn you know a bunch of
brackets aist into a regular
expression um
then then what is this commented out
okay that's a different way generate
regular expression from brackets okay
that's a different way to do it uh I
don't
remember so you know I have to look at
the code
let so there is Lambda oh then you map
concact okay oh you map concact make
them into a string
okay so and uh you know you so there is
the truth pick syndrome in emac lisp
regular expression because every
backslash needs to be to have double
back
slash and some of the regular expression
because parenthesis is literal in
regular expression in iMac LP so if you
want to do capture you have to have a
back slash in front of the parent so you
end up with two back slash in front of
parent and also for the alternative sign
you need a backlash so anyway you end up
with four backlash is
there uh so so okay anyway so this is
regular expression then okay
then so this x bracket match list is a
stack I suppose
okay uh then my operative button what is
that
I don't know what is this one my
operative button oh no documentation
that's that's interesting this must be a
hack get file path from properties so
what is this my operative button okay so
it must allow you to click and go
to uh yeah it allows you to click and
open open a file that has a mismatch
parent something like that okay yeah it
jump it opens the file you can see it
split the window open the file and go to
the Chart position so it jumps to the
file that has a mismatch parent at a
particular position this uh got let's
rename this
okay uh operate button so rename SAR
op button okay okay it's used somewhere
okay used
twice uh okay so then my process file so
this part is actually processing a
file so let's expand it okay so this
part is actually you know given a file
path you will go through it and check
the uh yeah so let's rename
it
to parent file okay uh let's
say check parent file okay rename that
rename rename okay go to the top rename
again okay so good
check okay now the name makes more sense
so check parent by file file path okay a
bunch of variable so there it is here is
our stack starting with empty now a
stack data structure in lisp is just the
list okay list is the best structure for
a stack because when you have a list
structure you can always add things to
the front and take one thing out from
the front so every time you add one item
and remove one item that's a this
okay so Char is a current character okay
God this is a lot code to go
through yeah but it's not too big okay
so for example I delete that whole
function undo single key press new
buffer paste it go to the top
let's make this EAC this mod and Shrink
shrink okay so it's it's uh 50 lines of
code if you remove the Commons in y
space it's 40 lines of code so that's
all uh not too
bad okay close that so
anyway so we have to go through this
because this is a heart of the thing
then okay okay then what we have then
done deal what where is the part that
checks all entire directory that's here
you
see so you declare a output buffer where
you want the error report to go
to okay
then then you know then you this you map
this function check
file uh to a list of directories you
know the input
okay and uh you also include the regular
expression you know what kind of file
extension you want so this actually
should be uh moved because this is
available sometimes you you don't always
want HTML so let's move this
[Music]
to yeah let's start to work get this to
work okay so
yeah so okay so let's go here let's make
um input file a test file so
okay I
want uh wait so uh file name extension
okay let's put let's put here okay
something like
that
uh let's just
say Okay so HTML so that's a file name
extension then you need to turn this
into yeah let's do that don't
we okay
that you need to turn this this into
that so you can just do it
by let's do it manually
okay
concact uh that by a dollar
sign and in front you
want double back slash and Dot there it
is okay so you don't need this part so
this is now better because this file
name extension is usually fre you know
is it's considered to be part of the
users option so that's why you don't
want to hardcode it okay wait undo undo
okay so
there okay uh yeah so but but uh another
thing we want to do is
that and you know and this bunch of
commented out I forgot what why what are
are these comment out what kind of they
must be alternative implementation and
uh okay but anyway so so you can see
save it close reopen so you can see one
of the most important thing is this
input okay let's search for currencies
of that so there
and there okay so now whatever below
this line is actual code whatever above
this this line these three are they are
user inputs it's a important dis
distinction okay so these are user
inputs uh let's remove that
so and
now now now in this program this x input
uh is uh yeah they okay that's all their
currencies you
know
uh check
exist make sure end in a slash okay when
you write it out it's much easier for
other people to understand check exist
okay now we have full
documentation and and this this part is
yeah this part is about getting the ARG
ment from from the command line okay
right now we don't
care okay so
now uh actually the bracket list you
should also be a user option
okay it shouldn't be part of the program
it should be a user option but there's a
problem about if you turn the list
brackets into a user option you have the
problem of designing an interface for
example how do you want this how is a
user supposed
to by what means they they list the the
the brackets you know you know for
example you can go by a text file or you
can do it on the shell command line but
that's usually problematic because then
what if user
gives they typed Mis mismatch bracket or
also so it's very tedious if every time
you require the user to type all these
different brackets so you want to a way
for the users to say just check all all
kind of matching brackets you know all
you and you also want be able to let the
user just say you know I just want I
just want to check parenthesis or I just
want to check you know the common asky
brackets per
uh square brackets or curly bracket
bracket you know like these
three and also another common one is the
you see these three are common these
three and another common one is the Cur
quote that's frequently got up so
anyway this these are brackets you want
a way to be able to let let the user
input them in a easy way okay that's
another problem by itself you know you
can use a menu like uh but anyway let's
worry about that
later right now I just want to turn this
file into a command okay then then we
gradually worry about the other thing
so this command first of all we want to
test to see if it runs okay
then okay so that's what we want to do
we want to test okay just run this file
and check if it runs because this is 10
years old code I haven't
touched so to do that you want to you
don't want to you don't want to have the
input be a directory well because a
directory has lots of files you want it
to be able to check one file okay so
let's modify this so if this input uh
um if it's it's if it's you know we can
make it so that it's uh you
know the program will check if it's a
directory or not if it's a directory
then go through all the files in a
directory if it's a single file like
that then just check that single
file uh so in order to do that so right
now it's you know it's takes a input
directory always because you can see the
program you know over here you know it's
getting a list of directories so you
want to
modify here so that you know if this
input is a single file then just do that
single
file uh yeah so that require uh okay
let's do that that requires me to change
a few variable names and so on am I
doing good say hi guys
uh okay
so yeah okay so what are we doing so we
want to
make what's the best way to do this we
want to be able to you know check a
single file or a directory right so
right now it's checking a directory so
let's do this okay let's do hey hey hey
hey hey hey Victor okay great thank you
guys so let's do this let's just rewrite
it here new fresh okay so people can
much easier to see what we're doing okay
so so we need a file name uh file F path
okay there it is a file path validate
brackets of current
um uh should it be a buffer or file path
you see when you actually code you have
lots of these little design details
which is
important uh for now let's just say a
file path okay uh well uh let's just say
validate bracket of file at file path
okay you know later on we can uh change
that okay so file path so make sure in
the stash we don't care check if not
exist uh yeah we want to check if it
exist okay so here when not file exist
uh this is the file
path what yeah
let's
say
God why is that okay never mind
so file exist there if not use the error
okay yeah let's do that okay so that
take carees of that then uh then you
need the brackets
okay so we we have a bunch of brackets
let's rename it lower case okay that's a
variable okay local variable so and uh
so you can actually put it
here there so we got a bunch of local
variables so for now let's
don't worry about that let's don't worry
about that don't worry about
that don't uh
What
uh wait what oh it's
interesting so we just only check the Cy
quotes right now we just only check the
C quotes Okay so bracket is defined as
so this needs to be a list so we got to
give it a quote that's how list is so
this is Association list P of pairs okay
so we don't care about brackets here
then then we need a regular expression
indeed
so we need to turn
this uh
to so we have brackets here then okay so
let's put it here so so let's rename it
because I don't want it
Capal okay so there is our regular
expression and uh there is our bracket
supposedly this will turn these brackets
into a regular expression fantastic
beautiful next next please you know like
20 years ago in the 1990s there's a this
Vietnamese
restaurant every time you get you go
there you know I was working as a typist
so at lunchtime you know I it's a it's a
restaurant you know it's a cheap
restaurant so lunchtime I go there then
you hear the vietnames women says
heiness
heiness heiness that means may I help
you help you may I help you the next one
you know heiness
tjack hello is least relevant today I
think about
AI um models and the need math it takes
okay is least relevant today not really
okay you want to know the short and
simple answer not really I mean what so
so put it this way if you are doing AI
most of them today is not written in
lisp
okay vast majority of AI code is written
in lisp back in
1980s
1990s okay but not today today you will
rarely if at all possibly find one
single you
know uh large language model you know so
called
llm chatbot or what whatever a I written
in this there are few okay there are few
but compare you know in 100 in 1,000 AI
programs today big ones useful you know
valuable ones you'll find you know maybe
one in 1,000 that's written in Lis okay
so maybe that answer your question is
this
relevant for AI okay so but is it
relevant well that depends on you you
know if you are coding for example if
you are doing text processing
that's what we are doing today text
processing extremely useful you know
validate also you can validate HTML for
example uh okay we are digressing but
let's do digress okay because it's fun
for example here's my keyboard blog okay
there are
1,000 HTML files in my keyboard blog
everything about keyboard you need to
know so you go to the directory you can
see magnify go to the bottom you know
1,59 files basically
okay so I want to validate I want to
know if I have ever
mismatched taxs for example
this SAS monitor 2008 okay SAS monitor
2014 then this book then in kassas
monitor let's say let's go to kassas
gaming machine okay copy the file path
close that open that okay showing
browser C gaming machine 2021 this is my
current machine so I want to know let's
go to the top you know if I got a
mismatched tag you know HTML is
basically like parentheses right so I
can
call validate oh okay there's a shortcut
key let's
see uh
tab
HED wait uh
what t Okay tab uh there it is you see
at the bottom looks good and the tab uh
command you can see is that one in the
pink window h HML validate HTML perer so
it just validated you know so what if I
cut out this part and put here so now I
got a mismatched tag you know we got a
closing tag H1 then here then you know
now let's call that command
again uh tap uh
H
error file this file cazar gaming
computer closing tag H1 at position 313
to 318 does not match last open tag men
at position 305 you see fantastic is
that
beautiful now let's say I save this
program without fixing it and I close it
now let's check the whole directory okay
this 1,000 files okay So Meta
X validate XML du enter okay which du
this
enter okay wait for 5 seconds there it
is
error error this and error that let's
see what is what what is error cound
gaming computer okay open that we
already you know so I mean we already
know this files
uh bad so let's fix it okay fix that
save close now the other error file what
what what what oh same thing actually
just that single
file you know it's basically saying the
same thing okay so now close this and do
again CU I validate XML to do it this
directory 10 uh 1,000 files done
validation you see done validation in
this directory any error are printed if
any you know looks good 1,000 and three
times so there's no error okay so that's
the power of this this is this task this
program let me show you the source code
by the way we we coded this last year so
if you go watch live stream uh you can
see this command okay let's go to the
source
code this is very much related to what
we are doing today uh in fact it's a bit
more complex because
HTML tags they are just like brackets
except they they got more characters
okay so you can see HTML engine the
source code there and uh we did C this
live about last year last year also so
you can go watch it on my YouTube
fantastic so that's Co that's a code and
of course then the other parts you know
so the main code is just this part uh
but then it's cing you see HTML validate
XML file you know
fantastic so what we are doing today is
very similar so okay I was talking about
text processing so this task is called
text
processing and for text processing
nothing beats emac disp not go land not
c not C++ not Java not python python
idiots not Pearl supposedly the most
powerful you know Swiss army knife
you know suppos the most powerful text
processing no not Pearl not python not
Ruby not
goand not not rust def Ely not rust rust
memory
edsy
not
hascal but functional programming no not
hascal not OK camo not Microsoft fop
they are all
lackluster when you want to do text
processing emac dis nothing beats emac
disp IAL I talked about this many times
why but what's the reason well the
reason is emac this is designed for text
processing more specifically because you
have the birer data type you can program
it programmatically move a curer uh do
search regular expression forward and
backward
too you know and you can sa position you
can narrow buffer you can narrow to
region you know all sort of things
that's and data structure and and
function that's designed for text
processing not even wolam language the
most powerful and beautiful
programs
uh is better when you want to do text
processing okay that's
emac you know can emac do this no but if
you want to do this validate you know
nothing beats iMac disp okay nothing BAS
there's no other system you know not Vim
neither because because VI or Vim or
neim they got a lousy
language emac L okay so that is you know
so that answer your question is it
relevant is lisp relevant that depends
on what you mean if you want to do text
processing nothing beats iMac dis if you
want to do for
example language design studies what is
is effect when a programming language
has lazy evaluation you know you
constantly need to trick your compilers
or trick your uh syntax if you want to
do that scheme disp is probably the best
choice not python not all the others
okay not Goan not hascal okay so depends
on what you mean so you know
so in you know in some cases lisp is
very still useful and
uh uh
yeah okay so then we digressed a lot
let's um close this close this let's go
back to our let keyboard block close it
we let's finish this uh you know pretty
we'll be done uh pretty soon okay so we
got a stack we got a regular
expression and uh okay then next this
this is the stack okay uh let's put the
stack here the stack
code okay and this is a variable let's
push the variable I mean we have to
declare a local variable and let's
rename it stack okay well let's
not uh I would but but we got to finish
finish this in live stream it's already
wow it's already on our
okay and here is a code that checks
the yeah actually here's the code we
don't you know okay
so so let's paste the code and let's
just start to you
know uh we don't need x file path okay
uh we already declared okay so let's
actually let's do it here open a new
buffer go to the
top so we our file name is that so
change all X path
to uh to what is this x okay let's not
change
uh okay let's
change x file path
okay change change change change change
change okay now put it to em this mod so
we got color so so process the file okay
so we already got this okay
stack uh oh it's already local what uh
we got some
what okay when T not string in case you
want to skip certain files okay per get
perate create buffer go Char one then we
search for
uh then we search for X regular
expression yeah oh God
so ah yeah so what we do so
we I mean we either welome here
or so but what is this
then what is this bracket match this
search oh so actually you need
it so it's begin empty
then oh God so
I
we got the we we got a situation we
have two branches going on here so where
which part should I focus on
so this
one this is a new okay it's maybe better
to focus on new but what is this bracket
match list what is this supposed to
do
search search search so it begin as a
empty list
okay
uh then when not equal
stack set that to cons xstack so
xstack okay I don't know what what is
going on
this okay I'm discouraged should I
continue
uh God
okay I want
to be able to at least have a one
command that just do the current file
okay so okay let's let's set that goal
just one command Okay 20 more minutes
should be
it so this supposed the already do it
okay so you create a stack to push for
the brackets each entry is a vector CH
and position oh okay also give a
position uh then X Char is the current
chart found set Q so wait so let's
highlight it so we can see where it
occurs
so then if it's true what is this doing
wait is is this even valid
syntax okay so it all goes all the way
down so basically it just it was some
condition so oh so
when oh yeah so I want to skip all
directory whose name start with
XX now I want to skip all files
whose name start with XX because that
was my temp
file but now we let's just say condition
is always
true uh but this okay yeah so okay so we
can actually ignore this when this when
goes down all the way to the bottom okay
so
now so now you get the buffer you create
a buffer this is a temp
buffer okay I create a temp buffer
without undo when you create a
buffer and you name it such that the
first character is a space that means it
create a buffer without recording undo
which is very useful when you are you
know processing files
programmatically because you don't want
to undo you know undo slows down you
know you don't need to so you set the
buffer that means make the buffer
current
then you insert the file contents of the
file path that's good okay then you go
to char which is
the beginning of the
buffer okay then you search forward okay
then you search for forward for the
rejects which is the
first uh you know the regular expression
here okay so you search for what
when you found it so while it is true
when you found it you set the position
the current c a position then you set
the character so the character push you
know get both a sub string you know you
get a character okay current character
composition then you print for debugging
purposes okay
then is a closing chart true so oh they
is uh wait this is a local variable is
closing
character and another local variable
xmatch opening chart okay so those are
Bings so let's clean the code so it's
easier to read here uh you don't need a
NE here because every local variable ini
initialize to Neil so you know my lisp
has improved since like 14 years ago so
let's remove that Neo it's redundant
okay uh okay so you just got two you
know two local variables
here then so now we set is closing
character q q means a question okay in Q
the naming of ending with capital Q
that's the wolam language convention
whenever you have a function that always
return either true or false you end that
function name or variable name capital Q
now the Lis convention is p but this is
not consistent for example in iMac this
but anyway so I was just using this
okay today you know anyway so it's not
too important
so it's closing character Q okay so you
all you can check whether the current
character the current bracket is a
closing one or opening one so you do
that by using the association
function okay that returns true or Neil
then is the uh okay so if if it is a
closing character then you
you you set this buing match opening
chart whether it matched or
not okay so wait so if it's closing
character you want to find X matched
opening character so that is the
matching character I think
oh yeah okay so wait so yeah so this
this is closing character is actually a
cons pair of two brackets one open one
close
Okay
then if it's found if it's not
new then
you you want to set the Matched opening
chart so you want to find the character
that matches
that closing parin okay
yeah then debug print debug information
then okay
if if the stack is not
empty uh car
stack wait
uh what what if you have a empty list
what does car return let's try it run
it okay it's still run uh returns NE so
that's good so if the stack is not
empty and equals to element cost stack
zero
so okay so the so we are checking the
item on the stack if it's not empty and
uh the item on the stack
is the opening opening bracket of the
current
bracket okay
then then uh then you remove that item
on the stack okay that's what you do
fantastic but if that character on the
stack is not the matching opening
of the current bracket then
you push it to the stack there it is
okay
then okay then you do this this is a
loop I think let's see yeah while you
see so this is a while loop there it
is okay so now once you are
done basically you are done because you
are searching every every parentheses I
mean every brackets okay so go to the
end so you when you are
done when stack is not NE you got a
problem setq bracket match list conses
uh
wait you got a problem so you need to
what set X bracket match oh is that
that's the variable that is the variable
oh
empty okay so what is this variable
for so set that so that was empty now
you set it to
cons so stack
I don't understand why are you doing
this so if the stack is not
empty that means you got a
mismatched bracket so then then you you
know you are printing the arrow
file right so you also print the stack
but what are we doing here what is
this set X bracket match list
cons okay cons means you add the stack
to
this I don't understand why are you
adding it to this list what is this list
for it's
undocumented
that's it's not nice of me usually I
document everything
anyway so you are pushing the stack to
that I don't know why but but uh
basically you should print this okay
eror and uh let's print yeah so
eror uh let's not print C
Let's
uh you need to print it okay so actually
you can just say messages better
so message
is error okay so you got
[Music]
error file
path Arrow at file file path
then then you can say stack okay when
you print a stack which is a Leist it's
not pretty so
so I think I know what's going on now I
remember so you see our program this
program written 14 years ago it
runs but it's not very robust because
you see when you found an error the best
thing you want to do is for emac
automatically put a ciser at that
position you know that's an advantage no
other problem programming language can
do that you know not Ruby not python not
Java or whatever so emac can just open
the file and put a CER there or and
highlight you know highlight
whatever you know the match supposed to
match the bracket you know whatever all
these kind of
things but this program does not do that
you know it just print the stack so what
happen when you print the stack well you
just see a bunch of parent you have no
idea idea I mean well you know paren and
position position you know you you can't
press a key to jump there so I remember
so that is
why you know so I mean it works it does
check you know whether you know the file
has mismatched parent but it doesn't
it's not so convenient so that's why we
need to fix
this now to fix this is is uh well it's
going to take another 20 minutes at
least to get going
because thank you so why are you using
Windows who is that asking that idiotic
question all the time I explained that a
thousand times as recently as two month
ago or so like there's a full one hour
discussion about which operating system
to use
okay and I believe yesterday also is
that you asked me about that
again
this now I I don't know who you are I
don't know what's your intentions but
some of my followers are the zomer
teenagers brainless type you know they
come here they want
to not necessarily you I don't know for
sure but they they like they want to
troll they want to like get me to talk
like something
dramatic these people are idiots okay
I'm not into those kind of
things okay so let's go back to code
so so yeah so this this will um print
stack you know print stack it's you know
it's it's like it's just a hack you know
it because when you print the stack it
shows a bunch things it's not really
um
great rather you want to put the
cruiser at a location that's a missing
brackets and explain whether you are
missing one or you are missing a left
one or right one what kind of brackets
you are missing you know things like
that
so yeah to fix this program you know it
will takes um
yeah I don't think I can do it so right
now we are already 80
minutes oh it's not your it's you are
not trolling it's your first time asking
that why are you use Windows inste
Linux it's a c question because when I
was on the
Mac then people say why are using Mac
not Windows or not Linux where Linux
people will say well are not you not
using Linux or or I mean Windows you
know just so
like so let me talk about this for a
minute just to answer your
question so when usually when people ask
when you ask that question why are you
using Windows instead of Linux there's a
implication the implication is that you
probably prefer Linux you probably don't
like Windows and more you know likely
you think Windows sucks and you think
Windows is like does not respect privacy
and things like that while Linux does
and Linux is more powerful it's more
open source therefore you know why are
you not using Linux come on because emac
is part of this Linux I mean the you
know it's G Linux okay Richard San
that's a a slightly different Camp free
software Foundation versus the open
source
Richard storman considered the
open source a scums okay maybe you don't
know that but that I'll tell you I
talked about this many
times so why why am I not using Linux
because in my opinion Linux Mac Windows
they have kind of pro and cons okay each
one of them there's
no but you know this Pro and cons such
that there's no easy answer to consider
Linux is the best like without any
criteria you can absolutely say oh yeah
Linux is the best operating system
besides it's free you know that's one of
the big advantage that's why you are
using Linux if Linux cost you 20 bucks
you will not use Linux anymore I can
tell you right away okay not to consider
about
privacy or how Superior technically it
is or whatever if Linux cost you just
$20 all the Linux Fanatics they will
stop using you know even even though
it's still open source but they'll
stop so there's
no easy so this Pro and cons among these
three operating systems so there's no
easy answer okay if you are you know if
you don't want hassle if you also play
video
games Windows is the
best if you are very concerned about
privacy you know you worry about oh the
the the the Boogie Buggy Man or some
glowy then Linux is probably your best
choice every day you just sit in front
of the computer how do I connect to USB
you know my USB I bought this USB stick
it's USB 3.4
but I can't get it to work and when I
plug in nothing comes up you go to you
know Linux you chat with your Linux
buddies oh you got to go you know go to
the sh kernel this then you know after 1
hour it worked oh Jesus the beauty of
Open Source that's Linux you know if you
are a Dev if you all all you do every
day every day is emac which is better
emac VM you know you don't care about V
whatever vs code whatever v v VI Linux I
must Linux I must Unix I want command
line I want talk about kernel that's my
love Linux is best for you okay you you
are Dev you don't play game you don't
play games okay
you oh you don't you know do other
things in Linux okay now if you are the
type who want the most best design you
don't have to worry about how do you
want the drivers or the colonel whatever
crap and things just work out of the box
including hardcore programming and
Technical computation like go
language if you are into that Mac is
your best choice the price you have to
pay is that everything is twice as
expensive you know you you buy the same
computer for the Mac it's you know for
Linux it's $11,000 for the Mac you pay
$2,000 for the same thing everything in
you know so that's the mac and also you
don't get it's it supports your privacy
there's no popup like going on and
there's no open source Fanatics shouting
at you in every screen please support
open source donate to this project
please
you just want to get on you with
your life code or play games or whatever
by the way you cannot play video games
neither if you want to play the you you
know the real video games basically
Windows is your only choice
okay uh and I talked about this in my
previous V video so many times you know
was one of the most shallow question
like people don't you know they don't
anyway I hope that's good enough
answer okay so back to this problem I
don't think you know by now we talked
for 90 minutes and uh it will take me
another at least 20 20 minutes to so I
think that's it for today I you
know uh we didn't explain the full but
you know we explained much of the Elis
coding and uh
also for those of you really into my
emac disp okay so you can just go
to my emac lisp website there is you
know go to
imag
L
tutorial and there is a new section so
for example emac this Basics everything
you need to know from the ground up on
emac this you know the basics buing
string what is a string how do you look
up documentation what's a number what
kind of Flo is you know do they have
integers or floating numbers what's a
syntax what's buing what's a variable
how do you define local variables how do
you do to if then else conditional so
Loop and what's a data structure list
vector and how do you create a function
so this Basics and then you have emac
this but there's a new section okay
video tutorial because I've been doing
videos for three years so there's lots
of these past videos which one you know
so I collected here these are good
videos each one is about one hour long
and they focus on one thing for example
this one is Sly Keys
introduction okay and if you want to
learn emac disp you know so this one for
example this one is about emac disp
workflow workflow
efficiency you know then if you uh and
go let's go back and then if you want to
learn iMac this from the ground up there
is that
one
uh that one
emac list for
beginner so I talk about you know how do
you create variables and all that and
then okay so you get idea so this
collection of emac and emac this video
tutorials okay that's it for that I
think that's it for today that's it
anything else any other questions
eight people okay so that's it for that
thank you sir thank you
T we shut down in one
minute so I'm doing you know I need to I
need this command myself so at least I
spend you know I went through we we went
through the
code um
have some idea how it works and we also
demonstrated the HTML validation which
is you know a bit more complex than this
but essentially the same thing exactly
the same problem so I did a video like I
mentioned before if you search for
validate there it is you
see talk show
2023 June 25th iMac thisp write a HTM
and XML
validator so there it is you know we
write we wrote it from scratch in real
time and then part two so that's what I
demo today
so thank you guys bye so another
question subet are you going to solve
this problem in your stream it's very
interesting for me as a beginner and
thanks oh okay
you want to see the
solution yeah okay let's try to sub
let's let's try to do it quickly okay uh
since you asked for it so uh don't
forget to donate okay if you donate me
of
course uh but since you asked let me
just do
it so we want to write a function that
quickly just check a file and tell you
if the parentheses are all matched okay
so let's just quickly do that uh now I'm
just going to quickly do this so we
don't we don't want this whatever that
is okay so buer stack so let's copy that
buffer stack
so so there's a buffer there is a stack
we need local variable there's a chart
we need and there's a position we need
okay local variable copy that
okay so that's local variables and then
Set uh set stack empty okay stack so
empty list we don't need
um actually we don't need this okay any
anyway
so because by default stack is Neo so
Neo is equivalent to empty list but this
part I need uh CH okay empty
string so let's uh so then let's copy
this whole when thing let's put it here
so let's check the file exists then this
is regular
expression uh wait does this occur here
no wait it does okay so it actually it
occurs there so okay so let's just copy
that copy go back here
so paste that here and go up go up and
when we have the regular expression so
we need to rename this rejects because
we have a name that there so rename this
Capital
by lowercase okay okay fantastic so this
is this is a regular expression to
search the brackets then let's predy the
code okay so when it's true always true
uh X perer um X perer do we have so we
got X perer local variable and file path
now what is this file path okay so we
need to rename that I
think yeah so go up here yeah so the new
name is that okay
so
uh so we need to read name this file
path
by one two three four okay search double
check yeah so so we are back here so we
when whatever is always
true
then create a buffer okay X buffer
search for that search yeah we got local
variable then make it current set buffer
then then insert the file content of the
buffer into the 10 buffer go to the
beginning of the buffer then while
search for the regular expression search
you know so that's our regular
expression of the brackets then the
position okay position and chart we got
the local variable yes position and
chart
um okay then then then then then is then
then um then where do we have that uh
that's a local variable okay then that's
also a local variable Okay then if not
empty uh then print okay uh format let's
let's print it out format match this top
item okay so if it's matched we don't
care
yeah then we remove that from the stack
otherwise
um we don't care so otherwise it didn't
match we push it to the stack
then then we are done okay so print
current stack we don't care so we don't
um okay pry the code uh actually let's
remove the print okay because let's move
the let's make the code
compact okay so pretty high the Cod so
we check the current current uh bracket
push to the stack or remove the from the
stack
then then we are done because this is
a uh wi Loop you can see
this is a while loop so that means it
reached the end of buffer okay
then
then then if the stack is not
empty so you can if not equals to Neo so
you can
see uh so if it the stack is not equals
to Neo I don't know what that is so move
that we don't need it so if it's not
near we got a arrow so Arrow at
file and print uh print the last
character of the stack okay fantastic
let's just do that so that should uh do
that then kill the temp buer okay then
also uncommon clean the code now let's
clean the code so what is this and found
CH let's remove that okay wait let's
make sure okay uh compact the code so if
doesn't match we don't care okay so
actually let's remove the
when
okay okay and uh let's make that one
line let's let's let's let's make let's
remove this redundant
okay uh actually let's check just for
for this square bracket because it's
easier to see okay so we only check for
square brackets right now okay so so
let's clean clean clean clean fantastic
that's it that's our code uh how many
lines of code 39 okay shrink a little
bit that's our code so now eval the
buffer now we evaluate the whole buffer
so we can actually call it okay so the
you know this takes a file path so we
want to meta X and call this it won't
work because it doesn't have a file path
so let's fix that so you just add an
interactive here so when when you call
this file
interactively I mean when you call this
command by meta X it will automatically
add the current
buffer the current Buffer's file path
will be passed
to the argument automatically okay when
you call this by meta X so this is how
you do so all you have to do is a perer
file name perer file name is a variable
that that Returns the current file path
full path of the current buffer okay so
that's done now eval the buffer now
let's go to some test file okay let's go
to we had some text test file here there
it is okay open it magnify magnify let's
add some more okay
now meta X some validate
brackets enter
please it didn't say anything so it's
good so when it's good you need to print
fantastic you are beautiful okay so
let's modify this code
when uh so you see we instead say
if
if if stack is NE so you don't need to
say equal you just say stack so if it's
empty that means it's NE so it's
NE
message
fantastic you are beautiful okay
no error fantastic no error you are
beautiful but if it's not Neo
then you got a
problem okay so
it's chick Ching who is that thank you
sub subet thank you
so so if stack uh yeah so if stack is NE
fantastic you are beautiful if stack is
not Neo then you need to uh message you
got a problem you got a problem at this
file path and message you got a problem
in this stack let's let's print so we
know what kind of thing it's going on so
this
bracket problem okay something like that
okay this this is just quick hack to get
this done okay so we modified it now
evaluate the buffer go back here meta X
some validated
brackets ah this wait we got this
bracket you got a problem what what a
problem
uh
what so if stack is true oh we got it
reversed so this got to be reversed so
if the stack is true that means you got
a problem if it's NE fantastic okay
evaluate the buffer you can see my
command course in the pink window s run
current file that's my custom function
to Evol buffer or you can just call Meta
X eval buffer okay so eval buffer go
here meta X validate brackets fantastic
no error you are beautiful it says is
that true it is true oh fantastic now
let's introduce an error okay let's
delete that okay now you got up
meta X do
it oh it says fantastic you uh
what okay we got a bug let's say let's
try to delete that one okay let's run it
yeah what it's always
fantastic we got a bug here
so s cute so God so you need now you
need to go into the logic of the stack
so so push
stack uh wait what what is going on so
if the what what is the reject let's
let's double check what is our rejects
okay the regular expression string
okay so messages
re okay rejects is you know maybe this
rejects is wrong okay evaluate the
buffer go back here cor
it fantastic no error but what is
rejects okay rejects is
that that is in uh okay
well oh I know because when you have you
see what you see the square bracket has
special meaning in regular expression
that's a pen because the square bracket
in emac this regular expression it means
you
know character
class uh so instead of okay so you know
so let's cheat let's just not check
scare square bracket
let's let's check the par instead
okay okay let's check P
instead
so evaluate the buffer let's go back
here remove that let's say parent parent
and parent and some more nesting and
parent okay run
it fantastic no errow but now let's
remove that one okay run
it it says still beautiful but it's
actually not true so what is
this H God regular expression the
regular
expression what is okay so we need to
check the regular expression what is
this
uh it's a pen to figure out the back
slash
so okay so uh there is a quote rejects
okay
quote quote
regular so what's the comment
in the bracket list do we have
square brackets
uncommented parenthesis also has meaning
no parenthesis parenthesis is literal in
Elis okay but anyway we need to there's
something we need to figure out here so
our code is not correct is
because um
okay so I mean okay let's for whatever
sake let's just try
the you know this C quote so you know so
it absolutely no no special meaning so
okay so close that close that cly quote
cly quote uh cly quote okay so we got
cly quote Yeah but C is hard to see so
actually so let me get fancy let's use
Cora quote okay Cora quote is a one of
the unic code character okay so remove
all that corner quote Corner quote okay
now uh valid bracket no arrrow fantastic
now remove delete that run it no errow
it's a beautiful okay you got something
wrong so what is uh
so what is the regular expression
regular expression let's do do it again
so what is the regular expression okay
evalue oh I forgot to eval the buffer
that's right so delete that okay Co do
it no error you are beautiful but that's
not true so if you look at the regular
expression It's that or that that that
is uh correct
you see the regular
expression is correct I believe so why
is this always no error
something if
stack so let's say that we know this is
going to be wrong for sure so C validate
bracket uh no errors this is wrong
because we at least pushed two opening
brackets there so now let's print
stack uh okay print
xstack stack length Okay length is uh
length Okay xstack Okay eval the buffer
go back to this buffer call the command
validate brackets go to the messages
uh stack length is zero this is wrong
okay so we didn't even uh push it to
stack for some reason so shrink what is
is if
stack is not
empty hey wait why is this check
emptiness yeah this is wrong
okay why do you have to check empty
if
stack okay set stack C stack set stack
cter so if it's not
empty and uh so wait did we
clear so stack is near here okay
we okay so stack is
Neo
so if it's not empty an element cost
stack zero
so what is the stack each entry is a
vector Char and position
okay so you want to each entry in the
stack is a vector Char and position okay
so okay I need a break so if it's not
empty then you get
the the first element of a stack and you
get the zero component which is the
character so if that character matches
the matching
bracket then you remove that stack okay
set stack to the cutter if it does not
match now what if stack is
empty oh you you you need to get rid of
this okay you need to more because when
the stack is not
empty
um
so when it's not empty but it doesn't
match so the emptiness should be your
separate check oh God so okay let me
just quickly do this okay without
thinking too much okay so this
block okay this block of code we need to
rewrite it okay let me rewrite it here
okay so first of all so okay so let's
rewrite if stack is
empty so
if stack is NE okay so if it's
Neo then okay let me just so if it's
Neil if the stack is NE simply push to
it okay actually you need to push it and
also make sure the current bracket is
not the closing bracket otherwise it's
errow okay so uh God so
oh so actually the stack is Char
position and also file path okay uh
wait Char position okay Char and
position not let's not push F path so
you got a vector character current
character and the
position uh then
say stack okay so actually you say push
you know this is my old style today I
would just say
push instead of using the cons so push
to stack and what do you push you push
that
okay
so that okay so
basically if stack is not
empty yeah you need a lot conditions
here okay so
so if stack is empty wait if it's empty
or not
empty so let's document because it get
confusing very
fast so if stack is empty what do you do
make sure
check
CH is not closing okay if it's closing
you got a
problem
so so how do you check well here is okay
so so this actually we comment out
no
opening bracket okay that's right then
okay let's just say that okay let's not
worry about anything else okay so if
it's closing
otherwise stack is empty okay so now
it's empty check the CH is not
closing if the closing you got Arrow
it's not closing you push it okay
so
okay
now now now when it's not empty
now when it's not empty what you do
so when the stack is not
empty you need
to check this thing
okay check this
okay okay you get the element from stack
and first element now if it's the
matching it match is the uh opening
chart for the current bracket then it's
good then you remove it okay
so then you just say pop okay so this
days I just say pop uh pop xstack
okay let just remove the first
item uh
yeah otherwise
so when it's not empty and the one on
the stack matches the is opening you
remove it okay but if it's not
[Music]
opening uh you need to push stack okay
so push again so push this so
there okay
so and this statement that we don't need
anymore so let's see so now it's
beautiful so instead of instead of
this this thing now we have the
um this thing
okay so remove that evaluate the
whole okay now go here
and uh remove the message soer deleted
and restart over did we evaluate I think
we did call it no error you are
beautiful my
ass so eval the buffer make sure we eval
the buffer so and let's do again here
Cod the command validate fantastic no
error stack length is zero that's
incorrect
God what is what is going on so did
we actually
clear wait
so what's going on
stack brackets okay now that's uh that's
a Association list right yeah that's
correct Association list uh regular
expression X perer is a temp perer okay
and uh then
sack is empty it's by default it's neon
so we actually we don't need this set
thing because stack by
default is uh already a uh
Neo so we got stack then we got chop
temp variable then position so stack so
we got a CH so um CH is the current Char
found okay
wait okay then when not file exist or
use error okay then we need to create
our regular expression that's right
regular expression is there anything
wrong no the regular expression seems
correct okay
then create a temper first set it to
current then insert the file into it
then go to
CH uh so what search for word new t
t means report error uh t means no error
okay don't report error if you cannot
find
it so it's going CH so if stack so where
is this stack going on
so last one if stack
let's let's print some more let's just
print some
more uh debug messages okay let's just
print the stack weever let's see what he
doing push uh did I get this right
push oh wait we we got this wrong push
cons Vector you don't need cons what the
yeah push Vector so okay so that's
why no wonder not cons since we not use
push so push Vector CH position to the
stack right push yeah so EV The Bu go
here close that call the function do it
no error you are beautiful show messages
stack length is zero no that's
not so why is it's not even printing
stack okay now cut that let's put it
here search
forward uh message okay stack is
evaluated go back here close that call
the command again uh no we got something
wrong fundamentally
okay uh let's just start to print
everything
everything ini initial interactive both
of file
name wait close that per of file name
that's a file right
uh okay
so let's
messages file path is let's
going crazy evaluate it go here call the
command Do It show the uh file path is
that file path is correct now at least
file okay save it is call it again do it
go to the message buer fail path and
rejects okay now now uh rejects
is that that seems correct now let's try
to with it so see if TT HH okay
random character EV the buffer go here C
that go here call the command Do It show
the uh message buffer there it is so
rejects you know got updated so that
seems correct so where did we go wrong
so let's remove move that
that so reject is correct set character
uh it's current Char found so what is
the oh
there ah idiotic wait did we set
it so search
forward there it is set character yeah
there we set the
character so we we don't even need uh we
don't need
this okay
so okay X CH that's just documentation X
Char is a current CH found okay
so so let's remove that let's put them
to where they
are uh supposedly used okay
so
extra there it is okay now find
documentation
superb okay so EV the buer and so first
of all we have regular expression temper
first so go to CH search
forward uh let's say beep
bracket found okay let's just say
whenever it found it you beep so run it
go back here close that call the command
m x do
it there's not even a be so it's not
even
[Music]
finding you see it's not even
finding the regular expression
I mean it's not even finding a bracket
okay that is why stack is empty all the
time so it's not even finding
a uh uh so what the is our regular
expression
it
yeah so
what H this is my first time catching
live hey thank you zuo oh great thank
you yeah we doing emac this
today
uh yeah and uh well anyway so let's
let's you know we got some
problem we are at the heart of it so
it's not even it's not even so it's not
even finding the bracket at all so that
means um uh this regular expression must
wrong this is the part I didn't want to
touch okay so if
we so what is our sub what you
know so LDA conact car in
C car in
C uh why do you need four I think four
is wrong okay
so okay not four maybe not four okay
maybe just two I don't want to think
about it let's just trial in error okay
close
that eval the buffer go back here call
the command Do It show there it is
symbols Valu as variable is void X
bracket oh God that's why all this
while there it is beep bracket found now
now it is actually finding a bracket
okay now set Q symbols value variable is
void X bracket so we got a typo there X
bracket somewhere there it is oh Jesus
uh so X so you know so X bracket should
be yeah lower case search yeah there it
is there it is yeah so eval buer go back
here close that all this trouble now
call the command m x validate brackets
fantastic no error no that's not right
so let's go back here let's see what's
on wrong so
rejects okay so B bracket found B
bracket found yeah I think you do need
four um backs slashes
okay we got wrong because we misspelled
the X bracket capitalized before okay
now EV the buffer go back here close
that meta X validate brackets do it now
show the messages buffer okay we got
that Reg expression is still that stack
length is
zero uh now they didn't even beep so no
beep means no regular expression is
found I mean no bracket is found okay
so so that means this oh Jesus
this there's a better way let me try to
there's a better way to create the
regular expression our problem is this
regular expression because let's try it
again
because uh doet show yeah it's not
finding even so if you have four it
doesn't
work um I think I evaluated I don't know
why uh do it again evaluate show the
message before now it's it's it found
you see
yeah so this is a proper regular
expression now it's found now it's found
uh stack length is zero so now bracket
found stack is new now bracket is found
why is stack still new so you found a
bracket here you then you print the
stack okay don't don't print it
yet so you found the bracket
then don't print yet okay then you say
the character the position then you set
the character then
check you know check the character is
closing you know which one is the match
matched
opening okay then stack okay if stack is
empty if Stacks is empty check the CH is
not
closing if it's closing you got Arrow
okay if it's not you push it to St
okay check uh push the character and
position as a vector okay now if the
stack is not empty then you check if um
you check if the parentheses on the
stack is the matching opening one if it
is then pop it you don't need it okay if
it's not then you push the current chart
to the stack okay now at this point we
can print stack
okay at this point we can print you know
because this this this is the you know
the qu Loop okay
then at at the end you print the stack
length Okay so evaluate this buffer now
go back here uh now close the message
sper call the command now show the
message but let's see so regular
expression looks good beep bracket found
that's good stack is
NE uh that's not good because when you
found a bracket is a opening bracket it
should have pushed to the stack so let's
go back here so if it's
[Music]
empty is closing CH
Q okay okay we got okay
so so is that a closing character no
that's not a closing character
okay then you push to stack right so you
push the vector to stack okay so why is
it now
let let's kind of shrink it
okay so this
stack right so you pushed it
stack is so you pushed it
here so if it's
empty then you check if it's closing
if it's not closing like the case we
have then you push to stack right is a
spelling error no now if it's not empty
so at least we should have one one thing
on the stack
right yeah it's yeah then you print it
so then you print the stack okay
evaluate the buffer again
go back here kill the message sper show
it again meta X do
it uh you see that's a problem stack is
near why the is stack near
wait eval let's try again do
it stack L zero stack is z stack L okay
the push is not
pushing uh what's the syntax new item in
place okay push we got two pushes
here and one is the new item one is
space now did
[Music]
we have the global variable position
correctly yes it includes the whole
thing
so and did we miss SP X stack
no so we have this push and it's not
pushing so describe variable push new
item
Place
uh okay I'm really getting impatient
here so this if
statement yeah so if stack is
oh we got the we got logic error so
if stack is
true this part should be at in a second
part okay so if it's true then that
otherwise if it's NE then that okay
finally EV go here close that go here
MAA X Cod the
command there it is show the message
buffer your stack is is that fantastic
correct thank you this bracket problem
this one at position five let's go to
CH go to CH position five there it is
you got a problem thank you yes I know I
got a problem but but but it should be
solved now let's you know now it it's
match okay call the command do it uh
wait not go to chart call the command
validate brackets do
it uh this bracket problem it's still
got a problem
what close that call it again do it uh
it say it's got a problem but actually I
don't think I got a problem you got a
problem uh so there's some bug so now we
don't need this messages uh this
messages
debug
so uh what C
show uh Cod show so file path so let's
remove the messages
okay regular expression I think is
correct um so what
okay okay let's check again yeah so this
is a mirror a error so let's is heart of
the code is this stack thing so if stack
if it's
true if it's not empty then we want to
know if that the current
character is equals to the one on the
stack okay so equals so oh wait oh wait
not car
okay so you do the car and element zero
is the what is the
stack
um each entry is a Char in in position
okay so okay zero is a chart
right so if it's not empty and it is
matched then you pop
it okay so you move remove it okay so uh
this should be equal no not not equal so
let's try let me show you because
there's a equ equality issue you see if
you have two strings exactly the same
string if you do equal will they return
equ
equal uh they will okay so actually
equal is
fine uh did you save The Bu app after
adding the
bracket uh I think so
yeah yeah I mean yes because every time
I switch Windows it automatically do a
save uh you can find that on my emac
tutorial if you interested I I find this
to be the best way to Auto saave every
time you switch window or out of emac it
saves all purpose so for example if we
make a change you can see two stars here
that means it's not saved but now if I
move to here you see it's saved you see
now show messages you can see you know
saving that file so anyway so uh we want
to get this uh going so uh we just need
to double check this uh the the the the
logic um of the
code the program logic okay so if Let's
uh so if stack is not is true that means
it's not empty then uh match opening
chart and and also if it matched opening
chart now is this valid did we write
that
correctly oh God
so not so many variables
so right Association so if it's a
closing chart how do we know if it's a
closing
chart well you check if the it's in the
brackets okay if the check if x Char is
there now let's print okay
messages is the closing chart and the
current CH is X Char okay so we print
them that that okay so arguments is
going to be
right we print the current chart and we
print is is it closing okay let's just
run it so we don't you know so trial and
error because we are very tired unknown
file extension
what oh wait so we need to meta X call
this uh let's go here
so oh there it is wait what okay so it's
closing ch
Force for that correct bracket found is
closing
Char false for that
correct now next bracket found is
closing
CH oh there is our problem it should be
oh no it's not closing because it
returns a pair so it's
true and uh yes indeed then next bracket
is closing yes it's true so checks out
so this closing chart so far checks
out uh but uh but what what what else is
the problem close that EV all the buffer
do it go to the messages no error okay
it says no error but now let's introduce
an error okay save the buffer call the
command do it problem
problem at position two opening bracket
fantastic which is
uh character two wait what
what whatever but the anyway it's got a
problem so now if you
do cut that paste it here okay save it
now call the command let's wait let's go
to the message sper clean message buffer
Now call the command do it MAA X Do It
show the message buffer no error you are
beautiful yes I'm always beautiful now
if you delete that first one save the
buffer call the command do
it it's still say no error but okay so
now actually it's a error so oh error no
opening bracket okay so we need to
instead of just say error we need to
stop like print like you know so no
opening so there so instead of a message
it should be uh eror
okay so errow okay so now remove that
message and remove all these messages
okay remove message clean the code
then's search for messages we don't need
the so okay uh search for message
okay regular expression is correct and B
bracket found actually I'm pretty sure
okay evaluate the buffer go back here
close that go back here should be a
error okay because you know so now we do
it validate bracket call it uh error no
opening bracket okay now actually remove
the message is beep so now it's clean I
think we are done uh it's works it now
works we worked on this so much I think
you you have now you get idea how this
thing works evaluate the buffer go back
here close that call command Do It show
the message before
error no opening bracket okay
so uh why is it doing if
yeah so it just say error here and okay
so well that's okay so now but now if we
add the opening bracket let's add it
okay now it should be fine again save it
show the message B clean it okay save it
call the command do it no error
fantastic I think that's right that's it
now if we cut this and put it here
that's a error again save the file Cod
the command do it error no opening
bracket fantastic we
got ah finally we got this problem
solved that took 2 hours and 30 minutes
I
think oh
what is that right
150 uh minutes wait 2 hours 120 plus 30
Dames thank you somebody is watching my
program thank
you okay I think we solved it okay so I
mean of course for me there's um there's
much to do but for now let's copy
this code go to the S Talk Show so I can
paste it so you know you guys can play
with it uh if you are learning emac
thisp okay so create a new preag wait
not well we want emac this that's right
paste it there showing browser go down
fantastic switch back press three keys
to syntax color thing showing browser
and uh there we have the
code oh God what ugly
code uh actually it's not too bad I mean
there it is okay that's today's code it
will check at least one file then you
can just make it check all directory and
you can add more yeah I basically we
covered it thank you guys for watching
fantastic fantastic for subit for the
donation thank you bye
guys yeah me bye guys byebye bye-bye