good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of some talk show
today we are going to do emacs list
coding it's been a while so today is
emac this coding
and i'm going to do
a i'm going to live code and tutorial of
emac lisp
of a
extension of a command that does find
and replace
of
a
file single directory so basically it's
like unix grip and set
it's all written in pure emac list okay
so let me check video check sorry i'm a
bit late so video check audio check and
we are ready to go
okay as you can see and this is my
keyboard kinesis advantage two
linear red switches
and this is um ultimate hacking keyboard
so you can see how i operate my computer
the most efficient way with soft light
keys okay so sapphire keys if you don't
know let me just uh do some um okay yeah
so
stuff like keys
uh git
fly keys where is it
uh here uh okay
so supply keys is the most efficient key
binding system for emacs which is what
i'm using and as i type every command
every keystroke you see will show on the
pink window you can see there okay and
let's turn on the
highline global line mod global highline
mod so you can see where my cursor is
okay so my command art is shown in the
pink window and we are going to do emacs
that's what we are going to do so how
are you today how are you guys
nuke squirrel
noob squirrel what's up
okay so let's let's begin shall we let's
so if you have questions ask me okay ask
me in live chat chat
um
so let's put that there
and uh okay so first of all let me
demonstrate what is it that we are going
to do what is it
so soft like it's fantastic okay
and by the way i i i want to make a
announcement okay
uh
comp
computer language blog so
programming star programming blog so i
have removed essentially all of my open
source code on github
so you can see i deleted
you know i have like 20 30 packages most
have you know more than half of them is
about emac list i have removed it
because
uh for reasons yeah i mean if you watch
my video you know why uh because
the open source model you know i'm
you know
uh
i want to change okay i'm not feeling
too good so now
they are still open source but if you
want to use them you have to pay you
know it's funny like before it's all
open source and every day i have to do
spend hours and
and in particular spend about 10 or 20
minutes to get commit push to github
for nothing for like nobody cares nobody
give a [ __ ]
but now
you know now i don't have to do that i
just code my code okay so anyway so
let's focus on emac lists okay i just
want to say i removed my github so if
but if you want my packages now you have
to pay okay you pay me um
okay let me show you
so you go to search for emacs blog
you go to the home page then and
and down here you can see casa packages
so here are my
uh
you know emac list packages
some flag keys it's still on github it's
the it's the one that's most popular so
you can still download from github
but
it's not going to be on mailpad anymore
so i request
a removal from mailpad so let's just
okay delete that
uh wait delete that so
delete that
okay
so you can see refresh
okay i need to also remove the mailbar
in store because it's not going to be on
mailpad anymore
but it is still open source
you know in the spirit of free software
foundation in fact right now it's still
a country licensed by gpr3
but
you know pay me okay that's uh that's my
point
because when you do open source
most of you people they work for
proprietary corporations such as google
facebook and so on
uh you know they have 1 000 lawyers in
apple and they sue each other every day
you know
patents and stuff that's what you do and
at night you know you just chunk out
open source code helping these
corporations wiping out good open you
know good free spirit programmers who
share their code
that that's me okay
so
open source you cannot survive you know
don't don't do that okay if you
so if you you know if you truly are
fanatic about open source then do not
work for proprietary cooperation then
you know then you are integral if you
work for proprietary corporation but
then you chant about open source day and
night you are not a good person you are
the
bad person
okay so
my packages they are still you know you
pay me
uh i need to adjust the prices a bit you
know you know you pay me then i send it
to you and they are still open source
open source and i must say
emphasize this they are still open
sourced by the definition of richard
stowman okay
um yeah for at least you know for emac
stuff because technically speaking for
emac stuff i should not
make them non-open source because of the
gpl okay so
you know it's kind of it's kind of a
gray um
area so
they will likely remain
open source
okay so that's about my packages some
update i removed them from github so
let's do so let me show you what we are
doing okay so so right now we are in the
directory you can see you can see i'm in
the directory uh ergo emacs directory
okay and what i want to do let's say i
want to grab you know find all
files 1000 files okay so they are they
are about a few thousand files here
okay let's show let's show how many
files okay so
uh so go up to powershell duh let me
show you the power of powershell
much superior than bash i tell you
okay and i tell you because
i have been diving into powershell in
the past half a year seriously i began
to write a powershell tutorial in 2009.
powershell powershell began around 2003.
beginning
uh it was named monad you know something
fancy anyway i started to write a
tutorial but it's not you know it's not
uh in depth but i started to dive into
powershell a lot spending hours every
day studying the details so i show you
all the most common things you need to
do and explain powershell in the most
concise and precise manner
so you can learn them in the in the in a
quickest time possible and accurate and
get what you want to do okay and here is
my discord join discord for you know
signings and discussions with very a lot
interesting people
so powershell let me show you okay so
i'm mentioning my powershot tutorial so
you go go read it you know it's uh you
know i i uh
okay so powershell let's go let's go
okay so let's go to this talk show so
show
show the pink window and today's talk
show of course we mentioned powershot
paste it here so you can see a link
powershell
uh and okay and we
now we yeah i want to show you the power
of powershell one button press operation
okay so you can see
uh get out of here and okay let me show
you how many files in my emacs directory
so
e-max the recurse include
html files
and
pipe it to
measure
so you can see there are 2 500 html
files in this directory and now let's
grab okay yeah let's do it in multiple
ways i have a great command i've written
in emaclisarfind.edl
in golan which is also on my website
let's show you so today is all about
grip the unix philosophy grip
okay so here's my goal line tutorial so
you go down you can find the code
find string okay so here is a code about
100 lines about 100 lines that's that
script and you also have a find replace
script now i can talk you know i talked
about this many times the the find and
replace is actually a fascinating uh
task and and in element in computer
science because it touches on formal
languages regular expression and formal
languages formal grammar it's all about
find and replace
it in fact it touches on lambda calculus
lambda calculus
combinators they are actually
essentially they are all about find and
replace strings okay so i didn't know
this
you know and you know in the past
several years i picked up you know it's
quite fascinating because you never you
actually never connect
the find and replace you know the unique
set or
yeah yeah the unix set you know you
never connect the
the task a very practical common task of
find replace with the most ultimate
theoretical computer science which is
regular
regular expression automata and you know
in but in particular
uh
uh grammar you know uh formal language
grammar and lambda calculus and
combinators they are all about find and
replace and why is it interesting
because there are many great there's
there's many uh uh
deep questions find find and replace
uh
for example grammar you know in
programming language you know you heard
the passing you you've heard of you know
writing a compiler first of all you need
to write a password but before you write
a password you need a grammar you need a
grammar specification for the language
and how is that done that is done by a
list of find and replace rules
find and replace yes exactly find
replace strings so
usually you know you don't hear
programmers talk about that very
interesting so i find so let me let me
summarize okay actually
let's um i'm going over all over the
place so let me actually copy the
okay let me show you the penguin.
okay i'm digressing into several
multi-level digression but let me go uh
get them back one one by one okay so we
can write it down so we have a
clear idea what
i'm talking about okay
grab and set in
elise golan
pearl
python i'm gonna going to show you okay
and powershell
is it big enough let's make it big okay
grab and set in e-lisp go land pearl
python powershell okay and then we are
going to end
the relation of find replace to
theoretical
computer science okay
formal languages
grammar
formal grammar okay usually you know the
full term is formal grammar it's all
about finding place and
lambda calculus
and the
combinator and you know i mentioned this
quite a few times watch my videos in the
past uh you know the past 10 videos you
know like as a youtuber you know many
youtubers they have 10 years that you
know they've been doing youtube for 10
years i've been doing youtube for about
three years
you know the first youtube is very bad
your first video then it gradually
improves so i've been doing uh youtube
for like three years now i i can talk
comfortably
and hopefully i make sense
i i'm hope you know hopefully i make
cogent persuasions
good morning dion brick uh
so you know we have a lot of great
programmers here uh good morning so let
me read a comment a little bit so yeah
okay i'm i'm a um
splatter brain you know i go over
most it's called multitasking guys i go
over all the place good morning alan
okay
wait let me let me finish the writing
here okay
so so greg said elise golan pearl you
know we're gonna we're gonna show you
code how to do grape and set in ev
school and per python powershell and
what else
uh
did i did i forgot something did i
let's let's see let's go computer
languages golan powershell python
i don't have one for ruby i don't i'm
not too
familiar with ruby pearl yes
emac this yes
uh and wufang language okay but i'm not
going to do it because i haven't
actually coded
uh find and replacing wufang language
but that would be spectacular and george
our forum member is a great programmer
he has done that
enclosure okay php i can do uh closure i
haven't coded for a long time okay yeah
so
these languages okay then the relation
of find replace to theoretical computer
science formal languages form of grammar
lambda calculus combinator okay let me
mention again lambda calculus and
combinator they are not not about you
know most programmers they think oh they
are about um
is it's like equivalent to tuning
machine
anyway
um lambda checker is in combinators it's
about
uh it's about the foundation of
mathematics okay they are actually not
the origin their purpose is not about
computer science about you know it's
about the foundation of mathematics or
in other words they are part of logic
okay a branch of logic they are part of
the philosophy you know the foundation
math so you look up their roots okay so
i would recommend highly recommend you
go read stefan wolfram stefan wolfer
in particular just go stephen
okay so
let me let me just help you out
okay so stephen wu from so he's got
three articles spectacular you know each
one of his article is 1000 pages you
know
so
i recommend you know you should go read
them okay read them after you watch my
video three there are about three
articles specifically on combinators
okay
why you read his why do i recommend
because
the the most salient thing is that once
you read it you realize the the essence
the what what is the essence of the
combinators okay
typical you know not not when you read
other
say for example wikipedia you
uh you get
misled into
you know you you you lost the sense what
it is for
okay but in my opinion wufang gives you
the
the actual
history and the the nature of and the
purpose and the of the combinators and
and also of course he talked about
lambda calculus lemonade accuracy is um
part of it okay
so they are originally about
finding a foundation for mathematics
okay it's not about
functional programming or lambda
calculus the root of function
my ass
okay you disperse out there
okay so copy that so watch uh so so make
a link that that okay show in browser
okay so we got the link combinator so
stefan wufang combinators then then
okay then i'm going to show you each of
my code for find and replace okay for
example showing browser so here is the
go land
and go line you go to the bottom so you
can uh you can find python's version
then perl version okay each one i have
written with the code so here's a python
version actually we want to
find and replace with regular
expressions
okay in or directory recursively or
otherwise
i talked about this topic quite actually
several times in the past but
let's do it again because the
but now because i can now talk better
better and i have
better equipment money can buy
this is america
powershell okay wait uh what is this
powershell right to fire wait where are
we here close that
second life come back video so okay we
are getting into
oh god
oh [ __ ]
okay we are back to the
programming okay what are we uh okay so
so let's not lose track okay so we got
golan python pearl
and emac these okay so i'm gonna show
you emacs list one
okay actually i talked random a lot we
wasted we kind of you know well
we
not necessarily
we didn't necessarily waste time because
this is star talk show talking is what i
do and i've been talking indeed so here
is the home page for xr
find replays emac list okay find replace
in pure emac this find and there's a lot
you know so you might wonder why do you
need to find replays you know today
people say oh you should use ark you you
should use silver they are much better
than unix scrap you know every three
every five years in the past
20 years you know there's a new newer
faster parallel grip
uh which which is good but uh
but
but um
but there are still good reasons um
you know to to have one emac list okay
you don't have to use those uh fancy
ones this one is pretty good
not just um
you know well so what i'm saying is that
the traditional unix script has lots of
problems i have written it down okay so
somewhere here uh traditional yeah
so here is article problems of coding
unix script in emacs okay let's let's
write it down okay we digressed over but
we'll get back to one item at a time so
problems of calling unix script in e-max
so this is article i give you the you
know
five major reasons that
when you use emacs
and when you need to find replace text
usually it depends on the unix script
which is it which sucks okay you
shouldn't you know you know emacs is a
powerful editor you should not depend oh
you actually you need to install this
other library otherwise your emacs
doesn't work one of the main major
feature you know a powerful text editor
doesn't work you you you need this you
know you need to install unix script you
know on linux this doesn't matter
because it's uh you know
it's not unix
actually linux is part of unix
long history but anyway so
it really should be built in and it can
be done therefore i have the you know
emac script you don't you don't you know
returning emac these you don't need uh
you know external
silver arc or whatever millennial
generation things you don't need it
uh
unless unless you know when do you
actually need you know those fancy new
ones ark silver you know there's like i
don't even forget that i forgot names
okay when do you need it that is if you
need to to find and replace on one
million files one million
files
to you do you do that okay if you don't
do one million files if you oh all i
need is just you know let's say five uh
let's say um
ten thousand files you need to find
replace on ten thousand eight you know
files source code okay then you don't
need silver you know those things
you can in emacs you can use well you
know you can use my package you know as
a choice um
okay this one and uh
but okay so i was saying so there are
many problems of the unix script okay
it's not just in emacs okay so first
first first of all
in emacs there are several problems of
calling the unique script in emacs okay
you shouldn't do that okay okay that's
one thing now another thing
the unix grip itself has lots of
problems okay i don't know if i have a
dedicated article on that unit script
you know
let me show maybe i should show a few
examples but we are digressing all over
uh we don't have time to code anymore we
need i need to start to code emac this
because
you know lots of problems with rip
one of the major problem is that you
cannot find a
uh a block of code such as look at my
screen okay a block of code that
contains the new line you see
if you know you cannot do it with unix
square because unix is line based
because unix philosophy you have the
line truncation problem you know the
hacker idiots they tell you oh you need
to you need to add a space whenever you
reach 80 lines otherwise your code is no
good [ __ ] them okay unix the entire unix
and the whole computing culture c
beginning with c and unix these are
scums you know the skin technology that
creates
kind of
permanent damage in computing so
because they created the concept of
things should be line based you know
everything is line based you know
remember you know for example you you
have count number of lines lines of code
and the git div they are all based on
lines you know don't change your format
because it screws up your div and so on
and then screws up your git repo you
know
like
permanent
how do you say um
pervasive damage in computing industry
these unix buckets beginning with c and
unix with line based you know and
truncate your lines you should not be
more than 89s you should do you know in
emacs it's called feel feel column feel
region let me show you okay
you see so
so
so so
so um okay so wait let me show you okay
so let me let me just remember okay so
please remember today
um
okay let's go to alice in underlying
line chapter one wait wait
alice in wonderland down the rabbit hole
chapter one okay so let's copy some
passage okay so so so you see okay so so
you see in the unix philosophy you know
like you this is too long this line is
too long it's illegal [ __ ] you [ __ ] you
you broke the idiom [ __ ] you know go we
don't you are not welcome in python
community emacs community you know
people don't welcome you because your
line is too long to [ __ ] it
okay so they want you to do field column
view paragraph like that okay
they want you so let's show
let's show the um okay can you see that
can you see let's show the white space
you see this line is too long no that's
illegal you need to feel column
feel column the [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] the
[ __ ] this could
[ __ ] these programmers
the eunuchs and hacker types you know
they want to do that
to do that you know like you go to
python
just about anywhere any code
they tell you know they have a
programming style guide they tell you to
do that okay if you don't do that you
know you are not kind of you're not
welcome
out of these [ __ ] and there's these
[ __ ] in emacs community who created
you know he's a good guy okay but i
disagree with you know i'm attacking the
mainstream ideas okay he's a good guy he
he goes by you know he in the emacs
community he's a great emac this
programmer his name is uh
bad bad something bad something he's in
eastern europe you know he created
closure he's maintainer of closure mod
or you know the closure
cider cider id and lots of other things
okay prelude yeah predict is one of his
emacs innate package okay very famous
guy you know he
he he he likes to he wrote several
programming style guide you know like
auto checker you know like uh what what
they call i don't use it uh
uh fl you know auto you know checkers
they check your formatting so they you
know and he also have one for ruby for
emac this you know he says okay this is
the community consensus
for how you should format your code
therefore you should you know before you
checking your code you should run this
you know i wrote this you know hero this
you know format checker so you should do
it so that you know it confirms through
the community [ __ ] idiot
the [ __ ] idiot supreme
you know ruby ruby the programming
language is created by a japanese guy
mats okay
and one of the characteristics of ruby
is that it does not require this it's
you know ruby the programming language
is not
it's not um let's say very much reliant
on
[Music]
on on on the new line character
but anyway he you know this this guy he
created this those
things
uh you know idiotic you know it's like
society's becoming better you know today
it's actually now after 20 years it's
actually becoming better [ __ ]
microsoft windows telling me power toy
update
[ __ ]
so program pro programming community is
getting better so what you guys are
saying programming community is getting
gradually better away from the unix
philosophy damage over the past 20 years
why because the hacker generation died
out
in replacement is the millennial
generation you know the self-entitled
idiots millennial generation they are
taking over
and with code of conduct and so on okay
so in so the hacker's generation is died
out so many of the hacker old you know
grand old ideas is gradually going away
such as such as oh
such as for example oh you should not
have a unicode in your in
you know in your source code for example
look at this character okay that's
unicode fantastic
efficient powerful and and necessary
okay next
let me show you okay so you see that
next button that's what that is you see
next page previous page you see at the
bottom
and what so what is that triangle that's
not css you know most of the css web
there they use css to create this
triangle anyway unit code okay one
single character does it you don't need
to go to css or svg you know 10
100 lines to create a triangle the hack
okay [ __ ] hack of the unix hacker
tradition hack the [ __ ] heads this hack
okay unicode fantastic
okay
you know many the unix tradition is that
source code should be pure ascii you
should oh god why are you doing this
being possible to [ __ ] idiots okay
but this but that generation the hacker
generation is dying out so comes
millennial millennial for the
millennials
unicode is fantastic in fact they
created emoji
you know
emoji drama they you know the millennial
generation emoji that's what they that's
their thing you know then
they then then then the skin color the
skin colors of the characters okay
anyway so that's new generation
millennial you know
so
so what i also i was saying you know in
the past 20 years gradually the hacker
generation dies out replaced by
millennial and so there and also many of
the old you know fashion unix
hacker generation concept about
programming style and so on is also
dying out so for example one of them is
unicode in source code you'll see a lot
of them you're seeing golan their
documentation you're seeing golem in
schemes you know i
i looked you know far deeper than most
most of you people okay you're seeing
goliath
in scheme programming community in html5
specification you they have unicode
right in their documentation okay it's
not a
extra rendering process okay you in
terms of it it's it's not going to go
away it's part of the society now
so unicode is one example the other
example is the the long lines okay
that's also kind of dying also also the
style guide you know the classic pearl
you know grew c programmer c programmer
style guide is also going away because
skolan you have go format
javascript you have deno and you know th
these these
they auto format your entire source code
1000 files just press a button they
formatted for you and in fact i have
written that you know i showed it many
times
so okay let me go back okay so
many of the old unix philosophy hacker
types of ideas are dying out for good
reasons okay one of them is
unicode in source code okay not a extra
rendering process direct unicode
directly in source code in fact if you
go to google style guide google you know
google the powerful empire they have
several style guides
style guides for python for css html
i've read them okay i've read them years
ago and i read it every few years
uh just just to keep myself relevant
okay so anyway so so
so in google style guide they tell you
they tell you right there in google's
style guide for html they tell you right
there whenever you have unicode use
unicode directly don't [ __ ] do not
[ __ ] use a escape mechanism like the
c [ __ ] you know for example to
represent this character you can um
you know in many languages you can do
wait what am i doing
i don't want um
ah did i just [ __ ] up my code
somewhere
what did i change i don't know
okay so anyway so so in in many
programming languages to represent okay
let's do this
okay we are digression digressing over
okay so in many programming languages
to represent that character
what you do is
you represent as
that okay that's a c [ __ ] invented
that the c program of [ __ ]
and unix you know they they are a virus
so they spread into c prosperous they
spread into pearl they spread into java
they spread into basically every
language javascript they all have
support
uh not a not six digit okay they only
support four
like that okay this is called literal um
format for for four characters okay
anyway and emacs two i have article on
each of these languages how do you do it
how do you represent unicode okay
um
so what i'm saying so yeah so
so what i was saying is that in google's
programming style guide they tell you
exactly whenever you have a unicode use
it directly don't use this kind of thing
okay or or in in um in html you would do
for example
uh
yeah what's uh
anyway so let's it's just not to be if
for in html you have to do something
like um
something like that or decimal okay so i
forgot so you know
i can um
you know so unicode so let's see html
tutorial allowed characters chart set in
encoding so you can see here's uh how do
you declare chart set and encoding
everything you want to want to know
about
unicode is for every language for
for python uh html golan
javascript emaclis i have a detailed
article on them okay so and including a
detailed article on what unicode is
about for example this one okay so
anyway so what i was saying is the
entities okay
uh where did i talk about entities okay
entities uh here okay
so here this is article about or
everything you you know the most
fundamental things you need to know
about unicode what's the character set
what's the encoding what's a code point
and so on
and this article is a complete list of
html entities entities is kind of an
escape mechanism like like the c [ __ ]
heads slash n slash t and so on escape
escape mechanism it's not good okay
don't [ __ ] escape [ __ ]
use direct
use characters directly okay simple sin
simplicity is one of the most
fundamental important thing on
um on the quality of source code
simplicity
you know the c
unix coders they they love one of the
things they love is complexity okay
when when there's something complex they
get excited oh pointers oh point
arithmetics you know that's the see
[ __ ]
the the the unix philosophy [ __ ] it they
love you know it's
they love that that kind of thing
okay so we digressed for long so
so let's go
go back okay so
okay where are we so we digressed
actually
quite far
so let's
copy that
oh yeah so i was showing the i was
showing the you know the gnu
the gnu feel column you know the [ __ ]
and idiotic the most idiotic name feel
god feel you know what what the [ __ ]
that is
feel
feel region via paragraph then the emax
phonetics they'll say oh you should use
autofill oh because i understand what
you mean you should just turn on
autofill you idiot
[Laughter]
[ __ ] idiots so do you so do i make
sense to you do you understand what i'm
saying you know these people they are
counter like oh
oh besides stupid because he says we
should you know we are using field
column of your paragraph but actually
you should use auto field
um
okay digression so so much digression in
fact we digressed so much we changed the
nature of today's talk show
because we were going to actually
you know live code emac this about this
find replace thing
uh then it's another imax trend okay so
here is uh uh
down the rabbit hole alice in wonderland
one of my favorite book actually
so let's um
close that and here we talked about
unicode
so get back here paste it here somewhere
unicode okay
so close that
did i did i screw up on my page
okay
so
you know
interactive unicode search you see
fantastic as you type
okay that's written in javascript of
course close that
okay we talked about entities copy it
close that go here
paste entities okay
then
close that
okay so what is this
wordy blog okay close that close that
close that
okay entities did we copy entities
now join the paragraph i mean join the
list
okay fantastic code so we can see
repetitions deleted okay
show in browser close close
unicode basics so we need to do that to
unicode basics
close that character set and encoding
did we do that
no okay so we need to add that
character set and encoding in html okay
and uh of course i have uh yeah let's
just uh this is uh let me show you just
uh all
the things you want to know it's yeah
let's talk about random okay
so we talked about how do you represent
unicode the multitude you know the
several ways named entities or decimal
entities or you or hexadecimal entities
for html and how do you do that in emac
lisp there it is let's see
uh
[Music]
unicode okay so here is how you do it
how you represent
unicode by their code point in
a stream in emacs
language okay that's how you do that
so also paste that
there
okay so that's about emac list what
about let's talk about javascript okay
so
let's go to
javascript
unicode
where
where is it
search
no okay so where is it uh
javascript
so we want to represent unicode in
by their code point how do you do that
okay so
let's see javascript basics
string coding string template string
string length
string methods arithmetics
the easiest way to find it is sardi
javascript unicode
there it is
javascript unicode escape sequence so
this you see here is how you represent
unicode by their code point in a string
in javascript the language okay copy
that paste it here make it a list
okay
close that close that
close that
chapter three down the rabbit hole close
that find and replace in pure e-lisp
okay we already have that let's do that
okay
uh so problems of koni calling unix uh
regress
unix script we talked about
okay close that
perl yeah we already have we don't we
have that python find replace by regular
expression close that
uh what is this find replace script go
land we have done that
combinatorial combinators with stefan
wufang fantastic article close that go
line tutorial close that question tv
fantastic
powershell working with directories
close that
okay so
so
let's so let's take a break
these are the things we talked about
today and now i'm going to read the
comments
hopefully i'm still alive like i'm not
talking to myself for the past
hour
okay so we already talked for like 50
minutes wow
so let me have a drink
and let me read the comments
and
then let's do emac this
dizziness says do you know joshua bach
pronounced jojo
back in english no
i don't know who that is okay let's read
the comments
so if you have a question for me right
now it's a time tag my name okay put my
name to it are you thinking about
updating to windows 11
um not sure you know i've been using
windows in the past half a year
uh and i don't like it okay the
windows the the telemetrics
the millennial jargon telematrix
which basically they're gonna call home
hey we got this guy he's doing this and
that they're gonna tell microsoft
call home
telematrix
uh it's a euphemism okay telematrix
uh you know microsoft windows and uh you
know the microsoft windows user
interface is uh
you know i've been writing articles
about it you know several articles and
i'm not you know it's not done yet it's
not it's half it's half complete the you
the windows you know so windows got
many many problems okay [ __ ] many
most idiotic problems many problems part
of it is user interface
okay user interface in windows is one of
the big idiocy
designed by extreme idiots okay no
there's no argument about it
i can tell you why well the reason is
that it's not because people don't know
it you know it's idiotic it's just
because it's a corporation it's you know
it's got three decades old of code and
programmers you know move on it you know
they got several departments each one is
concerned about their own
benefits you know they led by their head
of certain department this department
they don't work
you know so this is one of the problems
of big corporations they you know and
they
they don't care because windows they
sell cell you know they they are you
know already you know the so-called
network effect they're already popular
so part of the problem is the user
interface well the other part is the
getting into your pants you know they
want to know what you're doing
you know they you know telemetric and so
on is it you know for example for
example and today you know they become
open source open source you know
microsoft and google are the biggest
owner and funder
of open source today okay the biggest by
far
you know not
not linux the [ __ ] open source [ __ ]
[ __ ] idiots they made it they made
the society
they
for you know for a large reason you know
they are the part of the big reason they
made a society like today where
microsoft and google controls your life
because of the open source phoneticism
to [ __ ] them
where if you are a programmer
you have you know your only chance to do
it you don't have power okay your only
thing is to work for google and they you
know or microsoft and listen to what
they say you know sign contract sign
saying whatever agreement you know they
can fire you anytime you know you have
to agree to code of conduct you know
code of conduct
not funny
and
you know and if you don't work for them
well
good luck
you beg you beg for a little you know
peanuts like i did
for 10 years
uh but they did but these people don't
know because well you know they are part
of society they are just uh
and fro you know this
vast majority of programmers including
especially the archetypes who think you
know they they tend to think they know
about how things work in fact they don't
they don't
so they are just part of the
you know society you know
like decade by decade you know thousands
years old of human history they just
move with it you know so there's a
um
there's a word you know this award that
captures the thinking of the decade you
know like it changes right like before
you know like today you have social
justice you know
kind of many ideas before that it's
another thing before that it's another
thing it changes every every decade
every generation
so these programmers
you know they don't know they just they
made you know they are just part of
today you know like
like for example today's people
millennial millennial generation when
they look you know you guys okay when
you look at
how programmers do things in the 90s
some some of you might say oh god do
people actually believe in that
that's idiotic you know things change
then your children
when they look at what you were thinking
you know what what you were you know
excited about open source or whatever or
code of conduct maybe they'll say oh my
god that my dad's generation is like oh
you know they just you know history
uh so
yeah so so microsoft you know they have
lots of you know extremely idiotic use
user interface problems
uh then you know for example let's look
at let me show you just one okay so this
this you know someone showed me uh on
saw discord so this this screenshot you
are looking at is windows
is windows 10 okay current you know
windows or windows 11 you know part of
and they show you
part of the windows 11
where you can see
many user interface that's you know 20
years old over you know they are all
still in windows
so it's extremely inconsistent it
you know it's not just inconsistent for
you know it's not just a minor complaint
oh it's inconsistent if you really look
into it you know
but rather they are inconsistent to the
degree
that affect how you use window in you
know
every day like
one of the one of my big complaints is
that there's no way to tell today
there's no way to tell which window is
you know um
for example let's start another power
shell and let's say if you do it uh here
you know it's very hard to say for
example i have now you know
like look at this part of
can you see that okay and this
let me move it here so you see
this
that you you see there are several
windows here it's really hard to tell
which one is actually a window which one
is in front
so you know it's a windows user
interface is a big problem so also
windows 11 i heard that they are moving
to you know now it's required to have a
microsoft account in order to use it
they say you know they've been always
wanting to do that but usually you just
unplug your network install windows then
plug your network you know that usually
that's a way to avoid it but i'm not
sure within windows windows server maybe
if you unplug the network they don't let
you install
but people are saying that windows 11
that's one of the requirements so
if that's actually true i'm not you know
i'm going to back to linux
or mac you know linux is another very
sad story
linux you know because the open source
idiots you know linux you should have
20 years ago when i was young okay when
i was young
like you guys okay you know we think
okay linux oh microsoft is going to die
in 10 years because now linux okay now
it's 20 years well where is linux you
know it's not in your hand you know the
power is not in your hands the power is
with microsoft and google
you know it's not for the people you
know originally the idea of open source
you know or free software foundation is
that
you empower the people not the giant
corporations you know richard german
hates giant corporations but now
richard snowman is also problematic you
know he he now stands in microsoft's
building sport podium speaking
speaking to how microsoft is now the
good thing because they are now open
source
um
so windows got problems so i'm not going
to you know i i
move to linux
or mac likely mac you know mac is
another issue
mac is one of you know mac is the
extreme
corporate
corporate you know they
mac everything in mac is the highest
quality but however you know also it's
most secure relatively speaking
um
[Music]
privacy oriented you know
except apple knows your stuff but apple
um
don't have a apple doesn't sell your
data really
you know
not not compared to microsoft or google
at least
but mac they sell everything you know
three times
more expensive
anyway so that's that question
so um back to um
so yeah i'm gonna answer questions and
that's it today i think
the guy who wrote dive into python yes
exactly he abandoned open source
community too did he actually abandon
open source all i know is that he
disappeared you know this is uh internet
history like one day he just disappeared
from the face of the internet
like all his github or online presence
you know uh social network you know he
just disappeared
you know the start page is
this search engine start page is a
problematic you know we we um
dive into python you know this this
start page is
becoming problematic i don't know why is
it
wait is my internet down
okay we talked about we talked over an
hour now i'm thinking we should stop
why is the [ __ ] start
uh
okay
so i tried uh different search engines
in path month i tried you know because i
got really tired of dr go becomes very
bad i also tried start page it's not
good um
and right now i find the best is
actually kosia okay
so let's search for dive into python
so yeah dive into python this guy what's
his name he he was yeah pilgrim mark
piogen he disappeared
around
2008 or something he disappeared from
the internet because he's he's one of
the big giant internet
coding celebrity because he wrote dive
into python he will dive into
html css html5 dive into html5
and one day he just disappeared like you
don't like no warning no nothing
so
so people have been dived
into what happened you know it turns out
he just disap you know he just want he
don't want internet presence anymore
and so that's him
mark
he was working at google at the time i
think yeah i'm yeah he was um
you know he just disappeared from the
internet then there's also another guy
from the ruby community
whose name is what um the cat face or
something
do you guys know i'm sure you guys know
you know the there's a guy from ruby
community who wrote a lot ruby tutorial
say it okay if you remember the name
said he just disappeared too
the y guy okay ruby yeah so
ruby white guy okay his name is uh you
know why the lucky stiff guy he just
disappeared from the face of internet
two one day he just removed all his
tutorial he was i didn't know him but i
when i was learning ruby i learned you
know he was very
famous but very well known for writing
for promoting ruby uh and he
yeah the white guy
also disappeared from the internet you
know
me i'm not likely to disappear from the
internet i'm a permanent nerd
but okay so the question actually so so
dion the question is did
did mark pilgrim actually remove himself
from open source community is that
because i didn't know that
oh okay so deanna also mentioned the
lucky stiff guy
string rewriting system noob yes string
so we were talking about find and
replace
so
one of the technique becomes string
rewriting you know string rewriting
system brief
refers to
refers to a
particular programming language
paradigm of computation okay so string
rewriting system refers to a particular
programming language paradigm of
computation i believe that's uh that's
how you describe it i mean string
rewriting system i mean they of course
they have also
originally that it's not about
programming language it's from
theoretical background anyway wufam
language okay i've been talking about a
lot about wolfram language that's uh
that's based on string rewriting system
okay let's let's let's uh let's go
wikipedia so we can
anyway i talked about in my in my past
two videos also i talked about stream
rewriting systems you know so there's
you know you go to wikipedia there's
quite a few stream rewriting system okay
this is from wolfram so
um
math world is no good okay never never
never read anything from wolfram math
world website that's a
inc you know misleading bad information
okay never
never trust things on math word never
use it okay never use it wikipedia is uh
10 times better
so so you have rewriting in mathematics
computer science and logic rewriting
covers a wide range of uh
methods of replacing subterms of a
formula with other terms okay and so on
so you have you know anyway so
okay that's it for today
so who is this joshua buck
zeitgeist yes that's that was the word
you know that that's the word you know
describe
the thinking of each decade you know so
you know when you think about it
zeitgeist you know it's so it's kind of
um
it's somewhat strange in a sense because
today for example let's say us
you know we have certain opinions about
the world right we think you know in
fact we believe that actually it should
be this way this is the best way
you know just but but however then
but then you have the the word zyka
zeitgeist which means you know it
describes how
generations they actually have a
different style or way of seeing things
so that is a fact you know so you look
at history then you realize oh that
generation thinks something that way
then before that you know on all sorts
of things i'll say on slavery okay a
morality of slavery on ethics okay on
yeah variety and ethics on how you know
how you should treat you know certain
you know lots of things so each
generation and also different regions
they have different
perceptions okay so
so if you know that then then then
then you can ask yourself then then what
do you believe right now it's actually
you know maybe after 10 years you know
you'll generate your children
will actually think you are just wrong
you are just
you know but you you are
so into it
oh joshua is a success of marvin minsky
oh okay that's
no okay let lex friedman he's a biggest
idiot okay
i did a video on
on that on him on artificial
intelligence just search for my youtube
near the end 30 minutes okay on
artificial intelligence and in in
particular lex friedman i think he's the
biggest idiot
on youtube
talking about you know he tried he you
know he he you know he talked about
artificial intelligence he you know i
think he's the biggest idiot
okay that's interesting information
nico says no need for microsoft account
on windows 11 professional version okay
okay
okay i'm just going to go through the
comments and that's it for today
lee is my last name
is my first name dizziness
oh sorry yeah lee is my last name is my
first name yes so d is my family name
in chinese tradition you put your family
name first
so
you know that so you so you know in
western tradition you
put your first name first so i would be
exactly
but in chinese tradition you don't put
your first name first you put your
family
first
like how academia they you know
references they
they over they order the names okay so
family name first why because
you need to respect the elders that's a
chinese culture you know out your family
who have older people your family your
parents your ancestors they come before
you
not not you not not your individualism
that the american western thinking
individualism you know like like you are
you know we you know like teachers must
respect
uh students who don't know nothing but
what do you think you know
the independence the individuality or
the the
that's a western thing
so why am i mentioned you know why i'm
kind of making fun of it because okay
this
you know
each person you can have your your view
that's all right but however however
when you think
no view exists except your own
then that's bad okay that's what western
people are doing you know they think
you know they think
especially americans
you know they think oh you know
nothing you know
no other
theory exists is except their you know
western
thinking their brain
okay paul edward i need to counter your
argument i need to counter your counter
argument
[Laughter]
on open source okay paul paul edward
says
i know runs again is open source but i
disagree with the assessment
github red hat
etc
are all doing open source and ibm and
microsoft had to adopt or fall behind
it's great for open source programmers
so what do you mean it's great for open
source programmers how do you benefit
how do you benefit from open source when
microsoft
you know the giant corporations google
they own
your life essentially okay they control
everything when you write programs you
cannot sell you know there's no value
because they because they're open source
and controlled by them like you don't
have you know
so what do you mean it's great for open
source programmers
you mean you mean yeah okay so it's
great when you you can you can get
programs for free right like when you
are a team you can you know you can
download all the browsers are free
twitter is free facebook is free right
microsoft windows is free it comes with
every laptop that's what that's what you
mean by it's great
okay that's it
uh if you like my stuff pay me okay
donate patreon paypal
the thing about open source let me tell
you okay the thing about open source is
that if you truly believe it okay if you
are truly believe open source then
simply be
you know be integral to yourself do not
work
for any company
that
that you know cell proprietary code okay
stick with stick with your you know put
where your mouth is
you know so
you can you know in practice you cannot
do that if you do that you don't you
don't you don't get you don't get to
earn money you don't have food you don't
have food okay that's what happens
you know despite you know yeah
you know the only person who can do that
is this basically only one richard
stowman
he you know he become the one of the you
know indian guru
he just do nothing and you know there's
money coming to him because he's a he's
a god
okay bye guys
uh we
we didn't do actually we didn't do emac
this yeah that's disappointing we
because
uh
now it's almost uh i talked almost for
80 minutes now
we didn't do emac this
yeah and we didn't demo
okay yeah so today is mostly just rant
we didn't actually demo any of the find
replace code
so much rent
so
so yeah so i was showing for example i
was showing
so i was showing for example
the
yeah
the requests include okay let's magnify
so let's see
the requests include
uh dot html so in the emacs directory
actually go up
do it again
okay
and do it again this time
measure
so there are 2 500 html files in the
emac directory so let's say i want to
search for anywhere i mentioned haska
okay so let's just call it
let's do it
okay so let's say i want to replace the
word haskell by imagbeast okay so let's
do it
so call command you can see i'm coding
scifi and replace
in the pink window
so i call it and type pascal and replace
string will be elise okay and which
directory so directory will be that
html files h file path regular
expression yes html files request to
subdue
yes
right change to file no fixed case in
search yes fixed case in replacement yes
mark make backup yes okay so here is a
result
so you can see each the it
each of the red line is a file of
occurrence okay so you can see
so they are about you know there are
about 10 files that contains the word
haskell in my google emax
website okay so
for example so we you can you can just
press tab
press it to open the file and you can
see here is how where i mentioned
haskell john wagoy
haska okay so what was i talking about
so this is ximax blog 2014
november so search for
zhong
so i'm talking about some powerful
coders in emacs community who also
contributed to closure
so here are some of the great people
who has you know who are great emac list
coders and who also contributed to
closure you know the closure programming
language so they include phil haspel
work he's uh
also known as technomancy and he also
he's a creator of the keyboard
let me show you
let's talk random okay so he's also the
creator
of the keyboard
atrius okay he's the creator of this
keyboard and now it's sold by keyboard i
o in collaboration
okay so
um
phil's haggleberg
he is a you know all these people are
great emac visitors and steve purcell
he's well known he's a
most well known for as a maintainer
of melpa okay maintainer of melba by now
for 10 years and he is also known for uh
emacs init
what's the code what's it called there's
a emacs in it package you know
you know before even before melba
and
this guy basma
bass hit the bat so that's off this this
guy i mentioned mentioned he has a
insignia a batman you know he likes
he use he uses batman for us his logo or
something so he's a guy who are into
creating programming style guide
you know pretty fires you know he is
into he's very much into you know
programming style guide the most idiotic
you know
um and zhang
he's a haskar you know he's a he's a
compiler writer he's the ex you know he
imagines expert and compiler writer
expert because he as far as you know i
know that he been working as a compiler
writer for 10 years and he's in the past
since about five or ten years ago he
also started to become a haskell
coder in a day job and also a [ __ ]
called the [ __ ] is the math proof
assistant
so john gregory
so these people are great people you
know they you know i'm just blogging
back then 2014 i was doing closure they
also made great contributions to closure
and i also must add that christopher
wellens is
is a great is the greatest emac this
expert that i admire okay personally
among all these people i don't
you know the the emac this knowledge i
admire the most
that i've seen is christopher weylands
okay
so i respect that guy in particular
but i but i don't know i don't think he
does closure or haskell anyway so that
so that so i would i was demonstrating
the find package so you can see you can
jump to any uh occurrence or you can
jump to
any file okay so all these files
mentioned pascal
okay so that's how you do it you know
that's how you do it in uh emac this
song find replays okay and of course you
can also do it in powershell so how do
you do in powershell so let's go here so
we want to replace haskell by emaclees
right so
let's try
so
so the recurs include html then
then you want to for each
okay for each
actually i'm not good you know i don't
think i can do this in in um
in powershell like right off
because so
for so so this this percentage sign is a
alias for
for for each object okay so it's a
shortcut and gc is short for get content
okay
so you want to get content the file
then
then you want to um
yeah so i i don't think i can write it
in powershell right off the bat
something like that okay so you want to
get content
and
and replace
okay so yeah i don't i don't know
so let's go to powershell
tutorial
so powershell tutorial so let's go to
advanced string object string operators
so here is how you
do
replace strings string regular
expression replace okay
so
yeah so that's how you do so
so go back to powershell so you have to
that's an operator
that's a fine string
so you put find and replace strings
there so so you say haskell
and then you say emac lisp okay
so because directory include html files
for each object you get the content then
you replace haskell and replace by this
then you have to write it uh back to the
file so
so then
then you do that
then how do you write file is
out file okay read write file
there
there it is that's how you write a file
so this you know i don't want to run
this code it's dangerous because then
it's gonna replace all my but basically
this is how you do it in powershell okay
so let's
make it this into powershell mod okay so
watch the color so i'm gonna
so let's see hold on a second so
there it is
powershell mod you can buy with money
so how do you do that so okay so let's
let's clean up the code a little bit
the request includes for each object
wait why is this repeat
yeah so you need to copy that
yeah so this is what you do actually so
i believe this is the correct code so
so gc is get content okay let's see let
me show you the power of the
powershell mod so you can just say get
content press
completion you see
so get content
get content the current thing
replace haskell with emac this okay so
this uh let's put a string just
i don't think
i don't think you need the string but
because you automatically convert it to
string
i'm not sure
so you know i i
so
get content then i'll put on right file
so i think that's how you do it okay now
let's
let's try if this works okay so but you
know and
this is new for me i'm in powershell so
this is how you do find and replace in
powershell okay but now let's i don't
want to change to the whole directory i
just want to limit it to
one file okay so let's go back to emacs
let's find
let's find where the occurrence okay so
this page has one occurrence of the
of the haskell world
so
so let's modify the code
so and modify the code so we only
include this this page only okay
so you can see
so that's the line go back to powershell
cancel paste it here so let's see if you
know we just want that file
there it is okay
now
okay now we now we pipe it then we for
each object we get content replace
haskell by emac list then we pipe it to
output out file
uh all file uh okay so
yeah so here we can just uh we can just
do
all file dot full name
okay
um
this this will be the full path
basically overwriting the
original you know overwriting these
files
so i believe that's the code
so with new no no new line so let's try
this should be should replace that one
single file let's try it
i hope i didn't screw up you know i what
you know let's just do it okay
okay get content parameter cannot be
found that match is parameter replaced
yeah okay so
uh
oh yeah so yeah so get content you know
put in put them into a parenthesis okay
do it again
done now let's look at the file let's
see if it
changed or not okay
does not exist okay so wait
so where is this file okay so we need
the full path
okay let's open
it it did it indeed it changed the file
oh yeah because i said no new line so it
[ __ ] up the whole thing
okay so now we you know
but let's see if it uh
let's see if it uh change the head scar
so let's search for
zhang
there it is you see it changed it worked
okay but now let's go back let's revert
okay so
let's start ishow
now get now this is the power of the
unix philosophy kit kit is the last tool
of the
unix philosophy
style
so git
checkout
so we are reverting to an old version
update open there it is so we are back
to the file you see haskell
now we can do the change again but this
time
you know so let's say
clear
okay this time don't say no new line you
want the new line okay
and
do it
okay
you see it's changed emacs automatically
revert it but
okay let's
revert again
you see now it's back to haskell okay we
we are just doing random concurrent
users two
six
okay that's it
i'm tired you guys are tired bye guys
yeah i'm just i started to do some
random and also i wanted to show you go
lan code
when why not let's just continue this
why not
so go land so let's let's run the goal
line go line
find and replace okay so
so here is the here is my golan code for
find replace
it's
180 lines actually just 100 lines
because i you know these are
some files i want to replace
specifically specifically just for these
files again right now i'm showing you a
advantage over the traditional grip or
whatever because here i can specify
a exact list of files
you know if you use grep or somewhere
some of it
some of its replacement such as arc or
silver or whatever
i believe it's also possible to specify
a list of
lists of specific files
but
but then you have to put them in your
file you know
so anyway so
let's do this
so you you want to yeah so
so here we are doing something so
you want to find
pascal
replaced by elise okay
and in what directory
okay in the emacs directory in in this
directory okay hold on second
paste that
there it is so in that directory and
actually
i don't want to change everything in
that directory in fact just like we did
before i want just
i want it to happen only on this
specific file okay do it
okay so only on this
specific file now first we'll open the
file so you can see it says haskell okay
close the file now we're gonna run the
code this is scolan
you can see the find string and replace
string and in fact you can have several
pairs again this is another advantage
over the traditional grab or silver or
whatever you see because i can have
several pairs in one shot i can have you
know i can have you know replace
replace python by emac this replace you
know um
ruby but you know i can have several
find and replace pairs in one shot and
also they can also be regular expression
anyway do it
okay done so you can okay and here is
another power this now here is a
separate issue this is the power of
using e-max as a wrapper to this find
replace
uh applications because
you see now i have highlight i can jump
to it you know so this only one file
change usually there's a lot so you can
you can jump directly to the file okay
again go to it
wait
now in this case
anyway so i go to it you can see
there it is it changed okay
so can we undo here no because the file
was not open so anyway so
back to
isha
run the git checkout to revert it okay
close it now it's back to haskell
fantastic
because that so that's a demonstration
we saw we demonstrated emac this find
replace we demonstrated powershell find
replace
okay that single line
we demonstrated
land find find and replace 150 lines
okay
now there's you know find replays to me
so it's fine replaces to me very
interesting you know it's kind of
what i do for the past 15 years
so uh find replace you see now we can
see
actually i need also i also need to show
you a power version in python version
which is pretty similar okay so so the
purple version is right here okay
so let me show you
uh dot pl so
find replace pearl
so here is my pearl code
this code is written in year 2000
so you can see this is my first
yeah this is my first find replace code
written in year 2000 back then i was a
professional pearl coder working in
in dot-com you know we wrote server you
know we
we wrote the first online
e-store engine
and we sell it to verizon
you know the big you know the big uh
host so anyway so here's my pro code
that does find replace written in year
then there's a python one
so here is the python three one yeah
python three there's a plain text
version there's a regular expression
version so here is the python version
and as i showed this all the
code is all on my website
okay so now but there is an interesting
you know after writing all these find
replays in different languages then you
you can uh have an interesting sense you
know of a programming language you know
so
in powershell you see it's just one
single line you know so so powershell so
where's our code
so in powershell you see it's very
interesting okay so where is it yeah so
it's what this one single line now if
you don't want i mean you can you can
actually um
so you consider that you know four lines
okay
uh actually
so this this should be actually over
here kind of
sure you know let's you know traditional
format any anyway so in powershell it's
like four lines
but in gold land
emac this
python uh perl each you know these like
150 lines so
so powershell is very
you know i didn't want to learn xiao i
don't like i didn't want to learn sha
because i'm i have the idea of one
language for everything so um
but it turns out powershell is actually
just the most efficient for the for this
task because only three lines
okay
bye guys
the last question do you can do you
recommend configure just emacs or space
max for the jungle or python i don't i
don't really know because i don't i
haven't done jungle python development
yeah so the question is about emacs and
space max that really depends on you
yeah okay this is a real end
by so we covered
we covered um
[Music]
we demonstrated emac list
find replays go land find replace
powershelf and replace
anyway interesting stuff