Good morning boys and girls. Good
morning and good evening. Good morning
and good evening. Good morning and good
evening. Good morning and good evening
boys and girls. We are live. This is
talk show you are watching. And today
there's no schedule. There's this
random. This is office hours. So, you're
just going to watch me, an old man,
drink a little bit and I'm going to work
on my stuff, technicality and nerd
stuff. Advanced, very advanced nerd
stuff. Okay. So, show my uh show my
window. Let me tell you about this
keyboard. This is UHK80.
UHK stand for ultimate hacking keyboard.
80. Okay. Fantastic. So, search my
YouTube, you'll find my reviews. In
fact, I have the world's biggest
keyboard blog in the world. Okay. Uh, so
you just search for XA keyboard blog.
There are 1,000 videos. I mean the there
are 10,000 articles about everything
possibly you ever wanted to know about
keyboard, about mouse, about keyboard
layout, about key switch technology,
about the keyboard technology itself.
Um, and about uh mouse and track
everything. Okay, there's 1,000 articles
in it. So again, today I'm just going to
talk random. Okay, I'm just like
randomly working on my website and uh
like get 50% drunk actually 30% drunk.
Okay, that is the goal. That is the
purpose of this video. So if you are
this, if you are watching here, say hi.
Uh this is chat session. If you are
watching offline, play at 1.5 speed or
two. Okay, that's my discord. You are
watching. Can you see me? Yeah. Yes.
Video check, audio check, and uh my
Twitter. Oh, oh, you know, in the past
few days, we've been coding this woo fam
language uh animation truck hypotcoid.
It's amazing and beautiful. So,
yesterday, so ye yesterday we did a
video well in fact several, you know,
yesterday, the day before. So, we did,
you know, in past week or two, we did a
lot wam language um coding.
Now if you watched it yesterday it was
like 90 minutes you know kind of boring
but the result but then I worked on it
again. So the result is beautiful. So
let's uh for example let me show you
a number of frames 80. So this is going
to generate a bunch of this uh rolling
of a circle around another circle.
Beautiful. Okay. Fantastic. I mean the
the the key about this thing is not just
the graphics of course but the key why
is it beautiful? Well, the geometry, the
mathematics is beautiful because this
charco
uh anyway there's lots of interesting
stories, okay, about the spiral graph.
But I mean, but but but
besides that, the beauty is this code.
You see that mathematics and humanity we
have to this day we have this
which is called technology allows us you
know which includes type setting you see
rationalize numerator denomin
denominator that's mathematics and here
you also see pi that's advanced science
you know that's the deepest math
mathematics ever you you can get PhD for
20 years studying being of pi. Okay. And
then the fraction and you know so this
part and this the code the programming
language design. So the whole thing is
just amazing. That's what I that's what
I love. Okay. That's what I do for life.
So we improved the code a lot. Now we
brought back. So I wrote this originally
30 years ago and it turns out you know
I'm I'm quite meticulous when it comes
to like function parameters design. So
it turns out my design back then 30
years ago is pretty good.
So yesterday I I was trying to uh change
some of it but actually uh my design
yesterday is pretty good. Hello analytic
minded. So any questions you have for
me? Where are you from and uh age sex
location?
[laughter]
you know age six location that's the
most
common desired
question of human animals every human
animal when you see another like
starting with the online internet age
you know like before internet you see
when when you see other human animal you
see it in face real life right or
photograph right photograph is not
interactive but when you interact when
when you interact with another human
animal you interact via in real life
that is before internet. But beginning
with internet starting like 199 1990s
you started to have this internet
and when you interact with another human
animal you no longer like you know it's
not face to face you have this internet
you type you know you email you know in
the beginning it was email you type
messages then you have instant messages
like you know this chat you know you can
you know this is like 20 30 years of
evolution
evolution. I can tell you actually in
detail the history of internet because
I'm you know old enough to I lived
through it. back in. So, so in the
beginning you you know the as far as
internet communication technology goes
in the beginning you got email then you
got email is kind of like the uh like
the most essential the for the first
okay but anyway roughly you got email
then you got
inst instant messaging uh came around
like late 19
90s let's say year 2000 okay in you
started to have instant messaging, Yahoo
chat. Then before that you have um you
have uh computer like online message
forums. Well you before that you have
usernet which is like you post messages
to online but it's not internet. Okay.
It's not like website website. Okay. But
anyway,
so you post messages to you can exchange
messages online and other people will
read it usually after a day or after
several hours. Uh then they will
respond. So every time every day you
wake up, you you you you go to the
online forum whatever it was. It's not a
website though but like news group you
know anyway but it's just basically just
like online web kind of like the essence
is the messages you post a message you
ask maybe questions or something then uh
after a few hours or usually or tomorrow
people will answer or chat you can chat
you know random so so that's like 1990s
then uh in year 2000 you started to have
instant messaging that like Yahoo a AOL
chat. Hello guys. Um you know Yahoo and
AOL and then um you know Apple has its
own later but then so instant messaging
like like like the YouTube chat box.
Okay. So you can chat instantaneously
with your friends or co-workers. Then
you started to have like video like tiny
video screen uh instant video like you
can talk to your grandma but but then
you need to oh you know like what
version do I have you need to you go to
MSN video you know there's lots of
problems but still you started to have
video chat like in the early year 2000s
okay
then you start to have a quote of course
Wikipedia around 2002, Facebook 2003
something there you started to have this
social media Facebook 2003 2004 then
that Reddit uh Reddit you know hacker
news is online you know then okay and
sometimes if before that you started to
have online forums which is which is
like you go to a website website where
you um post message messages for example
there's a hacker keyboard uh website But
what's the name of that um
hacker keyboard? That's uh wait, what's
the name of that um
website? [ __ ] [ __ ] I don't even
remember. Hack geek hack. Okay, so gig
hack is one of the this this
website this
format is kind of the online forum. what
you call online forum where you go there
post messages messages are categorized
by thread. So let's let's turn on uh
JavaScript.
Okay. So, so anyway, but this website,
Geek Hack, is mostly about keyboards,
which I've been uh nerding for like over
15, actually 30 years since like 1993
before anyone else, you know, like back
in 1992,
I learned about the Vora keyboard
layout. Most people don't know, you
know, today you guys know, right? But so
in 1992 I I read it from a book then I
created there's no like you can't switch
to vorac keyboard layout like there's no
such thing. So I created the use the
rest edit on Apple
I told the story before. So there is
this restedit thing which is a um well
no not those you know they they [ __ ]
idiots rest edit Apple
uh Mac
you see yeah it looks like that okay so
this is 1992
there's application called restedit you
can use it to create like small
applications on the Mac so I used it to
create the vorac keyboard layout. So I
started to learn vorac layout in 1994.
So by 1994 end of it I master va layout
typist. So I've been obsessed with
keyboard because why? Because uh it's
just far more efficient. Okay, let me
finish the drink and get some more. Uh
so we what we were talking So yeah, we
were talking about the internet history.
So I was like trying to give you a quick
overview of internet history. So 1990.
So email first then instant messaging
well email first then um then use use
user group uh use group usernet
which is posting messages and the
computer
similar basically you call them online
forums that's a purpose. Okay. Then in
2000 year 2000 you got you started to
have instant messaging. Then year two
year 2002 Wikipedia social you know
Facebook began 2003 and you also started
to have a lot of in uh online forums
which is just messages and you and then
sometimes before that you started to
have so-called mailing list. Mailing
list is like online forum just like you
know you go to a website post specific
topic you know but it's like in email
via the email format. So every day you
compose an email send it to a specific
address. Let's let's say talking about
keyboards or talking about computers or
talking about programming language or
talking about play playing piano or
talking about sex like what what can
where can I find local sex club you know
there are things like that BDSM you know
this all kind of things okay so so this
mailing list you know so you send an
email and you and you'll get reply so
you can see all the people's post but
all via email so every day you got a
bunch of emails. So that's called
mailing list. For example, Python
mailing list still still exist. Python
mailing list. Okay, I'm not sure you
guys zoomers still know what that is
about. So for example, Python mailing
list. You go there. So you can see
mailing list. Python mailing list and
good news. [ __ ] Python. [ __ ] this Python
[ __ ]
You know, of course, I'm famous for I
had a lot of fights with these people,
especially like some of these admins
like they are the
uh priests,
you know, they sit on this mailing list.
They ban people, they control what you
can say, what you cannot say, things
like that. And of course, I've been
banned in many places. So, you have
mailing list is part of internet
technology. Then let's say around 2007
2008 you started to have iPhone Apple.
That's a tremendous innovation. That's a
change of humanity by Steve Jobs. Okay.
That's incredible. That's the you know
communication technology that basically
changed everything because from that day
on you begin you know not that day but
you begin to have the idea that every
person carries in their pocket a small
computer that can take photos that can
record videos that can talk to anyone in
the world in video in voice okay that's
Steve Jobs
incredible guy Now Steve Job Jobs passed
away in 2010 or so and then uh then then
the web become the Apple become [ __ ]
Okay. Apple become a scum. Apple become
idiotic but and scum or too. Okay. Uh
anyway so
so I have like 10,000 articles on my
website because you know I've been
blogging for like 30 years. So, you
know, these stories I've been told uh
quite a few times. Steve Jobs, the death
of sk Steve Jobs, Steve Jobs, and story
with Donald Groo. I I I told this story
a few times. Okay, so this article is
death of Steve Jobs versus Denise
Richie, a [ __ ] of the Unix [ __ ]
and with a Unix [ __ ] people. I
despise them. Okay, it's a story. Okay,
it's like a story around year 2010, I
mean 2011.
And then this is the day Steve Job died.
I recall I made a record a history
account of history. So this when when
Steve Job died on that day, Apple made a
record of it on their website. So I I
made a screenshot. Okay. Then Google
also did you know Steve Job actually is
one of the person there are quite there
are a few people like five 305 I have
admired and studied
quite a lot. Okay Steve Job is one of
them. I very much admire this guy and
one of the other guys Stefan Wuan
actually and another and also Bertron
Russell.
Okay, I'm gonna I think I'm gonna get
some drink. Um, so I mean like so
there's a lot to talk to, you know, I I
can I can start to talk nonstop for for,
you know, for a few hours. Then there's
Richard Storman whose comment on Steve
Jobs death, you know, he says he says,
"I'm glad he's dead." Something like
that. You know, Steve, you know, like
I'm not glad he's dead, but I'm glad
he's gone. Richard Stman and ever since
he made this comment a lot of people got
pissed. The the white people typically
the like the white people they are fan
of Richard Stoman free software
foundation they are donate donating
members then then then they started to
claim oh you know I I I stopped being a
member of free software foundation
because they so you know they got pissed
by this uh Richard Stman's remark. Okay.
Anyway, that's humanity. Okay. Lots of
drama, you know. Uh then uh for some
good, some bad. Then Steve Job, this is
Steve Jobs three months before he died.
We don't know he's going to die, but you
know, Steve Jobs, that's when he's
building the the the circular UFO
building for Apple.
Uh this is then here's uh here is uh
some photos I took in 2001 when Steve
Jobs started to have the idea the crazy
idea he's going to start brick and motor
stores
you know 2001
that's the beginning of internet you
know Amazon eBay are thriving and Google
and the idea is that brick and mortar
stores so-called is all going to die.
They're going to disappear.
You know, it's like all going to be
because internet is going to the future.
Internet is going to taking over which
actually is true to some to some degree
though. But so anyway, that was the
thought. But then Steve Jobs come along.
He says, "No, I'm going to start Apple
store, brick and mortar store, you know,
all over." So that's when Apple store
began in 2001. So I went with my friend,
uh, Brian Nakamoto. He's a fan of Apple,
too. Uh, so we, you know, so we, you
know, we went to the first store in Palo
Alto and we took photo and, you know,
Steve Jobs is there. Um, some of the
photo so photos are by my friends. Some
of the photos are by me, you know. Um,
anyway, that's 2001. Steve Jobs. Okay.
This is Palato. Palatoto is a rich city
near where I I'm in Mountain View. I'm
where Google is at. Okay. I'm where
Google Plex is at. So, Palato is where
Stanford University is at. Palo Auto is
basically rich man's city like you got
to be pretty rich you know uh like
usually people pretty rich lives there
okay let me finish this and get some
more and let me read the comments okay
uh actually there's a comment quite
early here yeah here so I don't have
time to even drink I need to finish my
drink
and Analytic minded says, "Have you ever
considered writing in markdown and
compiling to HTML instead of coding HTML
directly?" Of course, I have considered
that.
But but the such idea quickly um is
thrown thrown out thrown out. Okay.
Because with
I mean not it's you know but personally
for me I've been coding HTML since HTML
was born. HTML was born in like 1991 I
coded manually character by character in
a in Microsoft world.
So I know every aspect like every detail
like before JavaScript was born before
CSS was born I watched their birth just
like you guys are watching the birth of
AI you know oh there is a chachbd
happened you know what they do what who
created it what's going on you know like
when you watch the birth of some
technology in your life like the the day
one since the day one oh you know then
you know you know everything about it so
I watched the birth of HTML and internet
and then uh JavaScript and CSS right so
I know every I know every character then
then then the the okay so you are
talking about markdown markdown is so
called the markdown is by the scum by a
kind of like not exactly a scum but it's
like an [ __ ] okay the proper word for
that guy is [ __ ] the creator of
markdown you know markdown is one of the
markup You know the like people are
crazy. Everyone is trying to create a a
uh
everyone is trying to create a light
lightweight mark up language other than
HTML because HTML you know it's like too
much to type and unreadable you know
like uh like bracket you know less than
equal sign bracket p then then bracket
then slash less than equals you know too
much for most. So lots of people are
creating their own version of like um
lightweight markup in competition you
know for example there's BB BB um BB
code okay this quite a lot BB code
you guys probably don't know BB code but
you forgot but at one time it was the
most popular markup for the web okay BB
code and I actually have a emac this
package for it. Anyway, this is this
like turns, okay? Because everyone
because you you create this light uh
lightweight markup, you become famous
because you know, oh, oh, that you know
in history, you know, my name is in
history because I created that, you
know, because everyone is using it, you
know, like the markdown guy, the clock
face, the markdown, his name is what's
his name? He's a [ __ ] Okay.
Let me tell you, let me tell you the
story. Daring fireball. The daring
fireball my ass. You know this. He's
like he's he he's a guy in the era of
blogging, you know, like. So the era of
blogging is around, you know, maybe 2006
to let's say 2008 to 2015
something like that. It died when Google
killed the Google reader. Okay. So
there's a lot history. You guys may or
may not know. So I don't know how how
old are you.
So blogging lasted for like 10 years.
Blogging like you know you need to blog.
We blog is the future. Every person
should blog. So during the blog era he's
very famous. This staring fireball
[ __ ] He's he's you know this guy
this character is an [ __ ] like me.
kind of like me because we um you know
we we don't we don't kiss ass we don't
ask you know we are not polite we don't
kiss ass other people we say what we
want or today you guys will say uh based
based [laughter]
idiots based zoom will say based okay so
anyway this guy so what's his name
markdown so John guaba
he's one of the very popular during the
blogging era ve very one of the most
famous uh blogger. Okay. Actually, I
never know, you know, I I I I don't read
him much. Okay. So, okay. So, he looks
like that. So, anyway, he's a kind of
[ __ ] Okay. Among, you know, there's
quite a few. There's also Dave Winer.
Dave Dave Winer, which I despise SCA,
I don't have problem with him, you know.
I don't have much, you know. I don't
know. I don't actually don't know him
much.
work worked for barebones software. Oh,
okay. Interesting.
Cheers.
Oh, in 2004, Aaron Schwartz and Gubber
worked together to create the markdown
language. Aaron Schwartz is another
huge [ __ ]
If you guys don't know, okay, let me
tell you guys. Aaron Schrods the guy he
got killed by deep state. Very complex
story. Okay. He he he got killed
by deep state. What is a deep state?
Deep state today is doing lots of
things around certain area. Let's not
talk. Well, it's getting very
complicated.
Let me tell you. Okay. So what? So deep
state is doing war of course. What does
it mean? Oh [ __ ]
Mountain view. Okay. That's where I
live. Okay. So let's go to um
why does it uh
it's Google? Okay. Where I I live. So
there's a computer museum right there.
That's that's very close to where I
live. And Google is right here. Google.
Okay. But anyway, we wanted to go to um
we wanted to go to Oh, yeah. So, we want
to go show the Earth
more globe view. Okay.
And the satellite.
So, you show the Earth. Then, uh what is
deep state? Well, deep state is doing
something
in this region today. So that's Japan,
that's Korea, that's China, that's you
know then then then you you got India
big uh big India here then you got uh
then you got this uh this this these
places they got oil you see this yellow
colored places they got oil they they
pretty rich okay and the deep state is
doing things there. Okay. In this region
for the past like 20 years,
that's what deep state is. Okay. So,
Aaron Schrods,
he got killed by deep state because
apparently he's like talking to Wikip
uh Wikileaks
something. Okay.
Then anyway, Aaron Schro is an [ __ ]
the personality is he's known as [ __ ]
and the m John gober is also [ __ ]
because
because then there is another guy who um
the creator of the um
stack overflow they were trying to
standardize
the markdown and he John gober refused
you know he's he's saying no no no we
don't need any standardization
Markdown is just markdown. Let it be.
You know, let all flower spoon. We don't
want I don't want no [ __ ]
standardization. And you don't use my
name markdown for it. Okay? You can go
[ __ ] yourself and standardize. Call it
whatever you want, but don't call it
markdown because I John Gber created
Markdown and I don't want it
standardized.
That's this [ __ ] face. That's why he's
[ __ ] create a big you know big uh
controversy
anyway
so Aaron shots okay so you know I I
don't know him anyway I don't know him
much so the Aaron shots is also [ __ ]
and he's like doing things um
anyway so
so what he so markdown you know markdown
is like you know like so simple you know
so of course I got a tutorial for MDA.
Um,
let's see.
Donald Guth, Steve Jobs, and the idiocy
of typography. Okay, Steve Jobs. Did we
finish talking about Steve Jobs? So,
let's uh let's go to um
Okay, let's go to uh keyboard.
Uh what what are we going to talk about
today? Yeah, we were talking about
markdown. Yeah. Okay. So, markdown.
Oh, so I have an article. [ __ ] markdown.
So, there is markdown tutorial and there
is my Emacs Emacs markdown to HTML. So,
that's Emac Lisp code that turns
markdown to HTML.
We actually we did several live stream
about it. So, we talked about uh
markdown for several hours last year.
Okay. few three month ago. Two month
three month ago. Okay. December, you
know, episode 705, 715 and 716. We tal
we were talking about. Yeah. We were
creating um
markdown to HTML and HTML to markdown.
Okay. All kind of technicalities about
that. uh because you want it to be
efficient, you want to be robust, but
you also want it to be like is there a
standard markdown? It turns out well no
because well part of the reason is the
guy John Guaba refused to allow a
standardized one you know because he's
got you know he's got opinions. So
anyway the so one you know John Grober
is the one of the star of the blogger
blogging era which died then we were
talking about the deep state they are
doing
killings okay that's basically killings
you you don't know you don't care
because it doesn't affect you you see
because you most of you are American
like me you know we are we have comfy
life so someone else dies that's their
problem.
That's a situation. Okay, now let me get
some more drink.
Seven concurrent viewers. Okay, so for
those of you guys are watching, say hi.
Don't be shy. You should like say hi.
You know what one of the problem with
today's rumors is that everyone is
afraid. Everyone is a nonfox. a nonf
fox,
you know, known as a non coward, you
know, because you guys don't dare
to have a face. You guys don't dare, you
know, I'm not going to do that. I'm just
gonna, you know, cower in my little
corner and do, you know, go I gonna
create accounts and say things and, you
know, do whatever and do Bitcoin and do
crypto, you know, I'm just but I'm not
going to say anything about oh
something, but I'm going to try I'm
going to do Pepe, but I'm going to be a
non. I'm going to post Pepe stuff and
you know I'm going to talk but you know
that's that's you guys are all these cow
[ __ ] that that creates
collapse the collapse of society. Okay,
that's you Zuma idiots.
Okay, let me get my drink.
Okay, so the question,
have you ever considered writing in
markdown and compiling to HTML? Okay, I
guess I already answered that question
because in the process I mentioned about
where is it? Uh in the process I
mentioned, you know, I actually did
three live streams about markdown. So
you can watch that. Uh
you know, so so I grew up with HTML, you
know, in Emacs. I have so many commands
uh you know of my own device that I can
you know to create the same web page if
someone is using markdown or or mode you
know they they they generate then you
know they can convert to HTML then they
publish as like the static website using
the
haido or whatever that's oxo haido oxo I
always forgot the
Um
what's the name for generating static
website? What's the
popular software? They they there are a
handful. Hiko or something Jacko or
something like people people were
telling me every day like five years ago
have you used it? Have you used the Hugo
yet? Have have you do you think about
Hugo? like people were telling me every
day.
Hugo. Yeah. And the Jacko Jacko, you
know, those are white man things. Okay.
There's a story about them. Uh Jacko and
Hugo. Uh but I always forgot. So people
were telling me. So you can So a lot of
people,
you know, younger people, you you can do
that. No problem. I don't have a problem
with that. So you can write your you can
write a blog if you want to or your
notes in oak mode or you can write in
markdown. Markdown is becoming very
popular you know because Microsoft for
example Microsoft
almost you know Microsoft.NET
that's a that's a huge coding project.
It's all open source and every
documentation by Microsoft today is in
markdown. Okay. I learned that about two
years ago because you know when I was
doing research so you might watch my you
know this my live streams about
markdown. So Microsoft.NET
and I think every other Microsoft
documentation like the entire Microsoft
technology documentation is in markdown.
Okay. and their their doc has become
very good in the past five years also
become very good for example powershell
f you know for example I've been
learning you know doing powershell and
I've been doing powershell like for by
now 10 years I've been learning f too so
anyway so
so
for you guys you can write in markdown
or you can write in oak mode which is
very popular for emac users
Okay. And then you can generate you can
convert it to HTML. Then you can post to
the website using one of these Jacko or
Hugo whatever [ __ ] you know I don't give
a [ __ ] about them. Jacko or Hugo you
know they are like they generate static
websites. Okay you can do that. But here
is my claim. Me working in Emacs with
HTML mode. Um,
okay. With Kasar HTML mode, my mode for
HTML and all my bunch of my things, all
these Casar packages, I can code exactly
the same thing as your website, but less
keystrokes.
Okay, less number of keystrokes
when I do raw HTML and raw JavaScript.
and raw CSS
exactly the same thing you do but I type
less keystrokes and I have more powerful
more flexibility
even we if we created exactly the same
thing okay uh you know the entire you
know for example my CSS is entire
manually crafted because [laughter]
because I watched their birth you the
CSS, you know, in the beginning like
should we have a styling sheet, you
know, versus the controversy. Should we
have like CSS style versus like embedded
font tag, you know, which one is better,
you know, debate, big debate and drama
and then this or that.
Okay. So I code the same thing in my
HTML and my customized HTML eac code
whatever and softly keys of course not
to forget soft fly keys the most
efficient possible keybinding system in
the universe
not just on earth but in the universe
okay then vim or neoim or what whatever
[ __ ]
most of you know measured by science not
by oh I feel I feel by the Way guys I
feel Microsoft like key is is faster
than Vim. No by science meaning you
measure keystrokes you do massive like
thousand you know test cases
[laughter]
and stuff like keys is going to be less
number of keystrokes. Counting you you
know you measure control super old you
know you you have to count them like how
do you score them? Okay that is my
claim.
Okay. So, I'm uh right now 20% drunk.
Okay. Not too much, but let's
have more.
So, maybe I I think I answered that
question. Have you ever considered
writing in markdown and compiling to
HTML? Yeah, I considered it. But uh but
that's not my you know I wouldn't do
that because each person is different
for my past experiences
uh doing that would not it would be
worse you know
but for you guys it depends okay so for
you guys you know you might it's a good
you know it's a good option
of course you can also do like me you
you know, start from scratch, you know,
just write your e your your own HTML
mode or whatever manually do HTML, but
um
may not be better because first of all,
you have to you really have to, you
know, if you want to do, you know, the
thing like the way I do, of course, you
can buy my packages, you know, actually
actually you can do that. Um, you know,
you go to my website
Emacs, for example, Emacs, uh,
you know, I have like close to 1,000
pages about Emacs. Saw Emacs packages,
you can actually pay me and get all of
them like $400 or something.
But you know but but even if you do that
you are not going to be like me because
what you need is uh because I know I
have the knowledge about
you see I have deep knowledge about HTML
about CSS about JavaScript
you know JavaScript you may not care if
you don't care for your website to be an
app but you need you really need to know
HTML ML and CSS well okay very well like
master which is not difficult you you
know it takes you a month you know it
takes HTML is easy to learn CSS is easy
to learn you can learn both of them in a
week okay but the key is like if you
really like master especially about CSS
the nuances then it's a matter of like
one year or two year or more it it it
never ends because see it's still
changing
but anyway my point is that you can
be expert of HTML and CSS and it's not
too difficult okay few months you know
half a year let's say don't worry about
you know you might think oh half year is
long time not really you're going to you
you know you're going to have 10 five
years more 10 years in your life to do
coding so is coding your career here,
you know, so you're going to have, you
know, don't worry about five months, you
know. So, you can master HTML, C and
CSS, okay? So, if you want to be do the
way I do things,
you you have to be like kind of expert
at HTML and CSS like like the way they
work and things like that. You have
fairly very good idea how they work.
Okay, you you can be what you cannot be
is like the Zuma idiots like today the
Zuma idiots they don't even know what
see how exactly CSS works you know they
just you know if you want to do this
download you know npm this type this npm
you you know you kind of this you know
these things okay like the today's
Zumant generation idiots they don't know
how things book.
So again, if you want to do like me
everything from scratch, you you kind of
have you have to have good knowledge of
HTML and CSS.
Uh
I remember mailing lists. Boy, how they
clogged up the inbox. Yeah. You hate
Linux, Vim, and Python. Uh, and all the
things like I like what?
You hate Linux, Vim, Python, all things
I like. Uh, okay.
Uh, yeah. Well, that's that's like one
perspective. Okay. That's just like
that's kind of just one view.
Uh but in fact I may like a lot of
things you like.
Uh but actually you see
Linux, Vim, Python, they are all
technology first of all. So in other way
in other words what interpretation of
what you said is that we are already
very much alike. You see this you [ __ ]
it. You know like you are now [ __ ] it.
What? Whatever your name means. You see,
you hate you, you know, you say you hate
Linux, Vim and Python, all things I
like. That's kind of true. That's true.
Do I hate Linux? Yes, very much. I hate
Do I hate Vim? Well, yes, because Vim is
the Unix
crime. One of the Unix crime. VI. Okay.
Then people created Vim and you know new
vim. But it's a VI is idiot. Bren Unix
[ __ ] Okay. And the Python the G van
Russen the one of the most worst worst
language is Python. Okay. In my opinion
even I think PHP
uh is better language. Anyway they are
al they are also they are bad in
different ways but but Python you got
this leader this pre priest Gavan Rossam
the creator of Python. He's a He is um I
would say a idiot and not a good person.
He's promoting the social justice
warriors, you know, during the SJW era.
Okay. He's like, "Oh, I'm not going to
teach male. From now on, I'm just going
to teach women because I think women are
[laughter]
something something
gan fuckheads." That's his social deeds.
But also his language is just [ __ ] [ __ ]
in almost every way. Python. Okay. Now
you like Python. Well, you know, so so
first of all, you you you know, you you
like these, you hate these. You know, I
hate these things, but you like them. So
seems like we are very different. But
actually
another interpretation,
we are very much alike. Actually already
we are like both extreme nerds. Okay.
And also
you see any anyway so you know I'm just
rambling uh random.
Okay, I think maybe I should go in I
mean I I I think um how long has this
been going on? 1 hour. So maybe it's
time to stop. Let me finish my drink.
Okay. Steve Jobs was a great visionary
but was a terrible colleague. I heard
he's an [ __ ]
you know. So see just you know a lot
great men
are [ __ ] Not necessarily every great
great men must be [ __ ] but a lot of
them are. Okay. So Steve Jobs is an
[ __ ]
What what does it mean exactly? meaning
that he you know you if you work with
him some people you know including John
Grober and and quite a few okay [ __ ]
and including the guy who created the
Ruby on rails you know quite a lot of
them they they are [ __ ] they are cocky
you know they and and almost always they
are males females are not like that
women are different thing okay women
don't you know they they they They they
they they they are not [ __ ] That's why
women colloquially
in English we say girls are chicks. You
know the guys are dude or [ __ ] Okay.
So anyway a lot great men
are just [ __ ] Okay. So Steve Jobs
is one of the [ __ ] you know because
you know you work with him he's gonna
you know he doesn't respect you or
something something bad. you know there
some things things like that. Okay. Or
they scored you know they scored their
underlings you know they they scored
their whatever
analyticminded says I'm from the mid
1980s so fortunately not a zoomer. Oh so
you are like um you are even older
generation than me possibly. I see. You
see I cannot tell you know like like
these days you know
um like YouTube everything is
everybody's announce so so even you guys
like some of you analytic minded you've
been on my channel you know you've been
com commenting in the past I don't know
who you are like I have like
like I don't I can't like remember like
what what exactly you said in the past
and also there's a lot others right so
that's one of the issue with the live
stream
exacerbated by the anon because you see
if you if you guys I'm not saying you
must okay but let's suppose if if you
guys your name is like Frank Frank Joe
or something like a real life name and
you come with a face
then do I like even though I still have
a lots of comments you know from random
people but I'm more likely the the
likelihood that I take you seriously and
know who you are and we establish
friendship is much higher much higher
okay so but you know but given the
situation which which is partly due to
the deep state so everyone is like a non
box like I don't know who you guys are
that's you know That's really announce
really nasty problem and that's the you
see they designed it this way. They want
you know these deep state people they
want America they want it that way.
That's by design you know but but the
Zuma idiots they don't you know they
they don't know they they thought they
are you know they thought they are being
like rebels. Look, you see, you see, I'm
doing great because I, you know, the
deep state going to try to [ __ ] me, but
I'm a non. They don't know who I am, you
know. So, I'm doing so great, you know.
I watch, you know, I watch the uh Black
Poss
talk show, you know. I'm I know what's
going on. But these are the idiots. You
see, the deep state love you to be in
this state. That's what the deep state
want.
This anom the zoomer generation I truly
despise. Okay. Zuma [ __ ]
Hello GCS. Okay. Um so 1980s. Yeah. So
you see I didn't start programming even
uh until like 1993.
So I'm kind of late. By 1993 I'm already
20 like 21.
Um,
not everyone lives in a free speech
country. That's a Okay, that's valid,
but that's a different, you know, that's
different story. Okay,
so user says, "Yo, I think you could get
big as a live streamer. You just got to
advertise better, do some short
highlights, better title, better
thumbnails. You could make good money."
Yeah.
I heard of that. Uh but you know in
order to do that
for me
it's you know it's just not happening.
Uh because
first of all
first of all I really despise you see
when I see when I go when I see this
YouTube with the [ __ ] thumbnails you
know like oh something crazy or or or
the clickbaits I despise them. I don't
want to do that.
So that put me in odds with making money
because that's what kind of that's what
deep state wants. Okay.
Uh then the other thing is that I'm I'm
an [ __ ] just like many of the other
people I talked about.
So if you want to make money, you don't
want to be [ __ ] You want to be
polite. You want to say, "Oh, thank you.
That's a great idea." You know that, you
know, you you you want to make people
that because that's a that's fundamental
human communication. People perceive you
to be,
you know, if you like them, you know,
you like their ideas, then they say,
"Oh, this is a great guy. I'm going to,
you know, help him. You know, I'm going
to uh spread his videos because I like
him." You know, that's that's some of
the ways to That's how you go. That's
how you know that's the behavior of
politicians. You can see can you see all
the politicians they are very nice you
see they are moral people they they
always do good things they want help
women children humanity
all these politicians
that's what they do you see so if you
want money
you you kind of have to you know go that
way okay you have you have to do certain
you know it's kind of like that But
anyway,
[sighs]
okay, I think that's it for today. going
to vectorize that site and rack it up. A
nice mushroom shirt. Thank you. This is
This is a uh
conversation starter.
Zuma idiots. That's my real face by the
way. Luck. Oh, that what
[laughter]
I thought. That's a anime face.
Uh analytic analytic minded. You see,
another thing YouTube did is that today
you cannot like click on um
I believe it used to be that you can
click on you know this comment and go to
their website. Okay, you can still do
so. Right click that's your face. No,
that's a cartoon analytic minded. That's
your it may be based on your on your
real face but it doesn't serve the
purpose of what we were talking about
about real face. You know what you need
is not a cartoon representation of your
face in our context. You know in the
context I'm talking about what you need
is a mug shot. You know like when you go
to the police station they take a shot.
You know real life mug shot. That's a
real That's a real human animal. Real
humanity. That's what matters. The real
thing, not the phony fake makeup, you
know, things, you know, like u
cartoon character.
Brother, internet loves a strong [ __ ]
personality. I despise them. Do you
still enjoy Second Life? No, I haven't
been in Second Life for like over 10
years. I should go back, but I don't
have time. But anyway, I think that's
it.
Analytic minded. You need you need a
mugsh shot. That's right. Okay. Bye,
guys. Okay. Donate to me. Okay. If you
guys, you know, you got a job, you got
to donate to me. Go to.info.
xh.info.
Okay. I think that's it. Um, I'm going
to go have good dinner and uh hope
everything is well with you guys. And
that's it.
Fantastic Wuam language and coding and I
still need to fix my website because in
the past 20 days a month I wasn't able
to update my website because there's a
ringync problem.
So all these updates on my website has
not been updated for like for 30 days or
20 days. So I really need to do that.
Okay, but that's it.
Bye bye guys.