welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is through the 2019 November
29th Friday 10 o clock 10 after 10:00 in
the morning San Francisco time and
today's topic is JavaScript live code in
JavaScript first tutorial javascript and
SVG and we are going to do
check okay so my sound stops sorry about
that so today it's today's topic is
going to be JavaScript plus SVG live
coding first tutorial I'm going to
explain what I'm doing and we are going
to code a real-time rotation of platonic
solids now you hear okay so great so we
are going to code front live rotation
real-time rotation of photonic solids
and I did a video I did two videos
before but you if you want to start from
scratch check out the previous video
about three days ago on my youtube
channel so good morning Benjamin good
morning Matt so we got concurrent
viewers - okay so just you two guys well
okay so let me mention thanks to this
person breasts for donation you can go
to I have my paypal and patreon on my
website solid out info so let's begin
coding shall we okay so let's let's not
coding then JavaScript that's okay let's
start - Co JavaScript so I'm going to
okay exhaust start command log mod so on
the Left window you see all my Emacs
commands and actually let me magnify my
font okay let me do some Emacs setup new
buffer middle o menlo 15 on the Mac
evaluate it that's good
so Benjamin Matt Matt you do some
JavaScript right Benjamin do you go
JavaScript so let's let me get this
ready okay
today is today's Friday so Friday's
today is kind of relaxed day yesterday
is Thanksgiving today's so today is
Black Friday Black Friday shopping day
so close that and some talk show a live
stream that's right and we are going to
do JavaScript JavaScript okay some
JavaScript you've done okay so today we
are going to do polyhedron lifetime real
time rotation okay and okay let's let's
let's continue with that javascript live
rotation let's show this in chrome okay
this is not working for some reason the
apt Oh
good morning apt oh good morning to
Egypt's Egypt I believe right okay so
we're gonna go in to do some JavaScript
okay let's you know I need to get
started to warm up and get on the track
so first of all let's look at this one
from showing Chrome okay we're gonna
start with that one that one's got some
problems and we are going to also let me
prepare some code here so we need more
code here and what we need is what is
this okay so go to a Saudi blog and
sound row
and index showing Chrome browser and
open that polyhedron rotate okay so this
one
so we're gonna do some JavaScript good
morning Alan
Carrie Oh Egypt yes and good morning
Alan to sunny California okay so we're
gonna do JavaScript I need to get on
track so what so what are we doing today
so we are going to basically improve
this one you see this one is kind of
screwed the colors is not right it's
kind of transparent but it's not you
know you see this effect it's actually a
book so we we're gonna make it a solid
so you don't see the part behind it okay
that's the first thing we're gonna do
let's this just focus on that shall we
let's yeah let's just focus on this one
and that one doesn't work for some
reason I have like so many versions
right now you know so copy that close
that create a new window paste it here
so we're gonna fix this one so and which
one is this okay so this one is right
here so again for those of you new here
there is a another video a few days ago
I did two videos before but watch the
second one because that one start from
scratch that one is one hour and 15
minutes which we arrived at this state
where we have icicle icosahedron or
octahedron or da roca Heatran and
octahedron and cube and tetrahedron okay
okay so so we need to so so go back to
i cosa he'd run go back to us like thank
Allah he'd run and and my god Kody I I
should get prepared but okay okay let's
take it it's just let's just take it
easy and go to whatever if we cannot
finish then then we cannot finish so
what what's up you guys have you guys
eaten turkey okay first of all let's fix
the faces why is it like that
I don't know so I think the well I have
to explain you know coding live coding
and and also explaining what's going on
is not so easy you know basically you
have to choose something you know well
then you do it you don't go into places
you don't know well because otherwise
you're gonna think for 10 minutes then
coaches for a minute and nobody wants to
watch that so you want to pick something
you know we're already and you know like
noise so where we can just start to code
fast but the other issue is that when
you do live coding you have to do
explanation at the same time so you know
if you are coding by yourself you can
just type type away but often times you
have to explain and the explanation you
will take like 50% more than 50% of the
time because because when you're coding
there's so many maybe you made a typo
even if you made a typo you have to
expand it because otherwise because most
people we are not know what you know
because you are the way do you know it
but other people don't so what are we
doing now so we are trying to fix this
so in order to fix this there are there
are 280 days of code so we did this
before so I'm not going to explain you
know I'm not going to explain but but
where is the problem well I know it's a
problem okay that the problem is around
when you generate SVG face so let's see
so we have here feel we are using a
transparency here you see this RGB that
part is is transparent because of the
last value now this is by the way same
syntax as CSS so if you if we take away
feel cut and let's just say yellow
refresh then you can see the problem it
becomes really funky yeah that's an
interesting thing that's going on the
reason that's happening because right
now the code okay let me show you a
different version okay instead of yellow
this here is the line okay comment that
out and wait and do and do and do okay
so copy the line then comment this out
then in here we say yellow okay that's
the current version we have copy the
line paste it again coming out the
yellow and let's say Fionan okay refresh
now that's better that's wireframe you
see they are rotating in only one
direction let's see like you know it's
not to tell which direction they are
rotating but now if we say fear yellow
refresh then we get this kind of funky
thing
the reason that happens is that we are
drawing each of these polygons in a pen
some some are in front of the others but
how do you how can I explain this this
is very disorienting to see code first
explain after oh okay yeah so code first
explain after that that that seems a
good advice
code first explain later yeah
okay so but what are we doing what am i
doing so what I need to fix this
you know I okay I know what how do I
know what is wrong that's you know what
we can do is going to you see we have
the polyhedron data here so let me show
you yeah even I myself am confused
actually what am i doing I should have
really every time I start to do this I
thought I should have done this before
like you know just to review it so I can
do a better video but every time I
started to like to you know this is this
is not too hard
you know and I thought you just walk you
know whatever problems we can just
explain and do it you know live but but
when they actually start to do it
there are like several minutes delay
like I don't know like I have to read
the code and think about it okay so
anyway so here is the icosahedron data
you know what is you know it might be
interesting to see what happens to the
other
for the Hydra okay so here is octahedron
really funky let's see if you guys can
see it you guys can see it right so
let's go to the HTML let's remove that
okay now it's better
so that's ice icosahedron now darker
Heatran
it's really funky now at octahedron cube
okay that's a good question and the most
that's that's a good question
so that that that question gets us
started thank you thank you for asking
that so for for we what we are joining
right now is platonic solids so
basically they are convex solids that
means it's like a bow okay so it's not
concave it
there's no dent so everywhere it's like
puffy so when you have a convex solid
then it's really easy to determine which
phases is in front all you have to do is
is you compute the center of a of a
triangle let's see let's stop rotate
okay so you have this okay this is this
is really funky this is you know I'm
trying to figure out why does this
happen the way it is you know right now
I don't understand but I know I can
understand that if I try to figure it
out for five minutes try to think about
it why does this happen right now
currently you see but anyway that's one
topic okay that's very interesting topic
to figure out why you know how it draws
the way it is right now
that's very interesting so that's one
topic and the other topic is right now
we can just start to code you know we we
can start to add proper code so that the
facing front will show we all hide the
face behind it so so how do you do that
let me explain okay so so remember
remember there are two things we want to
do one is just to start to make it you
know how the algorithm should walk the
other one is a curiosity is to figure
out why it what's the exact reason it is
doing
what it is doing right now okay that's
one question we go back to that but
first of all let's try let's explain how
how to get it properly how so to
determine which phase in front which one
is impact all you have to do is for each
face you compute their center like a
face has three points in in
three-dimensional space so you can you
compute their center you got the center
of the face then it's just a matter of
seeing which of their z-axis has higher
value so the higher value for the z axis
the z coordinate is more in front that's
so that's very easy to do okay so let's
just do that first then then maybe we
come back to the curiosity so to figure
out the the to figure out the centroid
okay here is here's the computation so
you if suppose you have a triangle so
let's say a1 a2 a3 so that's one
coordinate of a triangle and and let's
see
ABC okay so now we have three points of
a triangle it can be more okay it
doesn't matter so let's add more ABCD C
to D okay suppose we have a anyway you
have a pulley you have a face you know
let's this just say triangle you have a
face in free space and each one is their
coordinates a1 a2 a3 b1 b2 b3 and to
compute the center that we now we need a
another point x1 x2 x3 such that this
point is the center of that face so the
way you do it is very easy you this is
what you do a 1 plus B 1 B 1 plus C 1
you add them divided by 3 because they
are three points total so basically you
just average them so here is what you do
so the new coordinate will be like that
ok so this is like the new code and let
me show you okay so this is this is the
centroid there's a math term they call
it centroid centroid you know the center
point among a bunch of points so and
this works in any dimension in any
number of points so you can have more
points so if you have another point
let's say okay let me do it here so
that's one thing here is one thing and
now we have another thing
so in this example in a second example
we have four points in space and if you
want to find the center this is all you
have to do you just basically just
average them wait ABCD okay so this is
gonna be AP see
oh yeah plus T so this is gonna be like
that
does that make sense the centroid guys
make sense this is called the centroid
okay
so now let's go back let's write a
function that takes a bunch of points
and returns the centroid so in but in
fact we have that code here already so
let me try to find it so does that does
that make sense
Emma knows let me know you know if you
can answer that would be great so
because I know oh I did something you
know good right so the question so let's
get the centroid okay so this the code
for centuries this one it's so simple so
here is the code for centroid
so get centroid then you give it a bunch
of vectors erase then it returns the
centroid of a list of points so that's
very simple code so let's put that code
into our polyhedron here so let's put a
function where where do we put it
let's say here okay well let's say above
okay here
okay get centroid so centroid is a arrow
function it takes list of points and
then it a price reduce it takes any two
points ABC and XYZ then it computes a
plus X P plus y C / Z okay then then it
does map it it divided by number of
points okay so so anyway so we got the
centroid right guys right
see if I'm 24 minutes okay so this is
this is this is not going so good
century we are not going to get anywhere
with this speed so now we have a century
now we want to look at the code where it
renders okay so render
hello sir hello Finch Fitch you know I
not doing good here and every time I
think you know I'll just stop but if I
stop that's not going to work because
because if I stop now then what what's
not next either we switch to some random
topic or or next day tomorrow we're
gonna do this again
so I need to do this anyway so centroid
so okay what am I gonna do with centroid
okay now okay so let me go methodology
Co by logically step by step so I got a
centroid function which returns the
center point of a bunch of a point in
our case it returns the center of a face
okay he returns the center of a face now
what do I want to do next what I want to
do is when this thing when I try to draw
this thing you try to find the centroid
for each face before you draw it you
find the center point then check if that
center point is on one side of the plane
XY XY plane so so when you do SVG here's
your plan this is X vertical is Y so
this plane is XY plane so I got a
centroid of a face somewhere in 3-space
all I want to do is I want to find out
if that point is on one side of the one
side of the plane
because this thing we are drawing is
centered on zero on the engine so if
it's on one side then draw it if it's on
the other side don't draw it that's half
the problem okay
so the next step is to find where is the
part that draws the polygons so that
would be invent in in render okay so
render it says face indexes for each you
append child cue a SVG face okay so for
each face you okay now I want I know
what to do so here it is trying to for
each face it creates a SVG element then
it draws so now we don't want to do that
for all faces only we want to do that
only when the face is on one side of the
of the XY plane okay that's very easy to
do so so we're gonna modify this line
here okay so if something else something
okay so if on one side of face so if get
centroid
get centroid we need a bunch of points
for the face but how do we know how do
we get the points of the face well it's
somewhere here okay yeah it's somewhere
here face sket face there it is
so get face J returns a array each
element is coordinate of a vertex of the
face number J okay that's what we want
to that's what we want now go back to
where we are here
so get centroid we're gonna call it okay
we're gonna core it and we're gonna core
it with weight we're gonna call it like
that go get face okay go get face J okay
so so far so good
even so far so not good you are stuck
with me so get centroid get face J so
get face returns a bunch of points then
get Centro it returns the centroid of
that bunch of points then we take the z
axis I mean the we take the Z coordinate
okay so which is the second index
because remember we have a sick
eccentric returns a point and this point
is in 3-space so it has three
coordinates XYZ so the last part is
index two so if the z coordinate is
greater than zero then you draw it okay
then we want to draw it okay so if that
draw else else else don't do anything
okay let's see okay let's try that okay
wait
yeah let's let's try what happens with
this
okay motive myself so okay so let's
refresh oops
okay okay
so I'm cooking pizza this morning and
inviting my roommates to eat pizza they
are heading off to work now so what is
the problem on court type error Oh God
you know I'm not sure I'm gonna sis this
is getting very bad six people watching
are you guys still getting anything okay
so let me let me see what's going on
so unquote okay so stop rotation you
know when you you know this keeps going
so what's his problem
PDS reduce is not a function what
okay maybe our centroid get centroid
face oh I know where is wrong I got it
wrong the syntax is wrong so it should
be here yeah
so you see get face then we have guessed
centroid then take take the Z coordinate
okay then if it's greater than zero then
Troy now let's try it
yay yay problem good morning Lyle card
Oh what is the problem
yeah indeed we got a problem but I don't
know what why is it drawing like that
but however you can see now look at that
picture carefully you can see that our
algorithm is actually working correctly
but we got some other problems for
example this you know we got this blank
thing there I don't know why is it blank
you know I know why is that like that
because yeah actually I know it is like
that because our data for I suck eyes
icosahedron is incorrect you see we have
the data here for icosahedron so here
are the vertices and here are the faces
I know it's incorrect because this data
is computed is given to me this code by
a my friend mathematician Herman and he
told me this is incorrect because he has
a new version so if we just replace the
data by a new version issue walk yeah
right yeah so I guess that's yeah when
you have
you see these vertices this this are
just a bunch of numbers you know Gigi is
a number the reason they are using Gigi
is because it makes it easier to compute
you see gigi is defined in in here
Gigi is actually the golden ratio now
when you need the vertices for a eggs
icosahedron you need golden ratio okay
let's go there let's let's go to now if
I cannot do code well I go to
mathematics to explain something
interesting but this is indeed
interesting because when you are trying
to draw a icosahedron or any polyhedron
you need a list of coordinates now for
cube the coordinates are easy to come by
because it's just 1 1 1 or 1 negative 1
you know it's a variation of what but
when you have something like like
icosahedron the vertices is you have to
compute them you and if you have not
studied it you may find this actually a
good very good
problem in geometry that is to find the
coordinates for this thing by yourself
you know you can you can try to do it
try to find the coordinates of all the
coordinates by yourself oh oh it takes I
mean the problem is that you have a
solid such that every face is a triangle
Wow it more than that but anyway you go
to Wikipedia you look up these things
you all know what's going on so anyway
the problem is to find all the vertices
the coordinates okay that's a geometry
problem and it turns out it's very
interests
it turns out there's a easy way to get
them now
okay they don't have it here
now there there it is you see this image
this image is the key to find the
coordinates for the icosahedron okay so
but you know they this is not the
version I want but but he but it is a
key but it is not the one the picture
I'm looking for
okay since I cannot find a picture
actually I do have a picture so you
search for Sally math wonder math wonder
sauce top 10 math wonders this article I
wrote back in 2010 about you know I'm
trying to pick the top 10 most
interesting wonderful things in math you
know so I just picked some of them so
here is a fractal here is Constance
golden ratio here is the picture I want
to show you open image so you can see
this image is pretty much this image was
from Wikipedia but now they change it it
to something more you know less
interesting they change it to this thing
less intuitive but anyway basically that
the two are kind of the same thing you
can see so when you have this so first
you know to find the vertices of this
icosahedron all you have to do is you
get this rectangle first so you get
these three of this rectangle then you
intersect them in orthogonal way then
the vertices will be the vertices on the
icosahedron okay so this is one this is
the best way to remember to calculate
the vertices of the icosahedron any any
comments questions type it okay keep
keep keep the things going so so how do
you so what is this rectangle this
rectangle
say golden rectangle this rectangle now
how do you remember golden rectangle
that's very beautiful okay so you want
to find a rectangle that looks like that
I mean it's called golden rectangle and
golden rectangle basically if you look
at my window if you look at the black
part of my screen a golden rectangle
looks something like that this
proportion so your job is to find so so
what is the ratio so if the side is one
what is the the width okay so how do you
find that so it's this is also very
specific and very interesting you find
it by the ratio kW over edge is such
that and see how I can explain it's such
such that okay if you take the hate and
if you draw a rectangle amia square with
the same hate then you will cut this
rectangle into two sections you see this
section and this section and the ratio
of these two sections will be exactly
identical to the ratio of the width and
hate okay do I make sense well I'm not
sure I do golden but you can you go now
you gotta wait Wikipedia I think you can
read it and okay they don't have that Oh
God there it is golden rectangle okay
they do have a explanation there it is
you see golden rectangle is a specific
rectangle in with a specific ratio of
the width and hate such that such that
well just just like the picture showed
you know the weight such that such that
the ratio of the hate and width is equal
to the ratio of
a and B here if you make a rectangle I
mean if you make a square out of the
rectangle so it's kind of self
referential its kind of the definition
you can think of it that way
and we keep here PDA shows you many ways
to construct to to derive the number so
you can find out exactly what is a plus
B a plus B it turns out it's a golden
ratio it's this number one point six one
eight and and so on
so that's you know this is a very
beautiful thing in math okay golden
ratio and golden rectangle and so once
you have that once you have this ratio
of the rectangle then you just put three
of them together like that then you know
the vertices of a icosahedron okay hi hi
knobby Hanavi you are late so let's
continue to okay so anyway so so that's
a that's kind of a side point about how
do you find the vertices of the
icosahedron now let's go back to our
code so that's why you see so we have we
have icosahedron vertices here you see
we have like how many of them I don't
know how many of them twelve or twenty
and see 12 of them 12 vertices and you
can see they are computed by gg gg is
the golden ratio okay so you go up here
you can see this formula is this number
is called a ratio okay so that's how we
get we get the vertices of a icosahedron
and the face now how are the face
computed the face the face just the face
data here they are just indexes of the
vertices so so for example here 0 1 4
means means the zeroes face I mean the
zeroes vertex connected to the first
vertex connected to the fourth vertex so
0 1 2 3 4 so connect to this one so
that's what this is 0 1 for me and
similar for the others so the that's the
data structure for the face now the
reason our code is incorrect like that
is because I believe it's because the
face information is incorrect that is
why we get that we get that funky thing
so to fix that I believe we have a
version that with the correct face so
let's use it ok let's use it
okay that's that's what we want this
code copy it close it close it make a
backup no let's face it okay and do oh
yeah
obviously it's incorrect because you see
here we don't have enough faces okay
let's let's do that again
so here how many facing a icosahedron
does anyone know we can see 20 but
however we only have 12 here so
obviously that's incorrect oh we got 20
faced that's why that's why we see these
horse okay no I know and now I
understand okay go back we want to copy
close that so we're gonna delete this
okay now back to 20 correct refresh
perfect perfect
God now this is great now I guess we can
say at least I did something for today
oh my god get this fixed now you see
that's one shot you know we fixed two
things we fixed our previous code that's
missing faces and we also fixed the
problem of of hiding the face behind
okay so let's let's add another feature
okay let's add a checkbox that says
whether you want it
wireframe or not okay
let's do that and let's see do we have
time enough to do something else let's
make it one hour okay let's make it one
hour right now we got 10 more minutes to
do and it's not okay so now we add a
checkbox so that we can choose wireframe
or not
front-end program a happy solution lose
face by ending stream I was thinking
ending stream early but that's no
solution because then what I'm gonna do
then tomorrow it's the same thing the
spice must flow okay see you later man
so we're gonna do we saw with let's to
check box okay let's go to JavaScript
blog and let's go to my tutorial DOM and
the Dom how do you do a checkbox here it
is so you do a check box by copying that
magnify so go back here go to the HTML
page don't save so go to HTML page put a
checkbox here and check box wireframe
okay
id wireframe type checkbox' name
wireframe value value check box my
friend actually no no value okay then
for wireframe
so we named it wireframe checkbox okay
and showing browser okay so showing
browser refresh
we got a wireframe checkbox right now it
does not do anything so now we need to
go to our code go to it and go to the
top and right now we can write this easy
because this is not math document get
element by ID and wireframe checkbox
okay we got the checkbox now we need to
do something with a checkbox so we do
that by going to the bottom and add a
add a event so this will be like that
wireframe checkbox add event listener
input and toggle wireframe okay let's
say yeah toggle wireframe so when people
check this wireframe checkbox if we are
Targo you it will call this function
toggle wireframe so what does i Function
do well I don't know let's look at our
go auto rotation so copy this search for
that okay so that is the function for
toggle auto rotation
okay well now second let's make a copy
of that rename it toggle wireframe
okay and then then if if toggle
wireframe okay hold on a second if go to
the bottom if wireframe checkbox if weif
and check box is checked
then rotate timer okay we don't want to
rotate time what is going on here it's
just
so basically if it's checked then do
something else do something okay so if
wireframe checkbox is checked okay I
know what to do then you say wireframe
style let's say a string okay feel none
okay
do you say feel styie okay that's what
you say feel style so if the checkbox is
checked wireframe is checked then you
draw the polygon and the feel is none
otherwise else feel equals to read okay
it's just saying that okay so we added a
new constant field style here so let's
go to the top and add a constant field
style okay so we need the field style
then we need to go to the place where it
tries to draw here and it will just add
field style not yellow but
like that okay so here is we create we
are creating a polygon SVG polygon in
that line then we add an attribute where
is the coordinates for the polygon then
then we add a style to it okay and let's
let's double check one more thing
so toggle wireframe so if that then that
then we need to call render okay because
every time user toggle wireframe we have
to render it so actually let's shrink
this this style coding code formatting
this style none of the C style crap okay
if else render if these two that else do
that feel style then we render it okay
let's hope everything is good Wayne's
good we can all go home oh yeah let's
check wireframe oops
and coach type arrow assigned to
constant variable of course I know that
shut shut up shut up you see we have a
constant fire field style which actually
should be not constant because we are
changing it so refresh click on
wireframe okay now this is another
interesting side effect visual side
effect the reason we see it like that
because the feel color and the edge
color are the same so we got that so we
don't want red
fear let's go to fear again blue okay
refresh click on wireframe now it's
beautiful oh my god this is beautiful
and in fact we got it reversed oh wait
my frame know why affair oh yeah is this
beautiful he got the problem solved guys
so should we we have actually we it's
one hour I think that's it
or should we do more what do you guys
think okay so Nabi has a suggestion Nabi
has a great suggestion to see the
background like transparency so we can
do that so instead of feel blue we just
use that transparent colors okay so it's
such for RGV so we just do this instead
okay so feel instead of a blue we say
that okay so here is the part you know
feel we give it a CSS color syntax
okay let's refresh okay refresh now no
wireframe now okay I know what's going
on too because because remember our
algorithm it's not drawing anything
behind at all because remember if the
point is above the z axis we draw it
otherwise we don't draw it at all so
it's not drawing anything behind it so
we need now we need actually to draw it
in order to see the well yeah we can do
that but let's try it okay let's go to
the place where we call get sent
okay here here you see if if the century
okay let me show that let's make this
easier okay z-coordinate okay equals to
hold on a second
so constants Z coordinate equal to get
face which is a bunch of points then we
call get centroid returns one point then
we get the last component which is the Z
coordinate okay so that's Z coordinate
so now if we if Z coordinate if is
greater than zero then we draw it okay
otherwise else well what we gonna do so
else we draw it too let's just do that
but it doesn't matter okay
okay so we have that you know we have
that but you see this this doesn't you
know we are using transparency so what
so so yeah we can do this but but this
is no different than just you know not
having the if statement at all for
example you know you see instead of
instead of the if-else we can simply
just draw it it doesn't matter it's in
front or not we just draw it we are just
using the transparency but since we do
have the ability to find out which one
is in front then why don't we do
something a bit fancy
such that if it's in front it should
have let's see more peg color or
something what so Nadia says if the
wireframe box is checked don't render
yeah that's what we did
yeah that's what we did I that's what we
did before I think that's you know
that's that's what we did for example if
we come and this out and comment that
out so if Z is greater than zero they
enjoy it otherwise do nothing so if we
now refresh you see yeah that I guess
that's oh okay I think maybe that's it
for today I was you know I was planning
to do some okay let's see oh
sone Abby's suggestion is yes good point
so nabis is saying now be saying if it's
not wireframe then you draw what is in
front but whatever is behind you simply
draw the wires you know not the polygon
okay yeah that's a good idea so let's do
that so if it if it is in front we draw
it no more okay now but if else if it's
in the back we how do we do it okay how
do we do it we have to change the field
basically but okay so wait so
so we need to pass a we need to add an
argument to render okay hmm
now that's it's just hack let's just
hack our way through it instead of the
instead of thinking of the proper way so
so else if it's not in front then we
just then Fiona yeah it's easy to do
Fionan okay right so there so if it's in
front
joy normally but if it's in the back
make the feel none let's try it
refresh okay click no wireframe what Wow
well the reason this happens is because
it has no effect right now because the
fear style is a global variable so you
once you set it here it affects the part
over there's we are as well so so let's
just do some more hack okay this it's
just to some hack let's see that works
okay let's do just do some more hack I
don't think your walk because because
the feel style is a global variable so
you act you actually need to put in the
place where I create SVG face there so
yeah so it doesn't work because the feel
style is global it justifies doesn't
matter you but as far as hack is
concerned we can try to hack it to make
it work so all we have to do is go to
the go to the create SVG face okay we
can kind of create a variable
okay we create a second variable here X
let's say feel okay let's say feel X
here
okay so I know what to do we can finish
this okay we can finish this no worry
okay
we remove all that we just create a SVG
face here right
okay we create SVG face and we go back
to the create SVG face then we do our
computing here get the get the z
coordinate if z coordinate is greater
than zero hold on a second yeah so if Z
coordinate is greater than zero we don't
need that anymore so if Z coordinate is
greater than zero then then
what what's going on so
oh we already have that then we
here okay we are hacking this code out
of shape so here if Z is greater than 0
then we we've we said attribute okay
else
I'm not sure this is going to work but
it's close
let's just try it refresh
no wireframe yes wireframe it doesn't
work we cannot use global variables
because this is global wait
refresh oh there it is we are seeing
something this is another interesting
effect know why a frame-by-frame doesn't
matter
oh I know why I kind of know why yeah I
think I know why because anyways it's a
bit complicated to explain yeah I see I
know what you mean knobby but but okay
do we want to I mean the question is
should we do that you know if we keep if
we want to do that I don't know how long
it's going to take because you know the
code we have to right now it's doing
that because
let's remove the let's remove the global
variable okay let's just put the actual
style here see what happens okay
refresh No
anyway I think that's a no hacker thank
you okay I think that's it it's in one
hour
well we did something now I wish I can
go back to the code where I forgot to
make a backup so we cannot we cannot go
back to the the correct code we had
before anyway that's it for today thank
you guys for watching bye guys
cross the video stream n stream