good morning guys
welcome to another episode of exert our
show today is August 13th 2019 Tuesday 8
o clock a.m. San Francisco time and ok
this so we are going to talk about so I
got prepared and we have several topics
so the topics are it's listed in the
description you know and so that the
topics are possible topics our tutorial
going over or JavaScript wats okay
that's number one and number two
tutorial on JavaScript es2015 features
number three random chat going over my
blocks on keyboard or programming or
Emacs or math or Unicode and topic
number four Emacs tired setup and tips
or topics number five any other topics
just type it in the chat box so you know
look at the descriptions hi guys I got
two people here so look at the
descriptions and type a topic and let's
you know talk about that today and okay
so let me set the window here and yeah
so so what what shall we talk about
today you know type of topic guys so let
me get my Firefox up my Emacs and let's
start saw command saw start command log
so on the left pane you can see all my
Emacs command such as forward word
backward forward cha backward cha up
down all my Emacs commands will show on
this window so if we are talking about
some Emacs topics
you Emacs users can see my commands you
can look them up
most most Oh Mac basically all my
commands are also on my website you can
so you can search it so let's see some
talk show santosh showed august 13th
o 13th today is not Friday okay okay so
yeah so here we got the possible topics
so guys hey Daniel Anglo is Daniel Anglo
is how are you so topic breaks it okay I
don't know anything about breaks it act
actually you know that's a European
Europe stuff and and you also you are
American right I'm American you are
American and you you are in California
right I believe so I don't know you know
the Britain with British Empire United
Kingdom you know what's what they are
doing I know it's a big thing that's how
I know and you know they trying to exit
but it's very complicated you know I
want to exit emergency exit okay
Danielle say something okay so who else
oh my god I got five people so people
please pick a topic you know like this
today's you know my chat is typically
casual and I'm not prepared I mean what
I mean this is impromptu this is not
scripted so you know just type of topic
you know what kind of topic you like see
you like to see and let's talk about
that okay oh yeah in the Danny
so three ways to the power of 2 minus 2
raise to the power of 3 equals 1 this is
that true I don't think that's true well
I don't know well hey jakab topic
sociology you guys are picking random
topics you know oh yeah so one random
topic is actually I guess it's part of
my topic you know you can be random but
you need to be specific like okay
sociology yeah but like what you know
there's so many things about sociology
oh by the way so okay so if you guys
want random knit you know we can do
random you know also breaks it you know
I don't know anything about Europe
I haven't been to Europe but there is
one thing I know about Europe that is
the naming of you wrote hold on a second
let me adjust the actually it's not just
that because last time I tried to shrink
this you see there's can you you can see
it right can you see it let me see yeah
so you see my the the video that shows
my head last time I try to shrink it and
it you know because they are blank on
the side you know you don't need the
bank on the side but it seems to me it
looks like it's going to slow down so my
slow down the video so that my talking
my speech is not synced to my video so
you know you rope okay so okay I guess
so any one last chance okay so because
once we started I start to talk about
something it's gonna be like 10 minutes
20 minutes 30 minutes so if there's
anyone who likes you know to be a
technical topic some Emacs you know on
JavaScript or stuff say it okay because
otherwise otherwise once we talk about
you know non-technical stuff you know
it's gonna be like random chat and we
don't have time to cover you know that
the other wats of javascript oath or the
new features of JavaScript 2015 because
each one of those is gonna take one hour
so gnarly
you roll path so let me show you okay so
let me say it again so if you want a
technical topic you know look at the
description and type it say now okay
you have five minutes to
that so Europa let me tell you about
Europa oh this one
this topic is fantastic interesting and
also this one you ropa you know so you
know who she is Europa and she is the
mother of Europe you know as far as name
is concerned
she is from quick mythology so she is a
girl and you see this sport is masculine
this giant you know huge you know the
girls it's a head you know the Pooh just
take off you know this you know the pool
represents the power the the masculinity
you know the boy just take off the girls
you know how fun for a ride so she is so
she is Europa and she's a girl and the
boy you know does anyone know who is the
ball like it does anyone know type it so
then your language is Jacob you you guys
know who is the ball let me tell you
okay and this story also from quick
Greek mythology the automata the Talos
his name is Talos automata it's very
interesting
oh by the way there is a voice to speech
recognition software that's new let me
show you sorry
blood and the name of that software is
called Talon
you know it's it's all coincidence it's
the Saudi keyboard blog okay so I'm
going to talk about Europa and the Talos
the automaton am I still alive check
check yes check okay I'm still alive so
you know so so let me tell you this news
voice voice text input for programming
okay you know you're a programmer and
you type a lot yes the neurosis the boo
is you
was exactly you know the sewers the god
Zeus all-powerful you know is the god of
all gods basically you know the room and
Zeus screws every girl every every
female basically so so okay let's go
back to this topic later so let's talk
about Europa okay so this Zeus so this
is quick mythology you know Zeus saw
this girl you know pretty good pretty
girl and and oh yeah so so so zeroes
changed himself into a bull you know a
beautiful you know masculine bull and
you know the Greek says seduce Europa
you know who stop and by the way so this
theme Europa in the boy is one of the
great topic subject matter in you know
in arts in I guess in poetry in arts you
know it's a quick mythology is kind of
the foundation of Western philosophy you
could say that you know so anyway so see
zoo zoos you know he changed himself
into this pool and seduce Europa you
know you know trying to get hurt haha
and then just took off what what a great
guy you know oh my god I wish I could be
Zeus and four girls they wish they could
be the girl you know that's typical so
there's this poetry so this poetry is
from Ovid now I don't know what that is
but I mean it's Asian poetry so he said
here's a description of abduction of
Europa in metamorphosis which is a poem
by Ovid okay so and this is back in 43
BC you know so there's a poem describing
the scene how she was seduced euro
and you know Europe have became Europe
you know that's that's you know that's
the name and and let me show you some
artworks okay so all these are ancient
now this one is in Pompeo was Pompeo
anyone knows I don't always compare I
thought it's in India but anyway so this
one is from first century ce e oh my god
I hate this see you know this
interesting thing about this naming of
the year see II and P you know so okay
like let me digress for a little bit
okay let me digress so before it used to
be PC and AD
okay that's Latin PCB basically means
before Christian before Jesus you know
something like that that BC so it's you
know years something some year PC before
Jesus then you have ad Eddie's Latin
stand for something something anyone
knows type it okay piece BC and AD we
can look up you know but you know you
guys can also look up so you know the
year used to be BC and AD ad which
basically means after Jesus is born then
the basically the the left leftist okay
the left a khadeem academicians they
change they you know they started to not
use that instead they use they use PCE
and Cee so BCE means before Common Era
okay BCE means before Common Era like
before Jesus then see II means Common
Era like the ad okay so there's this
change and you know then people fight
over it and it today it's it's quite
popular you know many universities
textbooks you know they they use the pc
and
see instead of the BC and AD right pcs
before before Christ and ad is anno
domini yes okay Thank You Jacob
yeah so you know there's this fight you
know you know left hitting versus your
Christians fight over the use the naming
you know like you know that like the
certain group you know clamoring about
she versus he you have to say he and she
and day and today you have you have
punch them and whatever you know
fighting so let me tell you the story so
before you know like 10 years ago
i am i all you know i have like five
thousands articles on my website I wrote
them and I use PC and ad but however I
am NOT a God believer okay so I don't
and when you know for you know before
2010 USA is very much very much a
Christian country so Christian has power
you know they rule you know gay is not
allowed police now allowed you know you
shall not do this or that you know the
the the Christians the you know rule
America so and I don't like that of
course well because you know the because
I'm not a Christian you know and so when
it comes to AD and BC okay people Jesus
you know the refers to Jesus I don't
like that I don't you know that that's
not my preferred I don't like that and
in the money you know in u.s. dollar
money you have in god we trust' well I'm
American but it's not God I trust you no
good that's that doesn't mean much to me
so I didn't like that but then oh yeah
so at around you know 2006 or so I
changed all my website you know those
ad the BC and AD I change it to the this
this scheme you know BCE before Common
Era and the Common Era you know because
I don't like you know when the Christian
is dominant you know george w bush for
example you know they tell you what to
do so I changed the years to this PCE
and see but now I want I'd I want to
change it back but cut because this lets
you know I don't want to mention the
names because a certain group you know
the political gang in USA I think that's
far worse than the Christians
okay so rise you know Christians rise
you know I don't like the BCE and see
anymore I want to change it back to the
PC and AD so you know that that's a
little digression about the you know the
fight you know the you know fighting of
the you know little straw goes
everywhere you see because you know
everyone has opinions it depending on
what you believe you want to they were
you know anyway there's this thing I
don't like today this left it's you know
leftist group you know that I think they
are much more Wars and they for example
we are talking about Europa and you know
quick mythology Europa sewers this is
this is the foundation of Western
culture in a big sense you know it's a
pillar of Western culture but today this
particular group you know they want to
destroy it you know they think oh this
is certain certain words you know they
have certain words I don't want to use
okay it's not use it okay don't type
them because you yeah that's gonna get
me banned you know I don't want get over
there so anyway you wrote I in the pool
that's you know so you have artwork so
this is first century you know BC C okay
so Common Era you know in first century
then you have this this is 460
BC okay you know 460 so it's to two
thousand five hundred years old and you
have this official coining of the
European Union is that called European
Union EU yeah European Union official
coin you know so and look at the artwork
that's here is the boy that's yours and
this girl is Europa so what is what does
it say constant choose on Europa so what
language is that I don't know anyway
anyone know what's a constituent
Constitution European I guess so pump
here was a Roman city destroyed by the
eruption of mount this of years oh okay
so you are you are knowledgeable cat 44
said okay thank you
so the mounts they serve years I have a
very vague Rico of that I think that's a
mountain in Italy right so yeah so I
guess Roman city yeah so that's in Italy
Pompeo is in Italy so let's look up so
yeah Italy Rome you know Rome and Greek
and Rome okay so let's see let's go to
Wikipedia let's just get a so how do you
pronounce it let's see Pompeii okay
Pompeii oh two eyes okay and again
Pompeii so it's in Italy so this is like
okay so okay so let's get back to Europa
so you have this artwork beautiful you
know I love I love Greek mythology I
think it's beautiful the you know not
just the artwork but the story of like
all the Greek mythology like you know if
someone asked me what's your religion
sometimes I would claim quick
mythology okay that is I truly love
Greek mythology because Greek mythology
and like for example you know forgive me
for saying unlike the Christians or
others oh well and Buddhism is a bit
different you know and you know the but
the quick mythology is such that they
reflect humanity the order you know the
good and the bad the human wantings the
desires that the the behavior the you
know the the foibles you know all the
flaws in the you know like you know for
example the story of Europa this sewer
sky all-powerful he wants to that's
what he want to do you know like like
guys especially powerful guys and the
girls
what do the girls want they want to get
you know princess in shining armor you
know whoever is powerful that I can
provide a them you know wealth and
security and so this is a story of
Europe are in the pool you know that's
one of the you know it reflects reality
you know that's that's how we are and
you okay so look at all these sculptures
and this one is in USA so European a
pool bike cow miles you know University
of Tennessee okay this one is modern and
another modern one you know so this one
is from France okay it's in France so
that's a story of the Europa and the
poor and I find it beautiful and there's
this poem here metamorphosis you know
with like when you study like I guess
most of us are programmers right
okay so then he was asking me what were
you complaining about physicists on
Twitter early today let's just random
that's
it's okay I'm not I don't like the world
troll that's just my random you can't
you don't say it's true
so let me let me talk about your iPad
here for a bit let me finish okay so so
the so there's this poem metamorphosis
from Ovid you know 43 year 44 43 BCE so
like most of us are programmers right
today we program us we we you know we
study or artificial intelligence oh you
know the technology Oh Google Oh iPhone
Oh Apple just came out with the new
phone this and that you know of you
know but if you look into philosophy
literature Greek mythology you know it's
like it's like you know it's like an
infinite hole you know there's so much
thing singing it you know humanity
history there's so much some and you
don't you cannot read them you know you
don't have time I mean even if you are
not a computer
I mean if even if you are not a
programmer I mean you I mean you can
devote your life to study program
instead of computer science theoretical
or math you know that's that's infinite
that's an infinite hole but in the same
way literature in humanity also called
the humanities you know Arts and
Humanities that's a big hole really and
you know so some people let me go
through the what's going on here
okay so metamorphosis what is this okay
so many metamorphosis is a Latin
narrative poem by Roman poet Oh
Ovid considering his Magnum Mack magnum
opus okay the best so comprising eleven
thousand lines fifteen books in over 250
means so anyway so you know in
humanities that's also that's very
extremely rich although they you know
Humanity is like poetry
arts for philosophy they don't they
don't make money for you as opposed to
programming that the the most shallow
you know you know I Spit non-programmers
you know the programmers UNIX
philosophy UNIX philosophy Oh Linux
Linux you know you know anyway anyway so
the literature so if you are a
programmer you know you make kudos or
money and well yeah it's practical you
know but if you go into poetry
philosophy history you make zero money
you become you know so-called artist you
know poor artist but however a society
with artists you need that because it
gives you it gives you the spirit the
culture the substance of you know of
society so in other words you know today
maybe I don't know if you feel it in USA
in lots of other countries you know
white countries Canada Europe Australia
but also China and Japan
you know we young people are looking at
phones every day you know to gain the
phones and all the problems we might say
is because art is dying you know uh you
know the people keep saying that but we
don't know for sure but however we could
you can you can kind of you can at least
say it you know we don't know it's
really happening or not you know art is
kind of you know we could say today we
have all these problems because you know
art and philosophy they kind of are
dying instead you know today we got this
crap and modern so-called modern art
like the toilet like a urinal is an art
piece in a museum like you know you know
this you you splash your piss into a
paint and in smash it down to war that's
odd
Modern Art you know so you you could say
you know it cause problems when a
society you know you don't have and and
today as you know one of the expert in
humanities one I truly admire I think
one of my two top favorite author is
Camille Paglia okay oops
what what's going on okay okay I have
the okay so I think you know I turned on
what what is these applications you know
I turned on oh
I think I turned on the sticky key and I
screwed up my that's why this is weird
things happening let me turn it off I
just turn out sticky keys like this
morning I thought I give it it it
another try
so let me go back to read the comments
in a second so let's turn off sticky
keys that is why I don't like sticky
keys because sometimes this happens you
press a key you don't know what's going
on so we were talking about art yeah so
one of my favorite oh god this is not
working anymore but it's
okay am I still alive okay Oh Mikey so
I'm not walking like god what's going on
sorry about that there's something I
cannot get off this reverb but I think
because the sticky key is screaming of
accessibility let me try it let's try it
again okay
and let me turn off
okay now I'm back sorry about that
that's a long delay so what one of my
favorite author camille paglia okay
let's see so that's her name I truly
admire her because she is king of
humanities she study art and pop culture
I mean any today you have a lot people
you know it's like young people they
think they are the cultural critic you
know anyone can be a critic but actually
you have to you know like if you have a
philosophy that does you know tip a lot
philosophers actually they are they they
have to know mathematics like they are
accomplished mathematicians or physics
you know that you you you don't they are
not just philosopher because you know a
lot philosophers actually great ones you
know you actually are already a
mathematician like like you you know
more math than typical mathematicians
but you do philosophy then you are a
philosopher okay things like that oh oh
neuroscience you know that study that
brain was something philosophers see in
a similar way Camille Paglia is
so-called a you know she one of her hat
is social critic could you know pop
culture critic or you know critics of
film and stuff but now she knows more
history then the investment or T of
historians you know that's what it you
know true you know a profession true
expert that's what it means
so she I admire so much so she can you
know for example she look at you know
Europe has she can tell you a whole like
she can do a lecture for hours on all
the related history and you know and the
art and relate how it relates through
language different you know like a
linguistic linguist you know a master of
languages and you know she can do that
oh my god and so
like that so okay so that let's read the
comment let's see what what's up so so
let's see it's let's quickly read the
comments first so I'm gonna talk about
my beef with feces in a bit so Maxime
good morning Maxim Maxim band name says
quick mythology is also cool because
it's rather easy to crime the martin
öhlin 'this just hearty bothered is it
white what why climb Mount Olympus by
the way is Olympus a real mountain Mount
Olympus we are we okay and Mark Maxime
says Oviatt wrote in key lines and think
he's a pro yeah I've I don't know but
that's a great poetry right it's an epic
okay so and not even debugged
okay so x stock prints good morning
most of Western culture is stolen at one
point of another for example question is
basically a stealing mechanism hard to
maintain the facade indefinitely okay I
don't know anything about that I don't
know and doctrine says thus they veer
towards technical the rational as a way
out I'm not sure about that Christian is
very old and Western and most Western
and you says most Western culture is
stolen at one point or another that's
hard to defend on the Sunnis face value
that's how to defend vision you know one
is one of the oldest religion you know
and
so if you say Christian is you know it's
one of the oldest religion by the way
there's something I don't understand
about Christian Christian allottee in
general so if you guys know type it let
me know ok it's like so Christian you
know there are many branches you know as
far as I know so you have a Abraham or
something I might pronounce it wrong
Abraham Abrahamic religions which
includes Christian arity is Islamism and
another one believed by Jews you know
what's the what's that religions name
type it guys ok let me know you know so
these 3 also called apple hammock
religions ok because they a former
scholar point of view I mean you know if
you are a Christian or if you are in
Islam you may you Judaism okay yeah so
so I guess so the Jews people the Jews
people is a very complex topic okay I
don't really understand it you know to
me it's just all white people like God
before I learned about Jews you know
it's just white people like not I think
I cannot tell but it's a big issue in
USA you know it's not my it's not my
story it's not my business because I'm
amazing I'm Chinese I don't know that
those stories even though you do have
choosing in China you know and you also
have is Islam's you know in China it's
very complicated story you know raising
stuff anyway so as far as I learned you
know this Apple hammock regions includes
you know Christianity Islam and Judaism
you know because you know you you know
as Christians has Bibles Islam has Quran
you know something and Judaism has
something how they call it they call
their scripture you know and you and and
you look at them I haven't read them by
the way I've just read stuff
you know you look at their story like
they have the same characters you know
like if you watch two movies you have
the same characters in them they just
stories are slightly different you know
you know if you watch superheroes you
know you have Superman in this movie but
you also have Superman in that movie you
know just the story is a bit different
so these three regions they they have
kind of the same route I think it's is
kind of a diversified but but in
christian ality you know as far as I
know then you have two big branches you
know you have the Protestants and you
have the Catholics Catholics you know I
you know I did I don't know about these
before like let's say twenty years ago
but eventually you learned about them
you know so American is mostly
Protestants American you know and Latin
America for example I think Mexico and
Brazil
you know para why they are Catholics and
I think most your Europe is Catholics I
think anyway the Catholic and
Protestants it's a one giant chapter of
history of Western history you know this
was you know with how many dead the
millions I don't know but you know this
protest ins and Catholics and the Pope
you know guide the Pope both guys the
Catholic thing it's not the you know by
the way you guys probably know and
probably you know CD listening to me
because if you are you know white guys
you go up you know white guys you know a
lot more than you know you think I'm a
seedy talking nonsense
anyway that's you know so you can see
you know from someone outside us you can
see you know what what I am seeing so
you have the Catholics then you have the
Protestants but then okay in America
then later on you also have the moments
you know in Utah you know this is this
you have these moments people okay they
have live they have a church of their
own style you know also
all these religions you know you know
their house of worship they all have
distinctive styles this is very
interesting you know so Islam they are
and names also you know they worship you
know they have the co-ed you know I what
you call them but but we can go to
Unicode okay I'm rambling all over the
place but basically my question is what
are the okay so let me finish my
question my question is so so per
distance you know and Catholics and in
USA you have also moments but there are
so many others there's like you know
I've heard you know Episcopal something
okay then there is a lot okay at the
moment then I can't you know I can't
remember the names but like often east
and something then I'd like this a lot
like do you guys is it a San Pedro can
someone like give a quick summary of the
branching like which which one
diversified into what so I know I guess
I moments is kind of diversified from
Protestants but okay so so what are the
episkopos thing and and also in Europe
you know the you also have that so I
don't I don't understand like I have no
idea so if someone knows type it okay
like you know give some general picture
and there are a lot of names you know I
can't I don't remember named at a moment
so if someone can give a quick if if
possible at all you know a summary of
what branches came out from what they'll
be great you know like a few times I try
to we read Wikipedia but but you know as
you know this is a giant topic so when
you go to Wikipedia it's like very
complex tens of pages you know you get
overwhelmed you don't get the nice
picture you get overwhelmed
the different branches anyway so you
know what so let's go look at Unicode
Unicode let's see let's go to places
faces okay then you see you have you
know you have different ok Church you
know in general Christian the the
buildings Christian worship is called
Church okay then
Japan is called in Japan or China the
Buddhism is called temple
okay then in the oh yeah those the
Judaism is called synagogue right I hope
I'm not making a mistake because if you
do if you do make a mistake on these
kind of things people get offended okay
and the Islam they worship is called
mosque mosque may be you finance it
mosque they okay yeah and yeah church is
the is a does church this is there a
distinction distinction between
Protestant or Catholic and then you have
this place called Kaaba which is like
one place in somewhere in middle Middle
East that's you know that's a giant
worshipping place
and that building looks like that it
looks is no it's a cube it's a black
cube and in Japan okay so Japan you have
this Shinto shrine you know Japan has
Buddhism but is slightly different from
China so I you know I don't really know
about Japanese Buddhism but in China you
have Buddhism yeah and and you know you
call it temples you know then you have
Taoist temples you have you also have
served several you know Buddhism like
branches I don't really know the details
oh yeah so there's a name orthodoxy
right
if Eastern Orthodox so let's see let me
read the comments so X Dark Prince says
monthly ism is basically cultural :
colonialism that was done in the Mideast
against the pagans mah theism does that
mean one God okay I guess that's what it
means monthly ism is basically cultural
Collin ISM colonialism that was done in
a middle heat Mideast again his pagans
okay I'm not too sure about that it's
not be too harsh okay this is a
sensitive topic and dark dark Francaise
Christianity or engine Aidid as a Roman
or ancient colonial propaganda against
Middle East okay okay I don't know for
sure and then says outsider's
perspective is usually very illuminating
okay well X stock trains so were you
from you have to say were you from so he
was you know get to know where you
coming from you know when you make
strong you know statements then says I'm
sure you can find good Wikipedia article
all those branches yeah but usually they
are overwhelming you know you look up
Wikipedia on Christian ology then it's
like forty fifty pages with you know
with hundred links branching off you
know like see detail these days you know
it's like that I have done that before
and also if your life is not tied to
these things you forget you forgot you
know you you forgot after you read them
so X dot Prince says mono thesis schisms
are like corporations getting
splitting up and driving force of
usually pursuit of colonial power and
parasitism facets of Kelowna loot
okay that's strong opinions okay so
doctrine says Christianity and Islam are
basically called colonial isms
well I wouldn't say that
you know I because you know even though
I don't those are not religions I
believe in but to say them was
colonialism that's that's kind of like
biased view I mean even though I I could
you know I could agree with you because
it's but but still I think it I think it
would be biased because any religion you
know Buddhism or any giant religion you
can you can call them all to be
colonialism you know because they are
Asian that's how human that's how human
we struggle for power or we you know
like you don't even have to say religion
you can say you know that you can apply
this color you can say anything is
called colonialism when when you speak
so you know that's what we do human
animals you know we can say we also as
animal species we also colonial eyes the
whole earth you see we we keep we bred
cows pigs we bred and eat them we you
have pets you know whose whole life
lives in your house and don't want to do
anything else they and they are happy
that's you know we are as a species we
are colonialism okay let's read what
Wikipedia say what definition okay
colonialism is the policy of a nation
seeking to extend or retain its
authority over the people or territories
yeah okay
so general generally with the aim of
economic dominance okay yeah so you know
if you say religion you know if you say
you know particularly children is that
that's kind of biased you know because
any big successful religion or
organizations is colonialism that
applies you know the said advice so mark
ok Maxime says Eastern Orthodox branched
off about one thousand years ago and
Protestants with Lewis Luther later ok
yeah so those are two big names that I
get confused
the your sentence seems ambiguous so
Eastern Orthodox branched off from what
from from where from which from Catholic
or Protestant and Protestants with
Luther later yeah that's so vague so
Luther is from where like sub Protestant
Protestants is a branch off from Luther
and where is Luther branch off from hey
so your sentence
it's I I'm pretty sure it's very clear
to you it's slowly confusing to me Oh
so also ducks by name means is not from
Catholics okay so it's so Catholics was
a branch okay so the still totally I'm
totally confused oh I know okay let me
try to summarize what I know oh I know
is this Catholics and there's protest
ins okay these two are like big - and
somewhere later than this moment's I
think it's a branch of Protestants you
could say that that's all right that's
that's basically where I know ok so then
there's this Eastern Orthodox so we
where where is it branching off from and
there is this Luther
where is it venturing off from you know
so I don't understand you know okay
so John Dewey says you have dig no point
in waiting without exact time Oh Jean
Jean Louise hi John Lewis is for master
Dan so you are saying the link did not
automatically update no point in waiting
without know I later no I did okay we
are talking about YouTube you know young
YouTube we I had a problem where I know
normally when you do a live stream you
can have a URL to send it to people so
people know Oh people when people go to
your channel they they will see you know
there's a live stream scheduled at
certain time and for me excuse me
hold on a second so wait okay so so for
me I never said that you know I never
got the URL but today I did thanks to
John Lewis who got me to do that so so
we were talking about that so so next
time whenever I'm going to do a live I
mean if you go to my channel I should
and now I know how to set it up so that
you know you got a URL in fact I think
the URL will always just be this one
this one this one you know youtube.com
slash C / sorry / life I think anyway
I'm getting better at this
let's get back to the comments and let's
see how long I've been talking what okay
I've been talking for 15 minutes so if
you guys have any questions you can just
post it maybe we will ended soon okay so
yes of course that is purely colonialism
okay so John we say is John Dewey says
that is why I do not join any
governments or similar suppressive
organizations okay auto docks by name
means it's not from Catholics
okay Catholics was a branch okay sure
Orthodox means unchanged okay so yeah I
read that Orthodox is the me it means
the original Church started by Jesus
supposed to be right that's I think
that's what it's supposed to be so both
Russian is also dogs
huge oh okay by the way were you from
John Lewis like what country are you so
you from Russian
Oh Christian energy is basically Jewish
is a so then why why why is there you
know the Jewish region Judaism yeah okay
so in doctrine says there are natural
religions akka paganism monotheism that
militates again his nature does not
compare what do you mean militate
military or metered okay Maxim says
Catholic late Catholics
let Rome to have a pope and Orthodox got
their head of church from Constantine
poor so either say what orthodoxy is a
branch of Christianity
okay oh my god this is getting really
you know complex you know involving all
this history constant yeah so that's
that is why it's very confusing so now
quote Co Co Co Co she all right that's
how you pronounce it kosher M near
Russia oh so you are from kosher let's
see how you how you pronounce that
and so Kashia is in Eastern Europe oh
wow yeah I guess let's see Wikipedia
cool
quake aisha Croatia something like that
so is a country at the crossroads of
Central and Southeast Europe
okay so Hungary so okay yeah there Oh
the frak is that interesting flag I
don't remember seeing this FAC you know
you got this you know race you know race
cause three motive in the middle that is
the this flag so let's see if I we if we
have C oh oh yeah so okay so that's yeah
that's a caution flag okay all these
talks about religion protest protesting
Tizen and other branches started around
1500 okay John says is in Bible Bible
was written for Jewish people not for
others okay the Western people who are
not Jewish found is suitable to
manipulate everybody okay
the Bible is advised
can I pagan religion okay so same stock
trains you don't like these religions
very much but you have to give some
information about yourself like where
you from
yeah I don't think I you know you never
said you have you know say a country you
know say a country at least mark same
says
Croatia okay so John Lewis says I'm a
cousin love wait oh this all these words
I don't understand I was willing you go
slow so yeah okay
great so we have a lot Cosmopolitan's
you know constable Politan is a
interesting word now is is cosmopolite
is that an english word or is it just no
it's not an English word you we say in
English I guess we say cosmopolitan you
know you don't say Kozma for late
let's look up let's see you know so
cosmopolitan that's an interesting word
but there's this magazine girls magazine
using that word it's become something
else
let's see dictionary okay a person who
is cosmopolitan in his or her ideas okay
so that is a English word Cosmo for
light okay Cosmo polite so you are
cosmopolite because you you you is you
are a cosmopolitan okay right see the
citizen of the world
okay so we are talking about religions
you know cosmos you know yeah these are
the topics about religions you know you
guys are not giving me a coherent answer
but maybe because there is no cookie
Vanessa because I were asking you know
the the branch branch how the the the
branches of Christianity but so far from
the various supplies the answers are
confusing so I don't get the picture but
probably because there is no you know
from the look of it there's no like easy
picture one can give you know actually
there I think there is you know you need
to you know you need to ask some of the
you know some people some of the experts
then they can give you kind of a like
outline you know when you give an
outline simplified version it's always
not correct you know some people will
say oh no that's wrong because but
however you see when you know when
wherever anything is given in a summary
or a line it's you know almost by you
know you know sense by definition is
incorrect it's like statistics or
stereotype you know today there's
certain group of people they say oh you
said you are Steve you're typing you are
wrong but however studio typing is is
like it's it's like the cream of
statistics you know it gives you you
know if you have to say certain subject
in one sentence so you know in one
picture
that's what statistics are you know a or
stereotype are that so you know since
that is actually you can say like in
math it's like actually a theory you
know it gives you the you know in one
word it condenses the whole thing into
one picture one word that's what
statistics or theories or you know
stereotypes are about
so anyways yeah so we rambled here and
over there and here we were talking
about let's talk about so there's this
you know let's change your subject you
know this so there is this voice input
for programmers
you know the software is called Talent
voice so you might try it today it seems
it has matured so you know check it out
so if you are you know programmer you
type a lot you hurt your hands this
could be very handy and I suppose you
know as us goes by this will be very
popular or mainstream because you know
the voice technology gets better and
better so it's worth checking out you
know he's doing encoding with voice
input so yeah so check that out and let
me put the links here
yeah that you know for new systems yeah
okay so John Lewis you are open-source
fan right thank did you know that I'm
not too much of open source fan yeah
because if you have seen my old pictures
I mean my my YouTube talk shows I a lot
of them I have flamed again East open
source and also by the way I was a open
source I was a free software foundation
phonetic okay so you are a free stuff
well it's kind of this it's not the same
though you know I mentioned this many
times in my talk show like some some of
my talk show like I rent for an hour
about this topic you know open source
and free software you know III was a
free software and Richard Stallman
phonetic you know and today not so much
you know I so anyway I don't want to
talk about that again because I've been
talking about that so very often in my
in my talk shows and also because you
know I'm you know what I do
you almost oh you know in my past 20
years you know I'm doing open so open
source stuff you know Emacs Python Perl
you know open source stuff Linux you
know UNIX so my readers my father's
tends to be all the you know the open
source or free software you know though
these cool peel people so anyway so any
anyway voice input yeah so if you know
if you want you know the open source
version usually it's hard but anyway go
to their website they show I don't know
if there is a open source version that's
workable like almost it's like Linux you
know like when you do Linux or anything
open source you know it's usually the
case that almost everything you do
especially when it comes to video audio
it's prob it's a problem you know you're
going to spend days you know to you know
find the right software of
bugs you know that you know things like
that on the other hand if you are on
Windows or Mac it's almost like it's
there you know you can just use it you
know so yeah so you got open source but
then you got you know you have all these
problems you know pros and cons anyway
so that's not good you know let's go
into that topic because then I'm going
to just I'm gonna talk for an hour about
that the open source in my R and again
about open source and free software
foundation because I you know because
really I'm deeply part of it and it's
not a happy story you know it's a anyway
so I think we are about to end because
we have been talking for an hour now
yeah yeah so so a few last thing
anything else you guys want to talk
about just type it open source can be
proprietary free software is different
no that is you didn't say it correctly
okay
free software I'm starting to go into
that direction
okay I can give you a definition with
free software is mostly about ethics
ethical quality you you want people to
have this ethical quality share software
which includes part of it includes that
meaning that the software must be open
source okay but that's not the focus the
focus is not about open source code it's
about is basically a more o oriented
perspective you want to share you want
to encourage people to share so we can
all share and grow together that's the
focus of free software foundation their
idea of free software open source is
about open source is about open source
code but not proprietary because by
definition when a source code is open
source you know they have licenses there
the open-source organization they define
what license is open source you can you
know say it's open source okay so when
you are open source it's not proprietary
if you its proprietary it's not
technically it's not open source but
however open source software you could
have like you could have open you know
you could have you could have you may
have patents and you may have you know
written trademarks you know like you
know things like that Google Facebook
you know Apple they are all and it today
Microsoft they are all big proponents of
open source they embrace you guys they
the waters one open source meanwhile
they are the most evil okay I'm gonna
stop going over there my my rants again
is sort of moving sauce so I never tried
the Talon voice actually I never tried
you know so that that video is not by me
so but it's worth checking out so I'm
just saying we can look let's have a
look you know since we are let's go have
a look-see
so Talon so they say okay dependencies
dragon 6 which is commercial on Windows
I think I'm not sure I think they also
have a Mac version but it may not be
supported anymore and also dragon they
have mini versions like each year or
every few years they have a new version
you know some of them early versions you
can buy on Amazon very cheap you know
five dollars but usually the latest
version is something like forty dollars
I think I never I never used it I have
of I had a friend who had dragon anyway
so there is dragon now Toby 4c I'm not
sure what it is let's have a look
Amazon so what is this Toby I tracker
foresee the game-changing eye tracking
peripheral okay so this is about using
eye-tracking or some mouse you know
that's another thing very interesting
hold on a second oh so okay so this is
for Mac only I guess so so I guess you
are not on a Mac yeah so you are not
lucky but typically I wouldn't be I
wouldn't be using it neither but however
I think I think there is more than one
Talent
okay did there's more you can look into
like go to this link now this this one
is done in 2003 you know check it out
there's a video by this guy and in
general like just search for voice input
like I've seen a few like in recent
years it looks like they are going you
know this technology okay I think that's
that's it for today we've been talking
for how yeah so how many people I got
six people
okay that's it for today thank you guys
thank you Luis and who else is here
thanks thanks John and bye guys
say I'm watching yeah