[music]
I can't tell you what I feel.
[musica]
Non so cosa dire.
I just [music] can't live without you.
Voglio che tu rimanga.  [music]
[music]
Don't look at me fade away.
I'm reaching something [music] in the
rain.
I just can't lose all the battles.
Solo una parte [la musica] può vincere.
I'm renegade.
Non andartene.
No love will change our fate.
I'm renegade.
[music]
Don't go away.
No woman will replace your place.
[music]
Don't talk to me that way.
As I tremble on [music] the phone.
You make arrows out of poisoned words.
You already fall the call.
[music]
We are strangers to each other.
Far from home and yet together.  [music]
Just acting rehearsed routines
with so [music] much space in between.
I'm renegade.
Non andartene.
No lovers will change your fate.
[music]
I'm renegade.
Non andartene.
Nessuna donna sostituirà la tua lama.
Your blade.
[music]
I'm renegade.
Non andartene.
No lovers [music]
will change your
fate.
I'm renegade.
Non lasciare che la musica se ne vada.
Nessuna donna sostituirà la tua lama.
Sono un ribelle [in ambito musicale].
No lovers will
change your
[music]
fate.
I'm renegade.
Non andartene.
[music]
I'm renegade.  [musica]
[musica]